Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
- You're just scared.
- Of course l'm scared.
Last time we were here,
33.3 bar per cent of us were flayed alive.
Nice job.
Do you have any idea
how hard it's been to act this cool?
That death thing was all part
of the master plan.
lf Short Round pulls off his end
of the bargain, we'll both become gods.
(Dawn) l saw Mom.
- Things are coming, Dawn.
- Why are you...?
When it's bad, Buffy won't choose you.
- lt wasn't her.
- What?
lt's the Big Bad, Dawn.
The one we knew was coming.
What the hell happened?
This big evil that's been promising to devour
us - well, l think it's started chomping.
- Oh, God.
- Buffy, this thing knows us.
lt made us think
that we were talking to people we knew.
l'm just a guy with his ear to the ground,
but even l can feel it.
Something's coming. l don't know
what exactly, but something's brewing.
And it's so big, ugly and damned, it makes
you and me look like little bitty puzzle pieces.
Buffy, he's been feeding... on human blood.
That's gotta do stuff.
l think there was something there,
talking to him, making him do things.
# How could you use a poor maiden...
Spike!
l remember.
l've killed, and l can feel 'em.
l can feel every one of 'em.
There's something playing with us.
- Why is it doing this to me?
- l don't know.
- Help me.
- l'll help you.
This thing has been closer to Spike
than any of us.
- And if you wanna understand it....
- l'm gonna have to get close to Spike.
Robson, are you here?
Robson!
- Dear God, l thought you...
- Gather them.
- What?
- lt's started.
lt's all right. l understand. l'll take care...
- So the basement was filled with bodies?
- Apparently.
And Spike could've sired countless others
and buried them around town.
And we're waiting for him to do what,
exactly? Do something crazy?
lt's not that simple.
Shouldn't we stab him in the chest? lsn't that
what we do when these things happen?
- Look, Buffy knows what she's doing.
- Xander, you know what we're talking about.
You've always been part
of the "Spike is evil" faction.
l've got a house to put back together.
Fine. You guys keep your heads
buried in the sand,
but we should prepare for the possibility
that William the Bloody is back.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Right. Looking good.
How do you feel?
- Good.
- Excellent. We've got work to do.
Do l have to do work right now? Can't l
just walk around for a while in my coat?
Don't go soft on me now. We're right in
the trench, and the exhaust port's in sight.
l thought that was it. l did what you told me.
lt's not my fault it didn't work.
- Why do l have to do all the wet work?
- Hey!
You know the rules.
l can't take corporeal form. Here. Feel.
- Cool.
- Pretty bitchin', right?
- l'm like Obi-Wan.
- Or Patrick Swayze.
Believe me,
l would do this stuff if l could.
l can't.
l need you. You're my iron fist.
l just don't think l can kill anybody else.
- Will you stop worrying about that?
- l didn't want to kill you. Warren made me.
Hey, l'm glad he did. This is the best thing
that's ever happened to me.
lt didn't hurt too much?
l'm not very good at stabbing.
You know, it wasn't that bad.
lt was like a sharp pain, then a burning,
then a general queasiness.
lt was like getting ulcers in high school, only
at the end l became one with light and hope.
l can't do it. l can't do it any more.
Hey, this isn't your fault, OK?
lt's my fault the ritual didn't work.
l screwed up.
l'm little. l don't have
as much blood as other people.
And l probably should've
told someone l was anaemic.
Don't worry. We're gonna fix it.
You gotta trust us.
We know what we're doing.
- l can't kill anybody else.
- OK, calm down. We can work around that.
We're gonna get to the bottom of this.
We just can't take any chances.
Don't.
Make it tighter. The knots will give.
lf l get free, someone's gonna die.
Now, guys, look,
we can settle this one of two ways.
You can repaint the walls, or...
l can suspend you and report this
little incident on your permanent record.
Fine. Do that.
OK, l was bluffing.
l hadn't really thought that one through.
Listen, this whole
permanent-record thing is a myth.
Colleges never ask for
anything past SAT scores.
lt's not like employers are gonna call to check
how many days you missed in high school.
So, listen, l could suspend you,
but that would mean calling your parents,
alerting your teachers,
filling out paperwork and quite possibly
having to talk to the school board.
All of which sounds
positively exhausting to me.
No.
No, l think it would be much easier
if l just called the police.
Let them deal with it.
Oh, and, in case you were wondering,
this is the part where l'm not bluffing.
- We'll repaint it.
- Good job.
(knock at door)
Excuse me.
Miss Summers. l'm with students.
l just wanted to tell you that Buffy
won't be in today. She's sick.
Oh, no.
Yeah. Last night she was vomiting.
This morning she was vomiting more,
and then, just when we thought
she was done, she started vomiting again.
Yeah, we got that stomach flu going around.
Her exact words were
"l've got stuff coming out of both ends."
Thank you.
That's... very helpful.
Sure. No problem.
- Hey, guys. How's it going?
- Pretty good.
Tell your sister not to worry about it.
We'll soldier on without her here.
Just... tell her to concentrate
on getting better.
Yeah, she'll be fine. She just needs
to get some stuff out of her system.
l need to find him as soon as possible.
He's not answering any of his numbers.
Miss Summers, the Watchers' Council does
not keep track of our lapsed employees.
Ever since Mr Giles
pulled up his stake in Sunnydale,
we've not made it our business
to follow his every move.
You don't need to get all British and dodgy.
l know you have ways of finding him.
l suppose if you feel the matter's urgent,
we can look into it.
- l'd appreciate it. Thank you.
- Not at all. Good day.
The girl knows nothing.
And we need to find Rupert Giles.
As soon as possible.
(breathes jerkily)
Can l do something?
l think you should probably g...
(groans)
Here.
(snarls and growls)
He's been feasting on humans for weeks.
He's having some pretty bad withdrawals.
- l think we need to get him some blood.
- Do you want me to kill Anya?
No.
We should probably try
to wean him off humans.
- He'll have to make do with animal blood.
- l'll go get some.
- You don't mind?
- No, l have to get out of the house.
Xander's installing the new windows and he
keeps giving lectures on tool maintenance.
Tool talk - not my thing.
Thank you.
How are you doin' in there?
He's in pretty bad shape, past the point
where he can tell me anything.
- l wasn't asking about him.
- l'll be OK.
(Warren) She won't feel a thing.
Just do it. Fast.
Cut her deep. Cut her quick.
lt'll be over before she knows what hit her.
- What if she squeals?
- Better go for her throat first.
(squeals)
Babe 2: Pig in the City was underrated.
- Don't think about Babe.
- Right.
You're Conan. You're the Destroyer.
lt's you against nature.
You're the hunter. You're primal.
You live off the land. You're Andrew.
Everyone knows you.
You play by your own rules.
- lt's kill or be killed.
- That'll do, pig!
(pig squeals)
You gotta corner it.
- Stay between it and the hall, or...
- (pig squeals)
That's the worst attempted
pig slaughtering l've ever seen.
l'm not very good at stabbing. lsn't there
some other way we could get blood?
Number 87.
l'd like 12 pork chops...
two pounds of sausage...
eight quarts of pig's blood,
three steaks, um...
halibut, and uh...
some toothpaste...
This is a butcher's shop, Neo.
We don't sell toothpaste.
Um...
OK, just the other stuff then.
You got it.
Hi.
Ooh, steak sauce.
(butcher) Number 88.
Wait a minute!
- Don't kill me!
- l'm not gonna kill you.
Don't send me
to an eternal pain dimension.
- l'm not gonna.
- Warren killed Tara.
l didn't do it.
And he was aiming for Buffy anyway.
- Not making it better.
- And you got your revenge.
You killed my best friend. We're even.
Even? You think l get satisfaction
from what l did?
Maybe not, but let me keep my skin, OK?
l'm not bad. l'm not bad any more.
l'm good. l do good things now.
Then why do you need
lots and lots of blood?
l am bad. l'm bad, l'm evil,
but l'm protected by powerful forces.
Forces you can't even begin
to imagine... little girl.
lf you harm me you shall know the wrath
of he that is darkness and terror.
Your blood will boil.
You will know true suffering.
Stand down, she-witch.
Your defeat is at hand...
Shut your mouth.
l am a she-witch.
A very powerful she-witch.
Or "witch", as is more accurate.
l am not to be trifled with...
- But l...
- l'm talking. Don't interrupt me.
lnsignificant man.
l am Willow. l am death.
lf you dare defy me, l will call down my fury,
exact fresh vengeance,
and make your worst fears come true.
OK?
- Look who l found.
- Oh, this can't be good.
Guess who was buying
mass amounts of blood.
- Your hair's not even black any more.
- What're you doing back in town?
- You'll get nothin' out of me, carpenter.
- We'll see about that.
- Careful with my coat. lt's expensive.
- ls it new?
Hey. Ow!
Now, we can do this
the hard way, if you want.
But believe me when l tell you,
this will go much easier
- if you just tell us what... you... know.
- Ow!
You're barkin' up the wrong asparagus.
l don't know anything.
Here's the thing. l don't believe you.
l haven't done anything wrong.
Then you won't mind
if we ask a few questions.
Yeah, OK.
Why were you buying blood
at the butcher shop?
l fell in love with a vampire in Mexico.
Now we're trying to make a go of it on
the straight and narrow, here in Sunnydale.
You think this is a game, junior?
People are dying.
- Friends' lives are in danger.
- Hey, Anya.
Now you wanna waste my time
with deceptions? Not on my watch!
Hey, Anya!
Can l talk to you outside for a second?
Did you see that?
l actually made him cry.
You were perfect. l worried l overdid it
with the "hard way" thing.
No, you were great!
l wasn't sure if l should slap him,
but then he made me want to,
so l thought "OK."
- He'll be singing in no time.
- What do we do now?
We let him stew in his own juices for a bit,
then we give him the hard brace.
Right. What's the status with your guy?
He's not talking yet.
We'll get there. How's your guy?
The weasel wants to sing.
He just needs a tune.
He's primed.
l'll be pumping him in no time.
He'll give us information soon.
Better?
Good.
l don't remember anything.
- You were having a pretty bad withdrawal.
- No, not that.
l don't remember... what l did.
- Nothing?
- Some flashes here and there.
lt's like l'm watching someone else...
do it, kill people.
l've been losing time for a while now.
Waking up in strange places.
When did your chip stop working?
l wasn't aware that it had, you know.
Not till now.
And the losing time?
How long has that been going on?
Oh, things have been wonky for me
ever since l got back. Ever since...
You got your soul.
l figured that's what it was like.
Been so long since l had one.
How did you do it?
How'd you get your soul back?
Saw a man about a girl.
l went to seek a legend out.
Travelled to the other side of the world,
made a deal with a demon.
- Just like that?
- No, notjust like that. There was a price.
There were trials.
Torture.
Pain and suffering... of sorts.
- Of sorts?
- Well, it's all relative, isn't it?
Meaning?
l have come to redefine the words "pain
and suffering" since l fell in love with you.
How can you say that?
l just slaughtered half of Sunnydale. l'm not
really worried about being polite any more.
So that's what this is about.
- You're feeling sorry for yourself, Spike?
- l'm feeling honest with myself.
You used me.
Yes.
You told me that, of course.
l never understood it though.
Not until now.
You hated yourself,
and you took it out on me.
You figured that outjust now?
A soul's not all about moonbeams
and penny whistles, love.
lt's about self-loathing.
l get it. l had to travel
around the world, but...
l understand you now.
- l understand the violence inside.
- Violence?
William the Bloody
now has insight into violence?
Not the same.
As bad as l was, as evil and as wretched
as l was, l never truly hated myself back then.
Not like l do now.
- How's your face?
- OK.
Sorry about that.
She shouldn't have hit you.
OK.
Thirsty? Go on.
That chick's psycho.
You don't know the half of it.
She's a vengeance demon, you know.
She's bad news.
This one time
l saw her having sex with Spike.
- She's killed more men than smallpox.
- Does it still kill people?
She's killed a lot of men.
She tortures them.
Anyone who incurs her wrath.
One time she...
- Never mind.
- What?
- lt's not important.
- What did she do?
Well, there was this one guy.
There was this one guy.
He hurt her real bad, so she paid him back.
She killed him, but she did it real slow.
See, first she stopped his heart,
and then she replaced it with darkness,
then made him live his life like that.
But he still had to go do his job
and see his friends
and wake up in the morning
and go to bed at night,
but he had to do it all... empty.
Without anything to look forward to. Ever.
- Sounds bad.
- Well, then she tore out his intestines,
- rubbed it in his face and took pictures.
- God.
But she's downstairs.
Don't worry about her.
- What if...
- See, the thing is,
we've all been a little on edge lately.
Bad things have been happening. The girls
are all looking for someone to blame.
- l didn't do anything.
- (Anya) You lying son of a bitch!
You're gonna tell us
what we need to know, now!
- Anya, no!
- Stop it!
Get off me, Harris!
- Come here, you pipsqueak!
- Xander, get her off me! l'll tell you!
l'll tell you what you need to know!
Excuse me.
Well.
We've got ourselves a problem.
(Andrew) Somebody help. Ow!
Everything OK?
Fine.
OK.
(Spike) What'd l do, get it half-done?
Never send a boy to do a man's job.
è Oh, don't deceive me
è Oh, never leave me
- Who were you talking to?
- What's that?
l heard you.
Who were you talking to?
Nobody. l was just
keeping myself company.
- Are you OK?
- Fine.
How are you?
You could talk, or l could keep hitting you.
Believe me, l'd love to keep hitting you.
- Spike?
- l'm fine, Buffy. Really.
l'm just... feeling a bit peckish,
l suppose.
Do you mind?
We needed more blood
to activate the Seal of Dan...
Argh! Argh!
He didn't seem to want
anything to do with me.
He just pushed me aside
and charged at the wall.
- Are you hurt?
- Not really.
How's whatshisname?
He's got a chunk taken out of his neck
but he'll be all right.
Had to tie him up again but mainly to
keep him from scratching at his bandages.
- What the hell happened up there?
- l don't know.
Spike and l were having a conversation,
and he was fine.
l mean, you know, fine as Spike can be.
Then l went to check on you guys,
and when l got back, it was...
like he was a completely different person.
Different like
William-the-Bloody-type different?
He was talking to someone. l heard through
the door. He was having this conversation.
- And then he started singing.
- Maybe it's another musical.
- A much crappier musical.
- He mentioned a song in the cellar.
He changed there too.
lnstantly became another person.
Trigger.
- The horse?
- No, in his head.
lt's a trigger.
lt's a brainwashing term.
lt's how the military makes sleeper agents.
They brainwash operatives and condition
them with a specific trigger, like a song,
that makes 'em drastically change
at a moment's notice.
ls this left over from your days in the army?
No, this is left over from every army movie
l've ever seen. But it makes sense.
We've had ghosts
or something haunting us, right?
Well, what if Spike's ghosts have figured out
a way to - not only haunt him -
what if they figured out how to control him?
Spike's been seeing things
since l found him in the basement.
So he gets his soul back, he starts seeing
spooky things, and he goes extra-extra-crazy.
This trigger. How do we...
holster or... safety or...
l don't know guns.
How do we make it stop?
Usually, the operative completes his task
and either blows his head off
or steals a submarine.
l need information. lf Spike's a bomb,
l need to know how to defuse him.
l wanna know what did this to him.
Spirits, ghosts, demons - check the lot.
Look for anything that could haunt
or possibly control like this.
l need to know what we're dealing with.
Did l hurt anybody?
You took a good bite out of Andrew.
Who?
Tucker's brother.
Oh.
He'll be OK.
l don't remember.
lt's OK.
Buffy, l don't know why.
We think we do.
Something's playing you.
Some ghost or demon
has figured out how to control you.
Got the gang researching it right now.
Xander has this theory
that you're being triggered.
Kill mm.
- What?
- Buffy, you have to kill me.
You don't understand.
When l left the room, l heard you talking to...
Do you have any idea what l'm capable of?
l was in the cellar with you.
l saw what you did.
l'm not talking about the cellar.
The people in the cellar got off easy.
l'm talking about me.
Buffy, you've never met the real me.
- l'm well aware of what you're capable of.
- No. You got off easy too.
Do you know how much blood you can drink
from a girl before she'll die? l do.
You see, the trick is to drinkjust enough,
to know how to damage them just enough
so that they'll still cry when you...
Cos it's not worth it if they don't cry.
lt's not your fault.
You're not the one doing this.
l already did it. lt's already done.
You wanna know
what l've done to girls Dawn's age?
This is me, Buffy.
You've got to kill me before l get out.
We can keep you locked up.
Keep you here and we'll figure it out.
Have you ever really asked yourself
why you can't do it? Off me?
After everything l've done to you,
to people around you.
lt's not love. We both know that.
You fought by my side.
You've saved lives. You've helped...
Don't do that.
Don't rationalise this into some noble act.
Because we both know the truth of it.
You like men who hurt you.
No.
You need the pain we cause you.
You need the hate.
You need it to do yourjob, to be the Slayer.
No.
l don't hate like that.
Not you... or myself.
Not any more.
You think you have insight now
because your soul's drenched in blood?
You don't know me.
You don't even know you.
Was that you who killed those people in the
cellar? Was it you who waited for those girls?
- There's no one else.
- That's not true.
Listen to me.
You're not alive because of hate or pain.
You're alive because l saw you change.
Because l saw your penance.
Window-dressing.
Be easier, wouldn't it, if it were an act.
But it's not.
You faced the monster inside of you
and you fought back.
- You risked everything to be a better man.
- Buffy...
And you can be.
You are.
You may not see it, but l do.
l do.
l believe in you, Spike.
- (Xander) Buffy!
- Dawn?
She's OK. ls this it?
l thought there was more of 'em.
Spike.
(Xander) They were so fast.
And organised.
They were after Spike all along.
And we were just in the way.
l know these guys.
l've fought them before.
We aren't being haunted.
This isn't some demon.
lt's all the same thing.
Spike's ghosts, the people
that you guys saw, "from beneath us..."
lt's all the same thing.
l know what we're up against.
The First.
(man) They took our files,
wiped out our records.
We've lost contact with operations
in Munich, Switzerland and Rome.
We've got casualty confirmations
coming in from as far away as Melbourne.
Sir, we are crippled.
lt's all right, Lydia.
We are still masters of our fate.
We are still captains of our souls.
Yes, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Our fears have been confirmed.
The First Evil has declared
all-out war on this institution.
The first volleys proved most effective.
l, for one, think it's time we struck back.
Get me confirmations
on all remaining operatives.
Visuals and tacticals.
Highest alert.
Get them here as soon as possible.
Begin preparations for mobilisation.
Once we're accounted for,
l want to be ready to move.
- Sir?
- We'll be paying a visit to the Hellmouth.
"My friends,
these are the times that define us."
Proverbs 24:6.
"For by wise counsel
you shall make your war."
You'll have to excuse the spectacle,
but l've always been
a bit of a sucker for the old classics.
Argh!
Oh!
Oh, don't look at me that way.
l wanted to do this more subtle-like.
My harbingers have a tendency
to call attention to themselves.
Argh!
You're the one who couldn't hold
his end of the bargain,
who couldn't take care of whatshisname,
who had to make breakthroughs
and learn something about himself.
Oh!
So now, fittingly, you're the one
who gets to do the honours.
l have to admit,
l'm glad it worked out this way.
l was going to bleed Andrew,
but you look a lot better with your shirt off.
To be honest,
l'm getting a little tired of subtle.
l think it's about time we brought
some authority to our presence.
Now, Spike, you wanna see
what a real vampire looks like?
(chanting)
(roars)
Visiontext Subtitles: Abigail Smith
Urgh! Argh!
ENGLlSH SDH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org