(# Cari Howe - "Anything"
by Sean Clement and Sean Murray)
# Lyin' down, givin' in to you...
Le hippo a piqué ton pantalon,
# I'm a hurricane
# I can't describe this feelin'...
# Now that I've found this love
- Do you really think you're ready, Buffy?
- What?
# I'll do anything for you
# Now that I've found this love
# I'm a fire
# Burnin' like a house aflame
# I am motionless
# I cannot move
# I only see you fly
# Now that I've found...
- Angel!
# this love...
Happy birthday, Buffy.
"Surprise" Part 1
Hold on.
Hey.
- Is everything OK?
- That's what I was gonna ask you.
You're OK, right?
Sure... I'm fine.
What's up?
I had this... dream
that Drusilla was alive.
What happened?
She killed you. Right in front of me.
It was just a dream. It wasn't real.
- But it felt so real.
- It wasn't.
I'm right here.
Angel, this-this happened before.
The dreams I had about the Master.
They came true.
Still, not every dream you have
comes true.
I mean, what else
did you dream last night?
Can you remember?
I dreamt... I dreamt that Giles and I
opened an office-supply
warehouse in Vegas.
You see my point?
Yeah, I do, but...
what if Drusilla is alive?
- We never saw her body.
- She's not.
But even if she was, we'd deal.
But what if she's...
What if what?
I'm sorry. Were we talking?
I'm sorry. I, um...
- I-I have to go to school.
- I know.
God, you feel...
You have to go to school.
All right. I know.
This is me. I'm going.
You still haven't told me
what you wanted for your birthday.
- Surprise me.
- OK.
I will.
This is nice.
I like seeing you
first thing in the morning.
It's bedtime for me.
Well, then, I like
seeing you at bedtime. Um...
Um... Y-You know what I mean.
I think so.
What do you mean?
I like seeing you.
And the part at the end of the night
where we say goodbye?
It's getting harder.
Yeah... It is.
"I like you at bedtime"?
You actually said that?
- I know. I know.
- Man, that's like... I don't know.
- That's moxie or somethin'.
- Totally unplanned. It just... came out.
And he was into it?
He wants to see you at bedtime, too?
Yeah, I-I think he does.
I mean, he's cool about it.
Well, of course he is.
'Cause he's cool.
I mean, he would never, you know...
- Push.
- Right. He's not the type.
- Willow, what am I gonna do?
- What do you wanna do?
I don't know. I... I mean,
"want" isn't always the right thing to do.
To act on want can be wrong.
- True.
- But... to not act on want...
What if I never feel this way again?
Carpe diem! You told me that once.
- "Fish of the day"?
- Not "carp"!
Carpe - it means "seize the day".
Right.
I... I think we're going to.
Seize it.
Once you get to a certain point,
then seizing is sort of inevitable.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
Wow.
Wow!
- Wow.
- Yeah.
Hey, speaking of "wow" potential,
there's Oz over there.
What are we thinking?
Any sparkage?
He's nice... Hey, I like his hands.
Mm. A fixation on insignificant detail
is a definite crush sign.
Well, I don't know, though.
I mean, he is a senior.
You think he's too old
'cause he's a senior?
Please! My boyfriend
had a bicentennial.
That's true. Uh... I guess... I just...
You can't spend the rest of your life
waiting for Xander
to wake up and smell the hottie.
Make a move. Do the talking thing.
What if the talking thing becomes
the awkward silence thing?
Well, you won't know until you try.
- Hey.
- Hey!
- Do you guys, uh... have a gig tonight?
- Oh. No. Practice.
See, our band's kinda movin' towards
this new sound where...
we suck, so... practice.
- I think you guys sound good.
- Thanks.
I bet you have a lot of groupies.
It happens... I'm livin'
groupie-free nowadays. I'm clean.
Oh.
I'm gonna ask you
to go out with me tomorrow night.
And I'm kinda nervous about it, actually.
It's interesting.
Oh. Well, if it helps at all,
I'm gonna say yes.
Yeah, it helps.
It-It creates a comfort zone.
Do you wanna go out with me
tomorrow night?
Oh! I can't!
Well, see, I like
that you're unpredictable.
Oh, it's just it's Buffy's birthday,
and we're throwing her a surprise party.
- That's OK.
- But you could come. If you wanted.
- Well, I don't wanna crash.
- No, it's fine.
You could be... my date.
All right. I'm in.
I said "date"!
So, Buffy's party.
Mañana,
Well, just because she's
Miss Save-The-World and everything,
you have to make a big deal?
I have to cook! And everything!
- You're cooking?
- I'm chips-and-dips girl.
Huh! Horrors!
All that opening and stirring.
- And shopping and carrying!
- Well, then you should have a person
who does such things for you.
Well, that's what I've been saying
to my father, but does he listen?
Um... So... Uh...
You're going, and...
and... and I'm going.
- Should... we maybe... go?
- Why?
I don't know. This... thing with us,
despite our better judgement,
keeps happening. Maybe we should
just admit we're dating.
Groping in a broom closet isn't dating.
You don't call it a date
- until the guy spends money.
- Fine. I'll spend, then we'll grope.
Whatever. I just think
it's some kind of whacked
that we feel we have to
hide it from all our friends.
Well, of course you wanna tell everybody.
You have nothing to be ashamed of.
I, on the other hand,
have everything to be ashamed of.
You know what? Enough said.
Forget it.
Must have been my
multiple-personality guy talking.
I call him "Idiot Jed",
glutton for punishment.
Oh, good morning.
Is everything in order for the party?
Absolutely. You ready to get down,
you funky party weasel?
Here comes Buffy. Now remember:
discretion is the better part of valor.
You could've just said "Sh". God!
Are all you Brits such drama queens?
Buffy! I feel a pre-birthday
spankin' comin' on.
I'd curb that impulse
if I were you, Xander.
Check. Cancel spanking.
- You all right, Buffy? You seem fatigued.
- Rough night.
I had a dream that Drusilla was alive,
and she killed Angel.
It just really freaked me out.
- You fear it was more of a, a, a portent?
- See, I don't know.
I don't wanna start
a big freak-out over nothing.
Still, best to be uh... on the alert.
If Drusilla is alive, then it could be
a fairly cataclysmic state of affairs.
Again, so many words. Couldn't you
just say "we'd be in trouble"?
- Go to class, Xander.
- Gone.
Notice the economy of phrasing.
"Gone". It's simple. Direct.
- Maybe I should get gone, too.
- Don't worry unduly, Buffy.
I'm sure it's nothing.
I know. I should
keep my slayer cool, but...
It's Angel, which
automatically equals maxi-wig.
I have your package.
Just put it on the table,
near the other gifts.
Are you dead set on this, pet?
Wouldn't you rather
have your party in Vienna?
But the invitations are sent.
Yeah... But it's just
I've had it with this place.
Nothing ever comes off
like it's supposed to.
My gatherings are always perfect.
Remember Spain?
Hey? The bulls?
I remember, sweet.
But Sunnydale's cursed for us.
Angel and the Slayer see to that.
Shh! I've got good games for everyone.
You'll see.
These flowers... are wrong.
They're all... wrong.
I can't abide them!
Let's try something different
with the flowers, then.
Can I open one?
Can I?
Just a peek, love.
They're for the party.
Do you like it, baby?
It reeks of death.
This will be the best party ever.
Why's that?
Because...
it will be the last.
Mall trip for your birthday
on Saturday. Don't forget.
Space on a Mom-sponsored
shopping opportunity? Not likely.
- So, does 17 feel any different than 16?
- It's funny you should ask that.
You know, I woke up feeling more
responsible, mature and level-headed.
Really? It's uncanny.
I now possess the qualities
one looks for in a...
- licensed driver.
- Buffy...
You said we'd talk about it again
when I was 17.
Do you really think you're ready, Buffy?
"Jenny Calendar."
- You startled me.
- You look well.
Yes, I'm fine.
I know I haven't written as much lately.
I've been busy.
I cannot imagine what is so important
to make you ignore
the responsibility to your people.
- Well, I've been working. And...
- The elder woman has been reading signs.
- Something is different.
- Nothing has changed.
- The curse still holds.
- The elder woman is never wrong.
She says his pain is lessening.
She can feel it.
- There is...
- There is what?
- A girl.
- What?!
- How could you let this happen?
- I promise you,
Angel still suffers!
And he makes amends for his evil.
He even saved my life.
So you just forget
that he destroyed
the most beloved daughter of your tribe?
That he killed every man,
woman and child that touched her life?
Vengeance demands that
his pain be eternal, as ours is!
If this... this girl gives him one minute
of happiness, it is one minute too much!
- I'm sorry. I thought...
- You thought what?!
You thought you are Jenny Calendar now?
You are still Janna,
of the Kalderash people!
- A gypsy.
- I know... Uncle.
I know.
Then prove it.
Your time for watching is past.
The girl and him, it ends now!
Do what you must to take her from him.
I will see to it.
And then my mom broke the plate.
It was just like my dream.
Every gesture, every word.
It was so creepy.
Yes, well, I'd imagine
it would be fairly unnerving.
Hey! It's the woman of the hour.
It's happy birthday, Buffy!
Not happy birthday, Buffy?
I-it's just that, um, part of the nightmare
that Buffy had the other night
actually transpired.
Which means Drusilla might still be alive.
Giles, in my dream, I couldn't stop her.
She blindsided me.
Angel was gone before
I knew what happened.
Even if she is alive,
we can still protect Angel.
Dreams aren't prophecies, Buffy.
You dreamt that the Master had risen,
but you stopped it from happening.
- You ground his bones to make your bread.
- That's true. Except for the bread part.
OK, so, fine. We're one step ahead,
but I wanna stay that way.
Absolutely. Let me read up on Drusilla,
see if she has any particular patterns.
Why don't you meet me here at seven?
We'll map out a strategy.
- What am I supposed to do until then?
- Go to classes. Do your homework.
Have supper?
Right... Be that Buffy.
Well, that's not a perky birthday puppy.
So much for our surprise party.
I bought little hats and everything.
Oh, well. I guess I'll tell Cordelia.
No, you won't.
We're having a party tonight.
Looks like Mr Caution Man,
but the sound he makes is funny.
Buffy's surprise party
will go ahead as we planned.
Except I won't be wearing a little hat.
- But Buffy and Angel...
- May well be in danger.
As they have been before,
and I imagine will be again.
One thing I've learned
in my tenure here on the Hellmouth
is that there is no good time to relax.
But Buffy's turning 17 just this once,
and she deserves a party.
You're a great man of our time.
And anyway, Angel's coming, so she'll
be able to protect him and have cake.
Precisely.
- Buffy.
- Oh, my God! I didn't see you there.
Sorry. Um... Giles wanted me to tell you
that there's been a change of plans.
Uh, he wants to meet you
someplace near his house.
I guess he had to run home
to get a book or something.
'Cause heaven knows there aren't
enough books in the library.
- Uh... He's very thorough.
- Oh, which is not to bag.
It's kind of manly in an obsessive-
compulsive kind of way, don't you think?
Mm-hm. Um... You know, my car's here.
Why don't I drive you?
OK.
- Are we going to the Bronze?
- I'm not sure.
Giles gave me an address.
I'm just following his directions.
This looks funky. Stop for a sec.
- No, Buffy. Maybe you shouldn't.
- Sorry. Sacred duty, yadda-yadda-yadda.
What is this?
Every time I see you,
you're stealing something.
You really should speak with someone
about this klepto issue.
- Where is she?
- Shh! I think I hear her coming.
Surprise!
That pretty much sums it up.
- Buffy, are you OK?
- Yes, what happened?
Uh... There were these vamps outs...
What's going on?
Oh. Erm...
Surprise party.
Happy birthday.
You guys did all this for me?
- That is so sweet.
- Are you sure you're OK?
Yes, I'm fine.
Are you OK?
Yeah... Hey, did everybody
see that guy just turn to dust?
Uh... Well, uh... sort of.
Yep. Vampires are real.
A lot of 'em live in Sunnydale.
Willow will fill you in.
- I know it's hard to accept at first.
- Actually, it explains a lot.
Hey, somebody give me a hand here?
- Those creeps left this behind.
- What is it?
I've no idea. C-Can it be opened?
Yeah. There's a secure release right here.
Well, clearly the Hellmouth's answer to
"What do you get the slayer
who has everything?"
- Good heavens. Buffy, are you all right?
- Man, that thing had major grip.
- W-what was that?
- It looked like an arm.
It can't be. She wouldn't.
What, a vamp's version of snakes in a can,
or do you care to share?
- Angel?
- It's a legend, way before my time.
Of a demon brought forth
to rid the Earth of the plague of humanity.
To separate the righteous from the wicked,
and to burn the righteous down.
- They called him the Judge.
- The Judge? This is he?
- Not all of him.
- I'm still needing backstory here.
Erm... He... He couldn't be killed, yes?
Erm... An army was sent against him.
Most of them died. But finally
they were able to dismember him,
but... not kill him.
The pieces were scattered,
buried in every corner of the Earth.
So all these parts
are being brought here?
By Drusilla.
- The vamps outside were Spike's men.
- She's just crazy enough to do it.
- Do what? Reassemble the Judge?
- Bring forth Armageddon.
- Is anybody else gonna have cake?
- We need to get this out of town.
- Angel.
- What?
You have to do it. You're the only one
that can protect this thing.
- What about me?
- What?
You're just gonna skip town
for a few months?
- Months?
- She's right. I gotta get this
- to the remotest region possible.
- But that's not months.
I can catch a cargo ship to Asia
and maybe a truck to Nepal...
You know, those newfangled flying machines
really are much safer than they used to be.
I can't fly. There's no sure way
to guard against the daylight.
I don't like this any more
than you do, Buffy.
But there's no other choice.
When?
Tonight.
As soon as possible.
But it's my birthday.
I'll drive you to the docks.
You lost it.
You lost my present.
I know. I'm sorry.
It's a bad turn, man.
She can't have her fun without the box.
The Slayer. She came out of nowhere.
I didn't even see her. She...
- Make a wish.
- What?
I'm going to blow out the candles.
You might give him a chance
to find your lost treasure.
He is a wanker, but he's
the only one we've got with half a brain.
If he fails, you can eat his eyes
out of the sockets for all I care.
I'll get it. Please.
I swear.
OK.
Hurry back, then.
I should go the rest of the way alone.
OK.
But I'll be back. I will.
When? Six months? A year?
You don't know how long it's gonna take,
or... if we'll even...
Hey...
If we'll even what?
Well, if you haven't noticed,
someone pretty much always wants us dead.
Don't say that. We'll be fine.
We don't know that.
We can't know, Buffy.
Nobody can. That's just the deal.
I have somethin' for you.
For your birthday.
I... was gonna give it
to you earlier, but...
It's beautiful.
My people... Before I was changed,
they exchanged this as a sign of devotion.
It's a Claddagh ring.
The hands represent friendship,
the crown represents loyalty.
And the heart...
Well, you know.
Wear it with the heart
pointing towards you.
It means you belong to somebody.
Like this.
Put it on.
- I don't wanna do this.
- Me either.
So don't go.
Buffy?
I...
Angel! The box!
You...
Buffy!
They should be back by now.
Maybe Buffy needed a few minutes
to pull herself together.
Poor Buffy. On her birthday and everything.
It's sad, granted. But let's look
at the upside for a moment.
I mean, what kind of a future
would she've really had with him?
She's got two jobs -
Denny's waitress by day, Slayer by night.
And Angel's always in front of the TV
with a big blood belly.
He's dreamin' of the glory days
when Buffy still thought
this whole creature-of-the-night routine
was a big turn-on.
You've thought way too much about this.
No, no. That's just the beginning.
Have I told you the part
where I fly into town in my private jet
and take Buffy out for prime rib?
- Xander...
- And she cries?
What happened?
Dru's guys ambushed us.
They got the box.
- Where's Jenny?
- Uh, she took Angel to get clothing.
- I-I had some here.
- And we needed clothes because...?
We got wet.
- Giles, what do we know?
- The more I study the Judge,
the less I like him. His touch can
literally burn the humanity out of you.
A true creature of evil can survive
the process. No human ever has.
What's the problem? We send Cordy
to fight this guy, and we go for pizza.
Can this guy be stopped? Without an army?
Erm... "No weapon forged can kill him."
Not very encouraging.
If we could only stop them
from assembling him.
We need to find his weak spots, and we need
to figure out where they'd be keeping him.
- This could take time.
- Better do a round robin.
- Xander, you go first.
- Good call.
- Round robin?
- It's when everybody calls
everybody else's mom and tells them
they're staying at everyone's house.
Thus freeing us up for world saveage.
And all-night keggers.
What, only Xander gets
to make dumb jokes?
Mom, hi... Xander... Yeah, uh...
Willow and I are gonna be studying
all night long, so I'm not gonna be...
I think I read this already.
I can't get over
how cool Oz was about all this.
Gee, I'm over it.
You're just jealous 'cause
you didn't have a date for the party.
No, I sure didn't.
Angel? Any luck?
It seems Buffy needed some rest.
Yeah. She hasn't been sleeping well.
Tossing and turning.
She told me! 'Cause of her dreams?
Now, now!
Hands off my presents,
No!
- Angel!
- Buffy, it's OK.
I'm here. I'm right here.
More music!
(# "Transylvanian Concubine" by Rasputina)
# If you want to know how to fly high
then go now to the place
# Where all the concubines meet,
and converse with them
# Marvel at their pale skin,
wonder how they chew on their pointy...
# Teeth and hair are beauty,
they know it's a duty
# To be Countess in their hearts and their
- Look what I have for you, ducks!
# Minds that have to whisper
# See in them a sister
Look into their eyes and you'll become
# Transylvanian Concubine
The best is saved for last.
# You know what flows there like wine
# Sorrow is their master,
cackling with laughter,
# Now he's having just one piece of...
# Cakey is their make-up,
Catholics try to shake up...
He's perfect, my darling.
Just what I wanted.
Cor...
- You...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- What's that, mate?
- You two stink... of humanity.
You share affection and... jealousy.
Yeah! What of it?
Do I have to remind you that
we're the ones who brought you here?
Would you like a party favour?
This one is full of feeling.
He reads. Bring him to me!
What's with the bringing?
I thought you could just... zap people.
My full strength will return in time.
Until then, I need contact.
No! No! No!
No! No!
Do it again! Do it again!
- Buffy, what's happening?
- She had another dream.
I think I know
where Spike and Drusilla are.
That's very good.
However, you... you do need a plan.
I-I know you're concerned, Buffy,
but you can't just go off half-cocked.
I have a plan. Angel and I
go to the factory and do recon,
figure out how far they've gotten
assembling the Judge.
You, guys, check any places
the boxes could be coming into town -
shipping yards, airports, anything.
We need to stop them
from getting all the boxes in one place.
Yes... Yes, well,
actually that's quite a good plan.
This thing is nasty and it's real, Giles.
We can't wait for it to come get us.
Right.
I saw this. The party.
What? What is it?
We gotta get outta here.
Well, well. Look what we have here.
Crashers.
I'm sure our invitations
just got lost in the mail.
It's delicious.
I only dreamed you'd come.
- Leave her alone!
- Yeah, that'll work.
Now say "pretty please".
- The girl?
- Chilling, isn't it?
She's so full of good intention.
- Take me. Take me instead of her.
- No!
Uh, you're not clear on the concept, pal.
There is no "instead".
- Just first and second.
- And if you go first,
you don't get to watch the Slayer die.
Don't touch him!
This way!
Go!
Come on. We need to get inside.
- You're shaking like a leaf.
- I'm cold.
Let me get you somethin'.
Put these on.
Get under the covers just to warm up.
Sorry.
What?
Oh, um...
It's OK.
I just have a cut or something.
Can I...
Let me see.
OK.
It's already closed. You're fine.
You almost went away today.
We both did.
Angel...
I feel like I lost you.
You're right, though.
- We can't be sure of anything...
- Shhh.
I...
You what?
I love you.
I try not to, but I can't stop.
Me... Me too.
I can't either.
- Buffy, maybe we shouldn't...
- Don't.
Just kiss me.
Ah! Buffy!
Buffy!
Subtitles extended & timed by UAR
www.tvsubtitles.net