Previously on
"Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
You wanna fry a witch?
I'll give you a witch.
Before thee,
let the unclean thing crawl!
She's a perfectly normal girl.
Then she's a rat.
We should get her
one of those wheel thingies.
- Can we not do this now?
- Forget it ever happened.
Forget.
What is wrong with you?!
I know you used that spell on me.
I will go a month without doing any magic.
- Go a week.
- Fine. That's easy.
When the fire goes out, and the crystal
turns black, the spell will be cast.
- I don't think this is gonna work.
- Are you gonna leave me?
- I'm placing an order.
- I'm not making any more girls.
Sure you are. And here's your specs.
So... you guys wanna team up
and take over Sunnydale?
- OK.
The Trio versus the Slayer.
We're, like, supervillains.
- I can't do this without you.
- You can.
That's why I'm going.
I'm headed back to England.
And I plan to stay.
We have to talk.
- About what?
- We kissed, Buffy.
- I'm sure we can work somethin' out.
- A deal of some sort. Anything you want.
I always wanted a pony.
Oh. You weren't really speaking to me,
were you? My bad.
Well, as long as I'm here...
- Lady!
- Wow. A mugging.
Haven't gotten one of those in a while.
Usually it's blood, and with the horror...
Just a good old-fashioned mugging.
Kinda sweet, actually.
Well, probably not for you.
Here. Go. Now.
Not too sweet for you either, huh?
Come on, rush me. It'll be funny.
No!
- What the hell are you doing?
- Thought they were demons.
Way to go with the keen observiness,
Jessica Fletcher.
- Remind me not to help you.
- More often?
Hey. A little sympathy for the man
with the migraine, can we?
- That's what you get for attacking a human.
- Yeah.
You'd think if the government
put a chip in my head,
I could at least attack criminals.
Yes, because muggers deserve to be eaten.
Just have to get your rocks off
fightin' demons.
There are other ways.
And to that, an extreme "see you later".
Buffy.
Spike, it's late, OK.
Can we just finish this another time?
So you wanna jump
right to the kissing, then, eh?
- I am not kissing you, Spike. Once was...
- Twice.
But not again.
You're a tease, you know that, Slayer?
Get a fella's motor revvin',
let the tension marinate a couple of days,
then - bam! - crown yourself the ice queen.
Need a few more metaphors
for that little mix?
It's only a matter of time before you
realise I'm the only one here for you, pet.
You got no one else!
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
What's the matter, Amy?
You lonely?
We need to get you a nice companion rat
that you can love... play with...
and grow attached to,
until one day they leave you
for no good reason.
Won't that be fun?
Relax, Amy. I'm just kiddin'.
I swear, if I could figure out
how to turn you back...
Any way...
Revele!
Ciò che fu, non è più.
Ciò che fu fatto, disfa.
Passato è il pericolo,
finita è la prova.
Metti le cose a posto.
- Dude, what are you doing?
- We're not breakin' into Langley here.
You never know what new stuff they have.
Better safe than...
The security system here
is a guy named Rusty.
- Now get up.
- Whoa, head rush. Cool!
Guys, come on. Quit jerkin' around.
See, that's cool. How come
he gets to play with all the cool stuff?
I'm allergic to methane
and you're afraid of hot things.
Besides, the tank kept
makin' both of us tip over, remember?
- Got it.
- It's beautiful.
Boys, congratulations.
Phase one of the plan is now complete.
Let's get the hell outta here.
What are you boys doing?
We're with a tour group.
The "Get The Freeze Ray" tour group.
Must've gotten separated.
Museum closed five hours ago.
Really?
Guess we just lost track of time. We should
probably get the freeze ray outta here now.
Cos we love the learning, Rusty.
Museums, libraries, Disney Hall
of Presidents... not boring.
But more to the point, goodbye.
Dude, that is so cool!
The freeze ray totally worked.
Yeah... Not exactly.
There's a kink or two.
It's just a prototype.
Hey, that's really neato and stuff,
but in the meantime, you know... ow!
Be a bigger wuss.
Can we just go back to the lair?
Because... I can't really feel my fingers.
Yeah, yeah. Come on.
- Is he gonna, like...?
- He'll be fine.
He'll defrost in a couple of days.
No harm, no foul.
- Won't he tell on us?
- And say what?
"Two guys and a mime took me out
with their freeze ray"? It's likely.
Come on.
Hey. Here's some hot chocolate. You want...?
No, thanks.
Still... kinda queasy.
OK. Maybe later.
Hey. No, it's OK. It's... it's just a siren.
It's... it's all right. OK?
- You OK?
- Mm-hm.
Yeah. Just... you know.
Everything feels weird.
I mean, it's like...
I felt like I was in that cage for weeks.
But it can still be OK... right?
I can still get into the swing of things.
Like... prom's coming up.
I was so hoping Larry would ask me.
We would make such a splash at...
Oh. Oh, God.
He hasn't asked someone else, has he?
Amy...
three things we have to talk about.
One, Larry's gay.
Two, Larry's dead.
And three, high school's...
kinda over.
How long was I in the cage?
How long?!
Willow?
Hey. How you doin'?
Oh. Um... OK.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Not parades and cotton candy, but... OK.
Will, um... can I talk to you
about something?
- Of course.
- Right.
OK. Um...
You know how we all make choices?
And sometimes they're good, and...
sometimes they're... less good.
Uh-huh.
Well, lately, I, um...
Oh, Tara, hey...
Amy?
The whole school?
By a giant snake thing.
OK, still adjusting. Hey, Buffy.
Hi.
- How've you been?
- Rat. You?
- Dead.
- Oh.
Well, I should let you guys catch up.
I can...
No, no, no, stay.
Do you have any cookies?
- Yeah. What kind?
- Any kind. Not cheese.
- Sure, in the kitchen. I'll just get 'em.
- No, I'll grab 'em.
OK, well, at least, you know,
let me make up the couch for you.
It's late, you should stay here.
Everybody does.
Thank you.
- Wow.
- I know.
Is... she gonna be OK?
Don't know. She's kinda freaked out.
But then I would be too.
Wow.
Yeah, I just realised I could.
Thought of the right thing, and...
It's nice, having another
magically-inclined friend around.
So, what were you gonna tell me?
You were sounding all serious.
It's nothing. I mean,
the whole Amy, rat, Amy thing...
No way I'm toppin' that.
Hey.
How you doin'? Need anything?
No, thanks. Good cookies.
- Sorry about your mom.
- Thanks.
It's crazy, all the things that've happened
since I went away.
No kidding.
Snyder got eaten by a snake.
High school got destroyed...
Oh, Gatorade has a new flavour. Blue.
See? Head spinning.
People getting frozen.
Willow's dating girls.
And did you hear about Tom and Nicole?
People getting frozen?
.. in critical yet stable condition,
as authorities continue their investigation
into the robbery
that left one man frozen solid.
Live from the museum, Bryan Morris, KOUS.
Weird.
Excuse me.
Great.
Well, well. Look who decided to show up.
What are you doing here, Spike?
Well, you know a man was frozen alive
in there? A little compassion, love.
As long as we're both here, you might
as well tag along. As a team, we could...
Yeah, that never really ends well, does it?
It did the other night.
You really seem awfully fixated
on a couple of kisses, Spike.
And you seem awfully quick
to forget about 'em.
Look, I'm sorry, OK?
I'm sorry if you thought that it meant more.
But?
But... when I kissed you... you know
I was thinking about Giles, right?
I always wondered about you two.
What?
Oh, gross, Spike!
He left. I was depressed. Ergo
vulnerability and bad kissing decisions.
But that's all that it was.
You have to let it go.
- Did it work?
- What?
You convince yourself?
Please, stop.
A man can change.
You're not a man. You're a thing.
- Stop walkin' away.
- Don't touch me!
You're a thing. An evil, disgusting thing.
Look at all the goodies.
That's right, you should scream.
Creature of the night here, yeah?
Some people forget that.
- Please.
- She thinks I'm house-broken.
- She forgot who she's dealing with.
- Anything...
Just cos she's confused
about where she fits in,
I'm supposed to be too? Cos I'm not.
I know what I am. I'm dangerous. I'm evil.
- I'm sure you're not evil.
- Yes, I am.
I am a killer. That's what I do. I kill.
And, yeah, maybe it's been a long time,
but... it's not like you forget how.
You just... do it.
And now I can - again - all right?
So here goes.
This might hurt a little.
What the hell is going on?
Good God, that's a lot of shake.
I mean, I know... part of
our big movie and milkshake fun day,
but... good God, that's a lot of shake.
Helps to wash down the Raisinets.
Promise me you will eat something green
tonight. Leafy green, not... gummy green.
- Movie was fun.
- Yeah.
It was ironic when all those cute inner-city
kids taught their coach a valuable lesson.
You know that I will
always be there for you, right?
There was actually more of a lead-in
when I practised that at home.
- I know.
- It's just...
I wanted you to know that...
my moving out had nothing to do with you,
and I will never stop loving you.
I know.
Do you think you'll ever get back together?
I wish I knew.
- But you still love her.
- Very much. I just...
Sometimes...
other things get in the way.
I know. She's been doing
a lot better lately, though.
She's been really good about...
being careful... about stuff.
Well, good.
Great. That's... that's great.
Here.
Says the guard's definitely gonna live.
He's all thawed out.
It says they used hair dryers. Huh.
Everything slowed down.
His nervous system, circulatory system...
He's still unconscious.
Anya?
It's such a pain. The text I wanted,
Giles took it with him.
He has this thing that...
owning a book makes it, like, his property.
What should we do? Should we call him?
It's, like, the middle of last night there.
Or maybe it's tomorrow.
Anyone remember how that works?
It's OK, no one freak.
We'll just do it another way.
I don't think we need to resort to...
I mean...
Oh. Hey. Cool.
Back to basics. A little old-fashioned
state-of-the-art hacker action.
That's great, Will,
I haven't seen you do that in a long time.
I don't remember that part.
It's quicker. It'll just take a sec
to go through the files.
OK. Internal police report.
A diamond was stolen from
the museum last night. A big one.
On loan from the British Museum.
They're withholding information
to smoke out the criminals.
It's pretty. There's a picture.
Well, is it a supernatural diamond? You
know, like, healing powers, or good-lucky?
Maybe it's cursed.
Diamonds are excellent for cursing.
Well, we'll keep checkin', shall we?
Well, you know, I am kinda beat,
and I betcha that's tiring,
that... thing you're doin' there...
- Guys, I'm fine. What's the deal with...?
- Oh, for cryin' out loud. This is bizarre.
You're all "la la la!" with the magic, and
the not talking, like everything's normal,
when we all know that Tara up and left you,
and now everyone's scared
to say anything to you.
Except me.
Is this that thing I do
that you were commenting...?
Guys, it's OK.
It's hard, but it's better this way.
Little things started taking over
- things that didn't matter,
but we saw them differently,
so... they got blown out of proportion.
And this time away
will help us sort through things.
Really.
Now, let's just keep working on this.
I don't wanna leave Amy
alone in the house so long.
Amy, is she...? How is she adjusting?
It's hard to say. It's a lot to take in.
I keep expecting her to do, like, ratty
stuff. You know, licking her hands clean,
shredding newspaper,
leaving little pellets in the corner.
Let's definitely not leave her alone
in the house too long.
- I didn't know it'd be so sparkly.
- And so big.
Yes, gentlemen,
it turns out size is everything.
No offence, man.
It makes colours with the light.
All right, we've finished the first part.
Time for phase two. Is the van fired up?
Check.
Hello! It's called knocking!
Knock, knock, robot boy.
Need you to look at my chip.
Is that British slang or something?
Cos we're not...
- In my head. The chip in my head.
- We're kind of in the middle of somethin'.
You can play holodeck another time.
Right now, I'm in charge.
What are you gonna do if we don't
especially feel like playing your...
Wait, what are you doing?
Examine my chip, or else
Mr... Fett here is the first to die.
Hey, all right. Let's not...
let's not do anything crazy here.
That's a limited edition,
1979 mint-condition Boba Fett.
All right. Dude... chill.
You can still make it right.
You know you don't wanna do this.
What I want... is answers, nimrod.
Right. But you don't wanna hurt the Fett,
cos, man, you're not comin' back from that.
You know, you don't just
do that and walk away.
- That right? Let's find out.
- One second.
- I think that's Spike.
- Of course it is, and he's evil.
- Completely capable of removing that head.
- I'm gonna help him.
Are you sure we can trust him?
I mean, we all have heads too.
We help him, and he owes us one.
We get Spike on our side,
we get info on Buffy.
Maybe we can even find a way
to keep her out of phase two.
Jonathan's right. Can we trust him?
Course not.
But alliances aren't about trust.
See, he needs us, we need him.
That's how these things work.
- I think we're ready. Agreed?
- Agreed.
Do what you need to do.
I think we can work somethin' out.
I'll take a look at your chip. It'll be
a deal. We scratch your back, you scratch...
I'm not scratching your anything. You do
what I tell you. That's the deal. Deal?
- Deal.
- Then let's go.
It's OK, it's OK. It'll be fine.
Amy?
God, you're back. You said
you wouldn't be gone that long.
- I wasn't. I mean, I thought it was...
- Let's go somewhere.
- Don't you wanna go see your dad?
- No.
I can't.
Not yet. Too many questions.
- About where you were.
- No, about how I got there.
I wish there was a way I could
make him forget the last three years.
Well, hey, I can help you with that.
Only... you might wanna sew your name
into your clothes first or somethin'.
I just don't wanna deal with him right now.
I think I would be... bored.
- Well.
- Come on, let's get outta here.
Well, what do you wanna do?
I don't know. Something fun.
Anything... not involving a big wheel.
Or... maybe...
you'd rather sit home all night,
alone, like in high school.
No.
No. You know what? I can have fun.
- Heck, I deserve some fun.
- Yeah, you do.
I can party! Not like I owe anyone anything.
I am totally free.
So let's make with the fun.
You're English, right?
Yeah.
I've seen every episode of Doctor Who.
- Not Red Dwarf, though, cos, um...
- Cos it's not out yet on DVD.
Right. It's not out yet on... DVD.
- Warren!
- Here... I am. Here.
Bloody hell. Get on with it, then.
Help me out here, Spock,
I don't speak loser.
OK. Right. Um...
Your chip works fine. Yeah.
- There's gotta be something wrong...
- No, no, listen.
I don't know what that thing does.
I'd like to.
- Hey.
- But whatever it is, it works fine.
The signal still is coming through
on a steady pulse - which it's supposed to.
- If you're lying to me...
- No! It's all right here.
I mean, it is. It's really not that hard
to figure out, if you just... What?
- You tell anyone about this...
- No, I promise. Who would I tell?
- I don't even know what this is about.
- It's about the rules having changed.
Everything's different now.
Nothin' wrong with me.
Something wrong with her.
Hello! We're home!
- Looks like no one's here.
- Well, I'm sure they'll be back soon.
I know Willow and Buffy were meeting up
with Xander to do some research.
Well, then, I should probably get back.
Or you can stay and wait for them.
Then you can get a chance
to catch up with... everyone.
Yeah, I don't think
that's such a great idea.
OK. Your call. I have the TV
to keep me company till they get back.
You notice how it's been getting dark
so much earlier these days?
Ha. Talking cat.
Fine. I'll stay,
but just until they get back.
And only to make sure that you're not alone.
This has nothing to do with... anyone else.
Sure. Cool.
Up to you.
I know. Xander engaged,
I couldn't believe it either.
It's so weird.
So, what's she like?
Thousand-year-old capitalist ex-demon
with rabbit phobia.
Well, that's so his type.
- Hey.
Hey.
Well, let's go, then.
We're gonna go dance. Do you wanna come?
Oh. No. You go.
I'll keep an eye on our drinks.
OK. You know, because if you want
something a little more your style...
I'm sure we can swing that.
No. Really, no.
Hi. Brie.
Willow.
Nice... um, top.
- No. Thanks, but no.
- Are you sure?
- I'm not... She... I'm still...
- It's cool.
Oh. Sorry.
- So, are we gonna go?
- Yeah.
- Sure you're gonna be OK?
- Yeah. Go. I'm all kinds of good.
No use looking at me like that.
It's the gullet for you, mister.
Hey. Sorry. I kinda got caught up.
No, it's OK.
You know, if rats could dance
they probably wouldn't gnaw so much.
Hey, come on. We're just gettin' started.
I think I'll sit this one out.
You can't just work us up like that,
then...
- Hey!
- I think she said no.
Well, nobody asked you... Ellen.
- You wanna dance?
- That's all.
Nice, slow... relaxing dance.
- Gee.
- I think I do feel more relaxed.
Aha! I got it!
Here's our villain, right here!
What?
That's a D&D manual, sweetie.
No, but it could...
Face it, we're not gonna find it
because it doesn't exist.
There's no such thing
as a frost monster who eats diamonds.
Well, maybe he doesn't eat them. You know,
maybe he just... thinks they're pretty.
We suck.
We need new brains. What's up with Willow?
- Out with Amy, I guess.
- Great, someone to do more magic with.
But at least she's not all cooped up
and crying. That's forward momentum.
I don't know everything
that happened with Tara, but...
Tara thinks Willow is doin' too much magic.
And she's not the only one.
I know. But I think she'll be fine.
It's Willow. She of the level head.
Those are the ones you have to
watch out for the most - responsible types.
Right. She might go crazy
and start alphabetising everything.
I'm serious. Responsible people are always
so concerned with being good all the time,
that when they finally
get a taste of being bad,
they can't get enough. It's all... kablooey.
- That's not true.
- OK, not kablooey, more like bam!
It's human nature, Buff. Will's getting
a taste of something powerful,
way bigger than her.
She was getting out of control with it
before Tara left, and now that she's gone...
It's gotta be seductive.
Just giving in to it, going totally wild.
- We need to keep an eye on her.
- OK.
We'll keep an eye. But we can't assume
everybody's getting seduced. Sometimes...
Magic Box.
Slayer.
Spike?
Meet me at the cemetery.
20 minutes. Come alone.
Spike?
Bloody hell. Yes, it's me.
You're calling me on the phone?
- Just be there.
- Why? Are you helping again?
You have a lead on this frost monster?
Something like that, yeah. Thought you
might be up for a little grunt work.
What?! No. No grunting!
I was talking shop, love,
but if you got other ideas -
you, me, cosy little tomb with a view...
- So, what did Captain Peroxide want?
- Nothing.
He just, you know, wanted to see
if I wanted to patrol, for the monster.
But I told him that I... would not.
I'm telling you, I think
there's something about this thing.
I don't know. It seems like
we've been through every book.
Even the ones that weren't
so boring you wanna die.
- We have those?
- All the things that have happened lately,
- the bank robbery, the jewellery heist...
- The exploding lint.
- Is it me, or do these things seem really...
- Lame?
Well, I was gonna go with unusual, but yeah.
I'll do a quick patrol tonight,
and after a good night's sleep,
we can solve this tomorrow.
- Optimism. I remember optimism.
- That's because you're, like, a thousand.
- Good night, guys.
- Night.
- Slayer.
- And so my night is now complete.
- You never showed.
- Sorry. Little busy actually doing stuff.
- You shouldn't be so flip.
- You gonna walk-behind-me to death?
I'm just sayin' things
might be a little different.
You ought to be careful.
Enough.
Get outta my way.
Or what?
Oh, the pain, the pain...
is gone.
Guess what I just found out.
Looks like I'm not as toothless
as you thought, sweetheart.
How?
Don't you get it? Don't you see?
You came back wrong.
It's a trick. You did something to the chip.
It's no trick. It's not me, it's you.
Just you, in fact - that's the funny part.
You're the one that's changed.
That's why this doesn't hurt me.
Came back a little less human than you were.
You're wrong.
Then how come you're so spooked, love?
And why can I... do that?
You're wrong.
You know, this music isn't quite...
Poor little lost girl.
She doesn't fit in anywhere.
She's got no one to love.
Me? I'm lost? Look at you, you idiot!
Poor Spikey.
Can't be a human, can't be a vampire.
Where the hell do you fit in?
Your job is to kill the Slayer.
But all you can do is follow
me around making moon eyes.
- I'm in love with you.
- You're in love with pain. Admit it.
You like me... because you enjoy getting
beat down. So, really, who's screwed up?
Hello! Vampire!
I'm supposed to be treading on
the dark side.
What's your excuse?
So we've kinda played this scene.
- Yeah.
- Return.
I just keep thinking there's gotta be
someplace, like, bigger than this.
Besides, it's way too early to go home yet.
- I wasn't plannin' on hurtin' you. Much.
- You haven't even come close to hurting me.
Afraid to give me the chance?
You afraid I'm gonna...?
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org