Oh, look!
- It's Buffy and all her friends.
- That's witty.
Do you ever wonder why nobody cool
ever wants to hang out with you?
Just thankful.
Were you this popular at your old school
before you got kicked out?
Careful. She might beat you up.
Hey! Buffy!
- You missed it.
- Missed what?
We just saw the zebras mating!
Thank you. Very exciting.
It was like the Heimlich, with stripes!
And I missed it. Yet somehow
I'll find the courage to live on.
- Where were you?
- Uh, I was looking at the fishes.
- Was it cool?
- It was fishes.
I'm feeling that you're not
in the field-trip spirit here.
Well, it would... It's nothing, I...
We did the same zoo trip at my old school
every year. Same old same old.
Buffy, this isn't just about
looking at a bunch of animals.
- This is about not being in class!
- You know, you're right.
- Suddenly the animals look shiny and new.
- Gotta have perspective.
Lance!
- How's it going?
- Hey, Kyle.
So, is this like a, uh, family reunion?
- No.
- I think it's a family reunion. It's so...
touching. Doesn't anybody have a camera?
Hey! Does your mom still
pick out your lice,
or are you old enough
to do that yourself now?
Quit it.
Hey! Guys, come on!
- It's got my notes in there!
- What's going on here?
I've had it up to here with you four.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Did I ask you to speak?
OK, I guess I did.
But I want the truth. Lance?
They weren't doing anything.
Really. We were just playing around.
All right.
I'll be watching you.
You...
...came through big time.
Way to go, Lance!
Flutie's been looking for a reason
to come down on us.
It's OK.
Come on, we're gonna
check out the Hyena House.
- But I think it's off limits.
- And therein, my friend, lies the fun.
What are Kyle and his buds
doing with Lance?
Oh, playing with him
as a cat plays with a mouse.
- What is it with those guys?
- They're obnoxious. Professionally.
Well, every school has 'em.
So, you start a new school,
you get your desks,
some blackboards and some mean kids.
- Yeah, well, I'd better extract Lance...
- I'll handle it.
This job doesn't require actual slaying.
- You don't think we should follow?
- Kyle and those guys are jerks,
but they're all talk.
- Mostly.
- Why don't we...?
Yeah, why don't we.
Hold it, hold it.
Are you blind or are you just illiterate?
Because hyenas are
very quick to prey on the weak.
- We were just...
- You're not going in there.
Anyone that does is in a world of trouble.
No. No one's going in there.
- Why is it off limits?
- It's a quarantine.
These hyenas just came in from Africa,
so keep out.
- Even if they call your name.
- What are you talking about?
A Masai tribesman told me that hyenas
are capable of understanding human speech.
They follow humans around by day,
learning their names.
At night, when the campfire dies,
they call out to a person.
And once they separate him,
the pack... devours them.
Cool!
I don't see any hyenas.
OK. Now we've seen it.
- It looks cute.
- I think it looks hungry.
- Come on, Spot! Suppertime!
- Stop... Guys...
Stop! It's not funny!
Stop it! It's not funny!
Why don't you pick on
someone your own species?
What, are you gonna get in my face?
"The Pack"
I thought Xander would be here by now.
That'd make him on time.
We couldn't have that.
Did he seem upset at all
on the bus back from the zoo?
About what?
I don't know. He was quiet.
I didn't notice anything.
But then again I'm not as hyperaware of him
as, oh, say, for example, you.
Hyper-aware?
I'm not constantly monitoring his health,
his moods, his blood pressure.
130 over 80.
You got it bad, girl.
He makes my head go tingly.
You know what I mean?
- I dimly recall.
- But it hasn't happened to you lately?
Not of late.
Not even for a dangerous
and mysterious older man
whose leather jacket
you're wearing right now?
- It goes with the shoes.
- Come on!
Angel pushes your buttons.
You know he does.
I suppose some girls
might find him good-looking.
If they have eyes.
All right, he's a honey, but
it's just... he's never around, and,
when he is, all he wants to do
is talk about vampires and I...
- I just can't have a relationship...
- There he is!
- Angel?
- Xander.
- Girls!
- Boy!
Sorry I'm late. I... just forgot
that we were gonna be here.
Hungry!
Xander, you still want me
to help you with geometry tomorrow?
We can work after class.
Yeah. What is this crap?
Well, it was my buttery croissant.
Man, I need some food. Birds live on this.
What?
- What's up with you?
- Is something wrong?
- Did I do something?
- What could you possibly do?
That's crazy talk. I'm just... restless.
- Well, we could go to the ice-cream place.
- I like it here.
- OK, now what?
- You took a bath.
Yeah. I often do.
I'm actually known for it.
That's OK.
And the weird-behavior award goes to...
(# "Reluctant Man" by Sprung Monkey)
# Oh, Reluctant Man,
- Oh, great! It's the winged monkeys.
# who's afraid to touch the world,
# why are you hiding?
# What is the base of all your fears?
# Do you find yourself
# in a cold cruel world?
# Dark and desperate,
# scared and lonely?
# Selfish Man,
# who never gave to no one else,
# what are you holding?
# Is it worth the price you pay?
- You know,
I don't understand
why you're sitting at our table.
Yeah, shouldn't you be
hovering over the football stadium
with Goodyear written on you?
The kid's fat!
Right! That's enough training for one day.
That last roundhouse was kinda sloppy.
Are you sure you don't wanna do it again?
No! No, no, that's fine.
You just... run along to class.
While I wait for the feeling
to return to my arms.
Oh, my God!
Look out!
Stop! Whoa! Get it! Get it!
Lordy, Herbert!
Gave Mr. Flutie quite a scare, didn't he?
Students, I'd like you all to meet Herbert,
our new mascot
for the Sunnydale High Razorbacks!
- He's so cute!
- He's not cute!
No! He's a fierce razorback!
- He doesn't look mean, Mr. Flutie.
- He's mean. He's ready for action, see?
Here are the tusks... A scary razorback.
You're right. He's a fine mascot
and will engender school spirit.
He'd better.
Costs a fortune to feed him.
All right, let's get you
back into your cage.
This way.
- I'm not getting this.
- It's simple, really.
See, the bisector of a vertex
is the line that divides the angle
at that vertex into two equal parts.
It's like a big blur,
all these numbers and angles.
It's the same stuff from last week.
You had it down then.
- Why do I need to learn this?
- 'Cause otherwise you'll flunk math.
Explain the part why that's bad.
You remember. You fail math,
you flunk out of school,
you end up being the guy at the pizza place
that sweeps the floor and says:
"Hey, kids, where's
the cool parties this weekend?"
We've been through this.
Do you have a headache?
Yeah. And I think
I know what's causing it.
Ah! That's better.
It goes right to the source of the pain.
- Xander...
- Look, forget it, OK? I don't get it.
I won't ever. I don't care!
We can finish this another time.
See, the problem is you kids today
have no school spirit.
Hold on. Let me get his outfit off.
Today it's all gangs and drugs and
those movies on Showtime with the nudity.
I don't have cable. I only heard.
When I was your age,
we cared about the school's reputation
and the football team's record.
All that stuff.
Of course, when I was your age
I was surrounded by old guys
telling me how much better
things were when they were my age.
Yeah.
All right... it's raining.
All regular gym classes
have been postponed.
So you know what that means.
Dodge ball.
For those of you that may have forgotten,
the rules are as follows:
You dodge.
- Here we go!
- On your guards!
God, this game is brutal.
I love it!
Xander?
What's wrong with you?
I guess you've noticed
that I've been different around you lately.
- Yes.
- I think I'm...
I think it's because my feelings for you
have been changing.
And while we've been friends
for such a long time
that I feel like I need to tell you something.
I've, um...
I've decided to drop geometry. So I won't
be needing your math help any more.
Which means I won't have to look
at your pasty face again.
Are you gonna say something to me?
- Dogs.
- Where?
You're out of your mind!
That's no way to play lead guitar!
- What're you talking about?
- That's just hunt and peck.
- It's not!
- Hey, Xander.
You've heard Wretched Refuse play. What
do you think of the guy who plays lead?
Hey!
- Hey! What are you guys...?
- Shut up.
You're sharing.
Friends like to share.
- Good?
- It's too well done.
Hey! That is not cool.
Hey!
Let's do lunch.
(# "Job's Eyes" by Far)
# I'm sure this rain won't last
# I'm sure its time is up
# Though it's pouring down
# I'm sure this rain won't last
# And it falls on Job's eyes
# This water of doubt
# And I'm wading in lies
# It's wearing me out
# But if you want it, alright
# I'll buy it, I'll buy it,
# I'll buy it, I'll...
I've known him my whole life, Buffy.
We haven't always been close,
but he's never...
I think something's wrong with him.
Or maybe there's something wrong with me.
What are you talking about?
Come on. He's not picking on you.
He's just sniffing you a lot.
I don't know.
Maybe three isn't company any more.
You think this has something to do with me?
Of course.
No. That still doesn't explain why
he's hanging out with the Dode Patrol.
Something's going on. Something weird.
What are you gonna do?
Talk to the expert on weird.
Xander's taken to teasing
the less fortunate?
And there's a noticeable change
in both clothing and demeanor?
Yes.
And, well, otherwise all his spare time
is spent... lounging about with imbeciles.
- It's bad, isn't it?
- It's devastating.
He's turned into a 16-year-old boy.
Of course, you'll have to kill him.
- Giles, I'm serious!
- So am I!
Except for the part about killing him.
Testosterone is a great equaliser.
Turns all men into morons.
He will, however, get over it.
I cannot believe that you, of all people,
are trying to Scully me!
There is something supernatural
at work here.
Get your books! Look stuff up!
Look under what?
I don't know. That's your department.
The evidence that you've presented me with
is sketchy at best.
He scared the pig.
- Well, he did.
- Buffy, boys can be cruel.
They tease. They prey on the weak.
It's a natural teen behavior pattern.
What did you just say?
Um... they tease.
They prey on the weak.
I've heard that somewhere before...
Xander has been acting totally wiggy
ever since we went to the zoo.
Him and Kyle and all those guys,
they went into the hyena cage.
Oh, God, that laugh.
You're saying that
Xander's becoming a hyena?
I don't know.
Or been possessed by one?
Not just Xander. All of them.
- Well, I've certainly never heard of...
- Herbert! They've found him!
- The pig?
- Dead.
And also eaten.
Principal Flutie's freaking out.
Testosterone, huh?
What are you gonna do?
Get my books.
Look stuff up.
You four!
- What?
- Oh, don't think I don't know.
Three kids saw you outside Herbert's room.
You're busted. Yeah. You're going down.
- How is Herbert?
- Crunchy!
That's it! My office! Right now!
Now!
You're gonna have so much detention,
your grandchildren'll be
staying after school.
Wow! Apparently, Noah rejected
the hyenas from the Ark
because he thought they were
an evil, impure mixture of dogs and cats.
Hyenas aren't well liked.
They do seem to be the schmoes
of the animal kingdom.
Why couldn't Xander be possessed
by a puppy or some ducks?
That's assuming "possession" is the right word.
Oh, I'll say it is.
The Masai of the Serengeti have spoken of
animal possession for generations now.
- I should've remembered that.
- So, how does it work?
Apparently, there's a sect
of animal worshippers known as primals.
They believe that... humanity...
consciousness... the soul
is a perversion, a dilution of spirit.
To them the animal state is holy.
They're able,
through transpossession, to-to...
draw the spirit of certain animals
into themselves.
And then they started acting like hyenas.
Only the most predatory of animals
are of interest to primals.
So, yes, that would fit.
So, what happens to the person
once the spirit's in them?
If it goes unchecked?
I gotta find Xander.
They are strong.
Xander!
This is ridiculous. We need to talk.
I've been waiting for you to jump my bones!
I have seen some sick things
in my life, believe me!
But this is beyond the pale!
What is it with you people? Is it drugs?
How could you? A poor, defenseless pig!
What are you doing?
- Get off of me!
- Is that what you really want?
We both know what you really want.
You want danger, don't ya?
- You like your men dangerous.
- You're in trouble, Xander.
You are infected with some hyena thing.
It's like a demonic possession.
Dangerous and mean, right?
Like Angel, your mystery guy.
Well, guess who just got mean.
Now stop that! You're only gonna
make things worse for yourselves.
I'll tell you how this is gonna work.
I am gonna call your parents,
and they're gonna take you all home.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
That is it!
Do you know how long I've waited
until you'd stop pretending
that we aren't attracted...
Until Willow stops kidding herself
that I could settle with anyone but you
Look, Xander, I don't wanna hurt you.
Now do you wanna hurt me?
Come on, Slayer. I like it when you're scared.
The more I scare you... the better you smell.
You're about this close to expulsion, people!
I'm willing to talk to the school
counselor and we can discuss options.
Get down from there this instant!
Ow!
Are you insane?!
Hurry up. We gotta get him
locked up somehow before he comes to.
- Oh, my God! What happened?
- I hit him.
- With what?
- A desk.
He tried his hand
at felony sexual assault.
- Oh, Buffy, the hyena in him didn't...
- No.
No, but it's safe to say that
in his animal state his idea of wooing
doesn't involve a Yanni CD
and a bottle of Chianti.
There. That oughta hold him. Where's Giles?
He got called to some teacher's meeting.
What are we gonna do?
I mean... How do we get Xander back?
Right now I'm a little more worried about
what the rest of the pack are up to.
The rest of the pack was spotted
outside Herbert the mascot's cage.
- They were sent to the principal's office.
- Good. That'll show 'em.
Did it show 'em?
They didn't hurt him, did they?
They, uh... ate him.
They ate Principal Flutie?
Ate him up?
The, uh, official theory is that wild dogs
got into his office somehow.
There was no one at the scene.
But Xander didn't. He was with you.
Oh! Well, that's a small mercy.
Giles, how do we stop this?
How do you transpossess someone?
I'm afraid I still don't have all the pieces.
Accounts of the primals and their methods
are a bit thin on the ground.
There is some talk of a predatory act,
but the exact ritual is, um...
The Malleus Maleficarum deals in the
particulars of demonic possession, which
may apply.
Yes. One should be able
to transfer the spirits to another human.
- Oh, that's great! Any volunteers?
- Oh. Good point.
What we need to do
is put the hyena back in the hyena.
- B-but until we know more, uh...
- Betcha that zookeeper could help us.
Maybe he didn't quarantine those hyenas
because they were sick.
- We should talk to him.
- OK.
- Oh, wait! Somebody's gotta watch Xander.
- I will.
- Will, are you sure? If he wakes up...
- I'll be all right. Go.
Come on.
Willow.
How are you feeling?
Like somebody hit me with a desk.
- What am I doing here?
- You're resting.
You guys got me locked up now.
'Cause you're sick. Buffy said.
Oh, yeah. Buffy
and her all-purpose solution.
Punch 'em out, knock 'em down.
I'd love to see what she'd do
to somebody who was really sick.
That's not fair!
Buffy's saved both of our lives.
Before she came here, our lives didn't
need that much saving, did they?
Weren't things a lot simpler
when it was just you and me?
- Maybe.
- When we were alone together.
Willow, I know there's something
wrong with me. I think it's getting worse.
But I can't just stand around
waiting for Buffy to decide it's time
to punch me out again.
Look, I want you to help me. I want you.
I am helping you.
You're doing what you're told.
Buffy's trying to help you, too.
You know that.
- Or Xander does.
- Yeah.
Buffy's so selfless.
Always thinking of us.
Well, if I'm so dangerous,
how come she left you alone with me?
- I told her to.
- Why?
'Cause I know you better than she does.
And I wanted to be here to see if
you were still you.
You know I am.
Look at me.
Look.
Xander...
Now I know.
Let me out! Let me out!
- The students have been possessed?
- Yes!
- Are you sure?
- We're really, really sure.
You don't seem
enormously surprised by this.
The zoo imported those hyenas from Africa.
There was something strange
about them from day one.
I did some homework.
That particular breed is very rare.
Totally vicious. Historically,
they were worshipped by these guys.
- Primals.
- Yeah. Creepy guys.
Now, they had rituals
for taking the hyena spirits, but
I don't see how that
could've happened to your kids.
We don't know how the ritual works.
Only that it involves, uh,
a predatory act and some kind of symbol.
Predatory act? Of course.
That makes sense.
- Where did you read that?
- D'you have Sherman Jeffries' work
- on cults and...
- Boys?
- Sorry.
- Look. Look...
I think we may have enough information
so that together we could
pull off a reverse transpossession.
What do we do?
You've gotta get those possessed students
over to the hyena cage right away.
I'll meet you there.
We can begin the rituals.
Well, we can guarantee you one of them,
but there are four more and
we have no idea where they are.
No, I wouldn't worry about that.
After hyenas feed and rest, they will track
the missing member of their pack
until they find him.
They should come right to you.
Willow!
I'm not listening.
Willow
Xander shut up!
Willow!
Run!
- I think they're going.
- They could be faking it.
No, they're hungry.
They'll be looking for somebody weak.
I'm really sorry, Will. I didn't know
they were gonna come after Xander.
- It's OK.
- We must lead them back to the zoo.
- if we're going to stop it.
- And before their next meal.
- Guess that's my job.
- Well, individually
they're almost as strong as you.
As a group, they're...
They're tough,
but I think they're getting stupider.
You guys go to the zoo
and I will bring them to you.
I didn't say she looks better than you.
I said she looks better.
I heard what I heard. Joey, chew.
You have to chew or you'll choke.
I don't see why we have to have
this conversation every time we see them.
I didn't start it.
Damn!
- Where are the keys?
- Huh?
Joey!
Joey.
Get out!
What's going on?
Hey, get off! Get off!
Joey! Joey!
Joey!
Didn't your mom teach you?
Don't play with your food.
Come on. You know what you want.
The pathway to the hyena house.
- Where's the zookeeper?
- He must be inside.
I'll go in and prepare things. You just...
warn, uh, us when you hear
Buffy and the others approaching.
Doctor?
Uh... zookeeper?
Oh, of course. The, uh...
Masai ceremonial garb. Yes. Very good.
Are you, uh, otherwise prepared
for the transpossession?
Almost.
Oh, right. The, uh sacred circle.
Yes, you'd need that to, um...
But this would be here when...
when the children first came.
Why would you...?
How terribly frustrating for you,
that a bunch of schoolchildren
could accomplish what you could not.
It bothered me.
But the power will be mine.
They're almost here! Giles! Giles!
Where are the hyenas
for the transpossession?
They're right here in the feeding area.
Stay back. They haven't been fed.
- Where's Giles?
- He's... laying in wait.
They're almost here!
Shouldn't you bring the hyenas out?
When the time is right.
I'm gonna need your help.
They're right behind me!
That's Buffy. Get ready!
- Here.
- What is this?
A predatory act, remember?
Uh, right.
You'll pretend to slash my throat and
- and put the evil in the hyenas?
- Something like that.
Buffy, it's a trap!
YU BA YA SA NA!
Willow!
Uh... did I miss anything?
I heard the vice principal's taking over
till they can find a replacement.
Shouldn't be too hard
to find a new principal.
Unless they ask
what happened to the last one.
OK, but I had nothing
to do with that, right?
- Right.
- You only ate the pig.
I ate a pig? Was he cooked
and called bacon, or...
Oh, my God! I ate a pig?
I mean, the whole
trichinosis issue aside, yuck!
- Well, it wasn't really you.
- Well, I remember
I was goin' on the field trip,
and then goin' down to the Hyena House,
and next thing, some guy's
holding Willow and he's got a knife.
- You saved my life.
- Hey, nobody messes with my Willow.
This is definitely the superior Xander.
Accept no substitutes.
I didn't do anything else, did l,
around you guys?
Anything embarrassing?
- Nah!
- Not at all.
- C'mon. We're gonna be late.
- See you at lunch.
Cool!
Oh, hey, going vegetarian, huh?
I've been reading up on my...
animal possession.
I cannot find anything anywhere
about... memory loss afterwards.
- Did you tell them that?
- Your secret dies with me.
Shoot me, stuff me, mount me.
Subtitles by: Claire Bates
Corrections & timing by: UAR
...
www.tvsubtitles.net