In every generation there is a Chosen One.
She alone will stand against the vampires,
the demons and the forces of darkness.
She is the Slayer.
No! Get off!
Hey!
Xander!
Xander, are you OK?
Man, something hit me.
- Where's Jesse?
- I don't know. They surrounded us.
- That girl grabbed him and took off.
- Which way?
I don't know.
Jesse...
This world is older than any of you know.
Contrary to popular mythology,
it did not begin as a paradise.
For untold aeons, demons walked the Earth.
They made it their home. Their, uh, their Hell.
But in time
they lost their purchase on this reality.
The way was made for mortal animals.
For-for Man.
All that remains of the Old Ones...
are vestiges.
Certain magics. Certain creatures.
- And vampires.
- OK, this is where I have a problem.
See, because we're talking about vampires.
We're having a talk with vampires in it.
- Isn't that what we saw last night?
- No, those weren't vampires.
Those were... just guys
in thundering need of a facial.
Or maybe they had rabies.
It could have been rabies.
And that guy turning to dust?
Just a trick of light.
That's what I said the first time
I saw a vampire.
Well, after I was done
with the screaming part.
- Oh, I need to sit down.
- You are sitting down.
- Oh! Good for me.
- So, vampires are demons?
The books tell the last demon
to leave this reality fed off a human.
Mixed their blood.
He was a human form possessed.
Infected by the demon's soul.
He bit another, and another.
And so they walked the Earth, feeding.
Killing some, mixing their blood
with others to make more of their kind.
Waiting for the animals to die out,
and the Old Ones to return.
Move.
Is this for me?
An offering, Master.
He's a good one. His blood is pure.
You've tasted it.
I'm your... faithful dog.
You bring me scraps.
I didn't mean...
I have waited.
For three score years, I have waited.
While you come and go, I am stuck here.
Here in this house of...
worship.
My ascension is almost at hand.
Pray that when it comes...
I'm in a better mood.
Master, forgive me.
We had more offerings,
but there was trouble. A girl.
And there was a girl.
She fought well and she knew of our breed.
- It is possible that she may be...
- A slayer.
And that would be a what?
For as long as there have been vampires,
there's been the Slayer.
One girl in all the world. A Chosen one.
He loves doing this part.
All right.
The Slayer hunts vampires.
Buffy is a slayer. Don't tell anyone.
Well, I think that's
all the vampire information you need.
Except for one thing. How you kill them?
You don't. I do.
- Well, Jesse's my...
- Jesse's my responsibility.
- I let him get taken.
- That's not true.
If you hadn't shown up,
they would have taken us, too.
Does anybody mind if I pass out?
- Breathe.
Breathe.
This big guy, Luke, he talked about
an offering to the Master.
Now, I don't know what or who,
but if they weren't just feeding,
then Jesse may still be alive.
I'm gonna find him.
This may be the dumb question,
but shouldn't we call the police?
And they'd believe us, of course.
We don't have to say 'vampires'.
We could just say there's a... a bad man.
They couldn't handle it even if they did
show up. They'd only come with guns.
You have no idea where they took Jesse?
I looked around but soon as
they got clear of the graveyard,
they could have just... voom!
- They can fly?
- They can drive.
Oh.
I don't remember hearing a car.
Let's take an
enormous intuitive leap, shall we?
And say they went underground.
Vampires really jam on sewer systems.
You can get anywhere in the entire town
without catching any rays.
But I didn't see any access around there.
Well, there's an electrical tunnel
that runs under the whole town.
If we have a diagnostic
of the tunnel system,
it might indicate a meeting place.
I suppose we could go
to the building commission.
We so don't have time.
Uh, guys?
There may be another way.
A slayer. Have you any proof?
- Only that she fought me and yet lives.
- Oh, very nearly proof enough.
I can't remember
the last time that happened.
1843, Madrid.
He caught me sleeping.
She mustn't be allowed
to interfere with the Harvest.
- I would never let that happen.
- Don't worry about it.
I believe she'll come to us.
We have something she wants.
If she is a slayer,
and this boy lives,
she'll try to save him.
I thought you're nothing more
than a meal, boy.
Congratulations.
You've just been upgraded,
to bait.
There it is.
- That runs under the graveyard.
- I don't see any access.
So, all the city plans are just...
open to the public?
Um... well, in a way.
I sort of stumbled on to them
when I accidentally decrypted
the city council's security system.
- Someone's been naughty.
- There's nothing here. It's useless!
I think you're being
a bit hard on yourself.
You're the one that told me
that I wasn't prepared enough!
Understatement!
I thought I was
on top of everything and then
that monster, Luke, came out of nowhere...
What?
He didn't come out of nowhere.
He came from behind me.
I was facing the entrance...
He came from behind me
and didn't follow me out.
The access to the tunnels
is in the mausoleum!
The girl must've doubled back
with Jesse after I got out.
- God! I am so mentally challenged!
- So what's the plan? We saddle up, right?
There's no we, OK?
I'm the Slayer, and you're not.
- I knew you'd throw that back in my face.
- Xander, this is deeply dangerous.
I'm inadequate. That's fine.
I'm less than a man.
Buffy, I'm not anxious to go into
a dark place full of monsters,
but I do wanna help. I need to.
Well, then help me.
I've been researching this Harvest affair.
It seems to be some sort of
preordained massacre.
Rivers of blood.
Hell on Earth. Quite charmless.
I'm a bit fuzzy however on the details.
It may be that you can wrest some
information from that dread machine.
That was a bit... British, wasn't it?
Welcome to the New World.
- I want you to go on the Net.
- Oh, sure. I can do that.
Then I'm outta here.
If Jesse's alive, I'll bring him back.
Do I have to tell you to be careful?
And where do we think we're going?
We?
I. Me.
We're not leaving school grounds, are we?
No. No! I'm... just admiring the fence.
You know, this is quality fencework.
Because if we were leaving school grounds
on our second day of the new school,
after getting kicked out of our old school
for delinquent behavior...
You see where I'm going with this?
Mr Giles.
What?
He asked me to get a book for him,
from the store.
I have a free period. And I'm a big reader -
did it mention that on my transcripts?
- Mr Giles?
- Ask him.
Well, maybe that's how
they do things in Britain.
They've got that royal family and all kinds
of problems, but here at Sunnydale...
nobody leaves campus
while school's in session.
- Are we clear?
- We're... clear.
That's the Buffy Summers
I want in my school.
Sensible girl with her feet on the ground.
- Murder, death, disaster. What else?
- Paranormal. Unexplained.
- Natural disasters.
- Earthquake, flood...
- Rain of toads.
- Right.
Rain of Toads! Do you think they'd have
anything like that in the paper?
I'll put it on a computer search.
If it's there, it'll turn up.
Anything that'll lead us to vampires.
And l, in the meantime, will help
by standing around like an idiot.
Not like an idiot. Just standing.
Buffy doesn't want you getting hurt.
I don't want you getting hurt.
This is just too much.
I mean, yesterday my life's like:
"Uh-oh! Pop quiz."
Today, it's "rain of toads".
I know. And everyone else thinks
it's just a normal day.
Nobody knows.
It's like we've got this big secret.
We do.
That's what a secret is, when you
know something other guys don't.
Right.
- Look, maybe you should get to class.
- You mean we. We should get to class.
Yeah.
Buffy'll be OK. Whatever's down there,
I think she can handle it.
- Yeah, I do too.
- So do I.
I don't suppose you've got a key on you?
They really don't like me dropping in.
- Why not?
- They really don't like me.
How could that possibly be?
I knew you'd figure out
this entryway sooner or later.
Actually, I thought
it was gonna be a little sooner.
Sorry you had to wait.
OK. Look,
if you're gonna be popping up
with this Cryptic Wise Man act
on a regular basis
- can you at least tell me your name?
- Angel.
Angel. That's a pretty name.
Don't... go down there.
Deal with my going.
You shouldn't be putting yourself at risk.
Tonight is the Harvest.
Unless you can prevent it,
the Master walks.
Well, if this Harvest thing
is such a suckfest,
why don't you stop it?
'Cause I'm afraid.
They'll be expecting you.
I've got a friend down there.
Or at least a potential friend.
Do you know what it's like
to have a friend?
That wasn't supposed to be a stumper.
When you hit the tunnels,
head east towards the school.
That's where you're likely to find them.
You gonna wish me luck?
Good luck.
- Xander, what are you doing here?
- Something stupid. I followed you.
- Well, you're...
I couldn't just
sit at home and do nothing.
I understand. Now go away.
- No!
- Xander, you're gonna have to!
Look, Jesse's my bud, OK?
If I can help him out,
that's what I gotta do.
Besides, it's this or chem class.
OK, so crosses, garlic,
stake through the heart.
- That'll get it done.
- Cool!
Of course, I don't actually have
any of those things.
Good thinking.
Well, the part of my brain
that would tell me to bring that stuff
is still busy telling me
not to come down here.
- I have this, though.
- Turn that off!
OK, OK!
- So, what else?
- What else what?
For vampire slayage.
Oh, fire, beheading, sunlight, holy water.
- The usual.
- You've done some beheading in your time?
Oh, yeah. There was this time
I was pinned down  by this guy
that played left tackle for varsity...
Well, he used to before he was a vampire.
Anyway, he had this really thick neck,
and all I had was this little X-Acto knife.
You're not loving this story.
No, actually, I find it oddly comforting.
"For they will gather and be gathered."
"From the Vessel pours life."
Pours life...
"On the night of the crescent moon,
the first past the solstice, it will come."
Of course.
That's tonight.
No!
It's supposed to
find the syntax and match it!
- Or wait...
- Are we going to the Bronze tonight?
No. We're going
to the other cool place in Sunnydale.
Of course we're going to the Bronze.
Friday night? No cover?
But you should have been there last night,
'cause I ran into Buffy.
And could she be any weirder?
She attacked me! Do you believe it?
I think we did this part wrong.
Why do we have to devise these programs,
isn't that what nerds are for?
What'd she do?
She's doing something else.
OK. And then "pattern run", right?
Or "go to end". That's it!
Maybe.
So anyway, I come out of the bathroom
and she comes running at me,
screaming, with a stick,
"I'm gonna kill you!
I'm gonna kill you!" I swear!
- Who?
- Buffy.
- The new girl.
- What's her deal?
- She's crazed.
- Did you hear about her old school?
Booted.
- Well, I exhibit no surprise.
- Why was she kicked out?
- Because she's a psycho loony.
- No, she's not.
What?
She's not a psycho.
You don't even know her.
Excuse me?
Who gave you permission to exist?
Do I horn in on your private discussions?
No. Why? Because you're boring.
OK, I think the program's done.
Finally the nightmare ends!
OK, so how do we save it?
- Deliver.
- Deliver? Where's that?
Oh!
- They're close.
- How can you tell?
No more rats.
- Jesse!
- Oh, no!
Jesse?
- Xander!
- Jesse, man. Are you OK?
I am not OK on an epic scale.
We gotta get outta here.
- It's cool. Buffy's a superhero.
- Hold on.
Do you think anyone heard that?
They knew you were gonna come.
They said that I was the bait.
Oh, great. Now you tell us.
- Oops.
- Oh, no, no, no, no!
- Do you know another way out?
- I don't know. Maybe. Come on.
Wait! Wait! They brought me through here.
There should be a way up. I hope.
- I don't think this is the way out.
- We can't fight our way back through them.
- What do we do?
- I've got an idea.
You can die.
- Jesse, man. I'm sorry.
- Sorry?
I feel good, Xander. I feel strong.
I'm connected, man, to everything!
- I can hear the worms in the earth.
- That's a plus.
I know what the Master wants.
I'll serve his purpose.
That means you die.
- And I feed.
- Xander, the cross!
Jesse, man, we're buds.
Don't you remember?
- You're like a shadow to me now.
- Then get outta my face.
Help me!
- We need to get out of here.
- There is no out of here.
Up there!
Go!
Xander, pull.
She escaped?
She walks free when I should be
drinking her heart's blood right now!
- Careless.
- Master, we had her trapped.
Oh. Are you going to make excuses?
You are all weak.
It has been too long
since you have faced a slayer.
It is no matter to me.
She will not stop the Harvest.
It just means there'll be someone
worth killing when I reach the surface.
- Is Luke ready?
- He waits.
It's time. Bring him to me. Uh, Collin.
You failed me.
Tell me you're sorry.
I'm sorry.
There. That wasn't so bad, was it?
Hold on.
You've got something in your eye.
- Buffy?
- It's just me.
- So, there's no word?
- Uh, not as yet, no.
Well, I'm sure they're great.
- Did you find anything of interest?
- I think maybe.
I surfed through the old newspapers
around the time of
that big earthquake back in '37.
And for several months before,
there were a rash of murders.
Great!
I mean, uh, well, not great in a good way.
Uh... go on.
Well, they sound like the kind
you were looking for. Throats, blood...
It's all coming together.
I rather wish it weren't.
My blood is your blood.
My soul is your soul.
My body is your instrument.
On this most hallowed night,
we are as one.
Luke is the Vessel.
Every soul he takes will feed me.
And their souls
will grant me the strength
to free myself.
Tonight I shall walk the Earth,
and the stars themselves will hide!
- Did you find Jesse?
- Yeah.
- Was he dead?
- Worse.
I'm sorry, Willow, but we were too late.
- And they were waiting for us.
- At least you two are OK.
I don't like vampires. I'm gonna
take a stand and say they're not good.
So, Giles, got anything
that could make this day any worse?
How about the end of the world?
Knew I could count on you.
This is what we know:
Some 60 years ago,
a very old, very powerful vampire
came to this shore, not just to feed.
He came 'cause
this town's a mystical whoozit.
Yes.
The Spanish who first settled here
called it "Boca del Infierno".
Roughly translated "Hellmouth".
It's a sort of, um...
portal between this reality and the next.
- This vampire hoped to open it.
- Bring the demons back.
- End of the world.
- But he blew it.
Or, I mean, there was an earthquake
that swallowed half the town, and him too.
You see, opening dimensional portals
is a tricky business.
Odds are he got himself stuck,
rather like a cork in a bottle.
And this Harvest thing is to get him out.
It comes once in a century, on this night.
The Master can draw power
from one of his minions while it feeds.
Enough power to break free
and open the portal.
The minion is called the Vessel,
and he bears this symbol.
So, I dust anyone sporting that symbol,
and no Harvest.
Simply put, yes.
Any idea where this
little get-together is being held?
- There are a number of possibilities.
- They're going to the Bronze.
Are you sure?
Come on. All those tasty
young morsels all over the place?
Anyway, that's where
Jesse's gonna be. Trust me.
Then we should get there.
- The sun will be down before long.
- I gotta make a stop. Won't take long.
- What for?
- Supplies.
Buffy?
- Mom!
- You're going out?
- I have to.
- I didn't hear you come in last night.
I was really quiet.
It's happening again, isn't it?
I got a call from your new principal.
- Says you missed some classes today.
- I was running an errand.
We haven't finished unpacking,
and I'm getting calls from the principal.
Mom, I promise,
it is not gonna be like before.
But I have to go.
- No.
- Mom!
The tapes all say
I should get used to saying it. No.
This is really, really important!
I know. If you don't go out,
it'll be the end of the world.
Everything is life or death
when you're a 16-year-old girl.
- I don't have time...
- You have all the time in the world.
You're not going anywhere.
Now, if you wanna stay up here and sulk,
I won't hold it against you.
But if you wanna come down,
I'll make us some dinner.
Senior boys are the only way to go.
Guys from our grade? Forget about it.
They're children, you know?
Like Jesse. Did you see him last night?
Following me around
like a little puppy dog.
You just wanna put him to sleep.
But senior boys?
They have mystery. They have...
What's the word I'm searching for?
Cars.
I just am not the type to settle, you know?
It's like when I go shopping.
I have to have the most expensive thing.
Not because it's expensive,
- but because it costs more.
- You know...
Hello? Miss Motor-Mouth?
Can I get a sentence finished?
Oh, I love this song! Come on!
What do you want?
Hey! Hello?
Caveman-brain, what are you doing?
Shut up.
Well, just one dance.
You need ID. Hey!
Nobody gets inside until I get some sorta...
Get inside.
Ladies and gentlemen,
there is no cause for alarm.
Actually, there is cause for alarm.
It just won't do any good.
I thought there was no band tonight.
This is a glorious night!
It is also the last one
any of you shall ever see.
Bring me the first.
What do you guys want, man, huh?
You want money?
Hey, what's wrong with your faces?
Watch me, people.
Fear is like an elixir.
It's almost like blood.
Next!
- It's locked!
- We're too late!
- I didn't know Iwas gonna get grounded!
- Can you break it?
No, not that thing. You guys try the
back entrance and I'll find my own way.
- Right. Come on.
- Uh, wait, guys. Here.
You get the exit cleared
and the people out. That's all.
Don't go Wild Bunch on me.
Uh... see you inside, then.
No joy.
We've got to get in there before
Jesse does something stupider than usual.
You listen to me. Jesse is dead.
You have to remember that when you see
him, you're not looking at your friend.
You're looking at the thing that killed him.
Almost free.
Give me more!
- This one's mine!
- They're all for the Master.
I don't get one?
I can feel the Master's strength growing!
I feel him rising!
Every soul brings him closer!
I need another!
The Vessel.
Tonight is his ascension!
Tonight will be history at its end!
Yours is a glorious sacrifice,
degradation most holy.
What? No volunteers?
Here's a pretty one.
No!
Oh, I'm sorry!
Were you in the middle of something?
You!
You didn't think I'd miss this. Did you?
- I hoped you'd come.
- Be right down.
OK, Vessel boy.
- You want blood?
- I want yours.
Only yours.
Works for me.
Hurry!
Come on out, let's go!
Come on! Come on! Come on!
Hurry up! Come on, let's go!
Come on! This way!
Heads up.
Hold still!
- You're not making this easy.
- Jesse, man. Don't make me do it.
Buddy!
I always wanted to kill a slayer.
One at a time! Quickly!
We're gonna have to open the front as well.
Jesse, I know
there's still a part of you in there.
OK. Let's... deal with this.
Jesse was an excruciating loser
who couldn't get a date with anyone
in the sighted community!
Look at me. I'm a new man!
Master, taste of this and be free.
How'd it taste?
Get off of him!
All right. Put me out of my misery.
You don't have the gu...
You forget. Metal can't hurt me.
There's something you forgot about, too.
Sunrise.
It's in about nine hours, moron.
No!
She did it.
I'll be damned.
I take it it's over.
Did we win?
Well, we averted the apocalypse.
I'd give us points for that.
One thing's for sure.
Nothing's ever gonna be the same.
Wait up!
Well, I heard it was rival gangs, you know.
Fighting for turf.
But all I can tell you is
they were an ugly way of looking.
And Buffy, like, knew them.
Which is just too weird.
I don't even remember much,
but I'm telling you, it was a freak show.
God, I wish I'd been there.
You should have been there.
It was so creepy.
- What exactly were you expecting?
- I don't know. Something.
I mean, the dead rose.
We should at least have an assembly.
People have a tendency to rationalize
what they can and forget what they can't.
- Believe me. I've seen it happen.
- Well, I'll never forget it. None of it.
- Good. Next time you'll be prepared.
- Next time?
Next time is why?
We prevented the Master from freeing
himself and opening the Mouth of Hell.
That's not to say
he's going to stop trying.
- I'd say the fun is just beginning.
- More vampires?
Not just vampires.
The next threat we face
may be something quite different.
I can hardly wait.
We are at the centre
of a mystical convergence here.
We may, in fact, stand between
the Earth and its total destruction.
Well, I gotta look on the bright side.
Maybe I can still get kicked out of school.
Oh, yeah, that's a plan. 'Cause
lots of schools aren't on Hellmouths.
Maybe you could blow something up.
They're really strict about that.
I was thinking of a
more subtle approach, you know?
Like... excessive not studying.
The Earth is doomed!
Subtitles by: Claire Bates
Completed and adjusted by: UAR
...
www.tvsubtitles.net