All right, you can
open them up now.
Fab. What's the occasion?
Faith, as if I need a reason
to show you my affection...
or appreciation for running
a small errand at the airport.
Airport?
What's next?
You gonna want me to help
a buddy of yours move a sofa?
This isn't a free ride,
young lady.
You know,
I'm beginning to think...
that somebody's getting
a little spoiled.
Maybe I should
take this back.
Sorry...
sir.
That's my girl.
Another cookie?
Now... a package is
arriving tomorrow night...
from Central America.
Something... and I can't
stress this enough...
something crucially important
to my ascension.
Without it...
well, what would
tollhouse cookies be...
without the chocolate chips?
A pretty darn
big disappointment...
I can tell you.
Ha ha ha.
Open your present.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
There.
That look on your face
is my reward.
This is a thing
of beauty, Boss.
Cost a pretty penny.
So, you just
take good care of it.
You be careful...
not to put somebody's
eye out with that thing.
Till I tell you to.
Got any particular
eyes in mind?
Sorry, honey.
That's OK.
Well, there's something
you don't see every day.
Unless, of course,
you're me.
That was bracing.
Wanna do another sweep?
It's what I live for.
Sad to say.
Too tired?
No.
It's just...
do you get the feeling
that we're kind of in a rut?
Rut?
You never take me
anyplace new.
What about that
fire-demon nest...
in the cave by the beach?
Thought that was
a nice change of pace.
So this is our future?
I mean, this is how we're
gonna spend our nights...
when I'm 50 and you're...
the same age you are now?
[Growling]
Let's just get you to 50.
Liking that plan.
Buffy?
When were you
going to tell me?
All right, busted.
I didn't think
you'd miss them.
You were accepted to
Northwestern University?
Honey,
I'm so proud of you.
That's wonderful.
Right, it's wonderful.
Hmm. I mean,
it's not cheap...
but, uh, I know
we can make it work...
if your father pitches in.
Not that Northwestern
is your only option.
It's a great school, though.
I am so proud of you.
You said that before.
And will again soon.
Mom, you know that I can't...
I... I just can't decide
on a school right now.
I mean, I want to sleep on it,
you know, mull it over.
Raise them up my inner flagpole,
see which one I salute.
I know, sweetheart.
I'm just so pleased
you have so many choices.
Ooh, you know what?
Your aunt Arlene
and her family...
are in Illinois.
I've got to call
and tell them.
Oh, Buffy...
I know.
You're proud of me.
Don't forget to put my earrings
back in my dresser...
before you go out.
Arlene?
Hi. It's Joyce.
How you doin'?
You are never gonna believe
where Buffy got accepted to school.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
OK, what's in the bag?
My lunch.
Is that the new
drug lingo?
No. It's my lunch.
Sit up straight.
Sounds like your mom's
in a state of denial.
More like a continent.
She just has to realize
that I can't go away.
Well, maybe not now,
but soon, maybe.
Or maybe I, too,
hail from denial land.
Faith's turn to the
dark side of the force...
pretty much put
the proverbial kibosh...
on any away plans
for me.
U.C. Sunnydale.
At least I got in.
But you... I can't believe
you got into Oxford.
It's pretty exciting.
There's some
deep academia there.
That's where
they make Gileses!
I know. I could learn
and have scones.
Although I don't know
how I feel...
about going to school
in a foreign country.
Everything in life
is foreign territory.
Kerouac. He's my teacher.
The open road... my school.
Making the open Dumpster
your cafeteria?
Go ahead, mock me.
I think she just did.
We bohemian,
anti-establishment types...
have always been persecuted.
Sure. You're all so weird.
I think it's neat...
you doing the backpack,
trail mix, happy wanderer thing.
I'm aware it scores kinda high
on the hokey meter.
But I think
it'll be good for me...
help me to find myself.
And help us to lose you.
Everyone's a winner.
Well, look who just popped open
a fresh can of venom.
Hey, did you hear about Willow
getting into Oxnard?
- Oxford.
- And M.I.T.
And Yale and
every other college...
on the face of the planet...
as in your face
I rub it.
Oxford. Whoopee.
4 years in tea bag central.
Sounds thrilling.
And M.I.T. is a Clearasil ad
with housing.
And Yale is
a dumping ground...
for those who didn't
get into Harvard.
I got into Harvard.
Any clue on what college
you might be attending...
so we can start calculating
minimum safe distance?
None of your business.
Certainly nowhere near
you losers.
You guys, don't forget to
breathe between insults.
I'm sorry, Buffy.
This conversation is reserved...
for those who actually
have a future.
Angry young woman.
Oh, Buffy, she was
just being Cordelia.
Only more so.
Don't pay
any attention to her.
Xander: She's definitely
got a chip goin'.
Maybe if you didn't
goad her so much.
I can't help it.
It's my nature.
Maybe you need
a better nature.
I don't understand.
I don't think I can
talk any slower, Wes.
I want to leave.
What, now?
No, not now.
After I graduate.
College?
But... you're a slayer.
Yeah. I'm also a person.
You can't just define me
by my slayerness.
That's... something-ism.
Buffy, I know we've talked
about you going away.
I got into Northwestern.
That's wonderful news.
Good for you.
All right, everyone. Monsters,
demons, world in peril.
I'll betcha they have
all that stuff in Illinois.
You cannot leave Sunnydale!
With the power invested in me
by the Council, I forbid it.
Oh, yes, that should
settle it.
With Faith gone bad...
and the mayor's ascension
coming up...
I know it's complicated.
I'm aware that my graduation...
may be, among other things,
posthumous...
but what if I
stop the ascension?
What if I capture Faith?
I very much
hope you will.
If I do that, then all
you guys have to do...
is keep the run-of-the-mill unholy
forces at bay through midterms...
and I'll be back in time
for homecoming...
and every school break
after that.
Can we at least
think about it?
Perhaps if circumstances
were different...
- I'll make them different.
- What?
I'm tired of waiting for Mayor McSleaze
to make his move...
while we sit on
our hands...
counting down
to ascension day.
Let's take
the fight to him.
No.
No! Much too reckless.
We're at a distinct
disadvantage.
We don't know anything
about the mayor's ascension.
She's right.
Time's running out.
We need to take
the offensive.
What's your plan?
I gotta have a plan?
Really?
I can't just be
proactive with pep?
You want to take the fight to them,
I suggest the first step...
would be to find out
exactly what they're up to.
Oh. I actually
knew that.
I thought you meant
a more specific plan...
you know,
with maps and stuff.
Great. We'll find out
what they're up to.
He in the car?
I'll take you to him.
The mayor was supposed to be
here in person with the money.
Well, the price just went up.
I don't like surprises.
[Whistling, Thud]
Surprise.
You killed him.
What are you, the narrator?
Get the keys to the cuffs.
Nothin'.
[Drops Bow]
That won't
cut through steel.
No, but it'll
cut through bone.
Hey-ho. There it is.
Ha ha ha ha.
Uh, what happened
to the courier?
I was supposed
to pay him.
Huh. I made him an offer
he couldn't survive.
You are one heck of
a girl, you know that?
I mean, geez, the initiative,
the... the skill.
Go on. Go on.
I will.
I'll tell you, if Buff...
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
If Buffy Summers
walked in here...
and said she wanted
to switch to our side...
I'd say,
"No, thanks, sister.
I got all the slayer one man
could ever need." Ha ha.
What?
Nothing.
Oh, it's 'cause I used
the "B" word, huh?
Don't tell me
you're still sore...
about that whole
Angel-Buffy thing.
No, I'm over it.
She can have him.
Better believe she can.
She deserves
that poor excuse...
for a creature
of the night.
You, on the other hand,
can do better.
Don't do that.
[Clattering]
So, what's in the box?
The Box of Gavrok.
It houses some great
demonic energy or something...
which His Honor needs to
chow down on come "A" day.
Wesley: What's that?
Maps and stuff.
Plans for city hall. They were in
the Water and Power mainframe.
The box is being
kept under guard...
in a conference room
on the top floor.
There.
Unfortunately, that's all I
could get out of my informant...
before his
aggressive tendencies...
forced me to introduce him
to Mr. Pointy.
Well, now, here's what
I think we should do.
I figure we can enter
through the skylight.
I'll take Angel with me.
Agreed.
There's a fire ladder...
on the east side
of the building here.
Yes, fine. But we still
need to consider...
It won't be enough to simply
have possession of the box.
Right. We have
to destroy it.
Not just physically,
ritually.
With some down-and-dirty
black magic.
Hang on. We don't know what
such a ritual would require.
I think the "Breath
of the Entropics..."
is standard for
this sort of thing.
Fairly simple recipe.
Xander.
I know.
I'm ingredient-gettin' guy.
All right, stop!
I demand everyone
stop this instant.
I'm in charge here...
and I say this is all
moving much too fast.
We need time to fully
analyze the situation
and devise a proper
and strategic stratagem.
Wes, hop on the train
or get off the tracks.
The mayor will
most assuredly...
have supernatural safeguards
protecting the box.
Oh, we all forgot
about that, did we?
Looks like a job
for Wiccan girl.
What do you say, Wil?
Big-time danger.
Hey, I eat danger
for breakfast.
But, oddly enough, she panics
in the face of breakfast foods.
Let's get to work.
I have a theory.
Your snide remarks earlier?
I'm guessing grapes
a little on the sour side.
Didn't get into
any schools, did ya?
The grades were there...
but, ooh, if it weren't
for that pesky interview.
10 minutes with you...
and the admissions
department...
decided that
they'd already reached...
their mean-spirited
superficial-princess quotas.
And once again...
the gold medal in
the being-wrong event...
goes to Xander "I'm As Stupid
As I Look" Harris.
Read 'em and weep,
creep...
U.S.C., Colorado State...
Duke and Columbia.
Wow. These are,
uh, great colleges.
I'm guessing
they must have seen...
a different side
of your father's money.
Go away.
Sure. If you'll excuse me...
I have to go back to helping
to save some lives.
Carry on. I know that you have
some important accessorizing to do.
Now, remember...
If anything
should go awry...
Wesley and I will
create a diversion.
Let's synchronize
our watches.
I have 214...
Yes, typical.
Maybe we could just
count 1-1,000, 2-1,000.
Be careful, all of you.
Tea?
You got the goods?
Yeah.
Essence of toad.
Twice-blessed sage.
Maybe that's the toad.
Well, we better be sure.
Destroying this box...
is supposed to be
a pretty delicate operation.
Then they shouldn't leave it
in the hands of the lay people.
Well, Wil laid it out
for us pretty well.
Wow, she even drew
helpful diagrams.
That's the pedestal.
And the ingredients.
And us.
See, there's you,
there's me.
Well, how can you tell
which is which?
I mean, they both kind of
look stick figurey to me.
Well, this one's me.
See the little guitar?
Oh, gotcha.
Yeah. Nobody
like my Wil.
No, sir, there is not.
OK... toad me.
Thanks.
Sis modo dissolutum.
Exposco validum scutum.
Diutius nec defende...
a manibus arcam intende.
Oh, yeah. I'm bad.
4 stars, Wil.
Now get gone.
I'm gone.
Got it!
[Alarm Rings]
Oh. Angel?
It's jammed.
Like very much
to come up now, please.
[Footsteps Running]
Angel!
I know.
Don't suppose you wanna
help me get down.
Didn't think so.
[Tires Screech]
Ha ha ha ha.
Well, this is
very unfortunate.
I just had this conference room
redecorated, for Pete's sake.
At taxpayers' expense.
And oh, yeah... gaah!
They've got my box.
Yeah, they do.
But looky what we got.
Heh heh heh heh.
How did you guys let this...
How did this happen?
We thought she stayed
with you.
They must have grabbed her
when she hit the ground.
Buffy, I'm sorry.
Look, it's nobody's
fault, OK?
We just need to focus
and deal.
Oz, I swear I won't
let them hurt her.
We go back.
Full-on assault.
They'll kill her.
We're assuming
they haven't already?
No. No, they know
what she means to us.
She's too valuable
as long as we still have...
the box.
We trade.
We can't.
No, it's the safest plan.
It's the only way. Right?
It might well be.
Look, we call the mayor
and arrange a meeting.
This box must be destroyed.
I need a volunteer
to hit Wesley.
Giles, you know
I'm right about this.
Wes, you want to duck and cover
at this point?
Damn it,
you listen to me!
This box is the key
to the mayor's ascension.
Thousands of lives depend upon
our getting rid of it.
Now, I want to help Willow
as much as the rest of you...
but we will find
another way.
There is no other way.
You're the one who said
take the fight to the mayor.
You were right. This is the town's
best hope of survival.
It's your chance to get out.
You think I care
about that?
Are you made
of human parts?
All right! Let's deal
with this rationally.
Are you taking
his side?
[All Shouting At Once]
Don't be ridiculous!
Listen to you people!
You'd sacrifice thousands
of lives? Your families?
Your friends?
It can all end right here.
We have the means
to destroy this box.
Giles, make the phone call.
[Grunting]
What are you doing?
Um...
I'm looking for
a sucking candy...
'cause my mouth gets dry
when I'm... I'm nervous...
or held prisoner
against my will.
And suddenly
I'm thinking...
"sucking"
isn't a good word...
to use around vampires.
Hey! Did you get permission
to eat the hostage?
I don't think so.
You're gonna be in some trouble
when the mayor gets...
No!
Just a little taste.
[Whimpers]
They're not gonna be
brain-damaged enough
to come back here tonight.
Mayor: Ever have a dog?
What?
I did.
Rusty.
Irish setter.
Swell little pooch.
A dog's friendship
is stronger than reason...
stronger than its own sense...
of self-preservation.
Buffy's like a dog.
And, hey, before you can say
Jack Robinson...
you'll get to see me
kill her like one.
Ohh...
The Books of Ascension.
Check out the bookworm.
Faith.
Anybody with brains...
anybody who knew what was
going to happen to her...
would be trying to claw her
way out of this place.
But you... you just can't stop
Nancy Drewing, can you?
I guess now
you know too much...
and that kind of just
naturally leads to killing.
Faith, wait!
I want to talk to you.
Oh, yeah. Give me the speech
again, please.
"Faith, we're still
your friends.
We can help you.
It's not too late."
It's way too late.
You know, it didn't
have to be this way.
But you made
your choice.
I know you had
a tough life.
I know that some people think
you had a lot of bad breaks.
Well, boo-hoo!
Poor you.
You know, you had
a lot more in your life...
than... than some people.
I mean, you had friends
like Buffy.
Now you have no one.
You were a slayer,
and now you're nothing.
You're just a big, selfish,
worthless waste.
You hurt me,
I hurt you.
I'm just a little more
efficient.
Oh, and here I just thought
you didn't have a comeback.
You're begging for
some deep pain.
[Breathing Hard]
I'm not afraid of you.
Let's see what we can do
about that.
Girls.
I hope I don't have to
separate you two.
Faith, you can play with
your new toy later.
Something's come up.
Faith.
You know I don't like
repeating myself.
I got someone.
I got him.
I just received...
a heck of an interesting
phone call.
The whole place
is locked down...
except for the front.
Yeah, it gives me that
comforting "trapped" feeling.
One way out
means one way in.
I want to see them coming.
I guess they're shy.
I can see all right.
Well, this is
exciting, isn't it?
Ha ha ha.
Clandestine meetings
by dark of night...
exchange of prisoners.
I just... I...
I feel like we should
all be wearing trench coats.
Let her go.
No!
Not until the box
is in my hands.
So you're
the little girl...
that's been causing me
all this trouble.
She's pretty, Angel.
A little skinny.
Still don't understand...
why it couldn't work out
with you and my Faith.
Guess you kinda just have
strange taste in women.
Yeah, well,
what can I say?
I like 'em sane.
Angel.
I wish you kids the best,
I really do...
but, uh, if you don't mind
a bit of fatherly advice...
I, uh... I just don't see
much of a future for you two.
I don't sense
a lasting relationship.
And not just because I plan
to kill the both of you...
but you got
a bumpy road ahead.
I don't think we need
to talk about this.
[Chuckling]
Y-You kids, you know...
you don't like to think
about the future...
you don't like
to make plans...
but unless
you want Faith...
to gut your friend
like a sea bass...
you will show a little
respect for your elders.
You're not my elder.
I got a lot
of years on you.
Yeah, and that's just
one of the things...
you're gonna have to
deal with.
You're immortal.
She's not.
It's not easy.
I married my Edna Mae in '03...
and I was with her
right until the end.
Not a pretty picture.
Wrinkled and senile...
and cursing me
for my youth.
Wasn't our happiest time.
And let's forget the fact...
that any moment of true
happiness will turn you evil.
[Snickers]
I mean, come on,
what kind of a life...
can you offer her?
I don't see a lot of Sunday
picnics in the offing.
I see skulking
in the shadows...
hiding from the sun.
She's a blossoming
young girl...
and you want to keep her from
the life she should have...
till it's passed her by.
And by God...
I think that's
a little selfish.
Is that what you
came back from hell for?
Is that your
greater purpose?
Make the trade.
Well, that went
as smoothly...
Nobody moves!
I knew you kids
were up to something.
Snyder, get out of here.
You're not giving orders,
young lady.
I suppose you're
going to tell me...
I won't find drugs
in this box.
Wait!
Principal Snyder...
I think we have
a problem.
Mr. Mayor,
I had no idea you...
I'm terribly sorry.
No, it's I who
should apologize.
I mean, coming down here
at night.
What must you be thinking?
But you see...
I just needed to...
Uh, no, don't do that!
Aah!
Aaaahhhh!
Oh, God.
Where'd it go?
Get that door open!
Giles: No!
You can't let that thing
out of here.
[Keys Drop]
I still want to know
where it went.
Listen.
Boss!
I wouldn't
leave that open.
No!
Is that all of them?
Uh... not really.
You see, there's
about, uh, 50...
billion of these happy
little critters in here.
Would you like to see?
Raise your hand
if you're invulnerable.
Faith, let's go.
Faith.
Snyder, you alive
in there?
You...
all of you...
why couldn't you be dealing
drugs like normal people?
Well, that went
swimmingly.
We did all right.
So Faith was like,
"I'm gonna beat you up,"
and I'm all,
"I'm not afraid of you."
And then she had the knife,
which was less fun.
And then, oh,
I... I told her...
"You made your choice.
Buffy was your friend."
Yes. This is
fascinating...
but just to get
back to the point.
You actually had your hands
on the Books of Ascension?
Volumes 1 through 5.
Is there anything that you
can remember about them...
that could be of use to us?
Anything at all?
Well, I was in a hurry...
and what I did read
was kind of involved.
If you ask me,
way overwritten.
Oh.
Actually, there were a few pages
that were kind of interesting...
but I didn't have a chance
to read them fully.
See what you can
make of them.
This is your night
for suave, Wil.
You should get
captured more often.
No, thank you.
Well, let's hope there's
something useful in those pages.
The mayor has
the Box of Gavrok.
And as of now...
we are right back
where we started.
Wouldn't you say?
Deep thoughts?
Deep and meaningful.
As in?
As in I'm never
getting out of here.
I kept thinking if I
stopped the mayor or...
but I was
kidding myself.
There's always
gonna be something.
I'm a Sunnydale girl.
No other choice.
It must be tough.
I mean, here I am...
and I can do
anything I want.
I can go to any college
in the country...
4 or 5 in Europe,
if I want.
Please tell me you're going
somewhere with this.
No.
I'm not going anywhere.
U.C. Sunnydale?
I will be matriculating
with the class of 2003.
Are you serious?
Say, isn't that
where you're going?
Oh!
[Squealing And Laughing]
I can't believe it.
Are you serious?
Wait, what am I saying?
You can't.
What do you mean I can't?
I won't let you.
Of the 2 people here...
which is
the boss of me?
There are better schools.
Sunnydale's not bad...
and... and I can design
my own curriculum.
OK, well, there are
safer schools.
There are safer prisons.
I can't let you stay
because of me.
Actually, this isn't
about you.
Although I'm fond... don't
get me wrong... of you.
But the other night...
you know, being
captured and all...
facing off with Faith...
things just...
kinda got clear.
I mean, you've been fighting
evil here for 3 years...
and I've helped some...
and now we're
supposed to decide...
what we want to do
with our lives.
And I just realized
that's what I want to do.
Fight evil, help people.
I mean, I... I think
it's worth doing.
And I don't think you do it
because you have to.
It's a good fight,
Buffy...
and I want in.
I kind of love you.
And besides, I have a shot
at being a badass Wicca.
And what better
place to learn?
I feel the need
for more sugar...
than the human body
can handle.
Mochas?
Yes, please.
It's weird.
You look at something...
and you think you know
exactly what you're seeing...
and... then you find out
it's something else entirely.
Neat, huh?
Sometimes it is.
Chase, what
are you doing?
Your break's been over
for 10 minutes.
I still need you
to restock the shelves...
and sweep out
the storage room.
Let's go!
It's gonna be fun.
Wil and I are gonna go
on Saturday, look at the campus.
I'm hoping my mom
will let me live there.
It's too far
to come home every night.
Plus the whole
lack-of-cool factor.
Either way, I'll be
close to your place.
I don't know what the mayor
was talking about.
How could he know
anything about us?
Well, he's evil.
Big-time.
He doesn't even know what
a lasting relationship is.
No.
Probably the only lasting
relationship he's ever had...
is with...
evil.
Yeah.
Big, stupid, evil guy.
We'll be OK.
We will.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org