In every generation there is a Chosen One.
She alone will stand against the vampires,
the demons and the forces of darkness.
She is the Slayer.
This is madness.
What can you have been thinking?
You are the Slayer. Lives depend upon you.
I make allowances for your youth,
but I expect
a certain amount of responsibility.
Instead of which,
you enslave yourself to this-this... cult?
- You don't like the colour?
- I d...
Do you, erm... do you ignore
everything I say, as a rule?
No. I believe that's your trick.
I told you, I'm trying out
for the cheerleading squad.
You have a sacred birthright, Buffy.
You were chosen to destroy vampires,
not to wave pompoms at people.
And as the Watcher, I forbid it.
And you'll be stopping me how?
Well, I...
By appealing to your common sense,
if such a creature exists.
I will still have time
to fight the forces of evil, OK?
I just wanna have a life.
I wanna do something normal.
Something safe.
Giles didn't approve, huh?
He totally lost his water.
We haven't seen a vampire in over a week.
I'd say he should get a girlfriend
if he wasn't so old.
We're behind you.
People scoff at things
like school spirit, but...
look at these girls
giving their all like this!
Ooh, stretchy!
Where was I?
Pretending to see scantily clad girls
in revealing postures
as a spiritual experience.
Who said I was pretending?
Hey! Here's a good-luck thing for try-outs.
- What's this?
- What's that?
- Oh, how sweet. "Yours, always".
It came that way. Really.
They all said that.
Just look at that Amber.
- Who does she think she is? A Laker Girl?
- I heard she turned them down.
OK, listen up. Let's begin with...
Amber Grove.
- If you're not auditioning, move off the floor.
- Amy! Hi.
Hi!
I didn't know you wanted to be
a cheerleader. You lost a lot of weight.
Had to.
- Do you know Buffy?
- Hi.
- How I hate this. Let me count the ways.
She trained with Benson.
He's one of the best coaches money can buy.
- They have cheerleading coaches?
- Oh, yeah! Don't you have?
I train with my mom -
three hours in the morning, three at night.
Hm. That much quality time with my mom'd
probably lead to some quality matricide.
Yeah... Well, I know it's hokey,
but she's really great.
What the...?
That girl's on fire!
Enough of the hyperbole!
It's OK. It's OK. You're gonna be... OK!
God!
I've been slaying vampires
for more than a year now,
and I have seen some
pretty cringeworthy things, but...
- nobody's hands ever got toasted before.
- I imagine not.
- So, this isn't a vampire problem.
- No.
But it is funky, right? Not of the norm?
Quite. Spontaneous human combustion
is rare and scientifically unexplainable.
But there... have been cases
for hundreds of years.
Usually all that's left is a pile of ashes.
That's all that would have been left
if it hadn't been for Buffy.
So we have no idea what caused this?
That's a comfort!
But that's the thrill
of living on the Hellmouth.
There's a veritable cornucopia of fiends
and devils and ghouls to engage.
Pardon me for finding the glass half full.
Any common denominators
in cases of spontaneous combustion?
Er, rage. In most cases, the person who
combusted was terribly angry, or... or upset.
So maybe Amber's got this power
to make herself be on fire.
- It's like the Human Torch, only it hurts.
- I need get the skinny on Amber.
Find out if she's had
colourful episodes before.
That means hacking illegaly
into the school's computer system.
At last something I can do.
- I'll ask around about her.
- You guys don't have to get involved.
What do you mean? We're a team.
Aren't we a team?
Yeah. You're the Slayer,
and we're, like, the Slayerettes.
I just don't like putting you guys in danger.
I laugh in the face of danger.
Then I hide until it goes away.
OK. Just walk softly,
at least until we know a little more.
I mean, what if Amber isn't
causing these problems herself?
Well, then we have to determine
who or what did.
And, er, deal with it accordingly.
- Hey!
- Hi. How was school?
Mm. A reverentjoy!
- What's all this?
- It's for the tribal art display.
Cool!
- We had try-outs today.
- Oh, great. How'd it go?
I didn't actually get to try out.
There was an accident.
- Pretty fierce competition, though.
- Oh, I know you'll do fine.
Keep on pluggin'.
Just have to get back on the horse.
- Mom?
- Yeah?
- What was I trying out for?
- Oh, uh...
..some activity? I have no idea. I'm sorry.
That's OK. Your platitudes
are good for all occasions.
I'm distracted.
I've got a lot of inventory
to go through here.
This is my gallery's first major show.
You know, it might not physically kill you
to give me a hand here.
- It was cheerleading.
- Oh, good!
I'm glad you're taking that up again.
It'll keep you out of trouble.
- I'm not in trouble.
- No, not yet.
I mean, you stopped cheerleading
just before the trouble.
So it's good you're going back.
- Oh, dear.
- What?
A fertility statue.
You don't need to see it.
You know, there's this girl,
Amy, and, um...
she trains with her mom,
like, three hours a day.
- Uh-huh?
- Sounds like her mom's pretty into it.
Sounds like her mom
doesn't have a lot to do.
Jeepers!
Despite the terrible thing
that happened yesterday,
we still have to pick new cheerleaders.
If you make the team, you'll find
your names posted in the quad after lunch.
Let's begin with group performance.
Why do my hands have to sweat
when I get nervous?
Don't worry. You'll do great.
Five, six, seven, eight!
Sunnydale! Sunnydale!
We never fail! We never fail!
Jump and shoot, swish and score,
the other team is such a bore. Yeah!
You saw that, right? That wasn't me.
You saw that, right?
Right?
- That's my mom.
- No?
Catherine Madison.
Get down with your bad self!
Her nickname was "Catherine the Great".
She took that team and
made them Tri-County Champions.
You know, no one'd ever done that before.
Or since.
She and my dad were
Homecoming King and Queen.
- They got married right after graduation.
- That's kinda romantic.
Well, he was a big loser.
Never made any money.
Ran off with Miss Trailer Trash
when I was 12.
OK. That part's less romantic.
- My folks split up, too.
- Drag, huh?
He left my mom with nothing.
She put herself through cosmetology school.
Bought me everything I ever wanted.
And never once gained a single pound.
She sounds really great, Amy. But, um...
it doesn't mean you need to lock step
as far as this cheerleading thing.
She was the best.
And I can't get my body to move like hers.
I choked in there so bad!
No, Amy, you did fine.
- I'm gonna get changed.
- Wait! No, uh...
Hey, Amy!
- Is she OK?
- Oh, she's... wiggin' about her mom.
The big "cheer queen" back when.
- Yeah. Her mom's kinda...
- Nazi-like?
Heil.
If she gains an ounce,
she padlocks the fridge
and won't eat anything but broth.
So, mommy dearest is really
Mommy Dearest?
There's a bitter streak. But Amy's nice.
We used to hang in junior high.
When her mom would go on a broth kick,
Amy'd come to my house
and we'd stuff ourselves brownies.
Hm! Hey, any word on Amber?
Nothing thrilling. Average student,
got detention once for smoking.
Regular smoking, with a cigarette -
not, like, being smoky.
- Hm.
- All pretty normal.
So we'll just have to wait
and see what happens.
Maybe nothing will.
I have a dream.
It's me on the cheerleading squad, adored
by every varsity male
as far as the eye can see.
We have to achieve our dreams, Amy.
Otherwise, we wither and die.
- Look, I'm sorry about...
- Sh...
If your supreme klutziness out there today
takes me out of the running,
you're gonna be so very beyond sorry.
Have a nice day.
- I told Buffy about Amber.
- Cool. Was she wearing it?
The bracelet. She was wearing it, right?
Pretty much like we're going out.
Except without the hugging or kissing
or her knowing about it.
So I'm just a figure of fun.
- I should ask her out, right?
- You won't know till you ask.
That's why you're so cool.
You're like a guy.
You're my guy friend
that knows about girls' stuff.
Oh, great! I'm a guy!
Oh, hey, they're posting the list!
I can't take this.
Yes!
Cover me, I'm going in.
- You're lucky.
- I made it?
- Ooh!
- I made it.
One of those girls hit me really hard.
We should test for steroids.
Not only did you make the team, but
you, Miss Summers, are the first alternate.
Amy's number three.
What better way to celebrate
than a romantic drive through...
Xander, alternates are the ones
who didn't make the team.
They only fill in if something happens
to the ones who did.
Excuse me.
For I am Xander, King of Cretins.
May all lesser cretins bow before me.
At least it's over. And you know
what I think we should do about it?
Brownie pig-out. My house. After school.
Just how many more hours a day
can I practise?
You know, how much more can I do?
This would've never
happened to my mother.
Never.
Give me the power.
Give me the dark.
I call on you,
the Laughing Gods.
Let your blackness crawl beneath my skin.
Accept this sacrifice.
Cordelia.
Feed on her.
Look what I've found.
It's my yearbook from junior year.
Oh, look! There I am.
Mom, I've accepted that you've had sex.
I am not ready to know
that you had Farrah hair.
This is Gidget hair.
Don't they teach you anything in history?
- Well, it's really cool, but I gotta book.
- Well, I was thinking.
I know the cheerleading thing
didn't work out.
Maybe you should think about
joining the yearbook staff.
I did. It was a lot of fun.
Not really my tip, Mom.
I was, uh, photo editor.
I got to be on every page.
Made me look much more popular than I was.
And have you seen the kids
that do yearbook?
Nerds pick on them.
Some of the best times I had in school
were working on the yearbook.
Oh, this just in. I'm not you.
I'm into my own thing.
"Your own thing", whatever it is,
got you kicked out of school...
..and we had to move here to find
a decent school that would take you.
Honey...?
Oh! Great parenting form!
A little shaky on the dismount.
Cordelia! You haven't been mean to me
all day. Is it something I've done?
See how she has no clue that I'm a man,
much less a human being?
- I see that.
- This is the Invisible Man Syndrome.
A blessing in Cordelia's case.
A curse in Buffy's.
- You're not invisible to Buffy.
- It's worse.
I'm part of the scenery. Like an old shoe.
Or a rug that you walk on every day,
but don't even really see it.
Like a pen that's chewed up - you know
you should throw it away, but you don't.
Not 'cause you like it,
more 'cause you're just used to...
Well, yeah. That is the point.
You don't have to drive it through my head
like a railroad spike.
I've gotta take your advice
and not beat around the bush.
Or, I could be wrong. Maybe you should
beat around the bush more.
Nah, I've gotta be a man and ask her out.
You know what I've gotta stop?
Giving her ID bracelets, subtle innuendoes,
taking Polaroids outside
her bedroom window late at night.
That last part is a joke to relieve
the tension. Because here she comes.
Into battle I go.
Would you ask her out for me?
No.
Man. Me battle.
Buffy?
- Would you like to...
- Is that even Cordelia's locker?
Huh? Oh, I don't know. What I'm saying is,
accompany me Friday ni...
Xander, I have to, um...
We can make this up later.
You don't mind, do you?
Nice of you to join us, Cordelia.
We didn't keep you waiting,
or anything, did we?
Your turn to drive.
OK, people, let's buckle up.
I don't wanna drive today, Mr Pole.
You've flunked driver's ed twice, already.
Show me some moves,
or you'll be taking the bus to college.
OK, check the brake.
Check the mirror.
Start the engine.
Hello? Put the car in drive.
Let's move forward through the cones
with a gentle, even turn to the...
Slow down! Slow... slow... Turn right!
- Turn right!
- Aargh!
Brakes!
Brakes! Brakes!
Everybody out!
- Oh, my God! I can't see anything!
- It's OK. Oh, God!
What's happening? I can't see anything!
Witchcraft. Blinding your enemy
to disorient and disable them - it's a classic.
First vampires, now witches.
No wonder you can still afford
a house in Sunnydale.
- Why should someone harm Cordelia?
- Maybe because they met her?
Did I say that?
And setting Amber ablaze?
- Yeah, they don't hang.
- They're both cheerleaders.
- Someone doesn't like cheerleading?
- Or likes it too much.
Amy!
- Amy.
- So, you, guys, are leaning towards Amy?
She's desperate to get on that team.
I've got this feeling she'd do just about
anything to make her mom's dream come true.
Let me make sure I have this right.
This witch is casting
horrible and disfiguring spells
so that she can become a cheerleader?
I think you're underestimating the amount
of pressure a parent can lay on you.
If you're not a picture of
perfect carbon copy, they tend to wig.
Cheerleading was kind of
her mom's last hurrah.
Look, we still have to stop Amy.
We should grab her and...
I think we should be sure she's the witch
before we arouse her suspicions.
She's capable of
some very unpleasant things.
OK. All right. So...
You're in high school. You are desperate
to make the team and please your mom.
So you turn to witchcraft.
What's the first thing you're gonna do?
Check out the books on witchcraft.
No! That would be the last thing you'd do.
You don't wanna leave a paper trail.
- Forget that.
- It'll just take a minute.
We don't have a minute!
Cheerleaders are in danger! Buffy's in danger!
You were the first alternate.
You're on the team now that Cordelia's out.
You could be next.
We gotta get you to a safe house.
- Xander?
- Yeah?
Witches: Historic Roots to Modern Practice.
Checked out by Alexander Harris.
- The Pagan Rites. Checked out by...
- All right, it's not what you think.
You like to look at
the semi-nude engravings?
Oh, well, I guess it is what you think.
Have you all quite finished?
We have to find a conclusive test.
There may be something in here.
Yes, this should do it.
You'll need some of her hair,
a little quicksilver and...
some aqua fortis.
That's just mercury and nitric acid.
You can get that at the science lab.
"Heat ingredients and apply to witch."
"If the spell has been cast in the previous
48 hours, the witch's skin turns blue."
Oh, and you'll need some eye of newt.
Those of you in track one
may begin your dissections now.
Those of you in track two,
take your hydrochloric acid
and your ammonium hydroxide
and carefully
pour them into
your beakers.
- Now, slow. Slow.
- I can't.
Capping one, and being safe. And you get...
- Eye of newt.
- ...that.
How's Buffy doing with the hair?
- Isn't this exciting?!
- Oh, yeah!
Amy, help me. Um... Which is the...
hydrochloric acid and which is
the ammonium hydroxide?
Well, the bottle that says
hydrochloric acid
is usually the hydrochloric acid.
Read the bottles! Concept!
Oops!
Wave hi to the nice little witch.
All set. Do you have a plan?
Spill it on her,
try and make it look natural.
We're right behind you, only...
further back.
Lishanne, can you tell me
why these chemicals have this reaction?
Lishanne? Are you...?
Oh, my God!
(muffled cries)
Did you see?
Amy was as freaked out as the rest of us.
- So it's not her.
- The test was positive. She's our Sabrina.
I just don't think
she realises what she's doing.
Well, should we talk to her?
Maybe we should talk to her mother.
I wander if she knows what she's created.
Where are you?
Another productive day in front of the TV?
I got a history report due tomorrow.
Write it.
I should be on that team by now.
But instead, Miss Buffy and friends
are sneaking around stealing bits of my hair.
I'll be upstairs.
# Macho, macho, man!
# I want to be a macho man. Macho...
Ooh, hey, juice! Mmm!
Quality juice. Not from concentrate.
- You're in a good mood.
- I am!
I'm on the squad! Which is great 'cause
I feel like cheering
and leading others to cheer.
Ooh, hey, juice!
Listen, honey, about yesterday? I really...
That is totally yester.
Besides, it's not like
you were wrong, you know?
I did get kicked outta school.
I'm just wacky that way!
Still, I just want you to know
that despite the problems you've had...
Mom, you just don't get it.
And believe me, you don't want it.
There are some things
about being a vampire slayer that...
- ...the older generation...
- Being a what?
- It's a long story.
- Are you feeling well?
What? Oh, I'm fine, you know.
What? Like I can't be in a good mood?
Is it like a new house rule? Fine, you know,
that's just fine, fine, fine. 'Cause...
# I'm a macho, macho man!
# I want to be a macho man!
Macho, macho man!
Five, six, seven, eight!
Turn up the music!
Get it together, Buffy!
We have a game in less than four hours!
Willow! Xander!
My buds are here! I love my buds!
Hi!
Hi! Oh!
Is it me, or is Buffy a bit looped?
We'd better get her out of there.
Yeah, before she...
hurts someone.
- Did I do that?
- You are so outta here.
It's not her fault!
- She's on medication.
- What?
Obviously, not enough.
Who's our next alternate?
Oh.
Amy, you just made cheerleader.
No, no, no! You don't want her, she's a w...
A wise choice indeed.
- She's a witchy!
- Buffy.
- I just got kicked off the team, didn't I?
- I don't think it was your fault.
I know you don't.
That's 'cause you're my friend.
You're my Xander-shaped friend!
Do you have any idea
why I love you so, Xander?
- We've got to get her to a...
- Let her speak.
I'll tell you.
You're not like other boys at all.
- Well...
- You are totally and completely...
...one of the girls!
I'm that comfy with him.
That's great!
Any other guy who'd give me a bracelet,
they'd... wanna date me. It'd be like a...
- Oh. I-I don't... feel so good.
- Buffy?
We've gotta get her to a hospital.
They can't help her.
This is a bloodstone vengeance spell.
Hits the body hard like a quart of alcohol
and it eradicates the immune system.
Vengeance spell?
Like she's trying to get even with Buffy?
'Cause she knows I know she's a witch.
The others, she just wanted out
of the running. You, she intends to, erm...
- Kill.
- How much time do we have?
- Ooh, er, I'm sure, er...
- Truth.
Please?
- A couple of hours. Three at most.
- How do we reverse the spell?
Well, I've been researching that,
and we can reverse all the spells if,
we can just lay our hands
on Amy's spell book.
And if we can't get a hold of it?
Well, the other way is
to cut the witch's head off.
Show of hands.
It's not Amy's fault.
She only became a witch
to survive her mother.
Look, I don't care why.
I just care that you go on breathing.
Giles, where would she be
casting these spells?
She needs a... a sacred space.
- A pentagram. A large pot.
- Her home.
OK, help me up.
We'll just go to her house,
and we'll get her book.
- OK, we'll go with you.
- No.
You guys stay here and keep an eye on Amy.
And keep her away from the science lab.
We'll need it to cast our counterspells.
Who are you?
Is there something wrong?
Mrs. Madison, we need to talk to you
about your daughter.
I'm not allow... You'll have to come back later.
- Excuse me.
- What?
Are you all right? Erm... in here.
Your daughter is meddling with something
very dangerous. Are you aware of that?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- I think you know only too well.
You've got to go.
She'll be home soon, and you...
This girl is very sick. Now
you will shut up and you will listen to me.
Your daughter has access
to some very powerful magics,
and somehow
your obsession with cheerleading...
I don't care about cheerleading!
It's not my fault she's doing stuff.
As her mother, you should assume
some responsibility for her actions.
Yeah, well, you know these kids today. I...
She's out of her mind.
Ever since Dad... her dad left,
I can't control her.
- You're afraid of her.
- Amy?
- Are you Amy?
- I don't understand.
She switched.
She switched your bodies, didn't she?
- Good Lord!
- She wanted to relive her glory days.
She said I was wasting my youth.
So she took it.
I didn't know anything about her powers.
I mean, when Dad was here, they would fight
and... yell, he would... call her a witch,
and I just thought he meant...
Oh, God, when he left,
I wanted to go with him.
But she wouldn't even let me call.
She went crazy. I mean,
she'd lock herself upstairs for days,
and she was always coming down on me,
telling me I didn't deserve
to have it so easy
and that I didn't know
how hard it was to be her and...
I guess she showed me, huh?
Amy, it's gonna be OK.
A few months ago,
I woke up in her bed.
I didn't know where I was.
- Then I looked in the mirror.
- She locked herself upstairs?
- Yes.
- Where?
No. If she finds out I've been here,
she'll kill me!
My God!
I believe we can
reverse your mother's spell.
- Well, all of them, in fact.
- You could?
- Really, you could?
- We need to find her books.
There'd be specific volumes she'd need
for this kind of casting.
Collect those dolls and any other personal...
Nice... kitty.
Let's see what you were guarding.
Ah, yes.
This is it.
- Did we find?
- We found.
Come on.
- But where are you going?
- We're going to school.
And you're coming with us.
I'm gonna stop this. I promise.
You just hang on.
How is she?
We only have a few minutes left.
Go, Sunnydale, go!
Go, Sunnydale, go! Go!
Five, six, seven, eight!
Go, Sunnydale, go! Go, Sunnydale, go!
Go, Sunnydale, go! Go!
Six, seven, eight!
Go, Sunnydale, go! Go, Sunnydale, go!
- Go!
- Six, seven, eight!
Go, Sunnydale, go! Go, Sunnydale, go!
Go, Sunnydale, go! Go!
Right, here we go.
The centre is dark.
Centrum est obscurus.
The darkness breathes.
Tenebrae respiratis.
The listener hears.
Hear me!
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight!
One, two, three...
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight...
Oh, it's working!
Unlock the gate. Let the darkness shine.
Cover us with holy fear.
Show me...
Amy, what's your problem?
She's coming!
- Amy?
- Get out of my way.
Wait. I need to talk to you.
I can help you.
Help me? With what?
Well, you know, all your witchcraft.
I know this really good cauldron.
Do you actually ride a broom?
Xander!
Corsheth and Gilail, the gate is closed.
Receive the dark.
Release the unworthy.
Take of mine energy and be sated.
Be sated. Release the unworthy.
Release!
Release!!!
- Buffy?
- Amy?
You...
You little brat.
Mom, please?
How dare you raise your hand
to your mother?
I gave you birth. I gave up my life
so you could drag that worthless
carcass around and call it living.
You've never been anything but trouble.
I'll put you
where you can't make trouble again.
Guess what.
I feel better.
That body was mine!
- Mine!
- Oh, grow up!
I shall look upon my enemy.
I shall look upon her,
and the dark place will have her soul!
Corsheth, take her!
Well, that was, erm... interesting.
You guys OK?
- I'm fine.
- I assume the, er...
..all the spells are reversed?
It was my first casting, so
- I may have got it wrong.
- You saved my life. You are a god.
- I didn't think you'd pull it off.
- I got her! Cut her head off!
- Xander, what are you doing?
- Saving you?
- Get your hands off of her.
- But she's evil.
- It wasn't exactly her.
- I was my mom.
Oh!
- Where is she?
- Hey, Willow, it's cool!
- It is?
- Yeah, I took care of it.
I don't get it.
What?
I've been doing a lot of thinking about
where you're coming from,
how to relate to you,
and I've come to a very simple conclusion.
I don't get it.
I'm inscrutable, huh?
You're 16. I think there's a
a biological imperative whereby
I can't understand you because I'm not 16.
Do you ever wish you could be 16 again?
Oh, that's a frightful notion.
Go through all that again?
Not even if it'd help me understand you.
I love you, Mom.
I don't get it!
My dad is so impossible!
He doesn't ever want me going anywhere.
He wants to spend
total quantity time together.
And I'm, like,
"Dad, I can go out. It's perfectly safe."
But he's got all this guilt
about leaving me with my mom.
And he's being a total pain.
- You're loving it.
- Every single minute.
This Saturday night,
he wants to stay in and make brownies.
Well, the brownies were my idea.
Hey, I'm really sorry you guys
got bumped back to alternate.
Hold it. Wait. No, I'm not.
Well, I know I'll miss the intellectual
thrill of spelling out words with my arms!
Ooh! These grapes are sour.
Oh, I'm sorry!
- I forgot you wanted to be on the squad.
- Oh, that's OK.
- Cheerleading's a little too hairy these days.
- Yeah. That's for sure.
"Catherine the Great."
And there's been no sign of her?
That last spell?
She said I'd never make trouble again.
Wherever she is,
I don't think we'll have to worry.
Twisted.
I'm just happy to have my body back.
I'm thinking of getting fat.
You know, I hear
that look's in for spring.
Subtitles by: Claire Bates
Corrected and adjusted by: UAR
...
www.tvsubtitles.net