In every generation,
there is a Chosen One,
She alone will stand against the vampires,
the demons and the forces of darkness,
She is the Slayer,
# Gilded ghetto
# Hollywood stained below
All I'm saying is, it's a stupid idea
to have a victory party at the beach.
It's officially nippy. So say my nips.
I think it's festive.
A party with nature.
Well, it's the team's choice.
It was their victory.
Team? Swim team.
Hardly what I call a team.
The Yankees,
Abbott and Costello. The A.
Now those were teams.
- Jealous?
- No! Yes, but "no" more than "yes".
I mean, look at that! Dodd McAlvy, last
month he's the freak with Jicama breath
who waxes his back. He wins a few meets
and suddenly inherits the cool gene?
Well, all I know is, my cheerleading squad
wasted a lot of pep on losers.
It's about time
our school excelled at something.
You're forgetting our high mortality rate.
- We're number one! Huh?
- Yeah!
- One!
Beautiful!
Isn't it?
- Yeah. It's just so...
- Eternal.
A true mother, giving birth to new life
and devouring old.
Always adaptable and nurturing, yet...
constant... and merciless.
Boy! I was just gonna go with big and wet.
Me and some of the other guys
on the team,
we come out here once a week
to train in it.
See, we swim against the current.
Funny. That's how I feel most of the time.
So, Cameron Walker,
you just won the state semifinals.
What are you going to do next?
I'm going to hang out with Buffy Summers.
Get to know her.
- Hey, pause that tape for a second.
- Hey, no pressure.
I just like being around you. That's all.
- Somebody help me!
- Yeah!
Come on, Jonny, you gotta
hold your breath longer than that
if you ever wanna make the team!
Hey, somebody time him!
Hey!
Nice tat. What,
they ran out of Tweety Bird?
- Hey, what's your problem?
- Had it coming to you, bro.
Chill, dude. A bunch of us are gonna take
a little night dip down on the beach.
- You in?
- Whatever.
- Hey, let's, let's get you a towel.
- No!
Why didn't you mind your own business?
I can handle this without your help.
See? It's fun to hang out with me.
Man, I can't believe Buffy.
Man, that girl gives me the creeps.
Oh, dude! What is that foulness?
Hey, Dodd!
Dude!
"Go Fish"
OK! Good pie charts, everyone.
Good.
- All good.
- Thanks!
Nice.
Good.
Gage. Your pie chart is...
looking a lot like solitaire.
- With naked ladies on the cards?
- What's your point?
No point.
Nice work in yesterday's meet, son.
Now, let's go for it!
- Uh, hi there, sir.
- Rosenberg.
- How's the class? Everything in order?
- Well, actually...
Great. I've been talking to the board.
We've been having trouble finding
a competent teacher this late in the term.
Do you think you can continue
subbing through finals?
Oh! Sure! I like teaching.
Isn't that nice?
You're a team player and I like that.
A team player wants everyone on the team
to succeed, wants everyone to pass.
Well, yeah. Sure.
I understand there's a problem
with Gage Petronzi.
Oh, good. Then you know. Well, yeah.
Besides the behavior problem, he won't
do homework and his test scores are...
Well, actually he
doesn't have any test scores,
because he never shows up when we...
I'm not interested in any of that.
I'm interested in why,
when this school is on the brink
of winning its first state championship
in fifteen years,
you slap a crucial member of that team
with a failing mark
that would force his removal.
- Is that how you show your school spirit?
- Yes. Well, I mean... no.
- I'm just trying to grade fairly.
- Gage is a champion.
He's under more pressure
than the other students.
And I think
we need to cut him some slack.
You're asking me to change his grade?
I never said any such thing.
All I'm suggesting is...
that you recheck your figures.
And I think we'll find a grade more
fitting to an athlete of Gage's stature.
Perhaps something in a D?
Just like that?
He actually told you to alter his grade?
Exactly. Except for actually telling me to.
But he made it perfectly clear
of what he wasn't telling me.
That is wrong. A big fat spankin' wrong.
It's a slap in the face to
everyone of us who studied hard
and worked long hours to earn our D's.
Xander, I know you take pride
in being the voice of the common wuss,
but the truth is, certain people
are entitled to special privileges.
They're called winners.
That's the way the world works.
And what about that nutty
"all men are created equal" thing?
Propaganda spouted out
by the ugly and less deserving.
I think that was Lincoln.
- Disgusting mole and stupid hat.
- Actually, it was Jefferson.
- Kept slaves. Remember?
- You know what really grates my cheese?
That Buffy's not here to share
my moral outrage about swim-team perks.
She's too busy being one of them.
I don't know, a dolphin.
A dolphin in the ocean.
Because, you know, when
I'm in the vastness of the ocean,
it's... it's like I'm never alone.
You ever hear of a woman
named Gertrude Ederle?
No. No, I can't say that I have, Cam.
First woman to swim
the English Channel. Same thing.
I mean, she would talk to it. I mean, she'd
carry on entire conversations with it.
Sometimes I do that.
I mean, once I was...
You know what, Cam? Thanks.
I'd... forgotten how nice it is
to just talk,
or, in my case, listen,
without any romantic pressure.
Hey, I'm not about pressure.
I just want you to be comfortable.
I'm comfy! I'm so comfy,
I'm nodding off, actually, which is why...
Are you wearing a bra?
What?
Come on. I mean, tell me you haven't been
thinking about this ever since last night.
What I'm thinking about is that
I should probably get out of this car...
Relax. I'm not gonna hurt you.
Oh, it's not me I'm worried about.
You like it rough!
Ow! Oh!
Oh, you broke my nose! Ah!
I wasn't the attacker, Principal Snyder.
I was the attacked.
That's not how it looked
from where I was standing.
I don't know what happened.
I mean, first, she leads me on,
then she goes schizo on me.
Lead you on? When did I lead you on?
Oh, come on. I mean,
look at the way she dresses.
- Coach.
- How we doing, Cameron?
Coach Marin, how bad does it look?
Well, luckily, it's not broken, but sure
as hell it's gonna sting for a few days.
I mean our chances of winning
the state championship.
- Oh.
- Can we still do it?
I'm gonna need Cameron back at 110%.
He's my best swimmer now, with Dodd...
- What happened to Dodd?
- That's... none of your concern.
You'd better hope that boy's nose heals
before the meet this Friday.
Walker, I want you to
hit the steam room, uh,
as soon as you're done here
and try to keep those sinuses clear.
- Take care of my boy, Ruthie.
- I always do.
And you, try to dress
more appropriately from now on.
This isn't a dance club.
So I'm treated like the baddie
just because he has
a sprained wrist and a bloody nose.
And... I don't have a scratch on me,
which, granted,
hurts my case a little on the surface,
but, meanwhile,
he gets away with it because he's on
the "aren't we the most" swim team
who, by the way, if no one's noticed,
have been acting like real jerks lately...
So, anything new with you guys?
Thank you for taking an interest.
Apparently, some remains were found
on the beach this morning.
Some human remains.
- Dodd McAlvy's remains.
- Vampire?
No. No, he was eviscerated.
Nothing left but skin and cartilage.
In other words,
this was no boating accident.
So, something ripped him open
and ate out his insides?
Like an Oreo cookie.
Well, except for, you know,
without the chocolaty cookie goodness.
Yeah, um, Principal Snyder
has asked the faculty
to keep the news quiet for now, um,
- so as not to unduly upset students.
- For "students", read "swim team".
- So, we're looking for a beastie.
- That, uh, eats humans whole.
- Except for the skin.
- This doesn't make any sense.
- Yeah, the skin's the best part.
- Any demons with high cholesterol?
You're gonna think about that later,
mister, and you're gonna laugh.
OK, son. I think you've had enough.
Time to hit the shower.
Too much research. Need beverage.
Hey! Watch it!
Oh, forgive me, your swim teamliness.
- Loser!
- Liking the nose, Cam.
- Good look for you.
- Meaning what?
Meaning Buffy must not be
on your list of privileges after all.
Man, I love it
when you guys mess with her.
You're lucky I'm hungry.
Oh, the cafeteria's closed.
Not to me.
God! What is that?
Grape. Orange.
Orange. Grape.
Oh, my God!
Oh, God!
No, no, no! The mouth's a lot bigger!
And downward. Like this!
With more teeth!
I'm doing the best I can.
Is that what you saw, Xander?
Yeah! I think so.
- Pretty much.
- Are you sure?
Well, it was dark and the thing
went through the window so quick.
And I was, uh, a little shocked
when I saw it, and...
Go ahead. Say it.
You ran like a woman.
Hey, if you saw this thing,
you'd run like a woman, too!
Buffy was right.
According to the statistics,
Dodd and Cameron
were the best swimmers on the team.
First and second, actually.
Which means if my theory's correct,
Gage Petronzi, the third
best swimmer on the team,
would be the next item on the menu.
God! This is so sad. We're never
gonna win the state championship!
I think I have lost
all will to cheerlead.
Raise your hand if you feel her pain.
If you're saying
these killings aren't random,
it would suggest
someone's out for revenge.
And raise the possibility that
someone brought forth this sea monster
from whence it came
to exact that revenge.
From whence it came?
I'm spending way too much time
around you.
Who would hate the swim team
that much, though?
Besides me, I mean.
- Willow?
- Jonathan!
He was bullied by Dodd
the other day on the beach, remember?
He did say he could
take care of things himself.
It's a good call.
You should question him.
Really? Me?
I'll crack him like an egg.
Meanwhile, I think swimmer number three
might benefit from your...
watchful eye and protection -
discreetly, of course.
- I'm on it.
- What about me? What can I do?
Well, you could go out to the parking lot
and practice running like a man.
So, Jonathan.
You tried out for the swim team twice
and never made it?
I'm asthmatic. I couldn't keep up.
- You resented it, didn't you?
- Maybe.
You hated being pushed around
by Dodd and the others.
- So?
- So, you wanted revenge, didn't you?
Didn't you?
Yeah! OK? I did!
So... you delved into
the black arts...
and conjured up a hell beast from the
ocean's depths to wreak your vengeance.
- Didn't you?
- What? No!
I snuck in yesterday and...
peed in the pool.
Oh.
Eww!
This is such a blow.
Sooner or later, the rest
of my boys are gonna find out.
How can I ask them to swim?
It's a terrible, terrible tragedy.
We all feel your pain, Coach.
I don't know two finer boys
than Cameron and... that other one.
But I know they'd want their friends
to go on and win that state championship.
It's time to think about the team.
Hell, I don't have
a complete team as it is.
If we don't find someone
by this afternoon's tryouts,
we won't be eligible to compete.
You'll find someone. All he has to do
is wear a bathing suit, right?
(# "If You'd Listen" by Nero's Rome)
# If you'd listen,
# We wouldn't have to go through this
# If you'd just let me finish
# Stop cuttin' and jumpin' ahead
# Yeah, if you'd just
shut your pretty mouth
# You'd save yourself some tears
# If you came back from the bathroom
# With somethin' on your shoe...
This "me and my shadow" act?
It's getting old.
What do you want from me?
Well, um...
It's a little embarrassing.
You see...
- I'm a swim groupie.
- Uh-huh!
Oh... yeah!
You know,
there's just something about the...
smell of chlorine on a guy. Oh, baby!
OK! OK! OK!
Obviously, my... sex appeal
is on the fritz today,
so I'll just give it to you straight.
There's something lurking out there,
and it's making fillets of the populace,
and I think you might be next.
Uh-huh. And you think that because...?
Well, it's already attacked.
It's already killed some people.
You're one twisted sister,
you know that?
Cam told me about your games.
Go find someone else to harass.
What a psycho bitch! Man!
Gotta be talking about Buffy.
- How'd you know?
- Uh, she and I...
had this thing once.
Biggest mistake of my life.
- Yeah, my condolences, dude.
- She's a real head-tripper.
Tell me about it. Girl acts
like she's God's gift or something.
- Who is she? The Chosen One?
- Exactly.
You know, what she really needs
is for someone
to really knock her down
off her notches.
- Yeah, that'd be sweet. Anyone in mind?
- You're in luck, my friend.
- Just so happens, I'm recruiting.
- No!
Ah! Somebody! Help!
Ah! Help! Ah! Ah!
Get him off me! Help!
Ah!
Why, Miss Summers! You're beautiful!
Was that the thing that killed Cameron?
No. That was something else.
S-something else?!
Yeah. Unfortunately, we have
a lot of something elses in this town.
Good night.
Hey!
Walk me home?
Swimmers! Take position!
Keep the stroking up.
Alright. Keep it going,
keep it going all the way to the end.
All the way to the end. Breathe deep.
Gage! You with us or not?
Come on, let's go!
So he spit it out?
- I thought Angel liked blood.
- He used to.
Maybe his eyes
were too big for his stomach.
Or maybe there was something
in Gage's blood Angel didn't like.
Say, for example, steroids.
That would explain
all their behavioral changes.
And their winning streak.
So maybe whatever's in their blood
is what's attracting
this creature to them.
Any luck researching our fish monster?
Zippo. We couldn't find any sea demon
that matched the description
that Xander gave us.
Not that Chicken Little's
much of a witness, but...
Oh!
Oh! Oh, my!
Now that, girls, is my kind of...
Xander?
Xander?!
What the hell are you doing here?
- I'm undercover.
- You're not under much.
Get out of here, before someone sees you
impersonating a member of the swim team!
I don't do impersonations.
I tried out for the team last night.
- I made it.
- Really?
Yeah. I figured I can keep an eye
on Gage and the others when Buffy can't.
When you're nude?
I meant to say changing.
Harris! You can flirt on your own time.
Okey-dokey, coachie!
I'm dating a swimmer
from the Sunnydale swim team!
You can die happy.
What about Jonathan? Is he involved?
Oh, no. He just... sort of...
peed in the pool.
Oh.
Oh!
Don't you, guys,
get claustrophobic in here?
I mean, what's the deal?
You perspire a lot. You can't breathe.
Or read. I mean, I guess you could,
but the pages would probably
get all wet.
You gotta love this undercover deal.
20 minutes in a hot room
with a bunch of sweaty guys...
- Where's Gage?
- I don't know. He was right behind me,
putting his sneakers on.
But it's not the Velcro kind,
so give him a couple of extra minutes.
Tag. You're it.
Oh, my God!
Help! Help me! Help me!
Ah! Help me!
Gage?
I don't think that this
is going to need stitches,
but you might wanna have
your family physician take a look at it.
- How are you?
- I'm definitely feeling the burn.
Well, the, uh, good news is that
it would appear that
none of your team actually died.
But the bad news is...
they're monsters.
- How could this happen?
- Are you saying you don't know?
Well, you work so hard,
you start to win suddenly.
You think it's just you.
You're inspiring the boys
to greatness.
But in the back of your mind...
you start to wonder.
You never asked any of the boys
if they were taking anything?
Maybe I was afraid to.
- There.
- Dodd McAlvy: torn tendon.
Gage Petronzi: fractured wrist,
depression, headaches.
It's all there
in the school medical records.
All symptomatic of steroid abuse.
But is steroid abuse usually
linked with, 'hey, I'm a fish'?
There must be something else
in the mix.
But the point is, these boys
were obviously drugged.
Nurse Greenliegh
treated every one of them.
She must have known.
If steroids are that dangerous,
why would they do that to themselves?
They needed to win.
Winning equals trophies,
which equals prestige for the school.
You see how they're treated.
It's been like that forever.
Sure. The discus throwers got the best
seats at all the crucifixions.
Meanwhile, I'm breaking my nails
every day battling the forces of evil,
and my French teacher
can't even remember my name.
So, what's the drill?
Get Nurse Greenliegh?
Let's throw the book at her!
She probably went home for the day.
I think it can wait.
Xander, why don't you see if you can
find out what these boys are taking,
or at least how they're taking it?
- Powders, pills, syringe?
- I'm "looking around guy".
- What about you?
- Giles loaded up the tranquillizer gun.
We're going fishing.
I feel good!
Lovin' the swimmin'.
Had some carrot juice this morning.
A little wheat germ mixed in with it.
Woke me right up.
Nothing like it, huh?
Breakfast of state champions. You betcha.
OK. So, when do we get our next dose?
- What do you mean?
- Who's carrying?
I need a little something
to improve my performance.
Give me an edge. Rrr!
The steroids. Where are they?
- You're soakin' in it, bud.
- Huh?
Aromatherapy. It's in the steam.
This has got to stop, Carl.
Those poor children!
What, are you a quitter? We have
no room for quitters on this team.
Do you even understand
what's happening?
- Listen to yourself.
- I'm very close to perfecting this.
We just need to adjust the mix.
Carl. You can't be thinking
of continuing to expose these boys.
They're gonna be the best.
I don't accept anything less.
They're gonna be monsters.
Carl, please. Don't make it any worse.
You've already lost three.
Lost? Why, they're not lost.
- Carl! What are you doing?!
- I'm just looking after my boys.
They may be out of the game right now,
but they're still a team.
And a team's gotta eat.
- Carl!
- You quitter.
They're absorbing the steroid mixture
through the steam.
Not they. We!
Me!
We need to find an antidote,
don't you think?
The clock is ticking, people!
I wouldn't break out
the tartar sauce just yet.
It's not like you were exposed
more than once.
- Twice?
- Three times a fish guy.
- Oh.
- Whoa.
- What am I gonna do?
- You, you, you!
What about me? It's one thing
to be dating the lame unpopular guy,
but it's another to be dating
the creature from the Blue Lagoon.
Black Lagoon. The creature from
the Blue Lagoon was Brooke Shields.
And thank you so much
for your support!
I think we'd better find the rest
of the swim team and lock them up
before they get in touch
with their inner halibut.
Yes. Yes, good. Uh...
We also need to know exactly
what's in this, this steroid gas,
so that the hospital's toxicology lab
can develop an antidote.
Well, I'll talk to Nurse Greenliegh.
You're really getting into
this interrogation thing.
The trick is not to leave any marks.
On that note, I think I'm gonna go
have a little talk with our coach.
Somehow, I doubt all he's been
giving these boys is inspiration.
You got some imagination, missy.
Oh, well right now,
I'm imagining you in jail.
You're wearing a big, orange suit, and,
oh, look, the guards are beating you up.
- You don't have any proof.
- Tell me what's in the steam.
After the fall of the Soviet Union,
documents came into light
detailing experiments with fish DNA
on their Olympic swimmers.
Tarpon... mako shark...
- But they couldn't crack it.
- And you did...
Sort of.
Why?
What kind of question is that?
For the win!
To make my team the best they could be!
Do you understand we have a shot
at the state championship?
Do you understand that I don't care?
It's over!
There's not gonna be any swim team.
Boy, when they were
handing out school spirit,
you didn't even stand in line,
did you?
No. I was in the line
for shred of sanity.
Which you obviously skipped.
Get in the hole!
In! Now!
- This isn't over.
- In!
You think I don't care about my boys.
But I do. They count on me.
So, what, you're just
gonna feed me to 'em?
Oh, they've already had their dinner.
But boys have other needs.
No one. Willow and Giles
must've rounded up the swim team.
- Does my neck look scaly to you?
- Well, of course it looks scaly,
the way you've been rubbing it dry
like an idiot!
I need to look in a mirror. Wait here.
But feel free to come in
if you hear me scream.
Any gills yet?
Xander, what are you doing? Xander?
Oh, my God! Xander!
It's me - Cordelia.
I know you can't answer me, but...
God, this is all my fault.
You joined the swim team
to impress me.
You were so courageous.
And you looked really hot
in those Speedos.
And I want you to know that...
I still care about you,
no matter what you look like.
And... and we can still date!
Or, or not. I mean...
I understand
if you wanna see other fish.
I'll do everything I can
to make your quality of life better.
Whether that means
little bath toys or whatever.
Uh, Cordy? That's not me.
Oh, my God!
In you go.
Stay calm, chaps.
Either we'll find
an effective antidote, or, or, uh...
Just stay calm.
Everyone's accounted for except Sean.
I think we can safely say
we found Sean.
He was in the pool skinless-dipping.
- Where's Buffy?
- She hasn't come back yet.
Great. This is just
what my reputation needs:
that I did it
with the entire swim team.
- What's up, Coach?
- Oh, Harris. Uh...
- How you feeling?
- A little dry.
Nothing a lemon butter sauce
won't cure.
Where's Buffy?
Buffy, hurry! Your hand!
Hold on!
- Pull!
- Hold on!
- Thanks.
- Just doing my part for our team.
Don't let go! Don't let go of me!
Hold me!
Hold me! Ah!
Grab my hand!
Boys... Boys, uh, now... Now, boys...
No. I... No, boys!
Those boys really love their coach.
Let's see. I gotta take
a make-up chem test at three.
And then I'm meeting some of the guys
for plasma transfusions at five.
It's turned into quite the busy afternoon.
The fun never stops with you,
does it?
Giles seems pretty confident
that the treatments are gonna work.
Well, turning into
a creepy-crawly wasn't on
my top ten list of things to do
before I turn 20.
I want you to know that
you've really proven yourself to me.
And you don't have to join the
new team next year if you don't want.
I'd be just as happy
if you played football.
The... people from Animal Control
have just left.
Our creatures have
apparently made a, a dash for it. Um...
So to speak.
Does that mean
we're gonna have to hunt them again?
No, I don't think so. I don't think
we'll be seeing them any more.
- Where do you think they'll go?
- Home.
Subtitles extended & timed by UAR
www.tvsubtitles.net