In every generation, there is a Chosen One,
She alone will stand against the vampires,
the demons and the forces of darkness.
She is the Slayer.
- Hi.
- Oh, that's what I was gonna say.
- What you lookin' at?
- This cheerleading trophy.
It's like its eyes follow you
wherever you go.
- I like it.
- So, did you like the movie last night?
I don't know. Today's movies are
kinda like... popcorn, you know?
You forget about 'em
as soon as they're done.
I do remember
I liked the popcorn, though.
Yeah, it was good.
And I had a really fun time with the rest.
I mean, the part with you.
Well, that's great.
My time was also... of the good.
Mine too.
Well, then...
Oh, there! I have...
my friend, so I will... go to her.
I'll see you, then...
Later.
Ohh...
Man! Oz!
I would love to get me some of that
Buffy and Willow action
if you know what I mean.
That's great, Larry.
You've really mastered the single entendre.
- Hey!
- Oops.
Oh, thank you, Thighmaster!
So, Oz, man, what's up with that?
Dating a junior?
Oh, let me guess.
That little, innocent schoolgirl thing
is just, uh, just an act, right?
Yeah. Yeah, she's actually
an evil mastermind. It's fun.
I mean, she's gotta be puttin' out,
or what's the point?
What are you gonna do? Talk?
Come on, fess up. How far have you got?
Nowhere. I mean,
he said he was gonna wait
until I was ready, but I'm ready!
Honest, I'm good to go here.
I think it's nice
if he's not just being an animal.
It is nice. He's great!
We have a lot of fun.
But I want smoochies!
- Have you dropped any hints?
- I've dropped anvils.
Oh, he'll come around. What guy
could resist your wily Willow charms?
At last count, all of them,
maybe more.
None of them know a thing.
They all get an F in Willow.
But I want Oz to get an A.
And oh, one of those... gold stars.
- He will.
- Well, he'd better hurry.
I don't wanna be the only girl
in school without a real boyfriend.
Oh, I'm such an idiot! I'm sorry.
I shouldn't even be talking about...
- Do you want me to go away?
- I wish you wouldn't.
- How are you holding up, anyway?
- I'm holding.
I was going on two minutes there
without thinking about Angel.
- Well, there you go!
- But I would do a lot better
if you and Xander and I could do that
"sharing our misery" thing tonight.
Great. I'll give Xander a call.
What's his number? Oh, yeah,
1-800-I'm-Dating-A-Skanky-Ho.
- Meow!
- Really?
Thanks. I've never gotten
a "meow" before.
- Well deserved.
- Darn tootin'!
I'm just saying, Xander and Cordelia?
What does he see in her, anyway?
What could she possibly see in him?
Excuse me?! We didn't come here
to talk about Willow.
We came here to do things
I can never tell my father about,
because he still thinks
I'm a... good girl.
I just don't trust Oz with her.
I mean, he's a senior.
He's attractive.
OK, maybe not to me, but...
And he's in a band! And we know
what kind of element that attracts.
- I've dated lots of guys in bands.
- Thank you.
- Do you even wanna be here?
- I'm not running away.
Because when you're not babbling about
poor defenseless Willow, you are raving
- about the all-powerful Buffy
- I do not babble. I occasionally run on.
- Every now and then I yammer.
- Xander.
- Yeah?
- Look around.
We're in my daddy's car.
It's just the two of us.
There is a beautiful,
big full moon outside tonight.
It doesn't get more romantic than this.
So shut up!
"Phases"
- Did you hear that?
- What is it now?
- I thought I heard something.
- I-is Willow sending out some sort of
distress signal
that only you can hear?
OK, now I know I heard something!
All right, that's it! You know
your mind hasn't been here all night.
How about I just drop you off...
Get us outta here!
- I can't find the key!
- We should be movin'! Let's go!
Told ya I heard somethin'.
- And you're sure it was a werewolf?
- Well, let's see, um...
Six feet tall, claws, a big old snout
in the middle of his face, like a wolf.
Um, yeah,
I'm stickin' with my first guess.
- Seems wise.
- Oh, oh, and then
there was that thing
where it tried to bite us.
- It was so awful!
- I know.
Daddy just had this car detailed!
- So, what's the word?
- Well, it seems there were, uh,
a number of other attacks
by a "wild dog" around town.
Several animal carcasses
were found mutilated.
You mean like bunnies and stuff?
No, don't tell me.
Oh, don't worry.
I mean, they might not look it,
but bunnies can really
take care of themselves.
- Yeah.
Yes, uh, um, fortunately,
no people were injured.
- That falls into "That's a Switch" column.
- Well, for now, but my guess is that this
werewolf will be back
at next month's full moon.
- What about tonight's full moon?
- Pardon?
Well, last night was
the night before the full moon,
traditionally known as...
the night before the full moon.
Meaning the accepted legend that...
werewolves only prowl during a full moon
might be erroneous.
- Or it could be a crock.
- Well, unless
the werewolf was using
last year's almanac.
Looks like Giles
has some schoolin' to do.
Yes, I must admit I, I am intrigued.
Werewolves. It's one of the classics.
I'm sure my books and I are
in for a fascinating afternoon.
He needs to get a pet.
Sunnydale is becoming
more dangerous all the time.
And full moon like tonight
tends to bring out the crazies.
But with some simple basics
of self-defence,
each of you can learn
how to protect yourself.
- Here's a suggestion -
- What you wanna do...
- move away from the Hellmouth.
- is gain advantage of the situation
as quickly as possible.
- Tag.
- Your attacker may have
- the benefit of surprise.
- Would you look at that!
- He's all over her! Psst! Hey, buddy!
- But if you plot ahead, then you can
- This is a public forum here!
- turn that advantage to yourself.
I think you've splashed on just
a little too much Obsession for Dorks.
(By being prepared, you have the power.)
OK, everyone get into your assigned groups.
- What happened?
- Oh, last week some huge dog
jumped out of the bushes and bit me.
39 stitches.
They oughta shoot those strays.
I've been there, man. My cousin Jordy
just got his grown-up teeth in.
Does not like to be tickled.
Theresa! Be still, my shorts.
We're in the same group.
I may have to attack you.
No, actually, I think in our group
there are a few of us.
And I'm one of the few.
Don't forget, you're supposed to be
a meek little girlie girl,
like the rest of us.
Spoil my fun!
OK, everyone listen up.
I wanna show you
what to do should you
be attacked from behind.
In this situation, bend forward,
using your back and shoulders
to flip the assailant over to the ground.
Nuh!
- Nuh!
- Oh, Summers, you are turnin' me on!
And that works, too.
And, uh, while there's absolutely
no scientific explanation for
lunar effect on the human psyche, uh,
the phases of the moon do seem to exert
a great deal of psychological influence.
And th-the full moon is, is,
seems to bring out our darkest qualities.
And yet, ironically,
it led to the invention of the MoonPie.
Oh
Yes, MoonPie!
You see,
the werewolf is such a potent, extreme
representation
of our inborn animalistic traits,
it emerges for three
full consecutive nights -
the full moon
and the two nights surrounding it.
- Quite the party animal.
- Quite, and it acts on pure instinct.
No conscience. Predatory and,
and aggressive.
- In other words, your typical male.
- On behalf of my gender - hey!
- Yes, let's not jump to any conclusions.
- I didn't jump.
I took a tiny step
and there conclusions were.
The point is that our wolfman
could also be a wolfwoman,
or anyone who was bitten
by a werewolf.
So, then I'm guessing your standard
silver bullets are in order here?
No, no bullets.
No matter who this werewolf is,
i-it's still a human being,
who may be completely unaware
of his or her condition.
So, tonight we bring him back alive.
- Anything yet?
- Yes, and you won't believe what I saw!
Brittany Podelle was making out
with Owen Stadeal,
but he goes with Bara Williams.
If she ever foun...
No, um, no, no sign of the werewolf.
How about you?
Uh, the same.
I thought we might, uh...
I thought we might
knock on a few windows, uh...
ask if anyone has seen anything yet.
Giles, no one's seen anything.
Oh. Yes. No.
Of-of-of course not, no.
Yes.
Gotcha!
- What the hell...?
- Giles! Giles!
Hey!
Whoa! Whoa.
Hands are good right about there.
Who are you? What are you doing?
The name's Cain.
I'm the one with the gun,
which means I'm the one
who gets to do the interviewing.
Ahem. Hey,
before we get all chummy here,
how about we do something
about me being in this net thing?
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
- I gotta say, I'm impressed.
- Excuse me?
Oh, it's good to get the fruit
while it's fresh.
You'd be wise to take that back.
Hey, what a man and a girl do
in Lovers' Lane at night is nobody's...
Oh, OK, hey, enough, Repulsive Brain!
It's not what you think.
We're... hunting werewolves.
OK, it's funny if you don't
believe in werewolves.
No, it's funny thinking about
you two catching one.
This guy looks like
he's auditioning to be a librarian and...
You, well... You're a girl.
- I assure you, she's quite capable.
- Uh-huh.
Let me ask you somethin', sweetheart.
Exactly how many of these animals
- have you taken out?
- As of today?
I tore a tooth from the mouth
of every werewolf that I killed.
This next one'll bring
the total to an even dozen.
- So, you're just gonna kill it?
- Well, see, that's the thing.
Their pelts fetch
a pretty penny in Sri Lanka,
and it's a little hard
to skin 'em when they're alive.
- You hunt werewolves for sport?
- No, no. I'm in it purely for the money.
It doesn't bother you that a werewolf is
a person 28 days out of the month?
That's why I only hunt 'em the other three.
I'd really love to stay and chat,
but I'm on a tight schedule.
Any idea where else the boys and girls
like to get together around here?
- You're looking for a party?
- No, but the werewolf is.
They're suckers for that whole
sexual heat thing.
Sense it miles away.
If this little doggy ain't here,
I guess he found another place.
Sorry. Wish I could help you.
But you don't know squat?
Gee, what a surprise!
- Where are we going?
- I think I know where to look.
We just have to make it there
before "Mein Furrier".
- Everything OK?
- Yeah, I just, uh...
I thought I heard something...
behind me.
- No one there.
- Oh.
I guess I was wrong. I coulda sworn...
It's OK. It can get pretty scary
out here, all alone at night.
Yeah.
Hey, don't I know you from somewhere?
Don't you go to school with Buffy?
- Oh, you know Buffy?
- Yes, I do, very well.
Come on. I'll get you home.
(# "Blind For Now" by Lotion)
# And then sweep this town
# into a Monster Truck of shame
# Carved out of soap and steel
and clay and salty fame
# You are the first
to look away and against me
# You shake the squirrel out your tree...
I mean, with Xander, it's always
"Buffy did this, Willow said that."
"Buffy, Buffy, Willow, Willow."
It's like I don't even exist!
- I sometimes feel like that.
- And then when I call him on it,
he acts confused.
Like I'm the one with a problem.
His "Do I smell something?" look.
All a part of his little guy games.
It's like he's there, then he's not there.
He wants it, but then
he doesn't want it.
He's so busy looking around
at everything he doesn't have,
doesn't even realise
what he does have.
Well, he should at least realize
that you have Oz.
Hm, I'm not sure I do.
Oz and I are in...
some sort of holding pattern.
Except... without the holding or...
anything else.
What's he waiting for? What's his problem?
Oh, that's right. He's a guy.
- Yeah, him and Xander. Guys!
- Who do they think they are?
Couple of guys.
- Looks as though your hunch was right.
- Who could resist Sunnydale's own
house of hormones?
- The werewolf, it's in there!
- Comin' through!
- You let it get away.
- I didn't let it do anything.
- I had the chain around its neck.
- Chain?!
What were you gonna do?
Take it for a walk?
I was going to lock it up.
That's beautiful.
This is what happens
when a woman tries to do a man's job.
Now you look here, Mr... Cain.
This girl risked her life,
trying to capture a beast
that you haven't as yet been able to find.
Uh-huh. And Daddy's doing a great job
carrying her bag of Milk-Bones.
You know, sis,
if that thing out there harms anyone,
it's going to be
on your pretty little head.
- I hope you can live with that.
- I live with that every day.
First they tell me I can't
hunt an elephant for its ivory.
Now I've gotta deal with People for
the Ethical Treatment of Werewolves!
Pillock! Right, let's move out.
Giles? Giles!
I didn't see you there.
I thought something had happened.
Oh, no, I'm, I'm, uh...
I'm OK. I'm just, um, fine...
Er, just, uh, I'm, uh...
Er, any sign of the, uh, werewolf?
No. I'm guessing
you didn't see anything either,
from that vantage point
of having your eyes closed.
It's, uh, it's, it's, uh, gonna
be light soon, so we'd better...
- Wait!
- Police say that the incident was
apparently connected
to the animal mutilation
which occurred two nights ago.
The coroner's office
has identified the body
as that of Sunnydale High School
student Theresa Klussmeyer, age 17,
Buffy, we're gonna get this thing.
We have another whole night.
There's nothing more we can do now.
It's... nearly sunrise.
That werewolf won't be
a werewolf much longer.
Huh.
Aunt Maureen? Hey, it's me.
Uh, what? Oh, it's...
Actually, it's healin' OK.
That's pretty much the reason I called.
Um, I wanna ask you somethin'.
Is Jordy a werewolf?
Uh-huh.
And how long has that been goin' on?
What? No, no reason. Um...
Thanks. Yeah, love to Uncle Ken.
I can't believe
I let that thing get away!
Cain was right.
I shoulda killed it when I had the chance.
- Killed what?
- Uh, the... the werewolf.
It-it-it was out last night.
Is everybody OK? Did anybody get...
bitten or, or scratched?
No, we're fine.
- Gladness.
- Yeah, but it got someone. Theresa.
Got, as in...?
Oh, I'm sorry.
And I coulda stopped it.
Well, we... We have one more night.
- Another night?
- Oh, yeah.
Believe me, I'm gonna give
that wolfie somethin' to howl about.
But while we hang here doing nothing,
there's a human werewolf walking around
out there, probably making fun of us.
The way werewolves always do.
But there's really no way
to tell who it is.
Oh, sure there is. Giles knows stuff
and I'm practically
an expert on the subject.
On account of once you were a hyena?
I know what it's like to...
crave the taste of freshly-killed meat.
To be taken over by
those uncontrollable urges.
You said you didn't remember
anything about that.
I said I didn't remember
Look, the point is that
I have an affinity with this thing.
I can get inside of its head.
I'm a big bad wolf. I'm on the prowl.
I'm sniffin', I'm snarlin',
I'm a slobbering predator, I'm...
Wait a second!
It's right in front of us!
It's obvious who I am!
I'm Larry!
The guy has practically got "Wolf Boy"
stamped on his forehead.
You got the dog bite,
you got the aggression,
not to mention excessive back hair.
And he was awfully gleeful
about tormenting Theresa.
- Still, that doesn't necessarily mean...
- I'm gonna talk to him.
- Gonna force a confession outta him.
- Good. Go.
Uh, in the meantime, we need to
cover our bases. Willow, um...
check the student files,
see if anybody else... fits the profile.
- Buffy?
- Where are we going?
If none of that works,
I think I may have an alternative.
Yeah, me and the werewolf
alone in a cage for three minutes.
That's all I ask.
- Are you OK?
- What?
- You kind of knew Theresa.
- Oh, yeah, I, uh...
I'm tryin' not to think about it. It's...
- It's a lot.
- It is.
But we can do stuff to help.
Sometimes it feels good to help.
- Uh-huh.
- Well, like looking up stuff.
I'm gonna be doing that
most of the night. You could...
help me. Help together?
I can't. Um, uh... I'm busy.
Oh. So...
I... I gotta go.
Harris! Cheesh! Next time, wear a bell.
Why so jumpy, Larry?
- Geeks make me nervous.
- Is that really it,
or is there something you're hiding?
I could hide my fist in your face.
I know your secret, big guy.
I know what you been doin' at night.
You know, Harris,
that nosey little nose of yours
is gonna get you into trouble someday.
- Like today.
- Hurting me isn't gonna make this go away.
People are still gonna find out!
All right, what do you want?
Hush money? Is that what you're after?
I don't want anything.
I just wanna help!
What, you think you have a cure?
No, it's just...
I know what you're goin' through,
because I've been there.
That's why I know
you should talk about it.
That's easy for you to say.
I mean, you're nobody.
I've got a reputation here.
Larry, please,
before someone else gets hurt!
Look, if this gets out...
it's over for me.
I mean, forget about playin' football.
They'll run me out of this town.
I mean, come on! How are people gonna
look at me after they find out I'm gay?
Wow. I said it.
And it felt... OK.
I'm gay.
I... am gay!
- I heard you the first time.
- I can't believe it. It was almost easy.
I've never felt I could tell anyone.
And then you, you of all people,
you bring it out of me!
It probably woulda slipped out,
even if I wasn't here.
No! No, because knowing
you went through the same thing
made it easier for me to admit.
- The same thing...
- It's ironic.
I mean, all those times
I beat the crap outta you...
It must've been because
I recognised something in you...
that I didn't wanna believe
about myself.
- Larry, no. I am not...
- Of course. Of course not.
Don't worry. I wouldn't do that to you.
Your secret's safe with me.
Oh, wow.
So, what's the scuttlebutt? Anybody
besides Larry fit our werewolf profile?
There is one name
that keeps getting spit out.
Aggressive behaviour,
run-ins with authorities...
- About a screenful of violent incidents.
- OK, most of those were not my fault.
Somebody else started 'em.
I was just standing up for myself.
They say it's a good idea
to count to ten when you're angry.
One. Two.
- Three.
- I'll keep looking!
I, um... noticed you were lookin' solo.
Yeah. Oz...
wanted to be someplace that was...
away... from me.
- I'm sorry.
- I can't figure him out.
I mean, he's so hot and cold.
Or lukewarm and cold.
Welcome to the mystery that is men.
I think it goes something like...
They grow body hair, they lose all ability
to tell you what they really want.
That doesn't seem like a fair trade.
Well, if you wanna up
the speed quotient with Oz,
maybe you need to do something daring.
Maybe you need to make the first move.
That won't make me a slut?
I think your reputation
will remain intact.
It used to be so much easier
to tell if a boy liked you.
He'd punch you on the arm
and then run back to his friends.
- Those were the days.
- Hey.
I'll see you guys later.
Cordelia asked me to
look over her history homework
before class.
I think that means I might have to do it.
Wow, those two gals
are hanging out a lot together.
This'd be a good time to panic.
- So, how'd it go with Larry?
- What's that supposed to mean?
I think it's supposed to mean,
'So how'd it go with Larry'?
He's not the werewolf.
Can't we just leave it at that?
Must you continue to push and push?
- Sorry, I was just wondering.
- Well, he's not.
- OK.
But there goes our lead suspect,
which then puts us back at square boned.
You're not boned, you're Buffy.
Eradicator of evil, defender of, um...
things that need defending.
Tell that to Theresa.
She could've used my defending
before she was ripped apart by that...
Werewolf.
Nowhere in any of the reports did it
say anything about her being mauled.
I mean, they were linked to the
animal attacks from the other night,
- so we just assumed werewolf.
- What else should we have assumed?
- Vampire.
- So, that's good, right?
I mean, in the sense of
the werewolf didn't get her and...
No, there is no good here.
No good. Instead of not protecting
Theresa from the werewolf,
I was able to not protect her
from something just as bad.
She had a lot of friends.
Buffy, you can't blame yourself
for every death that happens in Sunnydale.
If it weren't for you people'd be lined up
five deep waitin' to get themselves buried.
Willow would be Robbie the Robot's
love slave, I wouldn't have a head and...
Theresa's a vampire.
Angel sends his love.
Angel...
Are you OK?
This isn't happening.
- He's gonna keep coming after me.
- Don't let him get to you.
He's not the same guy you knew.
Oh, no, my life's not too complicated.
- Willow, what are you doing here?
- I had this whole thing worked out.
And I had it written down, uh,
but then it didn't make any sense
- when I was reading it back.
- Willow, this is not a very good time.
I mean, what am I supposed to think?
First you buy me popcorn, and then
you're all glad that I didn't get bit.
And you put the tag back in my shirt.
But I guess none of that means anything,
because instead of
looking up names with me,
here you are, all alone in your house,
doing nothing, by yourself!
Willow, we'll talk about this tomorrow!
No, dammit!
We'll talk about this now!
Buffy told me that sometimes what
a girl makes has to be the first move
and now that I'm saying this,
I'm starting to think
that the written version
sounded pretty good, but...
- You know what I mean.
- I know, I know. It's me. I'm-
I'm going through some... changes.
Well, welcome to the world!
Things happen!
Don't you think I'm going through a lot?
- Not like me.
- Oh, what? So now you're special?
You're Special Boy.
With... chains and stuff?
Why do you have... chains and stuff?
Willow, please!
Get outta here!
Oz?
Oz, what is it?
What's wrong?
There you are!
Sorry I'm late. I had to do some
unscheduled slayage in the form of Theresa.
- She's a vampire?
- Was.
Angel sent her to me.
A little token of his affection.
- Buffy, I'm so sorry.
- Not now, Giles.
We can all have ourselves a good cry
after we bag us a werewolf.
- All set. Let's go find this thing.
- One question...
- How exactly do we find this thing?
- It's Oz! It's Oz!
- Wha-what's Oz?
- The werewolf.
- Are you certain?
- Can't you just trust me on this?
He, he said he was
going through all these changes,
then... he went through
all these... changes.
- Where is he now?
- In the woods.
- Let's go.
- Go where? You're not gonna kill Oz!
Yeah, he's a werewolf,
but he doesn't mean to be!
Don't worry, Willow.
We're not going to hurt him.
We've put enough phenobarbital in this
to sink a small elephant.
It shoud be enough
for a large werewolf.
That's it. Let me see you.
Come on, suppertime!
Good doggy!
Now play dead.
Careful!
Dammit!
I shot Oz!
You saved us.
No wonder this town's
overrun with monsters.
- No one here's man enough to kill 'em!
- Oh, I wouldn't be too sure of that.
How about you let the door
hit you in the ass on the way outta town?
Is he gonna be OK?
He'll be a little sore in the morning,
but... he'll be Oz.
This is all so weird. I mean,
how are we supposed to act
when we see him?
It's gotta be weird for him too,
now that we know so much.
All I know is I'll never be able
to look at him the same again.
He's still a human being...
- Most of the time.
- Who are we talking about?
- Oz. Who are you talking about?
- No one.
Here, let me get those.
- Thanks.
- Hey, what was that?
Hey, Xander! Look, about what you did.
- I, I owe you.
- What did you do?
It's really nothing
we should be talking about. Ever.
I know, I know. It's just, well...
Thanks.
- That was weird.
- What?
It's not OK for one guy
to like another guy,
just because he happened to be
in the locker room with him
when absolutely nothing happened?
And I thought I told you not to push!
All I meant is that
he didn't try to look up my skirt.
Oh, oh, yeah, that's...
that's the weirdness.
Weirdness abounds lately.
Maybe it's the moon.
- It does stuff to people.
- I've heard that.
It's certainly gonna put a strain
on Willow and Oz's relationship.
What relationship? I mean, what life
could they possibly have together?
We're talking
obedience school, paper-training...
Oz is always in the back,
burying their things
and that kind of breed
can turn on its owner.
I don't know.
I kind of see Oz as the loyal type.
All I'm saying is she's not safe with him.
If it were up to me...
Xander.
It's not up to you.
- Hey.
Did you wanna go first?
I spoke to Giles. He said I'll be OK.
I just have to lock myself up
around the full moon.
Only he used more words
than that. And a globe.
I'm sorry about how all this ended up,
with me shooting you an' all.
It's OK. I'm sorry I almost ate you.
It's OK.
- I kinda thought you would have told me.
- I didn't know what to say.
It's not every day you find out you're...
a werewolf. That's fairly freaksome.
It may take a couple of days
getting used to.
Yeah, it's a complication.
So...
Maybe it'd be best
if I just... sorta...
What?
Well, you know, like...
stayed out of your way for a while.
I don't know.
I'm kind of OK
with you being in my way.
You mean, you'd still...?
Well, I like you.
You're nice and you're funny.
And you don't smoke.
Yeah, OK, werewolf, but...
that's not all the time.
I mean, three days out of the month,
I'm not much fun to be around, either.
You are quite a human.
So... I'd still if... you'd still.
I'd still. I'd very still.
OK.
- No biting, though.
- Agreed.
A werewolf in love!
Subtitles extended & timed by UAR
www.tvsubtitles.net