You are the Slayer.
To each generation a Slayer is born.
One girl in all the world.
The Chosen One.
- Who's that?
- That must be Angel.
Last season, on Buffy the Vampire Slayer...
Vampire in love with the Slayer?
It's rather poetic.
And in this time shall come the Anointed.
Buffy will face the Master...
and she will die.
She's not breathing. She's dead.
Breathe! Come on!
- You're dead!
- I may be dead, but I'm still pretty.
OK, um...
- It's your turn.
- OK. Uh...
"In the few hours that we had together,
we loved a lifetime's worth."
- Terminator,
- Good! Right.
OK, I got one.
- "It's a madhouse! A mad..."
- Planet of the Apes,
- Can I finish, please?
- Oh, sorry. Go ahead.
house!."
Planet of the Apes.
OK, good. Me. Uh...
Well?
I'm thinking.
"Use the Force, Luke."
Do I even have to
dignify that with a guess?
I couldn't think of anything.
- It's a dumb game anyway.
- What else d'you wanna do?
We already played rock, paper, scissors.
My hand's cramped up.
Well, yes, if you're always "scissors",
of course, your tendons...
I just gotta say this has been
the most boring summer ever.
Yeah, but on the plus side,
no monsters or stuff.
I'm just so restless!
I'm actually looking forward
to school starting up again.
Yeah, and that
wouldn't have anything to do
with a certain girl we both know,
who is a vampire slayer.
Please! I'm so over her.
Did she, uh, mention
when she might be gettin' back?
- About which I do not care.
- I haven't heard from her.
I got a couple of postcards when
she went to LA, but they're like nothing.
Well, she's probably with her dad
havin' a good time.
- And you don't care?
- Well, OK. There might be some interest.
I'm a man. I have
certain desires, certain needs.
I-I don't wanna know.
I got a movie for ya.
- Xander!
- You're Amish.
You can't fight back 'cause you're Amish.
I mock you with my ice cream, Amish guy.
Witness.
- My nose is cold.
- Let me get that for ya.
Xander!
Sorry, I can't help myself.
Your nose looks so tasty.
Willow, go.
Hi, guys.
Miss me?
"When She Was Bad"
- Buffy!
- Hey!
Hey!
Hey, Will.
Man, your timing really doesn't suck.
- When d'you get back?
- Uh, just now. Dad drove me down.
And I figured you two losers
would be getting into some kind of trouble.
I think we had the upper hand...
in a subtle way.
Does either of you even have a cross?
Very sloppy.
Well, it's been a slow summer.
I mean, it's the first vampire we've seen
- since you killed the Master.
- It's like they knew I was coming back.
So what about you? How was
your summer? Did you slay anything?
No. Just hung out, partied some,
shopping was also a major theme.
Oh, you haven't lost your touch.
That vampire...
I did kinda whale on him, didn't I?
I like your hair.
So, how did you guys fare?
Did you have any fun without me?
- Yes.
- No.
Our summer was yawn-worthy. Our
biggest excitement was burying the Master.
That's right, you missed it.
Right out by that tree.
Giles buried the bones and we poured
holy water and we got to wear robes.
Very intense. You shoulda been.
Have you seen Giles?
Why would I do that?
I'll see him at school.
Man, I'm really glad you're back.
Me too.
- OK, then. This is the last of it.
- More clothes?
- Oh, do shoes count as clothes?
- How much shopping did you let her do?
Oh, I just thought I was saving you from
the big back-to-school clothing nightmare.
My nightmares with Buffy in school
have nothing to do with clothes.
Did she manage to
stay out of trouble in LA?
She did, yeah.
She was... you know... great.
But?
She was just, I don't know, um...
Distant?
Not brooding or sulking, just...
There was no connection.
The more time we spent together, the more
I felt like she was nowhere to be seen.
Hence the shoes?
I may have overcompensated a little bit.
It's so strange. You know,
at least when she was burning stuff down
- I knew what to say.
- Welcome to my world.
I haven't been able to get through
to her for so long.
I'll just be happy if
she makes it through the school year.
It was a nightmare. A total nightmare.
I mean, they promised me
they'd take me to St Croix,
and then they just decide
to go to Tuscany.
Art and buildings? I was totally beachless
for a month and a half.
No one has suffered like I have suffered.
Of course, I think
that kind of adversity builds character.
Well, then I thought,
I already have a lot of character.
Is it possible to have too much character?
The first day back. It always gets me.
- Yes.
- I mean, it's incredible.
One day the campus is
completely bare, empty.
The next,
there are children everywhere.
Like locusts, crawling around,
mindlessly bent on feeding and mating,...
destroying everything in sight in their
relentless, pointless desire to exist.
I do enjoy these pep talks.
Have you ever considered,
given your abhorrence of children,
school's principal was not,
perhaps, your true vocation?
Somebody's gotta keep an eye on them.
They're a bunch of hormonal time bombs.
Every time a pretty girl walks by,
every boy turns into a gibbering fool.
- Ms Calendar.
- Mr. Giles.
Well, I... um...
Hello.
You see the way these kids
gaze at each other... all moony?
- It's good to see you.
- Yes.
Think they're thinking about learning?
Were you headed to the faculty room?
Sounds like fun.
I try and tell them about
the important things in life.
Discipline, responsibility, punctuality.
I might as well be talkin' to myself.
- How was your summer?
- Extreme.
I did "Burning Man" in Black Rock.
Ohhh, such a great festival.
You should've been there.
They had drum rituals, mobile sculptures,
raves, naked mud dances.
You would have just...
hated it with a fiery passion.
I can't imagine finding any redeeming...
Naked?
And you probably spent all summer
with your nose in a book.
Yes. I suppose you'd consider that
frightfully dull.
Depends on the book.
- Giles!
- Yo, G-Man! What's up?
Nice to see you.
And don't ever call me that.
Hi, kids.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Alive and kicking.
Buffy killed a vampire last night.
I think you can get a little more volume
if you speak from the diaphragm.
- Sorry.
- We've got vampires?
- I thought the Hellmouth was closed.
- It's-it's closed, but not gone.
The mystical energy that emanates from it
is still concentrated in this area.
Which means we're still
the undead's favorite party town.
I wonder if they're here
for any purpose particularly.
You're the Watcher. I just work here.
Yes, I must consult my books.
Oh, eight minutes and 33 seconds. Pay up.
I called ten minutes before you'd consult
your books about something. Thank you.
We'd better get to class.
Oh, Buffy, uh...
I realize you've only just returned,
but when you're ready
I-I think we should
start your training again.
I'm ready. I'll see you after school.
Well, I-I-I understand
if, if you want a few days to...
I'm ready.
Buffy, that's enough.
Buffy!
- Safe to say you've stayed in shape.
- I'm ready.
Whatever they've got
coming next, I'm ready.
Yeah.
We have been put down, kinsmen.
We have lost our way.
We have lost the night.
But despair is for the living.
Where they are weak, we will be strong.
Where they weep, we rejoice.
Where they bleed...
we drink!
Within three days a new hope will arise.
We will put our faith in him.
He will show us the way.
Buffy!
- Buffy?
- Fine. I'm fine.
Good. It's good that you're fine.
- What were you thinking about?
- Nothing.
Oh, come on, you can tell us.
We're your bosom friends.
The friends of your bosom.
Xander.
I wasn't thinking anything. Really.
- What did you do last night?
- Slept. I had weird dreams.
Dreams are meaningful.
Tsh! Tell me about it.
The other night I dreamt that Xander...
Uh, I-it wasn't Xander.
I-in fact it wasn't me.
It was a friend's dream and...
- She doesn't remember it.
- I bet she doesn't.
Buffy!
Giles.
What is it? You look worried.
This... vampire activity.
I think I know what they're up to.
- Well, we'll deal with it.
- I hope it's that simple.
It is not to worry. Trust me.
Well, I don't know.
I mean, I've killed you once.
It shouldn't be
too difficult to do it again.
What?
Hello.
Mind if I come in?
Be my guest.
How are you?
Peachy.
So, is this a social call?
It is kinda late...
Or, well, it is for me, anyway.
What is it for you, lunch hour?
It's not a social call.
Ah, so let me guess.
That means grave danger.
Gosh, it's good to be home.
I'm sorry. I wish I had better news.
So, some of your cousins are in town
for a family barbecue,
and we're all on the menu.
The Anointed One.
He's been gathering forces
somewhere in town. I'm not sure why.
Guess I'll find out soon enough, huh?
- You don't sound too concerned.
- I can handle myself.
Besides,
I could use a little action anyway.
Don't underestimate the Anointed One
just because he looks like a child.
He has power over the rest of them.
They'll do anything for him.
Is that it? Is that everything?
You know, 'cause you woke me up
from a really good dream.
(# "It Doesn't Matter" by Alison Krauss)
Sorry.
I'll go.
I missed you.
I missed you...
# It doesn't matter what I want
# It doesn't matter what I need
# It doesn't matter... (if I cry)
- How are your new classes?
# Don't matter if I bleed
Good.
Is there the slightest chance
that if I asked you
what was wrong you would tell me?
# You've been on a road
Course not. It would
take the fun out of guessing.
# (Don't know where it goes)
or where it leads
Angel stopped by? Wow!
Was there... Well, I mean,
was it having to do with kissing?
Willow, grow up.
Not everything is about kissing.
Yeah, some stuff's about groping.
- It wasn't about groping?
- OK, hormones on parade here?
It was pure shoptalk.
Remember vampires,
pointy teeth, they walk by night?
Am I ringing a bell?
What did he say?
Oh, something's up.
Nothing I can't handle.
Hey, did you guys hear that Cibo Matto's
gonna be at the Bronze tonight?
- Cibo Matto! They're playing?
- No, they're gonna be clog-dancing.
Cibo Matto can clog-dance?
- Oh, sarcasm. Right.
- We should attend, no?
Oh, look. It's the Three Musketeers.
- Was that an insult?
- Kinda lacked punch.
The Three Musketeers were cool.
- I see your point.
- I'd've gone with "Stooges".
Well, I just meant that you guys
always hang out together.
So, did you guys
fight any demons this summer?
Uh, yes! Our own personal demons.
- Such as lust and thrift.
- I would have to go with "Stooges" also.
What are you guys talking about?
I'm talking about
big squiggly demons
that came from the ground?
Remember? Prom night?
With all the vampires.
Cordelia, your mouth is open.
Sound is coming from it.
This is never good.
No. It's, see, we can't mention that stuff
in front of other people,
Buffy being the Slayer and all.
You haven't been talking about
our little adventure all summer, have you?
Are you nuts?
You think I would tell people
that I spent the whole evening with you?
Besides, it was all so creepy.
That Master guy, all the screaming.
I don't even like to think about it.
So, your secret's safe with me.
Well, that works out great.
You won't tell anyone that I'm the Slayer,
and I won't tell anyone you're a moron.
- Now, that was a good insult.
- A little too good.
What's up with her?
(# "Spoon" by Cibo Matto)
# Though
# the water boils
I just think something's up is all.
Willow, you're paranoid.
Buffy's never acted like this before.
Ever since she got back,
she's... different.
- Buffy's always been different.
- She's never been mean.
Any sign of her?
She said she was coming.
- No. The band's cool though.
- Yeah, cool.
# We belong as two together...
You got something on your nose.
Don't just stand there. Dig!
We have to hurry.
The ground is consecrated. It burns.
Dig.
(# "Sugar Water" by Cibo Matto)
# The velocity of time
# Turns her voice into
# Sugar water
- Hi.
So, is there danger at the Bronze?
Should I beware?
I can't help thinkin' I've done
somethin' to make you angry.
And that bothers me more than I'd like.
I'm not angry.
I don't know where that comes from.
What are you afraid of?
Me? Us?
Could you contemplate
getting over yourself for a second?
There's no "us".
Look, Angel, I'm sorry
if I was supposed to
spend the summer mooning over you,
but I didn't.
I moved on.
To the living.
# I'm on a concrete way
The wind is blowing...
Hey.
- Hey.
What's wrong with Angel?
Beats me.
# It smells like sands
of the southern island
Let's dance.
O...K.
# When a black cat
# Crosses my path
# A woman in the moon
# Is singing to the earth
# I'm riding on a camel
# That has big eyes
# The buildings are changing
into coconut trees
# Little by little...
Xander?
Did I ever thank you...
for saving my life?
- No.
# When a black cat...
# crosses my path...
# A woman in the moon
is singing... (to the earth)
Don't you wish I would?
# A woman in the moon
# Is singing to the earth
Buffy.
You're really campaigning for
Bitch of the Year, aren't you?
As defending champion, you nervous?
I can hold my own.
You know, we've never really been close,
which is nice 'cause
I don't really like you that much, but...
you have, on occasion,
saved the world and stuff,
so I'm gonna... do you a favor.
- And this great favor is?
- I'm gonna give you some advice.
- Get over it.
- Excuse me?
Whatever's causing
the Joan Collins 'tude,
deal with it.
Embrace the pain,
spank your inner moppet,
whatever, but get over it.
'Cause pretty soon you're not even gonna
have the loser friends you've got now.
I think it's about time
you start minding your own business.
It's long past.
Nighty-night.
I'll just see if
Angel feels like dancing.
Ms... Ms Calendar?
Oh, God! Ms Calendar!
- She's possessed.
- Possessed?
That's the only explanation
that makes any sense.
You should have seen her last night.
That wasn't Buffy.
Are we overlooking the idea
that she may be very attracted to me?
She's possessed.
- Possessed by what?
- Uh, a possessing thing.
- That narrows it down.
- You're the expert.
Hey, maybe when
the Master killed her, some...
mystical bad-guy
transference thing happened.
That's what it was! I mean, why else
would she be acting as such a B-I-T-C-H?
Willow, we're all a little too old
to be spelling things out.
A bitca?
Yes...
I suggest that...
the explanation for her behavior
may be something more... more mundane.
She may simply have what
you Americans refer to as "issues".
Her experience with the Master
must have been extremely traumatic.
She was, for at least a few minutes,
technically dead.
I-I don't think she's dealt with that
on a conscious level.
She's convinced herself
that she's invulnerable...
for the very reason that she feels...
That's a very interesting point
about trout, you just brought up now.
Trout? Trout!
Yes, trout... is a fish.
- Good morning. Did you sleep well?
- Like a rock.
Master's gone.
- I'm sorry?
- The Master.
I went by his grave last night
and they have a vacancy.
Good God!
What would somebody want
with Master bones?
A trophy? A horrible conversation piece?
They're gonna bring him back.
They're gonna bring the Master
back to life, and I seem to recall
you telling me he was history.
Buffy, I-I've never heard of
a revivification ritual being successful.
But you've heard of them?!
Thanks for the warning.
- Well, Buffy, Giles did bury him in...
- Look, this is Slayer stuff, OK?
Could we have just a little less
from the civilians, please?
- OK, that's just about enough!
- I believe some of us have class.
And some of us have jobs.
Y-yes, well, I'll, uh, I'll see you all,
uh, in the library. Later.
- We'll continue this discussion.
- About trout.
There are some things I can just smell.
It's like a sixth sense.
No, actually, that would be
one of the five.
That Summers girl.
I smell trouble, I smell expulsion,
and just the faintest aroma of jail.
Before you throw away the key,
you might consider giving her
the benefit of the doubt.
She may surprise you.
You really have faith
in those kids, don't you?
Yes, I do.
Weird.
All right, I've got something.
It's... Latin, so bear with me.
To revive the vampire,
they need his bones - which they have -
and the blood - this is very unclear -
of the closest person...
- Someone connected to the vampire.
- That'd be me.
- Perhaps.
- We were close.
We killed each other.
It really promotes togetherness.
Well, is there anything on
when the ceremony might take... Whoa!
This is Cordelia's.
"Come to the Bronze before it opens,
or we make her a meal."
They're gonna cook her dinner?
- I'll pretend I didn't say that.
- What do we do?
I go to the Bronze and save the day.
- I don't like this.
- Nor I.
- Yeah? Well, you guys aren't going.
- What do you mean?
I can't do it any more. I can't look after
the three of you guys while I'm fighting.
- Well, what about the rest of the note?
- What rest of the note?
The part that says "PS, this is a trap"?
You'll be playing
straight into their hands.
- I can handle this.
- Stop saying that!
- God! What's wrong with you?
- Cordelia may be dead.
This is my fight.
You know, being stalked
isn't really a big turn-on for girls.
You need help.
Someone to watch your back.
- Sure you don't mean my neck?
- Why are you ridin' me?
Because I don't trust you.
You're a vampire.
Oh, I'm sorry, was that an offensive term?
Should I say "undead American"?
You have to trust someone.
You can't do this alone.
- I trust me.
- You're not as strong as you think.
Think you can take me?
What?
Oh, come on. I mean,
you must have thought about it.
What would happen
if it ever came down to a fight?
You vampire, me the Slayer.
I mean, you must have wondered.
Well, why don't we find out?
- I'm not gonna fight you.
- Come on.
Kick my ass.
Don't you have somewhere to be?
- I do.
- Well, you're wastin' time.
Just stay out of my way.
Happy to oblige.
That's not Cordelia.
Cordelia couldn't make it.
- Where is she?
- I'm not supposed to tell.
I don't like this.
- Don't like what?
- There's the bait.
Where's the hook?
You're right.
Why would they send just one?
I still think we should've gone with her.
Buffy's about to lose it. I think we should
be trying to reach minimum safe distance.
Xander, you know it's a trap!
The Latin is translated from
the Sumerian, and rather badly.
"Closest" to the Master, actually
translates as "nearest", physically.
The person or persons who were with him...
when he...
It is a trap.
It just isn't for her.
Watch her.
Don't kill her unless you have to.
Buffy, what's going on?
I'll be back.
Xander!
- What happened?
- Vampires.
The ones you could handle yourself.
- Where are the others?
- I don't know.
I don't know what your problem is,
what your issues are,...
but as of now I officially don't care.
If you'd worked with us for five seconds,
you could've stopped this.
W-we just have to think.
Where would they have taken them?
If they hurt Willow, I'll kill you.
Why did they take them and not you?
Giles said the ritual was, um...
They needed people who were close to
the Master, physically close when he...
The ones who were
with the Master when he died.
- Giles, Willow, Cordelia...
- Ms Calendar.
Odds are they've got a complete set by now.
We need to find out where.
How?
One more time: where are they?
You're too late. Your friends are dead.
Tell me where they are!
What are you gonna do? Kill me?
As a matter of fact...
Yes.
But, since I'm not gonna kill you
any time soon...
the question becomes
how are we gonna pass the time till then?
So, one more time.
Begin.
Behold, these poor mortals.
Witnesses to our Master's wretched demise.
They will breathe their last this night.
The blood that pours from their throats
will bring new life to the Old One.
Gather for his resurrection,
for the dawn of this new hell.
Buffy!
We gotta do something now!
- You two get the others out of here.
- We need you to distract the vampires.
- Right.
- What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna kill them all.
That oughta distract 'em.
For the Old One. For his pain.
- For the dark.
For the...
The sacrifices! Stop them!
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm OK.
- Where's Buffy?
- She's workin' out her issues.
Enough!
Your day is done, girl.
I'll grind you into a sticky paste!
And hear you beg
before I smash in your face.
So, are you gonna kill me,
or are we just making small talk?
- It's over.
- No, it's not.
It's OK.
What an ordeal.
And you know what the worst part is?
- What?
- It stays with you forever.
No matter what they tell you,
none of that
rust and blood and grime comes out.
I mean, you can dry-clean
till Judgment Day,
you are living with those stains.
Yeah that's the worst part of
being hung upside down
by a vampire
who wants to slit your throat.
- The stains.
- I hear ya.
- I don't think I can face them.
- Hm? Oh, of course you can.
I can't!
What am I supposed to say?
"Sorry I almost got your throat slit.
What's the homework?"
Punishing yourself like this is pointless.
It's entirely pointy. I was a moron.
I put my best friends in mortal danger
on the second day of school.
What are you going to do, crawl into
a dark cave for the rest of your life?
Would it have cable?
Buffy, you acted wrongly, I admit that.
But, believe me, that was hardly
the worst mistake you'll ever make.
Uh, that wasn't quite as comforting
as it was meant to be.
Well, points for effort.
I'll see ya.
Hey, Buffy.
Hey.
We saved you a seat.
There's a rumor going around that, uh...
Mr. Cox is the most boring teacher
in the entire world.
Like, I think he won a belt or something.
Like, yes.
Well, I hear he nods off a lot,
so that's a plus.
- So, we Bronzin' it tonight?
- Wednesday is kinda beat.
Well, we could grind our enemies
into talcum powder with a sledgehammer,
but, gosh, we did that last night.
Hey, I gotta plan.
How about miniature golf?
- There's no course here.
- OK, uh... miniature tennis?
A very tiny form of tennis
that we could invent...
I hate that girl.
Subtitles by ?
Extension & timing by UAR
...
www.tvsubtitles.net