The project. It escaped.
Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
The Initiative created this.
They can't stop it, but we will.
It's Faith. She's awake.
- Are you all right?
- Five by five.
Open the box. Surprise!
- You sure you're OK?
- Five by five.
We've been looking for this girl
since she broke out of hospital.
- What'll happen to her?
- We'll get her checked out.
- If she's stable, she goes to jail, pending trial.
- I just hope she gets some kind of help.
The first thing is to keep her
from hurting anybody else.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
You'll be safe now. We may have
a couple of questions in the morning.
- Of course.
- Thank you, both.
- I'm glad we finally got the kid.
- She's not a kid.
- I just mean that she's very strong.
- Yeah.
This Faith chick? Definitely dangerous.
She truly is.
Faith.
Why do you think she's like that?
Well, you know. She's a nutjob.
I don't understand what could drive
a person to that kind of behaviour.
How do you know she got drove?
- I mean, maybe she likes being that way.
- I'll never believe that.
I think she's horribly unhappy.
Well, could be things are lookin' up.
A little stint in the poky,
show her the error of her ways.
I'm sure there's some big old bertha waitin'
to shower her ripe little self with affection.
Buffy.
I'm sorry, Mom.
It's just
when I think about
how she might've hurt you, I just...
I can't stand it.
Sorry.
No, I'm just sore from the fight.
- I've missed you.
- Cos I haven't visited, right? I knew it.
I know how it is.
You've got so much in your life now.
- I'm a busy little beaver. College and all.
- Of course.
But maybe we could
spend some time together soon?
Some night when I'm not being
held hostage by a raving psychotic.
Count on it.
I'm gonna take a bath.
Why, yes, I would be Buffy. May I help you?
Buffy.
You can't do that. It's wrong.
You can't do that because it's naughty.
Because it's wrong.
You can't do that. It's wrong.
I'll kick your ass. I'm gonna kill you.
- Let me go!
- Get me a sedative, now!
- Hold her.
- I have to go home. She's with my mother!
- No!
- Just lie still.
- You don't understand.
- Keep holding her.
She's taken my body.
- I wonder where she is.
- Who, Faith?
Yeah.
I wish she would make a move.
She's making my stomach all acidy.
But you think Buffy can handle her?
I think so.
But that doesn't mean
Faith won't hurt someone else.
Well, you should be safe.
Nobody knows you're here.
I mean, they don't even know I exist, right?
I know all about them, but...
I mean, that's totally cool.
I mean, it's good. It's better.
Tara, it's not like I don't want
my friends to know you. It's just...
Well, Buffy's, like, my best friend
and she's really special.
And there's this whole bunch of us
and we sort of have this group thing
that revolves around the slaying.
And I really want you to meet them.
But I just kinda like having something
that's just, you know, mine.
And I usually don't use so many words
to say stuff that little,
but do you get it at all?
I do.
I should check in with Giles,
get a situation update.
I am, you know.
What?
Yours.
Not too bad.
Score.
..six, four, four, seven.
Expiration, 5/01.
Yeah.
10am's your earliest flight? I'll take it.
What are you doing?
Just getting my mail.
That was Giles on the other line.
He wanted you to meet your friends there.
Said he had news.
Yeah. I got some time to kill.
I'll go see the gang. All my friends.
- You don't mind if I steal this?
- Is that the Harlot?
- Yeah.
- That's the same one Faith picked.
Burn it.
She's coming to.
Man, I want this kid's constitution.
Faith.
Move it. I wanna get her in before she's 100°%.
By order of the Watcher's Council, you are
being taken into custody until such time...
Skip the speech.
Let's go.
Buffy. Good.
The Scooby gang's all here.
Willow, Xander and...
everybody.
- What's up?
- It's about Faith, not surprisingly.
Didn't Joyce tell you?
I already kicked that ass.
- I feel a high-five comin' on.
- Where is she?
On her way to the big house.
Cops took her off my hands an hour ago.
Poetic justice.
How's that?
Well, she did all those crimes
and now she's being arrested.
I guess that's just regularjustice.
It's cool, anyway.
Unless I'm mistaken,
Faith is no longer in police custody.
What are you talking about?
The Watcher's Council.
They sent a retrieval team to capture Faith.
Well, yeah, cos it worked
so well when Wesley tried it.
This is a special operations unit.
They handle the Council's trickierjobs:
- smuggling, interrogation, wet works.
- What's wet works?
- Scuba-type stuff.
- I thought it was murder.
Well, yeah. But there could be
underwater murder, with snorkels.
- So they're taking her to England?
- It'll be a long, long time before she returns.
I'm sorry. It's just...
- I'm happy. Faith is evil.
- Yeah. I hope they throw the book at her.
- I'm not sure there is a book for this.
- They could throw other things.
- I forgot how much you don't like Faith.
- After what she's done to you?
I wish those council guys would let me
have an hour alone in the room with her.
If I was larger and had grenades.
I bet I know what Faith would say to that.
- So you're saying everything's fine?
- Yes.
I'm glad you called us here because that
information can never be conveyed by phone.
- What's up?
- I just thought it was best to convene...
I'd never let her hurt you.
- I know.
- But if you're keen to go,
- please, by all means, go.
- We kinda have a romantic evening planned.
We were gonna light a bunch of candles
and have sex near them.
- We don't wanna cut into that seven minutes.
- Hey.
I believe that's my "hey". Hey!
Lighten up. We're outta danger.
- Everything's good.
- We still have Adam to take care of.
Yeah.
Adam.
- What's up with him?
- I wish we knew.
Well, don't worry about it.
I'll patrol tonight as long as it takes.
You guys have your fun.
I'll be out there doing my job.
You.
And you.
What? Are you keepin' tabs on me?
You gonna give me a hard time now?
- Do I usually give you a hard time?
- Very funny.
Well, you don't have to worry
about me drinking.
Unless you're here to protect innocent beers.
- You're a vampire.
- Was.
And as soon as I get this chip
out of my head, I'll be a vampire again.
But until then I'm just as helpless as
a kitten up a tree, so why don't you sod off?
OK.
Fine. Throw it in my face.
Spike's not a threat any more,
I'll turn my back. He can't hurt me.
Spike?
Spike.
William the Bloody with a chip in his head.
I kinda love this town.
God. You know why
I really hate you, Summers?
Cos I'm a stuck-up tight-ass
with no sense of fun?
Well, yeah. That covers a lot of it.
Cos I could do anything and instead I choose
to pout and feel the burden of slayerness?
I mean, I could be rich. I could be famous.
I could have anything.
Anyone.
Even you, Spike.
I could ride you at a gallop until
your legs buckled and your eyes rolled up.
I've got muscles
you've never even dreamed of.
I could squeeze you
until you popped like warm champagne
and you'd beg me
to hurt you just a little bit more.
And you know why I don't?
Because it's wrong.
I get this chip out, you and me
are gonna have a confrontation.
Count on it.
It's too crowded. We gotta hold out for
a few hours, pick up a straggler. Some drunk.
Can't be calling attention to...
- ourselves.
- I've been thinking.
About vampires.
- This is my place.
- Your place.
Yes. The sewers.
You hide from them, crawl about in their filth,
scavenging like rats.
What do you fear?
Kill this guy already.
You fear the cross, the sun, fire,
and, oh, yes...
- I believe decapitation is a problem as well.
- You can have the place.
- We don't have to stay here any more.
- You fear death.
Being immortal, you fear it more
than those to whom it comes naturally.
Vampires are a paradox.
OK. We're a paradox. That's cool.
Demon in a human body.
You walk in both worlds
and belong to neither.
I can relate.
Come. We have a lot to talk about.
Well, it's awake.
- Who are you?
- Council.
We're taking you back to the mother country.
Seems you've been a naughty girl.
Listen to me. You've made a mistake.
I am not Faith.
I'm Buffy Summers. Faith performed
some kind of spell. She switched our bodies.
Congratulations. No one's
ever tried that one on me before.
You have to find Faith.
Call Giles. Just get him here.
Giles doesn't work for the Council any more.
For that matter, neither does Buffy Summers.
And what you are, miss, is the package.
I deliver the package.
I don't much care what's inside.
Come on.
He may not care, but I do.
The Watcher's Council
used to mean something.
You perverted it.
You're trash. We should have
killed you while you were asleep.
I can't believe you've never been here.
The Bronze is the coolest place in Sunnydale.
Of course, there's not a lot of competition.
I think the vending machine
at Bergen's came in second.
- You used to come here a lot?
- We lived here.
Me, Xander,
Buffy?
Wow. I didn't think she'd be here.
Come on, I want you to meet her.
Back off.
You're nothing but a disappointment.
- Hey, Buffy.
- Willow and...
- Buffy, this is Tara.
- Hi.
So we've never met?
Cool. Just having a thing with names.
Tara was in my Wicca group.
So, what's up? Patrol a no-go?
Got tired. You know, the whole Faith thing.
I let off some steam.
Good for you.
You shouldn't work yourself too hard.
That's my philosophy.
Anyone want a soda?
Water.
So, you guys been hanging out a lot lately?
Yeah. She's... she's really cool.
So Willow's not driving stick any more.
Who would have thought?
I guess you never really know someone
until you've been inside their skin.
And Oz is out of the picture?
I've never seen two people so much in love.
She just couldn't get enough of old Oz.
She said he w-w-w...
W-w-what? You gonna get
that sentence out some time tonight?
Buffy, guy in the corner.
Yeah. Good call.
- What?
- Vampire.
It's wicked obvious.
So I should slay him.
- You want help?
- Nah, I got it.
You'll live.
- He was so strong.
- Yeah, well, he's gone now.
Thank you.
Yeah. It's cool.
Everything poofed?
All is well in the world.
Tara's not feeling well.
I'm gonna walk her home.
Yeah. You give her whatever she needs.
Are you gonna be in later,
or are you going over to Riley's?
This'll bloody keep you quiet.
How about this?
I'll be quiet and you can scream.
Now, you unchain me very slowly
and politely, or I kill this guy.
When we go on ajob we always put
our affairs in order first, in case of accident.
- Collins!
- Sorry, Smithy.
- She's starting to bother me.
- Getting her across the border'll be trouble.
If the Council can even get us passage.
I'll call 'em.
It's time for a contingency plan.
Hi, baby.
I'm sorry you're feeling all bleghy.
But we'll get together with Buffy another
time soon. I think you'll really like her.
She's not your friend.
I may have overestimated
the "you liking her" factor.
No, no. I mean, I don't...
I don't think she's her.
- You lost me.
- Well, a person's energy has a flow, a unity.
Buffy's was fragmented.
It grated like something forced in
where it doesn't belong.
Plus, she was kind of mean.
So you think Buffy's not herself?
Like she's been possessed or something?
- I'm not sure.
- You didn't sense a hyena energy, did you?
Because hyena possession
is just unpleasant.
- Do you have anything of hers?
- Of Buffy's?
This ring.
I think there's a way we can...
The passage to the Nether Realm.
There's a ritual. If you can find Buffy there,
you should be able to see.
If it'll help her.
What?
The Nether Realm exists
beyond the physical world.
Accessing it is kind of like
astral projection. It's very intense.
I'd have to be your anchor,
keep you on this plane.
- I trust you.
- It's not like anything that we've ever...
I trust you.
You miss me?
I did, actually. Everything's OK?
Everything's great.
- What about Faith?
- Faith has won a fabulous trip to England
and I got the consolation prize, which is you.
So I don't have to worry
about Faith showing up?
Though I have to admit,
I was kind of curious to meet her.
- Or I was until about 30 seconds ago.
- You wouldn't have liked Faith.
She's not proper and joyless,
like a girl should be.
She has a tendency
to give in to her animal instincts.
- Door's open.
- So?
So my fantasies don't include
a bunch of marines starin' at me.
Maybe they could learn something.
- You're hurt?
- Not that bad, actually.
The drugs the professor gave me really did
make me stronger. I'm healin' pretty quick.
Maybe we should take you for a test drive.
I wouldn't say no.
So, how do you want me?
- How do I...?
- Yeah. What d'you wanna do with this body?
What nasty little desire
have you been itching to try out?
Am I a bad girl?
D'you wanna hurt me?
What are we playin' at here?
I'm Buffy.
OK. Then I'll be Riley.
- Well, if you don't wanna play...
- Right. I don't wanna play.
The sightless sea
Ayala flows through the river in me
The inward eye, the sightless sea
I love you.
Get off.
No.
No. No. Get off.
No. Off me.
- Get off.
- Buffy?
No. No. Get...
Buffy, what?
What's wrong?
Who are you? What do you want from her?
Should I not have...?
This is meaningless.
You're shaking.
What happened?
Nothing.
I have a gift no man has,
no demon has ever had.
I know why I'm here.
I was created to kill.
To extinguish life wherever I find it.
And I have accepted that responsibility.
You have lived in fear and desperation
because you didn't have that gift,
but it's time to face your fear.
Tell us what to do.
You are here to be my first.
To let them know that I am coming.
- We're ready.
- Then ask yourself: what is it?
More than man. More than anything else.
What is the thing you fear?
Hope you left him alive.
- What?
- Boy should be on the mend.
- I don't see you lettin' him get much rest.
- Stay out of other people's lives.
We've got a mission.
When Riley could think for himself...
A mission? I've been fighting demons
since before you could shave.
Yeah, you're a killer.
I am not a killer.
I am the Slayer.
- You don't know the first thing about me.
- You really care what I think?
No.
I don't care.
God, I don't care.
They can't get us passage.
They've ordered the kill.
- Torch the place?
- Get the gas.
She could've killed me. She didn't.
Lucky you.
Weatherby!
Keys, keys.
Stop her, you ponce.
OK. I'm good at this.
Drive.
OK, there you go.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Giles!
- God!
Don't move.
OK, Giles, you have
to listen to me very carefully.
- I'm not Faith.
- Really?
- Really.
- Cos the resemblance is striking.
I know. Giles, you just have to...
Stop inching. You were inching.
- Look, I know what you're going to say and...
- I'm Buffy.
OK, I didn't know what you were
going to say, but you're still crazy.
Faith switched. I mean, she had some device.
She switched our bodies.
Giles, I swear.
It's me.
If you are Buffy,
you'll let me tie you up, without killing me,
until we find out
whether you're telling the truth.
Giles, Faith has taken my body and, for
all I know, she's taken it to Mexico by now.
I don't have time for bondage fun.
Ask me a question. Ask me anything.
- Who's President?
- We're checking for Buffy, not a concussion.
- Yes. All right.
- This is...
Giles, you turned into a demon
and I knew it was you.
Can't you just look in my eyes
and be all intuitive?
- How did I turn into a demon?
- Cos of Ethan Rayne.
And you have a girlfriend named Olivia.
And you haven't had ajob since we blew up
the school, which is valid, lifestyle-wise.
I mean, it's not like
you're a slacker type, but...
When I had psychic power I heard Mom
think you were like a stevedore during sex.
- Do you want me to continue?
- Actually, I beg you to stop.
- What's a stevedore?
- All right. I need you to explain everything.
And I will, after we get Faith.
- Giles!
- Will.
- Oh, my God.
- Willow, wait. You don't understand.
You're Buffy. You and Faith
switched bodies through a Katra spell.
She understands it better than I do.
- How did you...?
- Tara.
- Tara, this is Buffy. Only really, this time.
- Hi.
- Tara's a powerful witch.
- Not really.
No, really. She knew
right away you weren't you.
So we connected with the Nether Realms to
find out what happened and we conjured this.
- What is...?
- It's a Katra.
Or the home-conjured version.
It should switch you back,
if you can get ahold of Faith.
Thank God.
I'll get it.
- Hello.
- Do you know where Faith is?
Yes. Buffy's here with me. Actually, she's...
All right.
Xander. Apparently,
there's a report on the television.
..and barricaded themselves
in the church with 20 parishioners.
One of the few who escaped described
the three men as disfigured, almost inhuman.
So far one escapee
has since died of severe neck wounds.
There is no report on the condition
of the parishioners still inside,
but their assailants have vowed to kill all
of them if police attempt to storm the church.
It's hard to believe.
I've been avoiding this place
for so many years and it's nothing.
It's nice.
It's got the pretty windows, the pillars,
lots of folks to eat.
Where's the thing I was so afraid of?
You know, the Lord?
He was supposed to be here.
He gave us this address.
Well, we'll just have
to start killing off his people.
See if he shows up.
- What did he say?
- He said I should defer command to you.
Wait till the reserves arrive.
This is a military situation.
- What, they got bombs in there?
- Your men aren't prepared to deal with them.
Buffy.
- How many are in there?
- We think there's three.
- I can do three.
- Not alone.
Wait for the troops to get here.
They're mobilising.
- How did you respond so fast?
- I didn't. I was just late for church.
When the troops get here
send them in, but I'm going.
- I don't want you risking...
- Don't tell me what to do.
I'm Buffy. I have to do this.
Then I'm coming with.
I can't use you.
Someone comes out, you get 'em to safety,
unless they've got fangs.
I told the cops, they send anyone in,
I start the whole massacre thing.
Well, I'm not the cops.
I just come to pray.
Now's a good time to start.
You're not gonna kill these people.
- Why not?
- Because it's wrong.
You're the Slayer.
The one and only.
- You people, get outta here.
- We've gotta get inside.
- The police are handling this. Back off now.
- But we can't. You don't understand.
- You have to clear the area.
- Damn it, man! We have to get inside!
Our...
Our families are in there.
Our mothers, and tiny, tiny babies.
You think we're afraid of you?
We're not afraid of anything any more.
Then let all these people go,
and all three of you can take me on.
I got a better idea.
- Forgot your coat.
- Riley.
It's OK, miss. Get yourself out of harm's way.
Riley, it's me.
- Never mind. How many are in there?
- Well...
Who are you?
I have strength you couldn't dream of.
Adam has shown me the way
and there is nothing...
- You can't win this.
- Shut up. D'you think I'm afraid of you?
You're nothing.
Disgusting, murderous bitch.
You're disgusting.
She's gone.
Not a trace.
Giles said the council guys
have cleared out, too.
I don't understand.
How could she have...?
I mean, how's it possible?
Magic.
I knew there was something.
I should've picked up on it.
I should've just...
You slept with her.
I slept with you.
Man, would I like to get my hands on her.
Not in a sex way.
- I don't think she's coming back.
- I guess she's had her fun.
Yeah.
Fun.
Subtitles by Visiontext
ENGLISH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org