You keep refusing to tell me where the Key is.
We had to hide the Key.
Made it human and sent it to you.
- Dawn.
- What's wrong with Mom?
- Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
- I don't know.
Buffy's like nobody else. When I'm with her,
it's like half of me is just on fire,
going crazy if I'm not touching her.
But she doesn't love me.
I know you got a lot on your mind.
If you decide you wanna let me in
on any of it, you let me know.
We could go somewhere else.
Someplace more private.
Sandy, Sandy.
My heart belongs to another.
Besides, I don't go out with vampires.
Spike, I want you.
God, I love you so much.
Oh, God, no. Please, no.
Are you OK?
The "nothing" I've been dealing with
the last two weeks might not be nothing.
What is it?
I'm staying overnight at the hospital
for observation. I'm getting a CAT scan.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
What is a CAT scan exactly?
I don't know. It's some x-ray, I guess.
Where do they get the "CAT" scan from?
I mean, do they test it on cats or...
- Or does the machine sorta look like a cat?
- Dawn, I'm really...
"Your One-Stop Spot to Shop
for all your Occult Needs."
- Catchy.
- Think so?
Uh-huh, in a hard-to-read sort of way,
but I think it's great.
- I'm saying I think it's rude.
- I wouldn't call it rude.
Rude-ish. Rude-esque.
Whatever you wanna call it.
If you make a destroy-all-vampires date,
it's courtesy to wait for your co-destroyers.
Am I right, Giles?
I'm almost certain you're not
but, to be fair, I wasn't listening.
The new phone book's in with Mr Giles's ad.
Nice.
- Am I mentioned?
- Not as such.
We were supposed to hook up with Riley to
take on a nest o' vamps holed up in a tomb?
So we get there and guess what?
Tell him, Will.
- Tomb go boom.
- Yep.
Captain America blowed it up real good.
All by his Ione-wolf Ionesome.
- Rather reckless of him.
- I'd say very rather.
I should think you'd be pleased
to avoid the confrontation.
That's what I've been saying. I mean, I for one
didn't wanna start my day with a slaughter.
Which really just goes to show
how much I've grown.
Yes. In any event, since you're all here,
Tara and I could use your help
researching Buffy's mysterious woman.
Oh, yeah. This has been fruitful.
Trying to look up something
you never saw and don't know the name of.
Just do what I do.
Flip through the pages and look busy.
It'd be nice if we knew where she was,
where she's hiding out.
No doubt lurking around
some sewer or condemned church
or rat-infested warehouse.
You know, the usual haunts.
Most Beauteous
and Supremely Magnificent One,
this dark spell I hold in my worthless
and scabby hand is our gift to you,
Most Tingly and Wonderful Glorificus.
Please, call me Glory.
Get up.
Looking at you is hurting my neck.
Forgive me, Shiny Special One.
I beg of you to rip out my inadequate tongue.
Gimme.
I thought...
You should know,
Your Elaborate Marvellousness,
that this dark incantation has been lost for
aeons, and great dangers have been faced...
Does this pump make my ankle look bony?
No.
No, Your Terrifically Smooth One.
It is the epitome of ankles.
To touch such an ankle would be...
But I'm not touching. I'm backing away.
- Thank you.
- Dreg, is it?
Yes. Dreg. Your Creamy Coolness
has honoured me by speaking my name.
- Your voice is like a thousand songbirds...
- I never tire of hearing that.
Look, just so we're clear,
this spell's gonna work, right?
Nothing worse than a gift that doesn't work.
Then I'd have to get all mad and kill you.
It's this whole big thing.
It will work, Your Extremeness.
Provided you have the other items you need.
Don't worry.
I'll have them, all right.
I'll have it all.
Hello?
Buffy?
What are you doing in here?
What, me? I was...
- What are you doin' here?
- Looking for the girl who'll rip your arms off
- when she finds out you were in here.
- Oh, yeah? Well, me too.
Were you just smelling her sweater?
No.
Well, yeah, all right. I did.
It's a predator thing. Nothin' wrong with it.
Know your enemy's scent,
whet the appetite for a hunt.
That's the stuff. Slayer musk.
It's bitter and aggravating.
Out.
Watch it. Easy, you're bruisin' the leather.
Look. I know for a bleedin' fact
the Slayer wouldn't mind me bein' here.
Right. What's a little sweater-sniffing
between sworn enemies?
She in the habit of
buyin' her enemies drinks?
Cos she spent the better part of
last night with me, doin' just that.
Cos you guys are such tight pals.
That's good. Tell me another.
OK. Twice recently, she's had the
lover-Wiccas do a de-invite on the house.
Keep out specific vamps. Asked yourself why
she's never taken my name off the guest list?
- Because you're harmless.
- Yeah, right.
Takes one to know, I suppose.
At least I still got the attitude.
What you got? A piercing glance?
Face it, white bread.
Buffy's got a type, and you're not it.
She likes us dangerous, rough,
maybe bumpy in the forehead region.
Not that she doesn't like you. But sorry,
Charlie, you're just not dark enough.
- Am I dark enough for you now?
- Pull me back in. I'm startin' to sizzle.
You don't know anything about Buffy.
I know what she needs.
So you're at the hospital now,
givin' her what she needs?
- What are you talking about?
- Don't you know? Didn't she tell you?
- You tell me.
- Her mum's sickly.
Buffy took her to hospital
for a bit of prod 'n' probe.
Bite-sized one went too. You know,
it's funny her not calling you about that.
I've known since last night.
Blanket!
- Riley.
- Sorry.
I heard. I thought maybe you'd need...
I do. I'm glad.
I just... I didn't...
I mean, until we knew what it was...
I understand. How's she doing?
Well, she's just had a CAT scan.
I was about to go in and find out.
Will you sit with Dawn while I talk to Mom?
- She's in the waiting room.
- Yeah, you got it.
Hi.
- May I come in?
- Of course, baby. Come on in.
Where's Dawn?
With Riley. Watching TV in the waiting room.
Excuse me, I'm just gonna
check on the status of the OR.
The OR?
Dr Isaacs says I'm lucky
there's one available on such short notice.
Some people wait for days,
sometimes weeks.
Mom, what did they find?
A shadow. I've got a shadow.
Somewhere over there.
He showed it to me, but they have to do
a biopsy to find out exactly what it is.
The doctor says it's
too early to be concerned.
Right.
- No concern.
- Right. Just a shadow.
I wish we knew what we were dealing with.
It feels like we're going around in circles.
Our circles are going around in circles.
We've got dizzy circles here, Giles.
Weeping Buddha.
Shoulders your spiritual burden.
Makes a lovely paperweight, too.
- Maybe she's not in the books.
- What do you mean?
I mean, what if she's not a demon, sorceress
or spirit, or whatever these books cover?
What if she's something else altogether?
Thank you. Come again.
- Something new, you mean?
- Something old.
So old it predates the written word.
Giles, the Dagon Sphere.
You said that was created to repel...
That-Which-Cannot-Be-Named.
So, I'm thinking maybe she...
Predates language itself?
If it means I don't have to read any more,
whoo. And might I add a big "hoo".
If Tara's right, then we're blind.
There's no way we can determine her moves,
her habits, where she'll turn up next.
- I beg your...
- Uh-huh.
- I want these.
- Yes, of course.
- Did you find everything all right?
- No problemo.
That's...
your receipt. And...
thank you.
She could be anywhere.
But if she is as powerful as Buffy says,
I imagine it won't be long
before she makes herself known.
Everything went fine.
They're moving her into Recovery now.
Do we have the results yet?
- Let's sit down over here for a minute.
- No.
Excuse me. No, I don't mean to be rude.
It's just I've been sitting for hours.
I don't wanna sit. I just... Tell me, please.
Your mother has...
the term is "low-grade glioma".
It's a brain tumour.
The clinical name is oligodendroglioma.
It's in the left hemisphere of the cerebrum.
In your mother's case,
the tumour seems to have started...
I know this is very difficult and, because
of the nature of your mother's illness,
unfortunately things may
progress very quickly.
Things? What things?
Symptoms.
There's a fair variety that might present.
Loss of vision or appetite.
Lack of muscle control. Mood swings...
But what can we do?
Not much, until we determine
if the tumour's operable,
which we are working on.
Is there something that I...?
I mean, can I help?
There's some literature
you might want to look at.
If we aren't able to go in surgically,
there are a number of new treatments
that are very promising.
Your mother's prognosis is a lot better today
than it would have been only a year ago.
Even if the tumour's not operable,
she has a real chance.
What's "a real chance"?
Nearly one out of three patients
with this condition does just fine.
Now, let me ask. Does your mother's
insurance company require copies
of the MRI and pathology reports?
- I'm not sure.
- Well, just let me know as soon as possible.
And I could use some information regarding
your mom's lifestyle and home environment.
For instance, does she use a cellphone?
I think so, yeah.
She has one of those ear things.
OK. Is your house near any power lines,
chemical plants, waste-disposal facilities?
I don't know. Maybe.
Well, the more we know...
I'm sorry.
Excuse me, Doc, but they told me
you're needed in ICU.
- Excuse me, Miss Summers.
- It's OK.
You looked like you needed
a break. That guy's great,
but he doesn't have that bone
in his head that tells him when to back off.
You mean that they didn't need him?
I'm sure someone does somewhere.
They always do.
He really is a good doctor.
Your mom's in good hands.
Thank you.
- It's Ben, right?
- Right.
He was just telling me
that there's nothing I can do.
And I'm gonna tell you the same thing.
Give yourself a break.
Listen, your mom's gonna be unconscious
for at least another six, seven hours.
- A break?
- Well, I just mean go out, get some air.
Come back later on this evening.
Talk to the doc then if you want.
My unsolicited advice for the day.
Buffy.
- It's bad.
- I know.
I have to do something.
- Do something?
- Yeah, like magic. Like a healing spell.
Buffy, people get sick.
- I don't think magic can help.
- That attitude's not helping.
I have to try.
OK.
I need to talk to Giles. Will you do me
a favour and drop Dawn off at school?
Tell her I'll meet her at the magic shop
when she gets off.
Of course. Whatever you need me to do.
Buffy.
What do you want me
to tell Dawn about your mom?
Tell her we don't know anything yet.
- Your "heys" are startling the customers.
- And pretty much the state.
You sold someone a Khul's amulet
and a Sobekian bloodstone.
- Yes, I believe I did.
- Are you stupid or something?
Allow me to answer
that question with a firing.
She's kidding.
An, we talked about the employee-employer
vocabulary no-nos. That was number five.
You never sell these things
together, ever. Bad news.
- Don't you know about the Sobekites?
- I do.
It was an ancient Egyptian cult,
heavy into dark magic.
Wasn't the Khul's amulet
a transmogrification conduit?
- Damn straight.
- But I still see no reason for concern.
The Sobekian transmogrification
spells were lost thousands of years ago.
And the young woman to whom I sold them
would have to have had enormous power...
Young woman?
Dear Lord.
What?
You're melting.
Guess I'm not hungry.
Maybe I'm not making this any better.
No, I just...
This is better.
I had my tenth-birthday party here.
- Really?
- Mm-hm.
We'd just moved to Sunnydale.
Mom rented the carousel for
an entire hour forjust me and my friends.
Except I hadn't made any friends yet,
so it was just me and Mom and Buffy
riding it by ourselves, over and over again,
for the whole hour, just so Mom
felt like we'd gotten our money's worth.
She's...
She's not gonna get better, is she?
Absolutely she will.
Summers women are tough.
- I'm really glad you're here.
- Thanks.
Buffy's glad too.
Yeah?
She sure cries a lot less with you
than she did with Angel.
Angel made her cry a lot?
Everything with him
was all "Eee!", you know?
AII...?
You know, "My boyfriend's
a vampire" crazy-crazy.
Every day was like the end of the world.
She doesn't get all
worked up like that over you.
I think you've been really good for her.
So I figure there has to be
some kind of mystical cure.
I mean like a potion or a spell
or something. We have to look.
We can look. I mean, we will,
but I haven't seen anything.
The truth is, the mystical and
the medical aren't meant to mix, Buffy.
Sorry. The human mind is very delicate.
Too much could go wrong.
I've heard stories about
people trying healing spells.
If we did something
it could make things worse.
We've done just about enough making
things worse for one day, haven't we?
Why? What do you mean?
Nothing. Anya broke a bippity boppity boo.
A thing. Don't worry about it.
- I did not. I didn't break...
- Anya.
Buffy doesn't need to hear
about your clumsiness right now.
My clumsiness. I mean, that is so...
like me. Slippery butterfingers.
- What happened?
- Nothing to concern you...
Giles.
The demon woman was here,
the one who attacked you.
It's no biggie. She just got
an amulet and a bloodstone.
- That can create a monster.
- OK. Biggie.
My God. Are you guys OK?
I mean, no one got hurt, right?
No, thankfully. No violence to speak of.
OK, so that's good.
How did she get away
with this bad mojo stuff?
Giles sold it to her.
I didn't know it was her. I mean, how could I?
If it's any consolation,
I may have overcharged her.
Anya figured out
what the demon lady's up to.
Yeah, a few thousand years ago
there was this cult, the Temple of Sobek.
Sobek?
Reptile demon. Sobekites
were reptile worshippers.
Just once I would like to run into
a cult of bunny worshippers.
Great. Thank you very much
for those nightmares.
Sorry.
Anyway, their high priest Khul
had great mystic powers.
He forged an amulet
with a transmogrifying crystal.
Transmogrifying is changing a living thing
into a different kind of thing.
We've managed to decipher the markings
that were on the bloodstone that I sold...
that she left with. A cobra.
She's going to transmogrify a cobra.
OK, so she's making a monster.
What for? What does it do?
That's the part... We're working on it.
Well, you keep working on it. I'll go kill it.
- Buffy?
- What? I'm going.
- Buffy, this chick creamed you last time.
- I wasn't ready for her last time. I am now.
- But you...
- But what? Will, I can'tjust sit here.
I have to do something.
Chill, worm. I'm gonna make you a star.
Chant.
Sobek, grant the power that it
may mould this wretched creature,
that it may be reborn,
that it may serve.
Dark incantations. Always overwritten.
Why can't they just cut to the...
Fight?
No fair.
Attacking when I wasn't even looking.
No, this is no good.
I'm out of the moment and
you're not giving me anything I can use.
Dreg, I am not hearing chanting. Continue.
Yes, Glory.
Work with me here.
There. That feels more real, don't you think?
Even if I do have to carry your performance.
Scene.
Arise.
He is arisen.
'Bout damn time.
Spawn of Sobek.
The power is yours to see what is unseen,
to find what is shrouded in shadow.
Already, you know what I seek.
I have given you form. Now find for me
the Key. Seek it out in the holy places.
Yes, yes, yes.
Let your vision guide you to its hiding place,
then return to me and tell me where it lies.
Now would be good.
Fun, fun, fun.
"Aleister Crowley Sings"?
Sadly, no, I don't carry that,
but I do have some very nice whale sounds.
Excuse me for a moment.
- Where's Buffy?
- She left a while ago.
What? Where?
That creepy demon woman's
conjuring some kind of monster.
And you let Buffy go after her? Alone?
"Let" isn't really a factor when she sets
her mind to something. You know that.
She'll get herself killed. It's crazy.
Yeah, crazy. Going off alone, half-cocked,
instead of waiting for much-needed backup.
Charging in with a big ol'
hand grenade... Oh, wait.
- This is different.
- Yeah, it is.
Buffy needs something she can fight,
something she can solve.
I don't know what kind of action
you're looking for. Do you?
- I'm not trying to get...
- It's cool.
You OK?
Just a little crazed. I hear ya.
If she needs me...
- Magic Box, your one-stop spot to shop for...
- Giles, it's me.
Buffy. Are you all right?
No, I'm really not.
I couldn't stop her.
I couldn't even slow her down.
- Where are you?
- Sunnydale Memorial.
- Are you badly hurt? I'll come right over.
- No.
No, I just wanted to warn you that
that thing she conjured, it's loose.
It's a big snake thing. Not Mayor big,
but it's pretty lethal-Iooking.
- Do you know why she raised it?
- I don't know yet.
- I'll warn the others. We'll get weapons...
- Wait a second. What time is it?
- Half past four. Why?
- School's out.
- Dawn's on her way over to you. Giles...
- Understood.
- We'll keep her safe here until you arrive.
- Thanks.
- And Giles...
- Yes?
Dawn's kind of fragile right now, about Mom.
- She doesn't know how bad it is.
- We'll not say a word.
Well, my mom's gonna wake up soon, and
I should be there when the doctors tell her.
She's in good hands, Buffy.
There's really nothing else you can do.
OK. Bye.
Bye.
Is she awake yet?
Yeah. She's waiting for us.
Can we take her home now?
We'll see.
Go get your stuff.
- So, any monster-reptile sightings?
- None.
Tara and I did a mini-patrol earlier,
but the biggie snake was nowhere to be...
- Dawn, are you OK?
- Why was the big snake afraid of Dawn?
It knows.
- I've gotta stop it before it gets back to Glory.
- Glory?
He called her that. She'll know
Dawn's the Key if we don't...
We will.
Please, mistress.
Perturbed, Yet Ultimately
Merciful One. Please, no.
What is taking so long, Dreg? You told
me snakey-wakey would find my Key.
Why isn't he back with a beautiful message?
I grovel like a bug, Most Silky
and Effervescent Glorificus.
Glory, Your Most Fresh and Cleanness,
it's just a matter of time.
Everything takes time. What about my time?
Does anyone appreciate
that I'm on a schedule here?
Tick, tock, Dreg. Tick frickin' tock.
- Do you want me to stay?
- No, I'm fine.
I think I should talk to Dawn alone.
OK.
Do I have bad hair?
I don't look like Scary Mom, do I?
No. You look beautiful.
OK. Let's do this.
Stay close.
I will.
Buffy.
You OK? You look pretty beat up.
Minimal damage of the fighting kind.
It's all the other kind.
Come here.
It's OK. Just let it out.
I'm right here.
I can't.
Not now.
They need me.
If I start now, I won't be able to stop.
Buffy?
Visiontext Subtitles: Julie Clayton
ENGLISH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org