In every generation there is a Chosen One,
She alone will stand against the vampires,
the demons and the forces of darkness,
She is the Slayer,
- This is so unfair.
- I don't think it's that bad.
It's the übersuck.
Mom could've at least warned me.
Well, a lot of parents
are doing it this year.
It's part of this whole
cultural-exchange megillah.
- The exhibit. The dance.
- I have the best costume for the dance.
A complete stranger
in my house for two weeks.
I'm gonna be insane. A danger to myself
and others within three days, I swear!
I think the exchange-student
program's cool.
I do! It's a beautiful melding
of two cultures.
Have you ever done
an exchange program?
My dad tried to sell me to some
Armenians once. Does that count?
Ooh! There's mine.
Sven. Isn't he lunchable?
Mine's definitely the best.
- What are you looking at?
- Pictures of our exchange students. Look.
100% Swedish. 100% gorgeous.
100% staying at my house!
So how's yours? Visually, I mean.
I don't know. Guy-like?
By guy-like, we are talking
big, beefy guy-like girls, right?
I was just told "guy".
You didn't look at him first?
He could be dogly.
You live on the edge!
Hold on a sec.
So this person who's living with you
for two weeks is a man?
With man parts?
This is a terrible idea.
What about the beautiful melding
of two cultures?
There's no melding, OK?
He better keep his parts to himself.
What's he doing?
That's Rodney Munson.
He's God's gift to the bell curve.
What he lacks in smarts,
he makes up in lack-of-smarts.
You just don't like him 'cause of that time
he beat you up every day for five years.
Yeah. I'm irrational that way.
I better stop him
before he gets in trouble.
I got it. The non-violent approach
is probably better here.
I wasn't gonna use violence.
I don't always use violence.
Do I?
The important thing is...
you believe that.
What are you... Oh, Willow, hi.
That's probably not something
you're supposed to be doing.
- You could get in trouble.
- Oh, no.
And they might kick me out of school?
Are we still on for
our chem tutorial tomorrow?
Yeah. I think I got almost
all 14 natural elements memorized.
There are 103.
Welcome, students. We shall now
proceed into the Incan burial chamber.
The human sacrifice is about to begin.
Typical museum trick.
Promise human sacrifice.
Deliver old pots and pans.
500 years ago, the Incan people
chose a beautiful teenage girl...
to become their princess.
I hope this story ends with
"And she lived happily ever after."
No, I think it ends with "And she became
a scary, discolored, shriveled mummy."
The Incan people sacrificed their
princess to the mountain god, Sabancaya,
an offering buried alive
for eternity in this dark tomb.
They could've at least wrapped her in those
nice, white bandages - like in the movies.
The princess remained there,
protected only by a cursed seal...
placed there as a warning
to any who would wake her.
So, Buffy, when's exchange-o boy
making his appearance?
His name's Ampata.
He'll be at the bus station tomorrow night.
Oooh! The Sunnydale bus depot. Classy!
What a better way to introduce someone to
our country than with the stench of urine.
Now, if you'll follow me this way, please.
Cool!
Damn!
"Inca Mummy Girl"
- So can I go?
- I think not.
- How come?
- Because you are the Chosen One.
Just this once, I'd like
to be the Overlooked One.
Well, I'm afraid that is not...
You have responsibilities
that other girls do not.
Oh! I know this one!
"Slaying entails certain sacrifices,
blah, blah, bitty blah.
I'm so stuffy, give me a scone."
It's as if you know me.
Your secret identity is gonna be
difficult enough to maintain
while this exchange student
is living with you.
Not...
with her.
In the same house as her.
Am I the only one who's objective enough
to make that distinction?
So! I think going to the dance
like a normal person
would be the best way
to keep that secret.
Giles, come on! Budge.
No one likes an un-budger.
Fine!
- Go.
- Yay! I win.
I'll just go and introduce
my shoulder to a... an ice pack.
So I guess we're dance-bound. Cool.
I think I can get my mom's car,
so I'm Wheel Man.
- I thought you were taking Willow?
- Well, yeah, I'm gonna take Willow,
but I'm not gonna "take" Willow,
in the sense of "take me".
See, with you we're three and
everybody's safe. Without you, we're two.
Ah. And we enter dateville.
Romance, flowers.
Lips.
Oh, come on. In all the years
you've known Willow,
you've never thought about her lips?
Buffy, I love Willow
and she's my best friend...
which makes her not the kind of girl
who I think about her lips that much.
She's the kind of girl that...
I'm best friends with.
Hey, guys.
Willow! Hi! We were just
talking about happy things.
Like the three of us
going to the dance together, see?
Happy. Not happy.
No. Uh, oh, y-yes.
No. Rodney's missing.
Trouble with Mr. Munson again?
His parents say
he never came home last night.
You know, I don't think I remember seeing
Rodney on the bus back from the field trip.
I didn't either. I hope
he didn't get in trouble at the museum.
Hey, maybe he awakened the mummy.
Right, and it rose from its tomb.
And attacked him.
On the other hand, maybe Rodney
just stepped out for a smoke.
- For 21 hours?
- It's addictive, you know.
We'll deal with that
when we've ruled out evil curses.
One day I'm gonna live
in a town where evil curses
are just generally ruled out
without even saying.
There was the seal?
It was right here.
And it's broken.
- Does that mean the mummy's loose?
- No. Comfy as ever.
Look at this series of pictograms.
Look out!
- OK. I just saved us, right?
- Something did.
Well we'll fret about the details later.
Let's just get out of here
before he comes back.
Giles,
were the Incas... very advanced?
Yes. Yes, very.
Did they have orthodontists?
Rodney looked like he had been dead
for 500 years. How could that be?
Maybe we should ask that crazy man
with the big old knife.
I don't think he seemed overly chatty.
The way he bolted when he saw Rodney?
I'd say he was as freaked as we were.
My resources on the subject
are extremely limited.
I gather that this particular mummy
was from the Sabancaya region
of eastern Peru. It's very remote.
Now, if there's an answer,
- then it's-it's locked in...
- In the seal.
It could take me weeks to...
translate these pictograms.
- Well, we'll start tonight with...
- Ampata!
- I was gonna suggest hunting.
- No, I'm late. I told mom I'd pick him up.
Buffy, where are your priorities?
Tracking down a mummifying killer
or making time for some Latin lover
whose stock in trade
is the breakage of hearts?
Ampata's there alone.
I don't know how good his English is.
He's from South... South America.
Hey, you know, maybe
he could translate the seal.
Oh, yeah. Fall for the old
"let me translate
that ancient seal for you" come-on.
Do you know
how many times I've used that?
Ampata!
Hello?
- 40 minutes late. Welcome to America.
- What if he left already?
Ampata! Ampata Gutierrez?
So, do we have to speak Spanish
when we see him?
'Cause I don't know anything much
besides "Doritos" and "Chihuahua".
- Ampata!
- Here.
Hello.
I am Ampata.
Ay caramba! I can also say that.
Dining room. And this...
- is kitchen.
- It's very good.
Yeah, you got your stove, your fridge.
It's fully functional. We're very into it.
Would you like a drink?
Uh, let's see, we've got milk,
and, uh, oh, older milk...
- Juice?
- Please.
So, Ampata,
you're a girl.
Yes. For many years now.
And not a boy. 'Cause we thought a boy was
coming, and here you are in a... girl way.
It's just one of those crazy mix-ups, Will.
So, have you ever been
to America before?
Uh, I, I have toured.
Where did... you go?
I was taken to Atlanta, Boston, New York.
New York! That's exciting.
What was that like?
I did not see so much.
- Your English is very bueno,
- I listened much.
Well, that works out well
because I talk much.
Hey.
- Sorry about the teeniness of the room.
- My old one was much smaller.
What's it like back home?
Cramped and very dead.
Well, you'll feel right
at home in Sunnydale.
Oh, no!
But... But you have so much here.
How about friends?
They're...
It is just me.
I've been there. But, hey,
you'll meet lots of people tomorrow.
Thank you.
You must teach me
everything about your life.
I want to fit in, Buffy.
Just like you. A normal life.
One normal life... coming up.
Devon, I told you
I'd be at the dance tonight
but I am not one of your little groupies.
I won't be all doe-eyed,
looking up at you,
standing at the edge of the stage.
- Got it.
- So, I'll see you afterwards?
Sure. Where do you wanna meet?
I'll be standing at the edge of the stage.
With that guy?
Sven. Momento, Needa.
This whole student exchange thing
has been a horrible nightmare.
They don't even speak American.
So I'll see you later? Bye.
Sven! Come!
- Oz, man. What do you think?
- Of what?
Cordelia, man!
She's a wonderland tour.
- You gotta admit, the girl is hot.
- Yeah, she's a hot girl.
Let me guess. Not your type?
What does a girl have to do to impress you?
Well, it involves a feathered boa
and the theme of A Summer Place,
- I can't discuss it here.
- You're too picky, man.
Do you know how many girls you could have?
You're lead guitar, Oz. It's currency.
I'm not picky. You're just impressed
by any pretty girl that can walk and talk.
She doesn't have to talk.
I worked really hard on my costume.
It's pretty cool.
OK, but what about me? I gotta think.
Well, it's a celebration of cultures.
There are lots of dress-up alternatives.
And a corresponding equal number
of mocking alternatives, all aimed at me.
- Bavarians are cool.
- OK. No shirts with ruffles,
no hats with feathers
and definitely no lederhosen.
They... make my calves look fat.
Why are you suddenly so worried
about looking like an idiot?
That came out wrong.
Your first day at school. Nervous?
It is just more people
than I have seen in a long time.
Don't worry.
You'll have no problems making friends.
As a matter of fact,
I know someone who's dying to meet you.
How do you do?
I was, I was wondering
if you could, um, translate... this?
That was in no way awkward.
- Is something wrong?
- No. It is...
- Why are you asking me?
- Well, uh, uh...
It's, well, it's an artifact...
from, from, uh, your... region.
It's from the tomb
of an Incan mummy, actually.
We're trying to translate it...
as a project for our, um...
Our archaeology club.
- Very good.
- It is broken. Where are the other pieces?
That's all we found.
It's very old. Valuable.
- You should hide it.
- Is, is, uh, anything you recognize here?
This, this, um... this chap here
with the knife, for instance?
Well, I do not know exactly.
But... I think this represents...
I believe, the word is... bodyguard?
Bodyguard? Interesting.
Legend has it that he guards the mummy
against those who would disturb her.
Well. Yes, that's a very good
starting point for our, um... club.
Oh! And, uh, as club president,
I have, um, lots to do.
Lots of stuff. Dull stuff.
- Willow, maybe you could...
- Stay with Ampata for the day.
I'd love to.
Yes. That will be fun.
Right. I'll...
continue with the translation.
Buffy, you research this bodyguard thing.
And, Willow... Willow!
Boy, they really like each other.
And this...
- is called... a snack food.
- Snack food?
Yeah. It's a delicious,
spongy, golden cake
stuffed with a delightful,
creamy white substance of goodness.
And here's how you eat it.
Oh, but now I cannot try it.
That's why you bring two.
Here goes.
Good, huh?
The exciting part is that they have
no ingredients that a human can pronounce.
So it doesn't leave you with that heavy...
"food feeling" in your stomach.
- You are strange.
- Girls always tell me that...
right before they run away.
- I like it.
- I like you like it.
Please, don't learn from my English.
Ha! Or possible ha.
Do you think this matches?
- Hey!
- Oh.
Yes. I'm caring about mummies.
Ampata's only staying two weeks.
Yeah. And then Xander can find
someone else who's not me to obsess about.
At least with you
I knew he didn't have a shot.
Well, you know, I have a choice.
I can spend my life waiting for Xander
to go out with
every other girl in the world...
until he notices me, or...
I can just get on with my life.
Good for you.
Well, I didn't choose yet.
Good Lord. Good work.
- My work?
- Yes.
This is most illuminating.
It seems Rodney's killer
might be the mummy.
- Where does it say that?
- Well, here.
It implies that the mummy is capable
of feeding on the life force of a person,
effectively freeze-drying them,
you might say.
- Extraordinary.
- So, then we just have to stop the mummy.
Which leads to the question, how do we
(a) find and (b) stop the mummy?
Well, the answer to that
is somewhere still in here.
Or in the rest of the seal.
You stole the seal! Where is it?
It is you!
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
Why is this guy so into us?
I mean, what's he want?
He said "Give me the seal."
Apparently this is more popular
than we realized.
I just don't know what we...
we should do with it.
Destroy it.
If you do not, someone could die.
I'm afraid someone already has.
You mean, the man with the knife
killed someone?
Uh, no. Well... not exactly.
You are not telling me everything.
You're right, Ampata. And it's time we do.
We're not an archaeology club. We're in...
We're in the crime club,
which is kinda like the chess club,
only with crime and, uh... no chess.
Please understand me.
That seal nearly got us killed.
It must be destroyed!
Ampata!
Ampata, listen to me.
Nobody's gonna hurt you.
I won't let them.
Your investigation is dangerous.
I do not want that. Just normal life!
Is she OK?
Wigged. I'm trying to convince her
that our lives aren't just
danger and peril around here.
- You should take her to the dance.
- That's a good idea! We'll all go!
- No, I mean just you.
- But you were psyched.
- And your costume.
- I'll see you there.
You know what, Willow?
You're my best friend.
I know.
I don't get it. Why would
the bodyguard have such a jones
for a broken piece of rock?
Well, um... Perhaps...
he needs to put it together
with the other pieces.
If he has them.
I mean, we didn't find them.
If he didn't,
then they'd still be at the museum.
So maybe we should go there and find them.
And odds are he'll show up too, right?
And hopefully, we'll be ready.
Hey! Look at us!
We came up with a plan. A good plan.
Right. We'll meet there tonight
after it closes.
No! Bad plan.
I have other plans. Dance plans.
Cancel plans.
OK. I have something to tell you.
And it's kind of a secret
and it's a little bit scary.
I like you... a lot.
And I want you to go...
with me to the dance.
Why was that so scary?
Well, 'cause you never know
if a girl's gonna say yes...
or if... she's gonna laugh in your face
and pull out your still beating heart
and... crush it into the ground
with her heel.
Then you are very courageous.
- Can I tell you a secret?
- Yeah.
- I like you, too.
- Really?
- Really.
- That's great! Really?
- That's great!
You're not a praying mantis, are you?
Sorry. Someone else.
- I will return to you.
- Where are you going?
Where you cannot follow.
I'll... wait outside.
I beg you...
- do not kill me.
- You are already dead.
For 500 years.
But it was not fair. I was innocent.
The people you kill now...
so that you may live...
They are innocent.
Please.
- I am in love.
- You are the Chosen One.
You must die. You have no choice.
Yes, I do.
I have thought. The dance?
I will go with you.
Gladly.
Buffy, I do not have any lipstick.
Oh, you can borrow one of mine.
There should be some on the desk.
- What is that?
- The station sent the rest of your stuff.
Of course. I forgot all about it.
- I will unpack it later.
- No worries. I can do it.
But... you must get ready for the dance.
- I'm not going.
- Why not?
I have work to do. Crime club work.
It's nothing for you to worry about.
Oh, I am not worried, thanks to Xander.
- He seems very happy around you.
- I am happy, too.
Mmm... This one?
Oh, no. That clashes. There should be
a gold one in there somewhere.
Thank you. You're always thinking
of others before yourself.
You remind me of someone from
very long ago. The Inca princess.
Cool. A princess.
They told her that she was the only one.
That only she could defend her people
from the nether world.
Out of all the girls in her generation,
she was the only one...
- Chosen.
- You know the story?
It's fairly familiar.
She was 16, like us. She was offered
as a sacrifice and went to her death.
Who knows what she had to give up
to fulfill her duty to others?
What chance at love?
Who knows?
I'll just unpack
the rest of your stuff for you.
No, really. Let me.
That's Xander and Willow. I'll get it.
- I've come for the dance.
- And what culture are you?
I'm from the country of Leone.
It's in Italy, pretending to be Montana.
Where are you from?
The country of white trash?
Mm. New line-up.
You and Willow are taking Ampata.
Giles and I are hunting mummies.
- Where's you and Willow?
- She's not coming... with us.
Oh! On a date.
Romance. Lips.
- Hello, Xander.
- Ho he th-thee ai uh...
I can translate
American salivating boy-talk.
He says you're beautiful.
- Hav su...
- You're welcome.
Ampata, don't you look wonderful!
Oh, I wish you could talk my daughter
into going with you.
I tried, but she is very stubborn.
Well, I'm glad someone else sees that.
Well, good night, then.
- Be careful.
- I will.
Hey!
You look good.
Look at that.
Two days in America and Ampata
already seems like she belongs here.
She's really fitting in.
Yeah.
How about that.
(# "Shadows" by Four Star Mary)
# She's in ecstasy
# Her hollowed sky,
# Pours down heavenly
# Fakes desire,
# I've been living here in the red,
Oh! Near faux pas.
I almost wore the same thing.
# We've been bored before
- Hey. Where's Sven?
- Ohh, I keep trying to ditch him.
He's like one of those dogs that
you leave at the Grand Canyon on vacation.
It follows you back across four states.
See? My own, speechless, human boomerang.
He's kinda cute. Maybe it's nice
skipping all that small talk.
Small talk.
How about simple instructions?
Get punchy.
You. Fruit drinky.
He can follow me.
# I've been feeling I'm dead again,
# And we've been bored before
# We'll be bored again
# We've been bored before and again,
Maybe I should have worn
something sexy.
Wow. You guys look great.
- I love your costume. It's very authentic.
- Thanks.
Yeah. You look, um... snug.
That's what I was going for.
- Where's Buffy?
# She's in ecstasy
# Her hollowed sky...
Thank heavens you're home.
Yep. Not at the dance. Not with my friends.
Not with a life. What are you doing here?
I thought we were gonna meet
at the museum to find the bodyguard.
No. He's already been found...
in the school rest room, mummified.
OK, I don't get it. Why would the mummy
kill her own bodyguard?
Well, I've cross-referenced
and I've looked at the pictograms anew.
He was a guard, all right.
But it was his job to ensure
that the mummy didn't
awaken and escape.
So Ampata translated it wrong?
Perhaps.
Hold on a sec. She was wiggy
about the seal from minute one.
Yes, I suppose she was.
- Her trunks!
- I beg your pardon?
It's definitely all boys' clothes.
Why would a girl pack these?
How about this one?
What kind of girl travels
with a mummified corpse...
and doesn't even pack lipstick?
(# "Fate" by Four Star Mary)
# Time's healing, I'm ahead,
# Find a reason once again,
# Take a moment out of time,
# I'll be standing back behind,
Do you, um...
Would you like to, uh...
- You know.
- I'd love to dance.
# Taken in, so out of time
Hey.
That girl. Who is she?
She's an exchange student.
I think she's from South America.
No, not her. The Eskimo.
# Time is healing, I'm ahead...
- Come on! Can't you put your foot down?
- It is down.
One of these days you're gonna
have to get a grown-up car.
# so out of time,
# All it takes is living,
# I wanna fly,
# I've never known fate,
# I've never known your name,
# I've never known fate...
OK. At least I can rule out
something I said.
I should have guessed.
Remember Ampata wanted us to hide the seal?
Then she wanted us to destroy it because...
Oh, wait!
Uh... waiting.
Well, we already know that the seal
was used to contain the mummy.
If breaking it freed her...
Reassembling it will trap her.
I'll go to the museum.
I'll drop you off.
I'll try and piece together
the fragments there.
OK. I'll still get Xander... before
he gets smoochy with mummy dearest.
Have you seen Ampata?
- What was that?
- I shrugged.
Next time you should
probably say "shrug".
Sigh.
I thought this exchange student thing
would be a great deal.
But look what I got stuck with!
"Momento", "Punchy fruity drinky".
Is Cordelia even from this country?
Your hands feel kinda... rough.
Aren't you with Xander?
Does it look like I'm with Xander?
Ampata!
That's my cue to leave.
There you are. Why'd you run away?
Because... I do not deserve you.
What... You think that
you don't deserve me?
Man, I love you!
Are those tears of joy?
Pain? Revulsion?
I am very happy.
And very sad.
Then talk to me. Let me know what's wrong.
I can't.
Hey, I know why you can't tell me.
It's a secret, right?
And if you told me, you'd have to kill me.
Oh! That was a... bad joke.
And the delivery was off, too. I'm sorry.
I, uh...
I'm sorry.
No! I can't.
Xander, I'm so sorry.
"Inca cosmology unites
the bird head with its paler twin."
Oh, here. Its paler twin.
The seal.
- Where's Xander?
- He's looking for Ampata.
We need to find him.
Ampata's the mummy.
Oh... Good... Xander!
- Where'd they go?
- Backstage, I think.
Hey, I...
Who is that girl?
Are you OK?
I think so.
Boy, that was some kiss.
- Where's Ampata?
- She said something about the seal.
- The seal. Giles! Come on.
- What's going on?
- He doesn't know?
- We'll tell him on the way.
There. That's it.
Just one more piece.
I'll say one thing for you Incan mummies.
You don't kiss and tell.
Looks like you've been
keeping secrets from me,
- You're not a normal girl.
- And you are?
This won't hurt.
Let her go!
If you're gonna kiss anybody,
it should be me.
Xander, we can be together.
Just... Just let me have this one.
- That's never gonna happen.
- I must do it.
I must do it now,
or it is the end for me and for us.
No!
You want life...
you're gonna have to take mine.
Can you do that?
Yes.
I'm really the fun-talking guy today, huh?
- Sorry.
- That's OK. You don't have to talk.
I just, present company excluded,
I have the worst taste in women
of anyone in the world. Ever.
Ampata wasn't evil.
At least not to begin with.
And I do think she cared about you.
Yeah, but I think that whole
sucking the life out of people thing
would have been
a strain on the relationship.
She was gypped.
She was just a girl and she had
her life taken away from her.
I remember how I felt when I heard
the prophecy that I was gonna die.
I wasn't exactly obsessed
with doing the right thing.
Yeah, but you did.
You gave up your life.
I had you to bring me back.
Subtitles extended and timed by: UAR
...
www.tvsubtitles.net