Previously on Buffy the Vampire Slayer:
You're never here. You can't
even stand to be around me.
- That's not true.
- You didn't wanna come back.
I know that. You wanna go away again.
- I'm in.
- Ante up.
You're gonna play cards?
I have been called,
and vengeance shall I wreak.
- Hello.
- Halfrek?
Anyanka?
Hey! How are you?
You two know each other?
Halfrek, I didn't summon you to kill Xander,
I called to invite you to our wedding.
Tara. What are you doing here?
It's OK for you to be here if you
have things that you have to be here for.
I'm doing better. No spells for 32 days.
Buffy, I promise,
there's nothing wrong with you.
There has to be. Why do I feel like this?
Why do I let Spike do those things to me?
- Don't tell anyone, please.
- I won't.
- I'm sorry.
- It's OK.
No, we're gonna sit down
and have a real dinner someday.
I hate running out in the middle.
It's just there's this thing out there.
- Definitely non-vampire.
- I understand.
Well, maybe when you get back
we can set up for your party tomorrow.
Yeah. This'll take a while, though.
I wouldn't wait up.
Besides, Willow's on birthday patrol,
- so there's nothing left for us to do.
- Right.
OK, so finish dinner, homework,
and don't stay up too late, all right?
- OK.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Run off, huh? Afraid to face a true warrior?
Ooh, shiny.
Do you think we should set up
candles for Buffy's party?
Not if they're that horrible slug kind
you keep trying to unload.
I don't know why people
get so turned off by slug.
Honey, slugs get turned off by slug.
- Actually, I wanted to talk to you about that.
- Slugs?
No, the party. Or, Tara at the party.
- Oh.
- It's just Buffy really wants her there.
It seems important to her,
so I told her I'd ask you.
Oh... Yeah, of course, she should
totally be there. It'll be great.
Hey.
Hey, Dawnie. Buffy out patrolling already?
So, anything new
about Warren and the nerd herd?
- No, just a big monster hunt.
- A nerd goes into hiding, he really hides.
Does anybody want to come
to the mall for birthday presents?
I would, but I've got my group. You know,
the whole Spellcasters Anonymous thing?
We're still looking for a better name.
Oh. Well, yeah, no, that's good.
You should do that.
- So what about you guys?
- Stuck in doing-the-books-ville.
I'd love to go, but I gotta finish
this new shift schedule...
for the crew by tomorrow morning.
Sorry, it just looks like
one of those nights. You know?
- Yeah.
- You OK going on your own?
Yeah. Somehow I'll manage to pull it off.
Buffy?
If we can think of things Jim lost during
his years in Shanghai, and things he gained.
- Excuse me, Miss.
- Who wants to...?
Dawn?
They need you in the guidance office.
I'm so sorry, I didn't mean to scare you.
Just a follow-up after your...
your loss. Since I'm new, I thought it would
give us a chance to get to know each other.
Great.
I've been looking through your file,
and your grades have slipped a little.
I have really hard classes this quarter.
Still, teachers say that
you've seemed a little distracted lately.
I'm not. I'm fine.
OK. It's just, I know it must seem weird,
talking to a stranger about stuff, but...
I want you to know that if something's
going on, something's up, my job -
the most important part of my job -
is looking out for you.
I'm really OK.
I know there's been a lot of loss.
Yeah. Kinda.
I mean, yes. People keep...
People have a tendency to go away.
And I miss them. And sometimes...
I wish I could just make them stop.
Going away.
But, seriously, it's no big deal. I'm fine.
- We're feeding an army!
- No, they couldn't make it.
So, who's coming?
You invite anyone else?
Just you guys, Willow, Tara. The gang.
Oh, and Sophie from work.
What? Like I'm a loser who can't make
friends outside her tight little circle?
No. I'm friendly.
We bonded instantly.
Peas in a pod. Bonded peas.
Really?
What's Sophie's last name?
- OK, shut up.
- We're all over the new-friend thing.
What new-friend thing?
Well, we invited someone for you.
A guy.
- For Buffy? Really?
- Ah, don't worry, it's not a setup.
Right. No.
Just an attractive single man, with whom
we hope you find much in common.
If you happen to form a romantic
relationship leading to babies,
and many double dates with us
so we have someone else to talk to, yay!
I assume that this was an act of kindness?
That'll help with the not throttling.
Hey, I'm gonna get this stuff out there.
People should be here soon.
Hey! You made it!
Of course, sweetie.
- How're you doing?
- Oh, you know.
Better. Mostly.
Sometimes.
So, is Spike coming?
No. He may be a chip-head, but
he still doesn't play too well with others.
Besides, I'm definitely not ready to...
- Come out.
- Yeah.
I'm all stay-inny.
- How are you doing?
- The word "gulp" comes to mind.
Just remember, we're all here to...
I have to... with the thing that I...
Coming!
- Hey.
Hey.
- How are you?
- Fine, thanks.
I'm fine. How are you?
I'm great! I mean, fine.
I'm Finey McFine fine.
- You look...
- Thanks.
I mean, great.
Thanks.
- You do too. Is that a new...?
- Oh, yeah.
It's nice.
Thanks.
- I'm gonna get something to drink.
- Great. You should.
You really don't wanna get thirsty.
- Hey, how did it...?
- Yes, please.
- Spike.
- Yeah. Willow mentioned the shindig.
Figured we were all part of the team.
Thought I'd swing by.
- Wait. What kind of team is this?
- Hi. We met once before.
Yes. Yes, we did.
You know: more, merrier, that old thing.
- Hi, I'm Clement. Clem.
- Tara.
- Buffy, Richard.
- Hey.
He was wondering
where the best place was to park.
- Oh, that's easy, just...
- Buffy will show ya.
OK. Uh, I'll be right back.
- The guy with the...
- Skin condition.
He doesn't like to talk about it.
Stupid git!
I don't know. He seemed cute.
Was he cute? I mean,
I'm not a very good judge, but...
I think he seemed cute.
I think he seemed cute, yeah.
If we get Buffy, can she start opening the
presents? It's been enough time, hasn't it?
- Not yet, sweetie.
- I think Buffy's busy right now.
Buffy's making a new friend.
A grown-up friend.
What, you mean the guy
you invited to set her up with?
Nothing.
It's not like I don't understand why
you invited him. I was there, remember?
I can hear you when I'm in the room,
you know? I do understand these things.
Yes, you do!
- You know I'm in high school, right?
- Yes, you are.
- You wanna slip away for a minute, love?
- What?
- I'll let you blow out my candles.
- Here? Now? I don't think so.
You worried about Richard? You don't
wanna make your new boyfriend jealous?
Shut up. He's sweet.
"Shut up, he's sweet. "
Maybe he's not the jealous one.
You think he'll take you out
on his ten-speed, pet?
Maybe he'll let you ride
in that little basket up front.
Jealous, my ass.
It's a battery-operated back massager.
It's portable so you can take it on patrol.
Wow.
It's, like, instant gratification
for all your little acheys.
Great! Thanks! What's next?
Here, do mine.
Dawn...
- Do you like it?
- It's gorgeous.
I was so nervous.
I was afraid you wouldn't like it.
It still has the security tag on it.
Huh. That's so weird.
I can't believe they didn't take that off.
Happy birthday, Buffy!
Oh, my God!
- Did you guys make that?
- Yes.
Xander did the building.
I offered helpful suggestions
while observing from a safe distance.
Holds basic weapons,
plus a few non-basic ones too.
Plus, there's a handsome CD holder.
It's something no one else would have.
A Xander Harris original.
I love it. Thank you, guys!
Buffy?
Oh! Sophie! Welcome!
We're somewhere between presents and cake.
- There is gonna be cake eventually, right?
- Hey.
My mom told me to say thank you
right away, cos...
otherwise I usually forget. So thank you.
And also I can't have any chocolate,
or peanuts or egg yolks.
- Is this the friend you brought from work?
- Yes.
- And sometimes dairy.
- No problem.
Our friend is better.
We can do official introductions
now everyone's officially here.
Dawn, do you mind getting the door?
Sophie, this is Anya,
and Willow...
Wish granted.
Hey. Great party.
- Everyone's having fun.
- I hope so.
I mean, look what time it is
and no one's even thinking about leaving.
I can't tear myself away.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Can I get you a drink?
- I'm good, thank you.
- OK.
I think I'll just head back in.
- Well, I'll look for you.
- OK.
Ooh, Buffy.
"Can I get you a soda pop?
I think I'm in love. "
Stop it. Someone's gonna see.
Mm-hm.
I had a muscle cramp.
Buffy was helping.
A muscle cramp?
In your pants?
What? It's a thing.
Right.
- No, you go.
- OK!
It's just a beer run. I'll go.
Oh, I can't drink beer, cos,
you know, barley.
- But I'll go with you to get some.
- Perfect.
Here we go. The beer-getting.
- This sucks. I'm out.
- No way. I think you're doing fine.
- You wanna try poker?
- Still say it's weird without the kittens.
No kittens.
He's quirky.
Look, we've already been playing for three
hours. It's two-something in the morning.
- You can't bail now.
- Yeah, come on, Buffy, stay.
I wanna bankrupt somebody.
Oh! We should totally have a slumber party.
Oh, I don't know...
I guess, as long as
everyone's staying up anyway.
Must be some late-night activities
to keep us busy.
How's that cramp, Spike?
Still bothering you?
What? Oh. Yeah.
Maybe you wanna put some ice on it.
Hey, Xander, we gotta be
at work in a few minutes.
OK.
I can't be late today.
You should go. Let's find your coat
and get you on your merry way.
Spike.
- I don't know why I'm not leaving.
- Me either.
Besides, Richard, you can't skip breakfast.
Growing boy like you.
Me, I used to love breakfast.
In the old days, I probably
would have eaten by now.
With that new diet of yours, you wanna be
careful what you put in your mouth, Spikey.
Yeah? I don't know.
Tummy's making all kinds of gurglies.
Maybe I ought to just feed on whatever's
around, even if it doesn't go down well.
- You, uh, work out?
- Okey-dokey.
'Scuse us.
Hey, Passive-Aggressive Guy,
you wanna take it down a notch or two?
What, poor dainty Richard can't take a joke?
We do not joke about
eating people in this house!
What are you gonna do, beat me up again?
I should have thrown you out. I was insane
to think you could hang out with my friends.
And I was insane to think...
No, wait. You were right. You're insane.
Oh, hi.
Hey.
Breakfast.
Didn't really plan for a sleepover.
No, me neither.
It's weird. I have class.
I know I should go...
I know, it's like I wanna leave,
but I don't want to.
Exactly.
- I think it's time for you to go.
- Yeah, well, can't. Daylight.
- OK. I'll go.
- I'll get the door.
- Fine!
- I'm actually trying to move right now.
- Me too.
Well, this can't be good.
- Something's keeping us in this house.
- Or someone.
Has everyone tried to get out?
What if we just, like, as a group,
got up and threw ourselves at the door?
All right. Count of three.
One, two,
three!
Here we go!
- Hence the problem.
- I really need to go.
- I mean, I have a job to get to.
- I have to open the Magic Box.
I have a shift at the Double Meat...
Actually, I'm OK here.
Yeah, I'm fine.
Willow and Tara have class,
I got to be at the site...
I know. We all have places
that we'd rather be.
Things we'd rather be doing.
I think the first priority
has to be to find a way out.
Sure. Of course you all wanna leave.
Cos being stuck in here with me
would really suck, right?
No, Dawnie. It's just we have
more important things to do.
Yeah, I know. Important.
Whatever that means, right?
- Dawn?
- What?
- Did you do something?
- Me?
- Do you know something? You can tell us.
- What would I know?
We're not accusing you of anything,
it's just...
you were kind of
taking it personal down there.
Oh. OK. So you've all just decided
that somehow I'm responsible.
Great. Here's me basking in the love.
No, it's just, you're upset cos we all
wanna leave. And now we can't leave.
Only thing missing is a cornfield.
There isn't a cornfield, is there?
Dawn, it's OK.
You know, we're not gonna be mad.
- Yeah, only I didn't do anything!
- You sure?
- Want me to ask my other self?
- We're just figuring out what's going on.
Figure it out yourself.
I'm done being talked to like a kid.
Well, sometimes we do something
that seems like a good idea at the time.
Like, say, invoke the power of a musical
amulet. And it turns out, not so much.
God! I didn't do anything!
I wish I had. I'm glad you're trapped.
How else can I get anybody
to spend any time with me?
Dawn, if you want us
to spend time with you...
I don't. Get out.
Get out, get out, get out!
- I think she's possessed.
- She's a teenager.
The phones are all out.
We're totally cut off.
- She's just so angry.
- It happens. We all went through it.
I know. I just can't figure out
why she didn't come to me.
Well, you have been a little busy lately.
I don't wanna stop the touchy-feelies, but
maybe the encounter group can meet later.
Say when we're not trapped in a house.
Even if Dawn does know something,
she's obviously not gonna help us.
- We need another way.
- I think magic's gonna be our best bet.
Something general, you know?
Cast a wide net.
But... Willow.
No, I'll do it. It's just...
Obviously I didn't bring any supplies.
Well, we don't have any in the house.
We got rid of everything.
Actually, not everything.
I might have
kept one or two things. Sort of.
Just in case.
That's great!
In a very bad way.
Just bring me what you have.
But then I'm doing this alone.
You need to stay away from it.
- So we're supposed to just wait?
- It won't take long.
All right, somebody wanna
tell me what's going on here?
I mean, we're trapped in a house by,
what, some unseen force or something.
Who knows what she's doing in there.
And I have to tell you,
I don't think that's a skin condition.
Release.
Try the door!
No. Can't.
- What the bloody hell was that?
- That's the demon I killed two nights ago.
Demon you thought you killed.
- It looks pretty bad.
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
Let's get him upstairs.
We need to get him to a doctor soon.
Hey, it's gonna be OK. Just trust me,
I promise we'll be out of here soon.
Oh, God.
OK, so maybe "soon"
was a bit of an overstatement.
So, you ever think about not celebrating
your birthday? Just to try it, I mean.
I'm gonna go check upstairs.
Keep an eye on things down here?
You stay here, OK?
What's that noise?
It's in the walls, isn't it?
Sorry.
Why is it so hot in here?
You're just a little freaked out,
that's all. It'll pass.
He's gonna die.
He's gonna die, and we're gonna watch.
An...
And we're just sitting here. Why are we just
sitting? Why aren't we doing something?
We are. We will. We've been through worse.
Not like this. Not trapped like animals.
Seriously, did someone turn on the heat?
I can't breathe, I just...
I just can't breathe...
An, stop.
Stop, An, stop. Stop. An!
Listen to me. You're just freaking out, OK?
It's normal. You're just scared.
We all are. We'll come up with a plan,
and we'll get through it, all right?
We'll do something.
What?
I don't know. Let me get you some water,
OK? It'll cool you down.
I'll be back in a second, OK?
Stay here, don't move.
Aaargh!
Xander?
Grab the sword!
Are you hurt?
- Here, let me see.
- Xander.
It's OK. I'm OK, see? Sh.
It's all right. I'm OK.
This is getting kinda scary. You OK?
Do you care?
Fine. Stay with Spike.
It's not like I meant for this to happen.
I never said that you did.
I didn't want this.
What did you want?
Nothing.
Dawn, come on.
No. You don't know.
You have this thing you do.
You have all these friends.
- You have no idea what it's like.
- What are you talking about?
- I don't know what what's...
- Being alone.
- You're not alone.
- Then why do I feel like this?
We haven't thought
of the right way out yet, that's all.
We can't stay put like cattle,
waiting for that thing to pop
out every time it gets peckish.
I'd say we do another spell,
but I think we've tried everything.
Well, that's not completely true, is it?
I mean, not everything.
Not exactly. We're sitting here
with an incredibly powerful witch.
Much more powerful than you, Tara. I'm
sorry, only no one seems willing to say it.
- I can't.
- No, see, that's not exactly true either.
Not "can't". "Won't".
You don't know how much I hate this.
I don't know if there's even
anything I could do.
Yes. And a good way to find out
is to sit around and try nothing.
- That was sarcasm, by the way.
- Look...
- It's dangerous.
- And so is all of us dying.
Will, look, I don't wanna gang up on you,
but Anya kinda has a point.
We brought you back from it once. It's one
little spell. We can bring you back again.
No. I can't.
If I start, I might not be able to stop.
Whose fault is that? If you hadn't gotten
so much of this in your system...
Hey! You're gonna back off!
She said no. That's it. You're not gonna
make her do something she doesn't want to.
And if you try,
you're gonna have to
go through me first. Understood?
Fine. If you all aren't willing to get
us out of this, then I will do it myself.
I wish you would have told me.
You haven't really been...
What? I haven't been what?
Around.
Dawn, the most important job
that I have is looking out for you.
You sound like my guidance counsellor.
She give you a handbook or something?
Talking to the Troubled Teen?
Counsellor?
Wasn't my idea. I didn't even know
we had guidance counsellors.
She called me out of class
like I was a total JD.
And you'd never met her before?
No, not until yesterday.
And she got you to start talking about
things that bothered you at home?
Yeah.
You didn't, by any chance,
happen to express,
like, a wish or something to her?
Maybe just a little.
Honey, come on,
this isn't the way. Calm down.
She knows something.
We have to find out what it is.
- Hey!
- An, just stop for a second.
- There's gotta be a clue in here somewhere.
- Stop it!
Anya, it wasn't her fault.
No!
Half this stuff is from the Magic Box.
How could you do this?
I work hard at that store, and I helped you.
I took care of you.
This is how you say thank you?
Anya, hold on, OK? Tell her
you didn't do this. Tell her it's a mistake.
No!
Buffy...
How are we supposed to trust you, Dawn?
I mean, you say you didn't put us here,
but look at this. How can we believe you?
Look, I don't think she...
I don't think it's all her fault, OK?
Someone pretending to be a guidance
counsellor made Dawn make a wish.
Guidance counsellor? You made a wish
to someone you've never seen before?
Yeah.
Did she wear a pendant
with a dark blue stone?
- And little red flecks.
- Oh, for crying out loud.
Halfrek! It's Halfrek, a vengeance demon.
- You made a wish to a vengeance demon.
- I didn't know.
Only a vengeance demon can break
her own spell. Nothing else will work.
She's the only one who can get us out
of here. Hallie, get your ass down here!
You rang?
I hope you die, you stupid jerkface!
Anya!
The sword!
Her pendant! Get her pendant!
There will be no touching of the pendant.
What? Did you think I'd be stopped
by a sword in the chest?
Flesh wound.
Honestly, Anyanka, you used to know better.
How could you? Why would you do this?
I told you I'd take care
of some business while I was in town.
Yeah, but cursing us?
Some of them are in the wedding party.
I just go where I'm...
William?
Hey, wait a minute.
You guys know each other?
Uh, no. No.
Not really.
I thought vengeance demons
only punished men who wronged women.
Oh, that was Anya's little raison d'être.
Most of us try to be
a little more well-rounded.
And actually,
we prefer "justice demon". OK? FYl.
Well-rounded? Is that how you
explain your thing for bad parents?
Oh, it's not a thing. The children need me.
Hm!
Daddy issues.
Sling all the little barbs at me
that you want, Anyanka.
It doesn't change the fact that this girl
was in pain, and none of you could hear it.
I could hear her crying out
everywhere I went in this town.
It was unbearable.
And none of you knew.
You people deserve to be cursed.
Enjoy your time together.
From now on, all you have is time.
Time, and each other.
Good luck.
Wait... Wait.
Time, and each other.
It's the curse, Hallie.
For crying out loud.
Fine, the curse is lifted!
We can all leave now!
Dammit.
Thanks. For before.
And for taking this stuff with you.
No problem.
Just so you know, I was never gonna use it.
I mean, not really. I...
I just kept it like a safety net.
Cos there was always
this thing in the back of my head.
This, you know, voice, saying, like
"What if things get bad?
I mean really bad?"
"And what if you can't handle it?"
And it made me panic,
so that's why I kept a couple of things.
I kept them so I didn't have
to think about it,
so I could focus on getting better.
I get it.
I really do.
But it's time to work without the net, Will.
You know, I don't know if you noticed,
but it actually did get bad in there.
Really bad, and you still said no.
- You have some weird friends.
- News from the file marked "duh".
- We're gonna get him to the ER.
- Then we're gonna talk about payment.
And, Dawnie, there are two words I want you
to get used to: "punitive damages".
Think it's worn off?
Just one thing to do.
- Who's pushing?
- Oh, look at the stars.
Good party.
I wanna run barefoot
so I can feel the dewdrops between my...
God, look at the stars!
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org