Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
Spike, this is the Hellmouth.
You have a soul? Fine. Show me.
- Get out of this basement.
- I don't have anywhere else to go.
There will always be vengeance demons.
But now you, Anya, you're out.
Whatever's between us... it doesn't matter.
- You shouldn't be alone in this.
- Yes, I should.
You'll live in there.
It looks like a closet, but it's a room now.
Don't touch my food. I take the first shower.
If I use all the hot water, tough noogies.
And I hate this plan.
Keeping up, or do you need an English
to Constant Pain In My Ass translation?
Invitation?
Is there something more emphatic
than "hate"? Can I "revile" the plan?
Fine.
I invite you in. Nimrod.
Don't want your sodding food anyway.
I don't understand when his problems
became yours - or mine.
The school basement is making him crazy.
We can't leave him there.
Why not? Crazy Basement Guy
is better than Stalking Buffy Guy.
It's true. You guys aren't...?
- You're not starting again with the whole...?
- No. A thousand gallons of no.
It's just things are different now.
He has a soul.
I'm sure that'll be a comfort
when he soulfully attacks you again.
Yeah, what does that mean exactly?
That Spike is all soul-having?
I don't know. But he's been through a lot, OK?
And nobody is attacking...
Buffy...
Sorry.
- No, it's me. I just...
- I'll go. This can't work.
It will. It already is.
You've been out for half an hour and you've
already stopped talking to invisible people.
Bollocks.
- There was that episode in the car.
- Bollocks to the whole thing.
- I don't need your mollycoddling.
- It's not coddling.
Now go to your closet.
- (Dawn) So what is it?
- (Buffy) What's what?
(Dawn) Last night, you said you weren't
helping Spike out of pity. What is it?
(Buffy) That's a good question.
Is sitting there drinking soda
some kind of a Zen non-answer?
No, I just...
I don't know what I'm feeling.
I think I can't stand him,
but then sometimes...
- You love him?
- No.
I... I feel for him.
- Feel what, exactly?
- Dawn...
No, I'm just trying to understand.
I mean, none of it makes sense.
First you say Spike disgusts you,
but you're doing it like bunnies.
And then Spike says he'd die for you,
but he tries to rape you.
For the record, Spike knew how wrong it was.
That's why he went away.
But to get a soul?
Like that would make him a better man?
Xander had a soul
when he stood Anya up at the altar,
and now he says he still wants her?
I just don't think it's the school basement
that's making people crazy.
- I should really get back. You coming with?
- I just don't see why people bother.
I mean, you put all this energy into
chasing and having and brooding and...
I don't get these relationships
where you do insane things.
- Bye, Rant Girl.
- You could, like, paint a beautiful mural
on every ugly wall in the world.
Then you could paint a beautiful mural
on every ugly mural in the wor...
(# "Theme From A Summer Place"
by Percy Faith)
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
(squeals and crashes to the floor)
(growling)
Maybe I'm not the right Anyanka.
Ever think about that?
There's tons of Anyankas out there.
Maybe one of them pissed off this...
What did you say his name was?
D'Hoffrynfefeffer?
Good thing I stopped by
and heard screaming.
So, I guess D'Hoffryn
decided to take you out after all?
Yeah.
He's, uh... not Head of Vengeance for nothing.
Well, thank you for the generous life-saving.
Now, please go away.
Look, I don't need anyone's help.
Or, OK, clearly I do,
but I don't want to need anyone's help,
so stop helping.
I get it. After last week, you feel
you need to be all renegade and broody.
- Taking yourself out of the loop.
- I need to figure out who I am.
Another something bad is happening.
I don't want my friends
out there alone right now, OK?
Well, I guess you guys
could use my help.
Willow's not very good with the practical
strategising. Except when she's evil.
And Dawn... she's not good for anything.
(# "Handsome Drink" by Aberdeen)
(girl) I've been thinking,
and I think I can still cheer.
I mean, I could use a chair.
Or we all could - like the Laker Girls.
(girl #2) You need to concentrate
on getting better.
Don't worry.
We'll find a replacement for you tomorrow.
I just feel like I let you down.
Hey, RJ!
Oh, Dawn.
- Hey, Summers.
- (Dawn) Um...
So, I was wondering.
You had Mr Gurin for English
back at your old school, right?
We all did.
I have him this year.
What a drag.
- I actually kinda liked him.
- Right!
Right. No, no, I like him.
It's just, you know,
I meant "drag" in a good, fun way.
So, are the tryouts tomorrow?
You're gonna make the new girls
jump up and down a lot?
God, gross!
A vending machine fell on Cheryl and all
you can think about is new cheerleaders?
Hey!
So, I heard someone saying that we're gonna
go all the way to the championships this year.
In football.
We have a good shot, for a new team.
If you can get us past Highland,
we've got a good shot.
- Like you could do better?
- We'll see.
- You think Coach'd start you at quarterback?
- Just saying.
The quarterback is
the most important member.
He is like the rudder that guides the ship.
- Right. Could I give you a hand with that?
- Would you really?
- Oh, it's OK, she can do it herself.
- Hey, we're all on the same team, right?
Yeah.
You're all on the team.
We'll talk later, guys. That's cool.
(# "New Slang" by The Shins)
Go-o-o, Razorbacks!
(girl #2) OK. Awesome. Thank you.
Up next, we have...
Dawn Summers.
- Nice outfit.
- (laughing)
(chants) Razorbacks, Razorbacks!
We're gonna play.
We got a secret weapon and his name is RJ.
Hear us cheer, hear us yell.
Listen what we say.
Razorbacks, Razorbacks!
Go, RJ!
Argh!
OK. Thank you.
Very... spirited.
- Come on, Dawnie. Come out.
- (sobbing)
Dawn, sweetheart, it's not that bad.
How would you even know?
RJ's never gonna notice me now.
From what you said,
I'm sure he noticed you.
I mean, with the falling
and the... spirit. Spirit!
- They said you were spirited, right?
- Go away!
Dawn!
Things a lot better, I see.
I don't think tonight's
gonna be good for videos.
Right, with the wailing and the crying.
Still better than a cosy evening with Spike.
Shall I order a pizza?
Don't teens in a snit like pizza?
It is not a snit!
I finally met him - the guy of my dreams,
OK? - and I blew it.
RJ hates me now.
Dawn, what is that?
Just the end of my life.
Remember when she used to have a crush
on me? I miss the much cuter "me" crush.
(# "School Blood" by King Black Acid)
- You shredded my outfit.
- I'll buy you a new one.
That's not the point.
I don't want a new cheerleading outfit.
Now, now, let's not be hasty.
Not the right time.
Dawn, I'm sorry that you feel so bad, OK?
But in the morning
this won't seem so terrible.
You don't even know this RJ. Not really.
I do know him.
I know his soul.
Really? Dawn, he wasn't even
on your radar yesterday.
It's the jacket. It's true. The big letter on the
chest makes girls get all swoony and crushy.
I saw it all the time in school. You couldn't
just pin a felt letter to your coat and get play.
- Not that I tried.
- It isn't a crush.
It's love.
I love RJ.
Again, since yesterday.
Dawn, it's awfully fast.
What? You're telling me
I don't feel what I feel?
No, of course not.
I believe that you think it's real.
It seems real, to you.
Know what? Maybe I don't want advice
from the dysfunction queen.
You have no idea how I feel.
You have no idea what real love is.
Maybe if you did,
you wouldn't make fun of me.
- Dawn, I'm not making fun of you.
- Just go.
Leave me alone.
(bell)
Brooks. I just talked to the coach.
I told you, all those fumbles in practice -
he was gonna come down on you.
I'm starting on Saturday.
Great. Who knew fumbling
all the time was the key?
It's just time to let someone else have a turn.
And you knew this was comin'.
Yeah. Sure.
- You can't do this to RJ.
- Oh, hey, it's you.
Nice cheering the other day.
It isn't fair. He works so hard.
What do you care?
This is how the game is played.
It's dog eat dog, may the best man win.
But nobody's better than RJ.
Yeah, well, that's not really
up to you, is it? Hm?
It all happened so fast.
One minute he was walking,
and the next he stumbled and... and he fell.
Why would he say
you pushed him down the stairs?
I don't know.
Maybe he was just embarrassed.
It's hard being clumsy, especially
when you're popular and athletic. I'd bet.
To be candid, it wouldn't be the first time
I caught O'Donnell in a lie.
- It'd be nice if they didn't involve my sister.
- I'll have to call Coach Wheeler
and tell him the bad news.
- Not a conversation I really wanna have.
- At least he's still got RJ to take over.
Yeah. I think we have
everything we need for now.
I'm sorry you had
to get involved in this, Dawn.
That's OK.
I'm just really sorry it happened.
Summers.
- Hey!
- Hi.
- I heard Wood hauled you into his office.
- Well, yeah.
- About O'Donnell?
- Yes.
That sucks,
facing the whole inquisition thing.
Yeah. "No one expects
the Spanish Inquisition."
God, it's like I have a disease or something.
It was really no big deal.
No. It was.
I think it's cool that you faced him. Wood.
We just talked. He just wanted me
to tell him about the accident.
Yeah.
It sucks when these things
just happen - out of nowhere.
Right. Out of nowhere.
I was thinking of heading out tonight,
after practice. You wanna meet up?
Um... hm.
(# "Little Fury" by The Breeders)
Spike definitely seems a little more cogent,
less bl-bl-bl-bl-bl.
I'm just sayin',
once you get back the soul,
doesn't that mean you start, like,
picking up your own wet towels off the floor?
No, but maybe you start to feel really bad
about leaving them there.
At least he's showering.
That's a refreshing and delightful change.
Buff.
- (Buffy) I think that's the guy.
- What guy?
The one who, according to Dawn, is the
"smartest, funniest, coolest, hottest,
and having the thickest boy eyelashes
boy in school."
- He don't seem so tough.
- Check out the fan club.
Daddy like.
- What is that shirt made of? Paint?
- Buff...
Glad Dawnie can't see her precious boyfriend
getting thrusty with some slut-bag hussy...
- Oh.
- (Xander) Oh. Oh!
No! "Daddy..." No, I wasn't...
When I was looking, I wasn't...
- Oh, God!
- Right there with ya.
So, do you have plans later? Or are you going
to the docks to wait for the fleet to come in?
- What?
- Where do I start with the bad?
First, you said
you were going to the library.
Second, you do not go on a date
without informing me.
Third, Anna Nicole Smith
thinks you look tacky.
Well, I think I look hot, and so does RJ.
I bet. Maybe I should
have a word with him.
No! Don't you dare
embarrass me in front of him.
I don't like this.
He has you acting crazy.
- It's my life. I'll do what I want to.
- I don't think so.
Oh. So, what? Suddenly you're Mom now?
No, I'm not. And I am glad
she's not here to see you like this.
- Look, I'm sorry. I just...
- You just can't handle it.
- What?!
- You've always been the special one.
Hot little Buffy with her boyfriends.
The Slayer.
Now someone likes me and you can't stand
that I'm getting the attention.
- That is the farthest thing from true.
- No, it's not.
Sorry, but I like
the way RJ makes me feel.
If you think that makes me a slut
or whatever, I don't care.
Oh, no, no, no. You are not
going back out on that dance floor.
(rattling)
RJ?
I know what you're doing, slut.
I saw you. I saw you with RJ!
- So? We were just dancing.
- Right.
You think I'm stupid?
You're gonna back off. Now.
You know what's sad? A girl who can't
move on when she's been dumped.
He didn't dump me!
First with the lap dance, now with the
catfight. Hey, wanna get drunk and barf next?
- Let go of me! This isn't finished.
- I'll never let you have him, bitch.
RJ is mine. I mean it.
Stay away from him!
Well, at least someone agrees
you shouldn't be dating this guy.
(bell)
How about if you try doing your own
homework for a change? All right?
No more getting these young,
impressionable women to do it for you.
Avoid detention, RJ. Sound good?
- Whatever.
- Oh!
Sweet, infectious enthusiasm.
Whoa. Hang on there, slappy.
I'm not done with you yet.
Oh, man. Like it's not bad enough
I got that guy riding my back all the time.
- Now I gotta deal with you, too?
- I'm a bit more formidable than Mr Wood.
You might come to look fondly
on his back-riding.
- Yeah, but come on...
- Sit.
- I told him I was sorry about the homework.
- Mm.
Not the homework, Mr Wizard. The girls.
What you're doing to them.
In specific, my sister.
I didn't do anything to your sister.
You saw how hot she looked last night.
- I think that proved...
- Ah-ah-ah! No more with the talky.
I know how guys like you work. You turn on
the charm, you get whatever you want, right?
OK, look, it's not like that.
I just get along really well with girls.
Oh, I see how you get along.
"Oh, look at me, I'm Mr Quarterback."
"I crush little girls
and all their little feelings."
"All I have to do is...
lead a team of high-school athletes
trying their best to do a good job,
everyone depending on me."
That is a lot of pressure.
But it doesn't mean you get to
disregard other people's feelings.
It's not like I meant to hurt anyone.
I know. I know that.
It's just... you're a leader.
A captain, OK? People look up to you and
you need to keep that in mind when you...
I bet... you run a lot, huh?
I mean... they work you
pretty hard, don't they?
Yeah.
I guess so.
I get that. I do.
I'm there. Or at least I was there
when I was still in high school.
Which I was just a couple of years ago, really.
You know, I just realised,
I'm basically the same age as you.
I'm not really older at all, actually.
I'm just like you...
but with the sexual experience and stuff.
I think I hear what you're saying.
Right.
I'm really glad that we had this talk,
so I think you'd better get back to class.
OK. Thanks.
(# "Theme From A Summer Place"
by Percy Faith)
(Buffy) Dawn? You wanna come talk to me?
Ambush.
I wanted to tell you
that I talked to RJ today.
He's OK. I think he likes you.
Really? Tell me what he said about me.
Every word, including intonation
and facial expressions.
Well, he thinks you're funny
and pretty and interesting.
Didn't have a thing to say against you.
Yes, he did. I can tell.
The tiniest thing.
He might have said
that you came on a little strong.
Oh, my God!
I'm the pushy queen of Slut Town.
No, honey, not at all.
No, no. It's just...
Lay back a little. Let him come to you.
I'm just scared that while I'm laying back,
some other girl's gonna sweep him up.
But we have inside info.
We know he doesn't like being swept.
He likes to be the sweeper.
Dawn, you're gonna come out the winner
here. With me looking out for you.
Yeah, I guess so. Thank you.
So we do know that six x plus y equals 16,
so we can solve for y in terms of iso...
Sorry to interrupt. We need to see
RJ Brooks down in the guidance office.
(# "Warning Sign" by Coldplay)
There's no one here.
Yeah, there is.
There's one of you...
and there's one of me.
You were the one in math class.
Tell me what that adds up to.
I'm not coming on too strong
if I just look at him.
(Buffy) I've always been
fascinated by football.
So what's it like to lead a team?
The thing of it is, the time.
Nobody gets how much time goes into it,
with practices and games.
I totally get it. I was kinda juggling
some stuff when I was in high school too.
Which was also very recent.
Principal Snyder was always on me.
I still say Wood's the worst.
You haven't seen the way that guy rides me.
I wish somebody
would just get him off my back.
Yeah. That would be cool.
And sometimes,
I didn't even do anything wrong.
You're like a teacher.
Not really.
But, I mean, does it bother you?
Not so much.
Dawn?
What's wrong? Is this...
Did that guy in the jacket...?
- I don't even wanna hear his name any more!
- I just called him "that guy in the jacket".
That's what I used to call him in my head
before I knew his real name!
Dawnie, honey,
you seem... extremely perturbed.
- Maybe I should go get Buffy...
- No!
I don't ever wanna see her again.
I thought this was about
that guy in the... um...
That guy with the thing.
No, it's about both of them.
Buffy, I think Dawn needs y...
Xander, hi.
- This is RJ.
- Hey, guy. It's called knocking.
I'm sorry. Checkout time was an hour ago.
We were hoping to make up the bed.
And also, it's a classroom,
you chowderhead!
Now get off the boy, Buffy.
We're going home.
Dawn, please stop crying. Please?
Crying isn't gonna make
his love for me go away.
You're under a love spell.
That's what this has to be.
You're right. He's right.
You're under a spell.
Oh, poor little Dawnie.
But we're working on it.
It'll be better soon.
Yes. Soon neither one of you
will be in love with this boy.
- He's not a boy.
- What do you know about our love?
It's true and real.
This isn't magic. This is my heart.
- Fine.
- We'll be working.
Look, I know this feels terrible,
but it isn't real. Try to hold on to that.
Did you hear that? It isn't real.
- You're just crazy.
- It is so real! I love him.
You knew how I felt, like I'd finally
found something, and you betrayed me.
I betrayed you? You constructed this
elaborate fantasy about you and my lover.
- Your lover? Your lover?!
- Guys, guys...
- I tried to get you to back away.
- That's right! You lied to me!
Did you want me to tell you
he's in love with me?
- That your little crush is hopeless?
- It's not a crush!
- Stop. You're not supposed to do this!
- Why?
Because he's younger than me? You know,
I'm extremely youthful. And peppy.
No.
Cos you were the one I trusted.
- Dawn, wait!
- (door slams)
- Crazy lust puppies, aren't they?
- At least the yelling went away.
It started to sound
like Christmas with my family.
Love spells. People forget
how dangerous they can be.
Hey, been there.
- Xander!
Stop it! Stop!
- Good times.
- Here. Something.
She's locked her door.
That spell has her good and loopy.
- Info on one RJ Brooks.
- Oh, let me see. Is there a picture?
Family stuff. Hey, I knew his brother.
He was a big jock at Sunnydale High too.
Couple of years ahead of us.
He used to stick chewing gum in my hair.
- Hm.
- What are you thinking?
I think my relationship with RJ's brother was
complex at best, but maybe he's a way in.
Now look for a picture.
We're tangling with a powerful spell here
and we don't know what the deal is,
so keep an eye out if this guy looks twitchy.
And don't let this guy charm you, either.
He had everyone around him practically
kissing his ring back in high school.
Yeah?
- Construction, huh? That's awesome.
- (Xander) Yeah.
So, what's up with RJ?
How's he doing at the old alpha mater?
Good. It's just... I know a girl that might be
going out with him and I was wondering...
God, and you wanna know if he's a good guy.
Truth is, he's the best.
Following in my footsteps. You might not
know it now, with a couple of extra pounds,
but back then, I was quite the guy.
Yeah, I gather that RJ is pretty popular too.
I gotta tell ya, there was a time
I was worried about RJ.
He used to be all into comic books,
Model UN, geek stuff - no offence, Harris.
One time, I found
all this poetry under his bed.
Turns out, he wrote it.
Then he, uh... what do you call it?
Blossomed. That's what it was like.
And do you have any idea why he, you know,
burst into a flower all of a sudd...?
(Spike) You're wearing your brother's jacket.
Here, in this picture.
No, he's wearing mine. That jacket
was with me all the way through high school.
Gave it to him when I graduated,
right before I started at the Pizza Barn.
- I'm in the management programme.
- So, Lance, where did you get the jacket?
Oh, Dad gave it to me.
Made a big deal about it too.
How he met Mom wearing that jacket.
She was a former Miss Arkansas.
- Very hot in her day.
- Wow, that's wonderful.
- Boy, it's getting late.
- You guys don't have to take off.
I got sort of a rumpus room
set up in the basement.
There's air hockey and a mini fridge.
We could party.
(Mrs Brooks) Lance?
Do you have guests?
There's boxes of raisins
if you want snacks.
We really gotta go.
Damn love spell. I have tried
every anti-love spell spell I can find.
Even if you found the right one, he'd probably
just do an anti-anti-love spell spell... spell.
- What?
- (doorbell)
I'll get it. Maybe it's Xander
with some answers from the brother.
- Oh, you have to be...
- I was looking for Buffy. Miss Summers.
- Buffy's not here. Go away!
- Are you sure?
No Buffy for you. Leave quickly now.
Uh... OK.
Tell her to call me.
Man!
Good thing Buffy and Dawn are upstairs.
(# "Theme From A Summer Place"
by Percy Faith)
- But you don't even know him!
- Yes, I do. I looked into him. I saw his soul.
He was walking away,
so unless his soul is in his ass...
AJ is my best friend
and my dearest darling.
It's RJ. And what you were picking up on
was his deep caring and devotion to me.
- What's going on?
- Willow's in love with my boyfriend, RJ.
What? No! You two can't do this.
Willow, you're a gay woman. And he isn't.
This isn't about his physical presence.
It's about his heart.
- His physical presence has a penis!
- I can work around it!
This isn't fair!
How can you all do this to me?
OK, wait. Everyone wait. Just calm down,
OK? I think I know what this is.
Clearly, you've both been affected
by the same love spell that got Dawn.
This isn't a spell.
He owns my heart.
Dawn, be quiet.
We don't need you interfering.
There's a simple answer to this.
Think about who loves him the most.
Clearly I do, since I'm willing
to look past the whole orientation thing.
- I need him.
- You're gonna have to do better than that.
- I'd kill for him.
- You'd kill for a chocolate bar.
- No.
- Yes!
Kill for him.
I'm the Slayer. Slayer means kill.
Oh, I'll kill the principal.
- That is hard to top.
- Yeah, well, I have skills.
- I can prove my love with magic.
- Yeah, right.
What're you gonna do,
use magic to make him into a girl?
Damn!
(Anya) Wait, I know what he'll like.
Sorry, Dawnie.
You're never gonna get him.
No.
Never.
Oh, Hecate, I call on you.
I humbly ask your will be done.
Hear my request, a simple change.
Create a daughter from a s...
Oh, man! Now I've gotta start all over.
Hecate hates that.
- What the hell are you doing?
- Proving I love RJ the most.
Will, honey.
- RJ's a guy.
- I did notice that, yeah.
That's why I'm doing my spell, cos
he doesn't have to be. Hand me my crystals.
- I don't have much time.
- Before what?
Before Buffy, Anya and Dawn
prove they love RJ the most.
- How are they gonna do that?
- Buffy's gonna kill Principal Wood...
Fine, OK, let's start there.
Hey!
- What are you guys doing?
- Locator spell. Human variety. Almost done.
I've got a principal to kill.
What's going on? Who are we looking for?
(train horn)
You realise Anya's probably
seducing RJ as we speak?
- God. You think so?
- I wouldn't put it past her.
- She's recently evil, you know.
- So am I. Why should I miss out?
Hey, crazy chicks, look.
Dawn?
- Dawn!
- Buffy!
(train horn)
- What were you doing? What is this?
- It doesn't matter.
This is a plan?
You're gonna steal RJ by being trisected?
What am I? Gonna compete with you?
You're older and hotter
and have sex that's rough and kill people.
I don't have any of that stuff.
But if I did this, then his whole life he'd know
there was someone that loved him
so much they'd give up their life.
Dawn...
And it would be true, forever.
No guy is worth your life. Not ever.
RJ is. And don't say he isn't.
Look what you were willing to do.
Dawn, I would give him to you
in a second if I could.
That's how much you're scaring me.
But I thought you wanted him... for you.
Nah.
Well, yeah.
My God, that boy is hot.
Sorry.
- I think I might be under a spell here.
- I hear ya.
- Now, you're sure you understand the plan?
- I think I got it, yeah.
Hey! Ow!
That, my friends, is the smell
of sweet, sweet victory.
Also, burning cotton-poly blend.
Xander, be honest. You didn't think about
slipping that jacket on just a little bit?
I refuse to answer that
on the grounds that it didn't fit.
This tool gets his jacket
from his brother,
who got it from their father, and we'll never
know where he got it. That bites.
Nah, welcome to the Hellmouth,
where even outerwear isn't safe.
- I can't believe I almost...
It was a spell. You were helpless.
We're not responsible for anything
we did morally or, you know, legally.
True. You fell
for a mystical, ancient curse.
Who hasn't made that mistake
seven, eight times?
You hear that? Not your fault.
I'm just so...
The way I acted.
The way I talked to you.
I feel so stupid. All over a spell.
Get ready to feel even stupider
when it's not.
Hey, Anya, you never told us
what you can't believe you almost.
Almost... Who, now?
No, you can't be the only
not-embarrassed one. What did you do?
I, uh... wrote a poem.
An epic poem.
Comparing him to a daisy
and a tower and a lake.
(radio) The latest on Sunnydale's
late-night bandit who is still at large.
A masked thief held up a number...
OK, great. Ice cream. My treat.
Visiontext Subtitles: Abigail Smith
Urgh! Argh!
ENGLISH SDH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org