Here's the thing. There's
moments in your life that make you,
that set the course of
who you're gonna be.
Sometimes they're little... subtle moments,
sometimes... they're not.
I'll show you what I mean.
We'll be back when we've found
a bit more cash money!
Keep the girls warm!
Let's go.
Come on. We'll sneak in
and take some of me father's silver.
He'll never miss it.
He eats with his hands, the pig!
Why don't you rest right here?
So... I'd ask myself,
"What's a lady of your station
doing alone in an alley...
with a reputation that this one has?"
Maybe she's lonely.
In that case,
I'd offer myself as escort,
to protect you from harm
and to while away the dull hours.
- You're very gracious.
- It's often been said.
Are you certain
you're up to the challenge?
Milady, you'll find...
that, with the exception
of an honest day's work,
there's no challenge
I'm not prepared to face.
Oh,
but you're a pretty thing.
- Where are you from?
- Around.
Everywhere.
I never been anywhere myself.
I always wanted to see the world, but...
I could show you.
- Could you, then?
- Things you've never seen.
Never even heard of.
- Sounds excitin'.
- It is.
And frightening.
I'm not afraid. Show me.
Show me your world.
Close your eyes.
Nice try.
I want you to get a message
to Angel for me.
Tell him I'm done waiting.
I'm taking the fight to him.
You got that?
Need me to write it down for you?
All right, I'll tell him myself.
I'm good. Don't worry about me.
You know you don't have to
patrol with me.
I had that guy under control
until he resorted to fisticuffs.
Oh! What is that, um...
Five vampires in three nights?
Yep, but no Angel.
Are you, uh, really that anxious
to come up against him?
- I want it over with.
- I hear that.
Oh, we'd better go. I haven't even
started studying for finals yet.
Oh, yeah! Finals!
Why didn't you let me die?
Ah, look on the bright side.
It'll all be over soon.
Yes, my love.
It will.
"Becoming. Part 1"
Careful now! Concentrate in this area.
There you go.
Hello?
- Rupert Giles?
- Yes.
Doug Perren. Thanks for comin'.
Oh, not at all.
I was flattered to be asked.
I spoke with Lou Tabor
at the Washington Institute
and he told me we had
the best authority on obscure relics
- right here in Sunnydale.
- Oh...
He may have, uh, exaggerated a little.
- Ah, this is the...
- This is our baby.
Construction workers
dug it up outside of town.
Don't have a clue what it is.
Any ideas?
A few... None I'd care to share
until I can verify.
You have, uh, carbon dated it?
The results'll be back
in a couple of days.
I'll go out on a limb and say "old"!
Um, yes, it, it certainly...
predates any, uh...
settlements we've read about.
- Um... May I?
- Yeah, sure.
I assume you've, uh...
you haven't tried to open it?
Open it?
I'll be damned!
I figured it was solid.
- What do you think is in there?
- I don't know.
Well, I guess we won't know
until we open it up.
Yes, but... could I ask, um...
Would, would you wait? I'd, uh...
I'd like to work
on translating the text.
It-it-it might give us
an indication of...
what we'll find inside.
- You don't wanna be surprised?
- As a rule, no.
All right. You're the expert.
But I'm pretty damn curious, though.
Yes.
Yes, so am I.
- "Tell Angel I'm gonna kill him."
- "No, wait. I'm gonna kill you!"
"Die! Die! Die!"
"Mother?"
- Is that it?
- That's it.
Scene?
That's exactly how it happened.
I thought it was riveting. Uh, I was
a little unclear about some of the themes.
The theme is, Angel's too much of
a coward to take me on face to face.
And the other theme was 'Buy American',
but it, uh, got kind of buried.
Do you think you're ready
to fight Angel?
I wish people would stop
asking me that.
Yes, I'm ready.
I'm also willing and able.
It's the one test
I might actually pass.
Don't say that!
You're gonna pass everything.
I will get you through this semester
if I have to sweat blood.
Do you think you're likely to?
'Cause I'd like to be elsewhere.
- It was only metaphor blood.
- I think you'd sweat cute blood.
Sixth period, after my computer class,
- we'll rock on chemistry.
- Ready to rock.
Boy, Willow, you've really got
the teaching bug.
Taking over computer class,
tutoring...
I love it, I really do.
I think it's great to do that before
you go out and fail in the real world.
That way you're not falling back on
something. You're falling...
well, forward.
And almost 65% of that was actual
compliment. Is that a personal best?
Gee, Xander, what are you gonna teach
when you fail in life?
Advanced loser-being?
I will teach...
- ze language of love.
- Don't! You have fish hands!
- Come! Let me caress! Let me in!
- Stop it!
- No! Don't!
- That's enough of that!
And you!
Are we having a chair shortage?
I didn't read anything about...
Oh. I get it.
These public displays of affection
are not acceptable in my school.
This isn't an orgy, people.
It's a classroom.
Yeah! Where they teach lunch.
Just give me a reason
to kick you out, Summers.
Just give me a reason.
How about because you're
a tiny, impotent Nazi
with a bug up his butt
the size of an emu?
- Sums it up.
- Don't you think?
Do you wanna come by
my house tonight and study, too?
Maybe. I do have to patrol.
Again? Do you really expect
Angel to turn up tonight?
No, I don't expect him to.
But that's usually when he does.
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
It's been two days
since my last confession.
Father?
That's not very long.
Oh, Father, I'm so afraid.
The Lord is very forgiving.
- Tell me your sins.
- I had...
I've been seeing again, Father.
Yesterday, the men were going
to work in the mine.
I had... a terrible fright.
My stomach all tied up
and I saw this 'orrible crash.
My mummy said to keep my peace,
it didn't mean nothin'.
But this morning...
They had a cave-in.
- Two men died.
- Go on.
Me mum says... I'm cursed.
My seeing things is
an affront to the Lord.
That only He's supposed to
see anything before it 'appens.
But I don't mean to, Father, I swear!
I swear!
I try to be pure in His sight.
- I don't want to be an evil thing.
- Oh, hush, child.
The Lord has a plan for all creatures.
Even a devil child like you.
- A devil?
- Yes, you're a spawn of Satan.
All the Hail Marys in the world
aren't going to help.
The Lord will use you
and smite you down. He's like that.
- What can I do?
- Fulfill his plan, child.
Be evil. Just give in.
No! I want to be good.
- I want to be pure.
- We all do, at first.
The world doesn't work that way.
Father... I beg you...
Please, please help me!
Very well.
Ten Our Fathers
and an Act of Contrition.
Does that sound good?
Yes!
Yes, Father, thank you.
The pleasure was mine.
- And, my child...
- Yes?
God is watching you.
Nice walk, pet?
I met an old man.
Didn't like him.
He got stuck in my teeth.
But then, the moon started...
whispering to me...
all sorts of dreadful things.
- What did it say?
- Oh, look who's awake!
What did the moon tell you?
Did you have a vision?
- Is something coming?
- Oh, yeah!
Something terrible. Pss, pss, pss.
- Where?
- At the museum.
A tomb... with a surprise inside.
You can see all that in your head?
No, you ninny.
She read it in the morning paper.
- Oh, my!
- That's what's been whispering to me.
- Sssh!
- Oh, yeah.
Don't worry, though.
Soon it'll stop.
Soon it'll scream.
Waah! This doesn't make any sense!
Well, sure, it does. See...
- Oh, no, this doesn't make any sense.
- It's senseless!
It is, but at least you know that,
so you're learning.
Yay me! It doesn't matter, anyway.
I mean...
when in the real world
am I ever gonna need
chemistry or history,
or math, or the English language?
- OK, I see your problem.
- I'm a moron?
Will you stop that?
You're not stupid.
You've just had a lot on your mind.
You can learn this real easily,
but if you're just gonna give up,
then don't waste my time.
- Wow! You are a good teacher.
- OK, look at this.
A covalent bond, which means
these two atoms are linked by...
Oh! Hold that thought.
- OK, I'm Learn Girl.
- OK, so see here...
- Déja vu.
- Really?
Yeah.
I have this... perfect memory
of the... pencil and...
Oh, hey...
You dropped this.
It's not mine.
It might be something
of Miss Calendar's.
This feels kinda morbid.
I've gone through
most of her files already.
Does that make it less morbid
or you really morbid?
I had to. To teach her class.
Relax, Will.
I was making with the funny.
- Does that say "restoration"?
- It's one of her spells, I think.
Ms. Calendar wasn't
a practicing witch,
- but she did dabble...
- Willow!
Oh, boy!
(Neither dead, nor of the living)
(I invoke you, spirit of the passing.)
(Return to the body
what distinguishes Man from the beast!)
(So it shall be.)
(Restore this one!)
It hurts, yes?
Good. It will hurt more.
- Where am I?
- You don't remember...
everything you've done for 100 years.
In a moment, you will.
The face of everyone you killed...
Our daughter's face...
They will haunt you
and you will know
what true suffering is.
Killed?
I d-, I don't...
No...
No.
No, no.
- What are you saying?
- The curse.
This is it.
Looks like Miss Calendar was trying
to replicate the original curse.
To restore Angel's soul again.
- She said it couldn't be done.
- Well, she tried anyway.
- And it looks like it might've worked.
- So he killed her...
before she could tell anyone about it.
What a prince, huh?
This is good, right?
I mean, we can curse him again.
Um... W-well, this, um...
certainly points the way.
But the ritual itself...
requires a greater knowledge
of the black arts than I can claim.
Well, I've been going
through her files and...
and researching the black arts for fun,
or educational fun,
and I may be able to work this.
W-W-Willow, channeling...
such potent magics through yourself...
It could... open a door
you may not be able to close.
I don't want you putting yourself
in any danger, Will.
And I don't want danger.
Big "no" to danger,
but I may be
the best person to do this.
Hi! For those of you
who've just tuned in,
everyone here is a crazy person.
So this spell might
restore Angel's humanity?
Well, here's an interesting angle.
- Who cares?
- I care.
Is that right?
Let's not lose
our perspective here, Xander.
- I'm Perspective Guy. Angel's a killer.
- Xander...
- It's not that simple.
- What? All is forgiven?
- I can't believe you, people!
- Xander has a point.
You know, just for once,
I wish you'd support me!
And I realize right now that you were,
and I'm embarrassed,
so I'm gonna get back to the point,
which is that Angel needs to die!
Curing Angel seems to have been
Jenny's last wish.
- Yeah? Well, Jenny's dead!
- Don't you ever...
- Can't you hear what I'm saying?!
- Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it!
What do you wanna do?
I don't know.
What happened to Angel
wasn't his fault.
Yeah, but
what happened to Ms. Calendar is.
You can paint this any way you want.
But the way I see it is that you wanna
forget all about Ms. Calendar's murder
so you can get your boyfriend back.
Hello?
I'll have one of these to go.
Dru?
Save me some.
Well, I'll do a couple of sweeps,
and then I'll stop by.
Yeah,
Xander was pretty much being a...
Willow!
Where did you learn that word?
My God!
You kiss your mother with that mouth?
I don't know.
I don't know what I wanna... do.
I'll... I'll see you in a little while, OK?
You know, polite people call before they
jump out of the bushes and attack you.
Just wanted to test your reflexes.
How about testing my face-punching?
'Cause I think you'll find it's improved.
I was on my way to your house,
saw you walking, couldn't help myself.
Which begs the question, and don't think
I'm not glad to see you, but...
why are you here?
Oh, wait. No, let me guess.
Your watcher informed you that a very
dark power is about to rise in Sunnydale.
- That's about it.
- Great.
So, you have any idea
what this dark power is?
It's a big rock.
Can't wait to tell my friends.
They don't have a rock this big.
Spike, boy,
you never did learn your history.
Let's have a lesson, then.
Acathla the demon came forth
to swallow the world.
He was killed by a virtuous knight
who pierced the demon's heart
before he could draw a breath
to perform the act.
Acathla turned to stone,
as demons sometimes do,
and was buried where neither man
nor demon would want to look.
Unless, of course,
they're putting up low-rent housing.
Boys...
He fills my head!
I can't 'ear anything else.
Let me guess.
- Someone pulls out the sword...
- Someone worthy.
The demon wakes up,
and wackiness ensues.
He will swallow the world.
And every creature
living on this planet will go to Hell.
My friends...
We're about to make history...
end.
I've been on the phone to the museum.
The artifact in question is missing
and the curator has been murdered.
Vampires.
And you're sure
this was the tomb of Alfalfa?
Acathla. And yes,
the information provided
by Kendra's watcher seems conclusive.
OK. Somebody explain the whole
"he will suck the world into Hell" thing.
Because that's the part
I'm not loving.
Well, the, uh, the Demon Universe exists
in a dimension separate from our own.
With one breath, Acathla will create
a vortex, a kind of um...
whirlpool that will pull everything
on Earth into that dimension,
where any non-demon life
will suffer horrible and...
eternal torment.
So that would be the literal
kind of "sucked into Hell"?
Neat!
Willow, I think
you should try the curse.
I tend to side with
your friend Xander on this one.
Angel should be eliminated.
Oh, I'll fight him.
I'll kill him if I have to.
But if I don't get there in time,
or if I lose,
- then Willow might be our only hope.
- I don't wanna be our only hope.
I-I crumble under pressure.
Let's have another hope.
We have.
Blessed by the knight
who first slew the demon.
If all else fails, this might stop it.
- I tink.
- Ooh. May I? May I?
Thank you. Well, I-let's, uh,
hope all else doesn't fail.
Um, how close are you to
figuring out the ritual of the curse?
I need about a day.
And...
an orb of Thesulah, whatever that is.
A spirit vault for...
rituals of the undead. I've got one.
I've been using it as a paperweight.
This means I can't help you study
for tomorrow's final.
Ah, I'll wing it.
Of course, if we go to Hell by then,
I won't have to take 'em!
Or maybe I'll be taking them for ever.
Angel has a ritual of his own
to perform before he can
remove the sword and awaken Acathla.
With any luck,
it should take some time.
Spike?
Spike, my sweet,
the fun's about to begin.
I will drink.
The blood will wash in me,
over me, and I will be cleansed.
I will be worthy to free Acathla.
Bear witness...
as I ascend,
as I become
everything that I am.
Everything that I have done,
has led me here.
God, are you disgusting!
This is really an unforgettable smell.
This is the stench of death
you're givin' off here.
And the look says, uh...
"Crazy Homeless Guy". It's not good.
- Get away from me!
- What are you gonna do? Bite me?
Horrors! A vampire!
Ah, but you wouldn't bite me
on account of your poor, tortured soul.
It's so sad - a vampire with a soul.
So poignant.
- Who are you?
- Let's take a walk.
What are you eating?
Like, a rat once a month?
Hey!
Look, you're skin and bones here!
Butcher shops are throwing away
more blood in a day than you could stand.
Good blood. If you lived in the world
a little bit, you'd know that.
I wanna know who you are.
- And I wanna know who you are.
- You already do.
Not yet. But I'm lookin' to find out.
'Cause you could go either way here.
- I don't understand you...
- Nobody understands me. That's my curse.
Dog me. Mustard.
- My name's Whistler.
- There you go.
Thanks.
Anyway, lately it is.
You're not a vampire?
A demon. Technically.
I mean, I'm not a bad guy.
Not all demons are dedicated
to the destruction of all life.
What do you mean, I can go either way?
I mean that you can become an even more
useless rodent than you already are...
or you can become someone.
A person.
- Someone to be counted.
- I just want to be left alone.
Well, yeah, you've been left alone
for, what, ninety years already.
And what a package you are.
The Stink Guy!
- What do you want from me?
- I want you to see something.
We'd have to leave now.
You see, and then you tell me
what you wanna do.
Where is it?
So I'm like, 'Dad, do you want me
to go to the dance
in an outfit I've already worn?
Why do you hate me?'
Is Tyler taking you?
Where were you when I got over Tyler?
He's of the past.
Tyler would have to crawl
on his hands and knees
to get me to go to the dance with him.
Which, actually, he's supposed to do
after practice, so I'm gonna wait.
OK. See you later. Bye.
- Call me. Call me. Call me.
- I will.
Buffy Summers?
- Yeah. Hi! What?
- I need to speak with you.
You're not from Bullock's, are you?
'Cause I meant to pay for that lipstick.
There isn't much time.
You must come with me.
Your destiny awaits.
I don't have a destiny.
I'm destiny-free, really.
Yes, you have.
You are the Chosen One.
You alone can stop them.
- Who?
- The vampires.
Huh?
Oh, God.
Oh!
Oh! Oh, not the heart!
You see?
You see your power?
- Why didn't you call?
- I'm sorry.
I-I didn't know it was so late.
- Tyler and I... were talking...
- That boy is irresponsible.
No, Mom, it's not his fault.
You know we worry, that's all.
Dinner's in ten minutes.
Yeah.
- Did she say where she was?
- She was with Tyler.
I don't want her seeing him
anymore, period!
- You're overreacting, dear.
- Don't do that!
- Don't talk to me like I'm a kid!
- I don't. Just forget it.
Just because you can't discipline her,
I have to be the ogre.
I am not having this conversation
again, all right?
She's gonna have it tough,
that slayer.
She's just a kid.
The world's full of big, bad things.
I wanna help her.
I want...
I wanna become someone.
God, jeez, look at you.
She must be prettier
than the last slayer.
This isn't gonna be easy.
The more you live in this world,
the more you see
how apart from it you really are.
This is dangerous work.
Right now you couldn't go
three rounds with a fruit fly!
I wanna learn from you.
All right.
But I don't wanna dress like you.
Again, you're annoying me.
You're lucky we need you on our side.
I have strayed.
I have been lost.
But Acathla redeems me.
With this act...
we will be free.
# Someone wasn't worthy
Dammit!
This is so... disappointing.
There must be something I missed.
The incantations, the blood! I don't know!
What are we going to do?
What we always do
in a time of trouble.
Turn to an old friend.
We'll have our Armageddon, I swear!
Tonight, sundown,
- at the graveyard.
- Excuse me?
You will come to him.
You will come to him or more will die!
Tonight!
His hour is at hand!
She said more would die.
I have to go!
- Then I should go with you.
- No!
I need you here, just in case.
I can take care of myself.
And look,
as long as Angel's fighting me,
then he can't do this end-of-the-world
ritual thingy, and that's a good.
Willow, what do you think?
- I just want to cross-check...
- We don't have time.
If this is gonna work,
it has to work now.
OK. Then I need maybe half an hour
once we're all set up.
Which means
you just have to hold Angel off.
Don't let him close on you.
If the curse succeeds, you'll...
You'll know.
Why don't you just wait here
to find out if it worked?
See if he phones you.
I can't risk him killing
any more people.
I'd better go.
Be careful.
- I will.
- Here!
In case the curse does not succeed,
this is my lucky stake.
I've killed many vampires with it.
I call it Mr. Pointy.
- You named your stake?
- Yes.
Remind me to get you a stuffed animal.
Thanks.
Watch your back.
Hello, lover.
I wasn't sure you'd come.
After your immolation-o-gram?
Come on, I had to show.
Shouldn't you be out
destroying the world right now?
Pulling a sword out of Al Franken
or whatever his name is?
There's time enough.
I wanted to say goodbye first.
You are the one thing in this dimension
I will miss.
This is a beautiful moment we're having.
Can we please fight?
I didn't come here to fight.
- No?
- Gosh, I was hoping
we can get back together.
What do you think?
Do we have a shot?
All right! We'll fight.
"Quod perditum est, invenietur,"
"Not dead, nor not of the living. "
"Spirits of the interregnum, I call. "
Come on, Willow!
"Let him know
the pain of humanity, Gods. "
"Reach your wizened hands to me.
Give me the sword. "
Get out! Go!
Go!
Jeez, is it me
or is your heart not in this?
Maybe I'll just go home
destroy the world.
Well, I think Mr. Pointy'll
have something to say about that.
Come on, let's finish this.
You and me.
You never learn, do you?
This wasn't about you.
This was never about you.
And you fall for it every single time!
Enough!
Look at me, dearie.
Be... in my eyes.
Be in me.
Night-night.
Let's get what we came for, dears.
Bottom line is,
even if you see 'em comin...
you're not ready for the big moments.
No one asks for their life to change,
not really.
But it does.
So what are we? Helpless? Puppets?
No. The big moments are gonna come,
you can't help that.
It's what you do afterwards
that counts.
That's when you find out who you are.
Freeze!
You'll see what I mean.
Subtitles extended & timed by UAR
www.tvsubtitles.net