(# "Never an Easy Way" by Morcheeba)
# I think I slip the net
# But I cut myself free
# I'm not losing yet
# So don't forget me
# I'll say it, replay it
Passion,
It lies in all of us...
sleeping, waiting,
And though unwanted, unbidden...
it will stir, open its jaws...
and howl,
# I'm on my knees to pray
# You'd think I learn by now
# There's never an easy way
# I'll get through somehow
It speaks to us...
guides us,
Passion rules us all...
and we obey,
What other choice do we have?
"Passion"
- He was in my room.
- Who?
Angel. He was in my room last night.
- Are you sure?
- Positive.
When I woke up, I found a picture
he'd left me on my pillow.
A visit from the pointed-tooth fairy.
Wait. I thought vampires can't come in
unless you invited them in.
Yes, but, uh, once you've invited them in,
thereafter they're, they're always welcome.
You know I think there may be
a valuable lesson for you gals here.
About inviting strange men
into your bedrooms.
Oh, God! I invited him in my car once!
That means he can come into my car...
whenever he wants.
Yep, you're doomed to having to give
him and his vamp pal a lift
whenever they feel like it.
And those guys never chip in for gas.
Giles, there has to be some sort of spell
to reverse the invitation, right?
Like a barrier, a "no shoes, no pulse -
no service" kind of thing?
- Yeah, that works for a car, too?
- Yes, well, I, I, I can check on my...
Hello?
Excuse me, but
have you ever heard of knocking?
We're supposed to get some books.
- On Stalin.
- Does this look like a Barnes&Noble?
- This is the school library, Xander.
- Since when?
Uh, yes, yes. Third row,
historical biographies.
Thanks.
What?
Oh!
Hey, did you say that was the...?
Hello?
So, Angel has decided
to step up his harassment of you.
By sneaking in her room
and leaving stuff at night?
Why doesn't he just slit her throat
or strangle her while she's sleeping
or... cut her heart out?
What? I'm trying to help.
Yes. Uh, look, it's-it's
classic battle strategy -
to throw one's opponent off his game.
He-he-he's just trying to provoke you.
Uh, to taunt you, to, to goad you into,
uh, some mishap of some sort.
The nah-nah-nah-nah-nah-nah
approach to battle.
Yes, Xander. Once more you've managed
to boil a complex thought
down to its simplest form.
Giles, Angel once told me that when
he was obsessed with Drusilla,
the first thing he did
was to kill her family.
- Your mom...
- I know.
I'm gonna have to tell her something.
- The truth?
- No. You-you-you-you can't do that.
Yeah! The more people who know the secret,
the more it cheapens it for the rest of us!
I've gotta tell her something.
I've gotta do something!
Giles, Angel has
an all-access pass to my house
and I'm not always there when
my mother is. I can't protect her.
- I told you, I will find a spell.
- What about until you find a spell?
Until then, you and your mother are
welcome to ride around with me in my car.
Buffy, I-I understand your concern,
but it's imperative that you keep
a level head through all this.
That's easy for you to say. You don't have
Angel lurking in your bedroom at night.
I know how hard this is for you.
All right, I don't. But as the Slayer...
you don't have the luxury
of being a slave to your, your passions.
You mustn't let Angel get to you,
no matter how provocative
his behaviour may become.
So what you're basically saying is
just ignore him and maybe he'll go away?
Yes, precisely.
Hey, how come Buffy
doesn't get a snotty
"once again you boil it down
to the simplest form" thing?
Watcher's pet!
Don't forget I need your sample
spreadsheets by the end of the week.
Oh-oh, and I want both a paper printout
and a copy on disk. Thank you.
- Willow.
- Yes?
Uh, I might be a little late tomorrow.
Do you think you could
cover my class till I show?
Really? Me? Teach the class? Sure!
- Cool.
- Oh, wait.
W-what if they
don't recognize my authority?
What if they try to convince me
that you always let them leave early?
What if there's a fire drill?
What if there's a fire?!
Willow... you're gonna be fine.
- And I'll try not to be too late, OK?
- OK, good. Earlier is good.
Will I have the power to assign detention?
Or make 'em run laps?
- Hey, Will.
- Hey, Buffy. Rupert.
Willow, I thought I might take in a class.
Figured I could use someone
who knows where they are.
Sorry. I have to talk to her.
She's a teacher
and teachers are to be respected, even if
they're only filling in until the real
teacher shows up because
otherwise chaos could ensue.
How have you been?
Uh, not so good, actually. Um...
Since Angel lost his soul,
he's regained his sense of whimsy.
- Well, that sounds bad.
- He's been in Buffy's bedroom.
I, I need to... drum up a spell to, uh,
keep him out of the house.
This might help.
I've been doin' a little reading
since Angel changed.
- I don't think you have that one.
- Thank you.
So how's Buffy doing?
How do you think?
- I know you feel betrayed.
- Yes, well,
that's one of the
unpleasant side effects of... betrayal.
Rupert...
I was raised by the people
that Angel hurt the most.
My duty to them
was the first thing I was ever taught.
I didn't come here to hurt anyone.
And I lied to you because I thought
it was the right thing to do. I...
I didn't know what would happen.
I didn't know I was gonna
fall in love with you.
Oh, God...
Is it too late to take that back?
Do you want to?
I just wanna be right with you.
I don't expect more.
I just want so badly
to make all this up to you.
I understand.
But I'm not the one
you need to make it up to.
Thank you for the book.
OK... What's wrong?
No, it's nothing.
Come on, you can tell me anything,
I've read all the parenting books.
You cannot surprise me.
Do you remember that guy, Angel?
Angel? The, um...
The college boy
who was tutoring you in... history?
Right.
He... I...
Oh, God. Um...
We're sort of dating.
Were dating. Um...
Going through a serious
"off again" phase right now.
Don't tell me. He's changed?
He's not the same guy you fell for?
In a nutshell.
A-anyway, um...
Since he... changed,
he's been kinda following me around.
- He's having trouble letting go.
- Buffy, has he done anything?
No! No, it's not like that.
He's just been hanging around...
A lot.
Just sending me notes,
that kind of thing.
I just don't wanna see him right now.
I mean, If he shows up,
I'll talk to him. Just...
don't invite him in.
I agree with Giles.
You need to just try
and not let him get to you.
Angel's only doing this to try
to get you to do something stupid.
I swear, men can be
such jerks sometimes.
Dead or alive.
I just hope Giles
can find a keep-out spell soon,
I know I'll sleep easier
when I can...
sleep easier.
I'm sure he will.
He's, like, Book Man.
Until then, try
and keep happy thoughts and...
And what?
Willow?
Thanks for having me over, Buffy.
Especially on a school night and all.
No problem.
Hey, sorry about your fish.
Oh, it's OK.
We hadn't really had time to bond yet.
Although, for the first time,
I'm glad my parents
didn't let me have a puppy.
It's so weird.
Every time something like this happens,
my first instinct is still
to run to Angel.
I can't believe it's the same person.
He's completely different
from the guy that I knew.
Well, sort of, except...
Except what?
You're still the only thing
he thinks about.
I brought something for you.
Poor thing. She's an orphan.
Her owner died...
without a fight.
Do you like her?
Mm?
I brought her especially for you.
To cheer you up.
And I've named her...
Sunshine.
Open wide.
Come on, love.
You need to eat something
to keep your strength up.
Now...
- Open up for Mommy!
- I won't have you feeding me
- like a child, Dru!
- Why not?
She already bathes you,
carries you around
and changes you like a child.
Why, Angel. Where have you been?
The sun is almost up
and it can be so hurtful.
- We were worried.
- No, we weren't.
You must forgive Spike.
He's just a bit testy tonight.
Doesn't get out much any more.
Well, maybe next time
I'll bring you with me, Spike.
It might be handy to have you around
if I ever need a really good parking space.
Have you forgotten
you're a bloody guest in my bloody home?
And as a guest, if there's
anything I can do for you,
any... responsibility I can assume
while you're spinning your wheels...
- Anything I'm not already doing, that is.
- That's enough!
You two boys...
fighting over me and all...
makes a girl feel...
- Dru, what is it, pet?
- The air...
It worries.
Someone... an old enemy,
is seeking help.
Help to destroy our happy home.
Oh...
Welcome. How may I serve you today?
- Uh...
- Love potion?
Perhaps a voodoo doll
for that unfaithful...
I need an orb of Thesulah.
Oh, you're in the trade!
Sorry about the spiel,
but around Valentine's Day
I get a lot of tourists
shopping for love potions
and... mystical revenge
of past lovers.
Sad fact is,
Ouija boards and rabbits' feet -
that's what pay the rent around here.
- So how'd you hear about us?
- My Uncle Enyos told me about you.
So you're Janna, then.
I'm sorry to hear about your uncle.
- Thank you.
- He was a good customer.
Well, no, there you go
One Thesulan orb:
spirit vault
for the rituals of the undead.
I don't get many calls for those lately.
Sold a couple as
New Age paperweights last year.
Yeah, I just love
those New Agers, boy.
They helped to...
send my youngest to college.
By the way,
you do know that the transliteration annals
for the Ritual of the Undead were lost?
Without the annals,
the surviving text is gibberish.
And without a translated text,
the orbs of Thesulah
are pretty much useless.
I know.
Well, I only mentioned it because
I have a strict policy of no refunds.
It's OK.
I'm working on a computer program
to... translate
the Rumanian liturgy to English
based on a random sampling
of the text.
Ugh! I don't like computers.
- They give me the willies.
- Well, thank you.
You're welcome.
By the way! Not that it's
any of my business, really, but, uh...
What are you planning on conjuring up
if you can decipher the text?
A present for a friend of mine.
Really?
What are you gonna give him?
His soul.
We'll be in hiding, probably...
- Where?
- Siberia.
Well, good morning, ladies.
What did you two do last night?
We had kind of a "pyjama party
sleepover with weapons" thing.
Oh, and I don't suppose either of you
had the presence of mind
to locate a camera to...
capture the moment?
I have to go. I have a class to teach
in about five minutes
and I have to arrive early to glare
disapprovingly at the stragglers.
Oh, darn. She's here.
Five hours of lesson planning
yesterday down the drain.
You know what? I'll see you in class.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Uh, is there something...?
Did you want something?
Look, I know you feel badly
about what happened
and I just wanted to say...
Good. Keep it up.
- Don't worry, I will.
- Oh, wait. Um...
He misses you.
He doesn't say anything to me,
but I know he does.
And I don't want him to be lonely.
I don't want anyone to.
Buffy, you know that
if I have a chance
- to make this up...
- We're good here.
Let's just leave it.
I put it here somewhere.
Oh, yes, yes. That's it.
Could you, uh, hang those up?
Thank you, it's all.
Buffy. So...
So how was your night?
Sleepless, but no human fatalities.
I-I found a ritual to revoke...
the invitation to, to vampires.
Oh, thank goodness! I actually had to
talk my grandmother into
switching cars with me last night.
Um, the-the-the, uh,
the ritual's fairly basic, actually.
It's just the recitation
of a few rhyming couplets
burning of, uh, moss herbs,
sprinkling of holy water...
- All stuff I have in my house.
- Hanging crosses...
I'm gonna have a hard time
explaining this to my dad.
You really think it'll bother him?
Ira Rosenberg's only daughter
nailing crucifixes to her bedroom wall?
I have to go over
to Xander's house just to watch
'A Charlie Brown Christmas' every year.
- I see your point.
- Although it is worthwhile
to see him do the Snoopy Dance!
Willow, are you aware that
there are no fish in your aquarium?
You know, Cordelia,
we've already done your car.
- Call it a night, if you want.
- Right. Thanks.
And you know I'd do the same for you
if you had a social life.
Oh! This must be for you.
It's for you.
Mom.
Mrs. Summers, I need to talk to you.
You're Angel.
Did Buffy tell you about us?
She told me she wants you
to leave her alone.
- Oh, I can't. I can't do that.
- You're scaring her.
You have to help me.
Joyce, I need to be with her. You can
convince her. You have to convince her.
Look, I'm telling you to leave her alone.
You have to talk to her for me, Joyce.
Tell her I need her.
Please, look,
I-I just want to get inside, OK?
You don't understand, Joyce.
I'll die without Buffy.
She'll die without me.
- Are you threatening her?
- Please! Why is she doing this to me?
I'm calling the police, now.
I haven't been able to sleep
since the night we made love.
I need her.
I know you understand.
Just leave us alone.
'His verbis consensus rescissus est.'
(With these words permission is withdrawn)
Sorry, Angel. Changed the locks.
- Hello?
- Oh!
Hey.
- You're... working late?
- Special project.
- I spoke to Buffy today.
- Oh!
Yes?
She said you missed me.
Well, uh, she's... a meddlesome girl.
Rupert...
OK, I don't want to
say anything if I'm wrong,
but I may have some news.
You know, I need to finish up here.
Could I see you later?
Yes, yes...
You could stop by my house.
OK.
Good.
Sorry, honey. We're closed.
- What do you want?
- Miss Sunshine, here,
tells me you had a visitor today.
But she worries.
She wants to know what you
and the mean teacher talked about.
Come on. Come on.
That's it.
It's gonna work! This... will work.
Angel.
- How did you get in here?
- I was invited.
The sign in front of the school:
"Formatia trans sicere educatorum, "
"Enter all ye who seek knowledge."
What can I say?
I'm a knowledge seeker.
Angel, I've got good news.
I heard. You went shopping at
the local boogedy-boogedy store.
The orb of Thesulah.
If memory serves, this is supposed
to summon a person's soul...
From the ether...
Store it until it can be transferred.
You know what I hate most
about these things?
They're so damn fragile.
Must be that shoddy,
gypsy craftsmanship, huh?
I never seize to be amazed
how much the world has changed
in just two and a half centuries.
It's a miracle to me.
You-you put the secrets
to restoring my soul... here!
It comes out here!
"The Ritual of Restoration."
Wow. This... This brings back memories.
- Wait, that's your...
- Oh, my cure?
No, thanks. Been there, done that...
Déja vu just isn't what it used to be.
Boy, isn't this my lucky day?
The computer...
and the pages.
Looks like I get to kill two birds...
with one stone.
The teacher... makes... three.
Oh, good.
I need to work up an appetite first.
Sorry, Jenny. This is where you get off.
I never get tired of doing that.
- Willow. Good evening.
- Hi. Come on in.
- Here's the book.
- Right.
Guess, I should
do my apartment tonight.
- The ritual go all right?
- Oh, yeah, it went fine.
Well, it went fine
until Angel showed up
and told Buffy's mom
that he and Buffy had...
Well, you know.
That they had... you know.
- You do... know, right?
- Oh! Yes, yes, sorry.
Oh, good. 'Cause I just realized that,
being a librarian and all,
you... maybe didn't know.
No, thank you. I got it.
You would've been proud of her, though.
She totally kept her cool.
OK, well, I'll tell Buffy you stopped by.
Would you, um... Perhaps I should, uh,
intervene on, on Buffy's behalf
w-w-with her mother?
Maybe... say something?
Sure. Like, what would you say?
W... Uh...
- You will tell Buffy I dropped by?
- You bet.
That stuff with the...
Latin and the herbs, uh,
he's just real superstitious.
Oh.
- We just thought if...
- Was he the first?
No, wait. I don't wanna know.
I don't think I want to.
Yeah, he was the first.
I mean, the only.
- He's older than you.
- I know.
Too old, Buffy.
And he's obviously not very stable.
I really wish...
I just thought you would
show more judgment.
He wasn't like this before.
Are you in love with him?
- I was.
- Were you careful?
- Mom, this is no time...
- Don't "Mom" me, Buffy!
You don't get to get out of this.
You had sex with a boy
you didn't even see fit
to tell me you were dating.
- I made a mistake.
- Yeah, well, don't you just say that
to shut me up,
because I think you really did.
I know that!
- I can't tell you everything!
- How about anything?
Buffy, you can shut me out of your life,
I am pretty much used to that.
But don't expect me
to ever stop caring about you,
because it's never gonna happen.
I love you
more than anything in the world.
That would be your cue to, uh...
roll your eyes
and tell me I'm grossing you out.
You're not.
Oh, well...
I guess that was "the talk".
So how'd it go?
I don't know. It was my first.
Hello?
Jenny?
It's me!
# Sei mia
# V'aspettan gli amici
# Già mi mandi via?
# Vorrei dir, ma non oso
# Di'!
# O soave fanciulla
# O dolce viso
# di mite circonfuso alba lunar
# In te ravviso
# Il sogno ch'io vorrei
# sempre sognar!
# Ah, tu sol
# comandi, amor!
# Le dolcezze estreme
# Tu sol comandi, amor!
Mr. Giles, I need to ask you
to come with us.
Just to... answer a few questions.
Of course.
Yes.
Procedure.
I need to make a phone call,
if that's all right?
Passion is the source
of our finest moments:
the joy of love...
the clarity of hatred...
and the ecstasy of grief...
Giles?
Hello?
Really? No...
No...
No!
- Where's Giles?
- No luck.
By the time we got to the station,
the cops said he'd already left
I guess they just wanted
to ask him some questions.
Cordelia, will you
drive us to Giles' house?
Of course.
But don't you think
he wants to be left alone?
I'm not worried about what he wants.
I'm worried about what he's gonna do.
Hello?
Giles?
I guess Giles had
a big night planned tonight.
Giles didn't set this up.
Angel did.
This is the wrapping for the gift.
Oh, man.
Poor Giles.
Look, all his weapons are gone.
But I thought
he kept his weapons at the library.
No, those are his, uh,
everyday weapons.
These were his good weapons.
The ones he, uh...
breaks out when company comes to visit.
- So he's not here?
- Well, then where is he?
- He'll go to wherever Angel is.
- That means the factory, right?
So Giles is gonna try to kill Angel then.
- Well, it's about time somebody did.
- Xander!
I'm sorry, but let's not forget
that I hated Angel
long before you, guys,
jumped on the bandwagon.
So I think I deserve a little something
for not saying
'I told you so' long before now.
And if Giles wants to go after the, uh...
fiend that murdered his girlfriend,
I say 'Faster, pussycat. Kill, kill!'
- You're right.
- Thank you.
There's only one thing wrong
with Giles' little revenge scenario.
- And what's that?
- It's gonna get him killed.
Are you insane?
We're supposed to kill the bitch,
not leave gag gifts in her friends' beds.
But, Spike, the bad teacher
was going to restore Angel's soul.
What if she did? If you ask me,
I find myself preferring
the old Buffy-whipped Angelus.
'Cause this new, improved one
is not playing with a full sack.
I love a good slaughter
as much as the next bloke,
but his little pranks will only leave us
with one incredibly brassed-off Slayer!
Don't worry, Roller Boy.
I've got everything under control.
Jeez, whatever happened
to wooden stakes?
Uh-uh. No fair going into the ring
unless he tags you first.
All right. You've had your fun.
But you know what it's time for now?
My fun!
Gonna let your old man just burn?
Why did you come here?
This wasn't your fight!
Are you trying to get yourself killed?
You can't leave me.
I can't do this alone.
It hurts sometimes
more than we can bear.
If we could live without passion,
maybe we'd know some kind of peace...
but we would be hollow:
empty rooms...
shuttered and dank...
Without passion...
we'd be truly dead.
In my years as... Watcher...
I've buried... too many people.
But Jenny was the first I've loved.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I couldn't kill him for you...
For her...
When I had the chance.
I wasn't ready.
But I think I finally am.
Hi.
Principal Snyder asked me
to fill in for Ms Calendar...
until the new
computer-science teacher arrives.
So, I'm just gonna stick to
the lesson plan she left.
I can't hold on to the past any more.
Angel is gone.
Nothing's ever gonna bring him back.
Subtitles extended & timed by UAR
www.tvsubtitles.net