In every generation, there is a Chosen One.
She alone will stand against the vampires,
the demons and the forces of darkness.
She is the Slayer.
Zachary didn't return
from the hunt last night.
The Slayer.
Zachary was strong and he was careful.
But still the Slayer takes him,
as she has taken so many of my family.
It wears thin.
- Collin, what would you do about it?
- I'd annihilate her.
- Out of the mouths of babes...
- Let me do it, Master.
- Let me kill her for you.
- You have a personal interest in this.
- I don't get to have any fun.
- I will send the Three.
The Three?
Let's go.
Get it. Come on, get it right there.
I got it.
Free drink, please.
The Fumigation Party.
It's an annual tradition.
The closing of the Bronze for a few days
to nuke the cockroaches.
It's a lot of fun.
What's it like where you are?
I'm sorry. I was just...
thinking about things.
- So, we're talking about a guy?
- Not exactly a guy.
For us to have a conversation about a guy,
there'd have to be a guy for us
to have a conversation about.
- Is that a sentence?
- You lack a guy.
I do. Which is fine with me
most of the time, but...
What about Angel?
Angel? I can just
see him in a relationship.
"Hi, honey, you're in grave danger.
I'll see ya next month."
He's not around much, it's true.
When he is around,
it's like the lights dim everywhere else.
You know how it's like that
with some guys?
- Oh, yeah.
Hey, Annie!
Dino! Just leaving.
Please get your extreme oafishness
off my $200 shoes.
- Sorry, I was just...
- Getting off the dance floor,
before Annie Vega's boyfriend
squashes you like a bug?
Oh, so you noticed.
Yeah, thanks for being so understanding.
- Sure.
- You know, hey, I don't know what
everyone's talking about. That outfit
doesn't make you look like a hooker.
Boy, that Cordelia's
a regular breath of vile air.
What are you vixens up to?
Just sitting here
watching our barren lives pass us by.
Oh, look. A cockroach.
Whoa! Let's stop this
crazy whirligig of fun. I'm dizzy.
All right. Now I'm infecting those nearest
and dear to me. I'm gonna call it a night.
- Oh, don't go.
- Yeah, it's early. We could, um... dance.
Rain check? Good night.
Want a free drink?
It's late, I'm tired
and I don't wanna play games.
Show yourself.
OK. OK. Nice.
OK. OK. Look, I really don't wanna
fight all three of you unless I have to.
"Angel"
Good dogs don't... bite.
Look out!
Run!
Get in! Come on! No!
It's all right. A vampire
can't come in unless it's invited.
I've heard that before,
but I've never put it to the test.
I'll go get some bandages. Just...
take your jacket and your shirt off.
Nice tattoo.
I was lucky you came along.
How did you happen to come along?
I live nearby. I was just out walking.
So, you weren't following me?
- I just had this feeling you were.
- Why would I do that?
You tell me.
You're the mystery guy
that appears out of nowhere.
I'm not saying
I'm not happy about it tonight, but...
if you are hanging around,
I'd like to know why.
- Maybe I like you.
- Maybe?
Honey, what are you doing?
There's a lot of weird people
outside at night. I just...
feel better with you safe and sound inside.
You must be beat.
I am. We're a little gallery.
You have no idea how much...
Then why don't you go upstairs and get
into bed and I can bring you some hot tea.
That's sweet. What'd you do?
Can't a daughter just be concerned
about her mother?
- Hi.
Oh. OK.
Angel, this is my mom.
Mom, this is Angel.
We ran into each other on the way home.
Nice to meet you.
- What do you do, Angel?
- He's a student.
Uh, first year... community college.
Angel's been helping me with my history.
- You know I've been toiling there.
- It's a little late for tutoring.
I'm gonna go to bed. And Buffy?
I'll say good night and do the same.
It was nice to meet you.
Good night.
We'll hook up soon
and do that study thing!
Look, I don't wanna
get you in any more trouble.
And I don't wanna get you dead.
They could still be out there.
So...
Two of us. One bed.
That doesn't work.
Um... Why don't you take the bed?
You know, you're wounded.
- I'll take the floor.
- No, that's not...
Believe me, I've had worse.
OK.
Um, then... Why don't you check and see
if the Fang Gang is still loitering
and, um... keep your back turned
while I change?
I don't see them.
You know, I'm the Chosen One.
It's my job to fight guys like that.
- What's your excuse?
- Uh, somebody has to.
Well, what does your family
think of your career choice?
They're dead.
Was it vampires?
It-it was.
I'm sorry.
It was a long while ago.
So, this is a vengeance gig for you?
You even look pretty when you go to sleep.
Well, when I wake up,
it's an entirely different story.
Here.
Sleep tight.
Angel?
Hmm?
Do you snore?
I don't know.
It's been a long time since anybody's
been in a position to let me know.
He spent the night?
In your room? In your bed?
- Not in my bed. By my bed.
- That is so romantic.
Did you, uh...?
I mean, did he, uh...?
Perfect gentleman.
Buffy! Come on.
Wake up and smell the seduction.
- It's the oldest trick in the book.
- What?
Saving my life?
Getting slashed in the ribs?
Duh! I mean, guys'll do anything
to impress a girl.
I-I once drank an entire gallon of Gatorade
without taking a breath.
It was pretty impressive.
Although later there was an ick factor.
Can we steer this riveting conversation
back to the events that
happened earlier in the evening?
You left the Bronze and were set upon
by three unusually virile vampires.
- Did they look like this?
- Yeah. What's with the uniforms?
It seems you encountered the Three.
Warrior vampires.
Very proud and very strong.
How is it you always know this stuff?
You always know what's going on.
I never know what's going on.
You weren't here from midnight
until six researching it.
No. I was sleeping.
Obviously you're hurting
the Master very much.
He wouldn't send the Three
for just anyone.
We must step up
our training with weapons.
Buffy, you should stay at my house
until these Samurai guys are history.
- What?
- Ah-ah-ah, don't worry about Angel.
Willow can run to your house
and tell him to get out of town fast.
Angel and Buffy are,
are not in any immediate jeopardy.
Eventually the Master will send
someone else, but, in the meantime,
the Three having failed
will offer their own lives in penance.
We failed in our duty,
and now our lives belong to you.
Pay attention, child.
You are the Anointed
and there is much you must learn.
With power comes responsibility.
True, they did fail.
But also true,
we who walk at night share a common bond.
The taking of a life -
I'm not talking about humans, of course -
is a serious matter.
So, you would spare them?
I am weary,
and their deaths will bring me little joy.
Of course sometimes a little is enough.
Cool. Crossbow.
Check out these babies.
Goodbye, stakes. Hello, flying fatality.
- What can I shoot?
- Nothing.
The crossbow comes later.
You must first become proficient
with the basic tools of combat.
Now, let's begin...
with the quarterstaff,
which incidentally will require
countless hours of vigorous training.
- I speak from experience.
- Giles, 20th century?
I'm not gonna be fighting Friar Tuck.
You never know with whom or what
you'll be fighting.
These traditions have been handed down
through the ages.
Now, you show me good, steady
progress with the quarterstaff
and in due course we'll discuss
the crossbow. Put on your pads.
I'm... not gonna need pads to fight you.
We'll see about that. En garde!
Good. Let's move on to the crossbow.
- Angel?
- Hey.
I brought you some dinner.
It's a little plateless. Sorry.
So. What did you do all day?
I read a little. And just thought about
a lot of things. Buffy, I...
My diary? You read my diary?
That is not OK. A diary is like
a person's most private place.
You don't even know
what I was writing about!
Hunk can mean a lot of things. Bad things.
And, and when it says that your eyes
are 'penetrating', I meant to write...
- 'bulgy'.
- Buffy...
And 'A' doesn't even stand for
'Angel' for that matter, it stands for...
'Ahmed', a charming
foreign exchange student
so that whole fantasy part has nothing
to even do with you at all...
Your mother moved your diary
when she came in to straighten up.
I watched her from the closet.
I didn't read it. I swear.
Oh.
I did a lot of thinking today.
I really can't be around you.
- Because when I am...
- Hey, no big. Water... over the bridge.
all I can think about
is how badly I wanna kiss you.
Kiss me?
I'm older than you, and this can't ever...
I better go.
How much older?
- I should...
- Go.
You said...
What? What's wrong?
Buffy, what happened?
Nothing. I saw a shadow.
- Angel's a vampire?
- I can't believe this is happening.
One minute we were kissing
and the next minute...
Can a vampire ever be a good person?
Couldn't it happen?
A vampire isn't a person at all.
It may have the movements, memories,
even the personality of the person
that it took over, but it-
it's still a demon at the core.
There is no halfway.
So that'd be a no, huh?
Well, then what was he doing?
Why was he good to me?
Was it all some part of the Master's plan?
It doesn't make sense!
All right, uh, you have a problem
and it's not a small one.
Let's take a breath
and look at this calmly and objectively.
Angel's a vampire. You're a slayer.
I think it's obvious what you have to do.
- It is a slayer's duty.
- I know you have feelings for this guy.
But you're not in love with him, right?
In love with a vampire?
Are you out of your mind?
What?
Not vampire.
How could you love an umpire?
Everyone hates 'em.
Where did you get that dress?
This is a one-of-a-kind Todd Oldham.
Do you know how much this dress cost?
Is this a knockoff?
This is a knockoff, isn't it?!
Some cheesy knockoff!
This is exactly what happens
when you sign these free trade agreements.
You think we have problems.
Who's here?
A friend.
Hi. It's been a while.
- A lifetime.
- Or two, but who's counting?
What's with the Catholic schoolgirl look?
Last time I saw you, it was kimonos.
And last time I saw you,
it wasn't high-school girls.
Don't you like?
Remember Budapest?
Turn of the century?
You were a bad boy during that earthquake.
You did some damage yourself.
Is there anything better
than a natural disaster?
The panic. The people lost in the streets.
It's like picking fruit off the vine.
Nice. You're living above ground.
Like one of them.
You and your new friend are attacking us.
But guess what, precious?
You're not one of them.
- Are you?
- No.
But I'm not exactly one of you, either.
Is that what you tell yourself these days?
You're not exactly living off quiche.
You and I both know what you hunger for,
what you need.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
It's who we are.
It's what makes eternal life worth living.
You can only suppress your real nature
for so long.
I can feel it brewing inside of you.
I hope I'm around when it explodes.
- Maybe you don't wanna be.
- I'm not afraid of you.
I bet she is, though.
Or... maybe I'm underestimating her.
Talk to her. Tell her about the curse.
Maybe she'll come around.
And if she still doesn't trust you,
you know where I'll be.
Here's something at last.
Can you, please,
warn us before you do that?
There's nothing about Angel in the text,
but it suddenly occurred to me that
it's been ages since I've read the diaries
of any of the watchers before me.
That must've been so embarrassing
when you thought
he had read your diary,
but then it turned out he hadn't
but then he felt the same way...
- I'm listening.
- There's mention some 200 years ago
in Ireland of-of Angelus,
the one with the angelic face.
They got that right.
I'm not saying anything.
I have nothing to say.
Does this, uh, Angel have, um,
a tattoo behind his right shoulder?
Yeah. It's a bird or something.
Now I'm saying something.
You saw him naked?
- So Angel's been around for a while.
- Not long for a vampire. 240 years or so.
240. Well, he said he was older.
Angelus leaves Ireland,
wreaks havoc in Europe for several decades
and then about 80 years ago
the most curious thing happens.
He comes to America,
shuns other vampires and lives alone.
There's-there's no...
no record of him hunting here.
So he is a good vampire.
I mean, on a scale of one to ten.
Ten being someone
who's killing and maiming every night
and one being someone who's... not.
I say that there's no record. But...
Vampires hunt and kill.
It's what they do.
- Fish gotta swim, birds gotta fly.
- He could've fed on me. He didn't.
Question: a hundred years or so
before he came to our shores,
what was he like then?
Like all of them.
A vicious, violent animal.
Don't think I'm not grateful,
you letting me kill the Three.
How can my children learn
if I do everything for them?
But you've gotta let me
take care of the Slayer.
You're giving me orders now.
OK. We'll just do nothing
while she takes us out one by one.
Do I sense a plan, Darla?
Share.
Angel kills her
and comes back to the fold.
Angel. He was
the most vicious creature I ever met.
- I miss him.
- So do I.
Why would he kill her
if he feels for her?
To keep her from killing him.
You see? How we all work together
for the common good?
That's how a family is
supposed to function.
OK, so let's review.
Reconstruction began when?
Buffy?
Reconstruction.
Reconstruction began
after the... construction,
which was shoddy,
so they had to reconstruct.
After the destruction of the Civil War.
Right. Civil War. During which Angel
was already 100 and change.
Are we gonna talk about boys
or are we gonna help you pass history?
Sometimes I have this fantasy
that Xander's just gonna grab me
and kiss me right on the lips.
If you want Xander,
you've gotta speak up, girl.
No, no, no, no. No speaking up.
That way leads
to madness and sweaty palms.
OK, so here's something I gotta know.
When Angel kissed you...
I mean, before he turned into...
How was it?
Unbelievable.
Wow. And it is kinda novel how
he'll stay young and handsome forever.
Although you'll still get wrinkly
and die and...
Oh, what about the children?
- I'll be quiet now.
- No, it's OK.
I need to hear this.
I need to get over him, so I can...
So that you can...
Like Xander said, I'm the Slayer
and he's a... vampire. God, I can't.
He's never done anything to hurt me.
OK, I need to stop thinking about this.
OK, let's give it another half an hour
and maybe something will sink in.
Then I'm going home
for some major moping.
OK. The era of the Congressional
Reconstruction, usually called Radical...
- Hello?
- Hi, I'm Darla.
- A friend of Buffy's.
- Oh, nice to meet you.
She didn't mention anything about me
coming over for a study date, did she?
No, I thought she was studying
with Willow at the library.
She is. Willow's the Civil War expert.
But then I was supposed to help her
with the War of Independence.
My family kinda goes back to those days.
Well, I, I know she's supposed to be home
soon. Would you like to come in and wait?
It's very nice of you
to invite me into your home.
You're welcome.
I've been wrestling with the IRS all night.
- Would you like something to eat?
- Yes. I would.
Let's see what we have.
Do you feel like something little
or something big?
Something big.
Let her go.
I just had a little. There's plenty more.
Aren't you hungry for something warm
after all this time?
Come on, Angel. Just say yes.
Welcome home.
Hey. I'm home.
You're not welcome here.
You come near us and I'll kill you.
Mom? Mom, can you hear me?
Yes. I need an ambulance.
1630 Revello Drive.
My mother cut herself.
She lost a lot of blood.
Please, please hurry.
- Mom?
- Hey, Buffy.
- Oh, my God!.
- What happened?
Angel.
- Do you remember anything, Mom?
- Just... Your friend came over.
- I was gonna make a snack.
- My friend?
I guess I slipped and cut my neck on...
The doctor said
it looked like a barbecue fork.
We don't have a barbecue fork.
Are you another doctor?
No. Mom, this is Mr. Giles.
The librarian from your school.
What's he doing here?
I just came to pay my respects.
Wish you a speedy recovery.
Boy, the teachers
really do care in this town.
Get some rest now.
She's gonna be OK.
They gave her some iron.
Her blood count was a little...
A little low.
It presents itself like mild anemia.
You were lucky you got to her
as soon as you did.
Lucky? Stupid.
- Buff, it's not your fault.
- No? I invited him into my home.
Even after I knew who he was,
what he was.
And I didn't do anything about it.
Because I had feelings for him.
Because I cared about him.
If you care about somebody,
you care about them.
- You can't change that by...
- Killing them?
Maybe not. But I think it's a start.
- We'll keep an eye on your mom.
- Buffy!
You can't stop me.
The Three found me near the Bronze.
- And so did he. He lives nearby.
- This is no ordinary vampire.
If there is such a thing.
Now, he knows you.
He's faced the Three.
I think this is gonna
take more than a simple stake.
So do I.
She's out hunting you right now.
She wants to kill you.
- Leave me alone.
- What did you think?
Did you think she would understand?
That she would look at your face,
your true face,
and give you a kiss?
For 100 years you've not had
a moment's peace because
you will not accept who you are.
That's all you have to do. Accept it.
Don't let her hunt you down.
Don't whimper
and mewl like a mangy human.
Kill.
Feed. Live.
All right.
- What do you want?
- I want it finished.
That's good.
You're hurting me.
That's good, too.
She talks about you all the time.
It's important to have teachers
who make an impression.
She makes quite an impression herself.
I know she's having trouble with history.
Is it too difficult for her,
or is she not applying herself?
She lives very much in the now. And-and...
history, of course, is very much
about the... the then.
B-but there's-there's no reason...
She's studying with Willow.
She's studying with Darla.
I-I mean, she's trying.
Darla? I don't believe I know...
Her friend who came over tonight.
Darla came to your house tonight. She's
the friend that you mentioned earlier?
Poor thing. I must've frightened
her half to death when I fainted.
Someone should really check
and make sure she's all right.
Yes, someone should.
Right away. I'll do it.
That school is amazing.
We have a problem.
I know you're there.
And I know what you are.
Do you? I'm just an animal, right?
You're not an animal.
Animals I like.
Let's get it done.
Come on. Don't go soft on me now.
- A little wide.
- Why?
Why didn't you just attack me
when you had the chance?
Was it a joke?
To make me feel for you and then...
I've killed a lot of vampires.
I've never hated one before.
Feels good, doesn't it?
It feels simple.
I invited you into my home
and then you attacked my family.
Why not? I killed mine.
I killed their friends.
And their friends' children.
For 100 years, I offered an ugly death
to everyone I met.
And I did it with a song in my heart.
- What changed?
- I fed on a girl about your age.
Beautiful. Dumb as a post,
but a favorite among her clan.
- Her clan?
- The Romany.
Gypsies. The elders conjured
the perfect punishment for me.
They restored my soul.
What, they were all out of
boils and blinding torment?
When you become a vampire,
the demon takes your body
but it doesn't get your soul.
That's gone. No conscience, no remorse.
It's an easy way to live.
You have no idea what it's like
to have done the things I've done,
and to care.
I haven't fed on a living human being
since that day.
So, you started with my mom?
- I didn't bite her.
- Then why didn't you say something?
But I wanted to.
I can walk like a man,
but I'm not one.
I wanted to kill you tonight.
Go ahead.
Not as easy as it looks.
Sure it is.
- We're near the Bronze. What now?
- Keep looking for her.
I have a question.
what if we find her and she's fighting
Angel and some of his friends?
What the heck
are we gonna do about it?
Do you know
what the saddest thing in the world is?
- Bad hair on top of that outfit?
- To love someone who used to love you.
You guys... were involved?
For several generations.
Well, you've been around since Columbus.
You are bound to pile up a few ex's.
You're older than him, right?
Just between us girls, you are
looking a little worn around the eyes.
I made him.
There was a time when we shared
everything. Wasn't there, Angelus?
You had a chance to come home,
to rule with me in the Master's court
for a thousand years.
But you threw that away because of her.
You love someone who hates us.
You're sick. And you'll always be sick.
And you'll always remember
what it was like to watch her die.
- You don't think I came alone, do you?
- I know I didn't.
Scary.
Scarier.
Don't worry. Bullets can't kill vampires.
It can hurt them like hell, but...
Did you just hear...?
So many body parts. So few bullets.
Let's begin with the kneecaps.
No fun dancing without them.
Close, but no heart.
We need to distract her. Fast.
Buffy, it wasn't Angel who
attacked your mom. It was Darla!
Come on, Buffy.
Take it like a man.
Angel?
Forget her.
How dare you. She was my favorite.
For 400 years.
She was weak. You don't need her.
I'll bring you the Slayer.
But to lose her to Angel.
He was to have sat at my right hand,
come the day.
- And now...
- They're all against you.
But soon you shall rise,
and when you do,
we'll kill them all.
Ah, the post-fumigation party.
Okay, so what's the difference between
this and the pre-fumigation party?
Much hardier cockroaches.
So, no word from Angel?
Nah.
It's weird, though. In his way
I feel like he's still watching me.
Well, in a way he sort of is.
In the way of that he's right over there.
(# "I'll remember you" by Sophie Zelmani)
# I can hear a heart beat
Is it yours or is it mine?
# I look at your lips
I know how soft they can be
And I don't need to watch
because I'm not threatened.
I'm just gonna look this way.
# Did they know what they wanted
# the times they kissed me?
# And your hands
I held in mine
I just wanted to see if you were OK
and your mother.
We're both good. You?
If I can go a little while without
getting shot or stabbed I'll be alright.
# I'll remember you
- Look, this can't...
- Ever be anything. I know.
For one thing, you're like
224 years older than I am.
# But that is all that I can do
I just gotta...
I gotta walk away from this.
I know. Me, too.
One of us has to go here.
I know.
# Your eyes
#  That always make me shiver
# Now they are closed
# They just sometimes twitch a little
- What's going on?
- Nothing.
Well, as long as they're not kissing.
# And your body
I could hold for an hour
# It sent me to Heaven
# With its heat and power...
You OK?
- It's just...
- Painful.
I know.
See you around?
# I'll remember you
And that is all that I can do
# But I'll remember...
Subtitles by Visiontext
Corrections & timing by UAR
...
www.tvsubtitles.net