Previously
on Buffy the Vampire Slayer:
- Why won't you sleep with me again?
- I don't love you.
- Hey. Clothes.
- Better not get used to 'em.
Yes, ma'am.
Say good night, bitch.
Good night, bitch.
- Don't do...
- I'm gonna make you feel it.
Stop!
Ask me again why I can never love you.
Get nice and comfy, Slayer. I'll be back.
And when I am... things are gonna change.
You think you can do that to me? You think
I'd let you get away with that? Think again.
Tara?
Tara?! Baby?
Buffy?
No!
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
She's in the back. This way.
- She was shot in the chest.
- Accidental?
No, no, it was a...
He was trying to kill her.
Oh, God! Oh, no! Please!
Please, come on!
Come on, Tara!
Please, come on, baby.
By Osiris...
I command you, bring her back.
Pulse is 100 and weak. Lung sounds are wet.
What does that mean? Is she gonna...?
You need to stand back, OK? If you want us
to help her out we need some space.
Hear me, keeper of darkness!
Witch, how dare you
invoke Osiris in this task?
Please. Please bring her back.
You may not violate the laws
of natural passing.
How? How is this natural?
It is a human death by human means.
You raised one killed by mystical forces.
This is not the same.
She is taken by natural order. It is done.
- No! There has to be a way!
- It is done!
No!
Sunnydale Memorial, do you copy? We have
a Caucasian female, 21. GSW to the chest.
Buff, hang on.
We're gonna get you to the hospital.
- Willow. My God, are you OK?
- How did this happen?
- Warren, he had a gun.
- Warren.
It went down too fast. I couldn't stop it.
Hey.
Will!
Sir, we have to go.
Are you coming with us or not?
Think they'll let my aunt
bring me my Discman?
That's what you're worried about?
In-flight entertainment? We're in jail.
We're in custody.
We haven't been charged yet.
Thank you, Dragnet.
It doesn't matter what they call it.
They got us, OK? We're goin' down.
That guy's been lookin' at me.
I think he wants to make me his butt monkey.
Don't flatter yourself.
He's in here for parking tickets.
That doesn't mean anything.
The joint changes you.
I hear they like the small ones
with little hands.
You have got to chill out.
This isn't Oz. It's, like, Mayberry.
Besides, Warren is gonna get us out of here.
I'm sure he'll be bustin' us out any minute.
He will. He's coming up with a plan.
Like WarGames. Remember that decoder
Matthew Broderick used?
Oh, yeah. That was rad. The one he made
from the scissors and the tape recorder.
I miss Ferris Matthew.
Broadway Matthew... I find him cold.
Really? No, I...
Shut up!
Nobody's coming to get us,
not even your aunt
- who won't return your one phone call.
- She must be out of town.
She doesn't care. And neither does
your partner in crime Warren.
Don't say that. What do you mean,
my partner in crime? We're in this together.
What do you mean, what do I mean? You two
were totally gonna leave me holding the bag.
- We weren't. I was... going to carry you.
- No.
You two were setting me up, and then
Warren was gonna screw you over too.
- That is so not true.
- Sure.
He's a nice murderer who keeps his word.
You're wrong.
He's coming for us.
He's out there right now devising a
brilliant way to get us out of here.
Whisky. Straight up. And get a round
for the house. I'm feelin' expansive.
Hey.
- Bet you don't get a lot of humans in...
- I'm watching my programme.
Wouldn't interrupt your me time.
Not even to buy the guy who
killed the Slayer a drink.
- What's that?
- I took her out myself.
I've been heading an organisation -
the Trio - you've heard of us.
No.
Not important. I cut them loose.
I figure now Buffy's out of the picture
some things have got to change.
I need a real gang.
Not a couple of wannabes.
- And you killed the Slayer?
- With these hands.
- What are you, a warlock?
- Funny you mention that.
I've explored all the dark arts -
witchcraft, demonology...
You name it, I tried it against the Slayer.
But you know what I found really works?
Gun.
- You killed the Slayer with a gun?
- In her own back yard.
Don't underestimate science, my friends.
Good old-fashioned metal meets propulsion.
- Oh, man, this is gonna be good.
- The best.
The town is ours!
Ours, maybe. You... are screwed.
Metal meets propulsion, yeah.
But you still better be a good shot.
This isn't the evil laugh of victory, is it?
More like the evil laugh of
"you're a dead man".
OK. What's the joke?
It was just on the news.
A girl was shot.
In her back yard.
She survived. She's in the hospital.
And Slayers heal fast. Real fast.
Yeah. I was gonna eat you myself
during the commercial,
but now I think it'll be more fun
to let the Slayer de-gut you.
Might wanna get a head start, my friend,
cos this girl's gonna be
comin' for you big time.
- Willow.
- Where do you keep the black-arts books?
Something terrible happened,
but you don't have to...
I need power.
Not with those books.
I can't let you. Willow!
Stop.
That's better.
Buffy?
Hey? Hello?
The door was...
Tara?
- All right, who's next?
- I am.
- You're new.
- Yeah.
I come bearing dead presidents, so you
think we can just skip the small talk?
- How'd you find me?
- I talked to a guy.
One of your regulars.
Offered to show me the way for 20 bucks.
Most of my customers
will bring you here for five.
Great. I'll file that away.
Look, I'm in a bit of a situation here.
I tried to do us all a favour
and eliminate the Slayer, but I...
I... I guess it didn't take.
Killin' a slayer.
That's big business for a kid.
I'm not a kid.
OK.
I had my own guys. The Trio.
Yeah, you've heard of us.
Right. What were you? A band or something?
I thought word travelled in the underworld.
We were evil. Robots were my thing.
- You didn't hear about the freeze ray?
- Sorry.
Why aren't your guys helping you?
I thought this was a
cash-for-a-service gig,
not an interview process. I need protection.
I've got the Slayer after me.
The Slayer is the least of your problems.
Oh, you right.
Let's talk about my skin troubles.
You know, I'd say,
on the scale of problems, that she ranks.
If I were you, I'd worry about the witch.
- Witch? Which witch?
- Willow.
The Slayer's pal.
She's the new power, man.
Anybody with intuition can feel it.
She's gonna blow this town apart.
Startin'... with you.
Me? What did I do to her?
Oh, OK, OK. I...
- I shot her friend.
- I feel death.
But the Slayer is alive, and she heals.
Yeah, she might, but somebody
is stone cold. And that...
is why the witch wants your head.
She can sense your essence right now, man.
It's just a matter of
time before she finds you.
Take it. There's that, and I can get more.
Just give me something.
- Hide or fight?
- Both. All of it.
I have a few tricks up my sleeve,
but it's not enough.
I need a cover and lots of fire power.
I can't guarantee anything. Not this time.
The girl is runnin' on pure fury.
I've never felt anything like it.
Thank you for the tip, Nostradamus.
Just load me up, OK?
Gotta stop that bleeding
by the left ventricle.
BP is down to 80 palp.
Got more bleeding.
What's happening?
Leave.
- Willow.
- Now.
Will, what are you doin'? She's gonna die.
No, she isn't.
It's so small.
- What happened?
- Buffy!
- Oh, my God, are you OK?
- Sure. How'd I get here?
You gotta stop doin' this.
This dying thing's funny once, maybe twice.
- Willow?
- Buffy. Hey.
- What's wrong?
- I'll explain.
- But we've gotta go.
- Why?
It's time to find Warren.
This'll get me all the way to the border?
You'll have to change bus.
It's all in the folder.
- Faster.
- I'm going as fast as I can.
- Faster!
- Cut that out. If you wanted to drive...
- Stop. I don't like this.
- We're close. I can feel him.
We'll catch him and he'll go to jail.
I'm finding getting shot very motivating.
- But you're using magic.
- If I wasn't, you'd be dead.
Maybe. But this isn't right.
OK? This isn't how I want it.
- Sometimes you don't have a choice.
- Buffy gets the tiebreaker on this.
- She was on the ouchy end of the bullet.
- Will, you do have a choice.
- This isn't good for you.
- You decided to stop for a reason.
You promised us. Can I ask what's with the
makeover of the damned? I mean, the hair...
- Turn right. Go!
- Where?
Over there! Now!
- Will...
- Turn.
Fine. Puppet master wants to drive?
Go right ahead!
- Willow, wait!
- Stay back!
Get out.
Please. I'll do anything.
It's a robot.
I could feel his essence.
- He tricked me. We'll find him another way.
- And then what?
- Then we'll kill him.
- You need to calm down.
- Calm down?
- Look, you're angry.
There's no excuse for what he did, but...
He shot Tara.
When he shot you, he hit her too.
Upstairs, in my room.
- Guess the last shot was the charm.
- She's dead?
She's dead. Now he's dead too.
Oh, my God.
Tara.
- Christ. How come you didn't say anything?
- I'm busy.
Willow, please, just stop.
We love you. And Tara.
But we don't kill humans. It's not the way.
How can you say that? Tara is dead.
I know. I know.
And I can't understand... anything.
Not what happened,
and not what you must be going through.
Willow, if you do this
you let Warren destroy you too.
You said it yourself, Will. The magic's
too strong. There's no coming back from it.
- I'm not coming back.
- Will, please!
- We'll get through this together.
- We won't. Not your way.
- Please, just...
- No. No more talking. It's done.
Willow?
Dawn?
Maybe she went to the hospital to find you.
I left there hours ago.
She would've been back by now.
Dawn?
Oh, God.
I didn't wanna leave her alone.
Dawn? Sweetheart.
Come on.
Honey, we need to get outta here, OK?
Dawn, sweetheart? Be strong for me, OK?
Dawn, we need to go downstairs.
I don't understand.
I don't understand either.
If you can just sign this?
Sure.
Call this number tomorrow.
We'll have more information.
OK, thanks.
- Thank you.
- I'm sorry for your loss.
- So that's it.
- Have the police gone too?
Coming back tomorrow
with more of their pretty yellow tape.
We need to find Willow.
Yeah, she's off the wagon big time.
- Warren's a dead man if she finds him.
- Good.
Dawn, don't say that.
Why not?
I'd do it myself if I could.
Because you don't really feel that way.
Yes, I do. And you should too.
He killed Tara and he nearly killed you.
He needs to pay.
- Out of the mouths of babes.
- Xander!
I'm just sayin', he's just as bad
as any vampire you sent to Dustville.
Being a Slayer
doesn't give me a licence to kill.
- Warren's human.
- So?
So the human world has its own rules
for dealing with people like him.
And we all know how well those rules work.
Sometimes they do.
Sometimes they don't.
We can't control the universe.
If we were supposed to, then the magic
wouldn't change Willow the way it does.
And... we'd be able to bring Tara back.
And Mom.
There are limits to what we can do.
There should be.
Willow doesn't wanna believe that.
And now she's messing with forces
that wanna hurt her. All of us.
I just...
I've had blood on my hands all day.
Blood from people I love.
I know.
And now it has to stop.
Warren's going to get what
he deserves. I promise.
But I will not let Willow destroy herself.
OK, where do we go? She could be anywhere.
I don't know. Maybe the Magic Box.
There's some kind of locating spell.
- I could... go myself.
- No, no, I'm cool. I'll go.
- Dawn can't stay here by herself.
- Let me go with you. I want to.
No, honey. It's too dangerous.
But... it's Willow. She needs us.
She does. And you'll help her. Lots.
OK? But first we have to
get her home in one piece.
- But...
- Dawn, I'm serious.
You've been through enough
for more than one... ever.
You should be someplace
where you feel safe.
Fine. I want to go to Spike's.
- All right.
- What?
Is not al right. Are you kidding?
- After what Spike did to...
- Xander!
I'll get the coats.
- You're leaving her with Mr Attempted Rape?
- He won't hurt Dawn. He physically can't.
Besides, he wouldn't.
After the other night, I'd say all bets
are off for what he's capable of.
Dawn feels safe with him. We don't have
a choice. Right now, he's all we've got.
Blood of the slain, hear me.
Guide me to Tara's killer.
- John, forget this foolishness.
- Stop right where you are.
John! John!
- Spike.
- Sufferin' cats!
Where did you come from?
Oh, Clem, sorry. I didn't
mean to startle you.
It's OK. You just snuck up on me is all.
- I made you spill your snacks.
- Don't worry about it.
Like I need any more of this. Oh, hi!
Hi.
Can I get you something?
Some Country Time?
- We're looking for Spike, actually.
- He didn't tell you?
- Tell me what?
- He left. Town.
Oh.
- He just took off?
- That's why I'm stayin' here for him.
A sweet pad like this goes empty
for a few days, he'll lose it for sure.
Plus I... don't have a TV.
I'm surprised he didn't tell you.
He kinda left in a hurry, I guess.
Sure I can't get you somethin'?
I've got Bugles and liverwurst.
We're fine, thank you. Um...
But... you could do us a favour.
Do you think Dawn could hang out here
with you for a while?
I have some stuff that I need to do,
and... I really don't want her to be alone.
- I still don't see why I just...
- Dawn, we've been through this.
- What do you think?
- No problem.
I'd love the company.
Do you like Parcheesi?
- Sure.
- Or we could rent videos.
- I'm dying to see The Wedding Planner.
- Either way, I'm good.
Oh, here.
- You can have the comfy chair.
- I'll be back as soon as I can.
- I promise.
- OK.
Thank you.
- Did he say when he'd be back?
- Spike?
No. Only that he could be gone a while.
I'm not asking for permission, mate.
You seek me, vampire?
You do the finger paintings? Nice work.
Answer me.
Yeah, I seek you.
Something about a woman.
The Slayer.
Bitch thinks she's better than me.
Ever since I got this bleedin' chip
in my head, things ain't been right.
Everything's gone to hell.
And you want to return to your former self?
Yeah.
- What?
- Look what she's reduced you to.
It's this bloody chip.
You were a legendary dark warrior
and you let yourself be castrated.
And you have the audacity
to crawl in here and demand restoration?
- I'm still a warrior.
- You're a pathetic excuse for a demon.
Yeah?
I'll show you pathetic.
Give me your best shot.
You'd never endure the trials
required to grant your request.
Do your worst.
But when I win...
I want what I came here for.
Bitch is gonna see a change.
Are you feeling any change? Can you talk?
It's wearing off.
Willow put the whammy on me
and then went straight to
the dark-arts books and sucked them dry.
- Look, Anya, something terrible happened.
- I know.
Tara.
Willow's out for blood big time.
We need to find her before she finds Warren.
Is there something you can do?
A locator spell?
I don't need a spell. I can feel her.
- You can...
- Feel her.
Her thirst for vengeance, it's overwhelming.
Is that, like, left over from your
vengeance-demon days? You just sense her?
No. Not left over.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
- When?
- When do you think?
- Is everyone OK? Did Willow...?
- Got her power boost and took off.
Anya's... Anya was saying
she knows where Willow is.
- A spell?
- Not exactly.
Seems Anya got her vengeance on again.
So Willow's all wrathy.
Why don't you go to her?
Isn't that your gig?
Normally I'd have to.
But she doesn't want me.
- She wants to do it herself.
- Yeah.
Look, Anya, we don't have much time.
Which side of this are you on?
If you know where she is, you can help us.
I'll help. But I'm helping Willow.
She's close to him. He's in the woods.
Run all night, Warren. I'll still find...
Axe not gonna cut it.
Freeze.
That's cute. That's a cute trick.
It was an accident, you know.
Oh. You mean, instead of killing
my best friend, you killed my girlfriend.
- It wasn't personal, that's all.
- Well, this is.
Capture!
Cute tricks.
You are really askin' for it, you know that?
I'm asking for it?
I'm gonna walk away from this.
And when I do,
you're gonna beg to join your girlfriend.
- She wasn't your first.
- First who?
Tara. She wasn't the first girl you killed.
- I don't know what you're talkin' about.
- Reveal!
I should've strangled you in your sleep.
Back when we shared a bed.
I should've done the world a favour.
- It's a trick.
- Why, Warren?
- You could've just let me go.
- Make it shut up. Make it go away.
- It didn't have to be like that.
- I'm not kidding!
How could you say you loved me
and do that to me?
Because you deserved it, bitch!
- Because you liked it.
- Oh, shut up.
You never felt you had the power with her.
Not until you killed her.
- Women! You're like the rest. Mind games.
- You get off on it.
That's why you had a mad-on for the Slayer.
She was your big O, wasn't she, Warren?
Are you done yet? Or can we talk
some more about our feelings?
- What's happening? What do you feel?
- She's stronger now. Close.
- What about Warren? Has she...?
- He's still alive. She's not done.
Help! Let me go.
Somebody! Help!
What's the matter?
I thought you wanted to talk.
No.
OK.
I'll talk.
- What are you doing?
- Shh!
Hey, I'm sorry, OK? I'm sorry.
Wanna know what a bullet
feels like, Warren? A real one.
- It's not like in the comics.
- No. No.
I think you need to... feel it.
Oh, God! Stop it.
It's not gonna make a neat little hole.
First, it'll obliterate
your internal organs.
Your lung will collapse. It's like drowning.
Please, no.
When it finally hits your spine,
it'll blow your central nervous system.
- Please, stop!
- I'm talking.
The pain'll be unbearable,
but you won't be able to move.
A bullet usually travels
faster than this, of course.
But the dying?
It'll seem like it takes for ever.
Something, isn't it?
One tiny piece of metal...
destroys everything.
It ripped her insides out.
Took her light away.
From me.
From the world.
Now the one person
who should be here is gone.
And a waste like you gets to live.
A tiny piece of metal.
Can you feel it now?
Over there.
I said... can you feel it?
Please! God!
I did wrong. I see that now.
I need... jail. I need...
But you... you don't want this.
You're not a bad person. Not like me.
Willow!
When you get caught, you'll lose them too.
Your friends.
You don't want that.
I know you're in pain, but...
Bored now.
Oh, my God.
What did you do?
Willow, what did you do?
One down.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org