Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
- Dawn, what happened here?
- l saw Mom.
lt's the Big Bad, Dawn.
The one we knew was coming.
l believe in you, Spike.
They were after Spike all along.
l know what we're up against. The First.
Now, Spike, you wanna see
what a real vampire looks like?
(Giles) As Neanderthals are to human beings,
the Turok-Han are to vampires.
Ferociously powerful killing machines,
single-minded as animals.
They are the vampires that vampires fear.
Nice place. Bit of a mess.
- They're all slayers?
- Potential slayers.
Waiting for one to be called. There were
many more like them all over the world.
Now there's just a handful,
and they're all coming to Sunnydale.
- How many girls arriving today?
- Just one.
But since Giles has the coven
searching for other slayers-in-waiting,
we'll be seeing a lot more soon enough.
- Rona, right?
- You're her!
Another potential arrived in town
the day before yesterday.
She's cold. Been dead for days.
She made it all the way to Sunnydale
just to get killed.
- Eve.
- Eve, who's in our house?
- Get away from them.
- Buffy, what did Eve do?
- That's not Eve.
- One more down.
Oh, well, can't save 'em all,
can ya, Buffy? Bye.
l don't know what's coming next,
but l do know it's gonna be just like this.
Hard. Painful.
Believe it. We'll be the ones left standing.
You.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
(twig snaps)
Agh!
OK... These two are dead. Why?
Cos the black chick always gets it first?
- What was that, Rona?
- l'm dead because he's a vampire.
l don't have slayer strength,
slayer speed. lt wasn't a fair fight.
Vi, do you think l care if it's a fair fight?
No... No, sir.
You don't play by the rules, and l have
learned a valuable lesson of some sort. Ow!
OK, Spike.
You're right. You don't have slayer strength,
but that doesn't mean that you're not strong.
You have inherent abilities
that others do not have.
- Not like you do.
- No.
Not yet, but it's there.
You have the potential.
You have strength, speed, instinct.
You just have to learn to trust yourself.
Rona, what did your instincts
tell you to do just then?
Block his attack, keep him off balance,
gain the advantage...
- No, they didn't.
- They told me to run.
- Vi?
They're still... sort of telling me to run.
Don't fight on his terms.
Your gut's telling you to run, run.
Regain the higher ground.
Make the fight your own.
Spike, what did your instincts
tell you to do just then?
Hunt. Kill.
Come at me, full speed.
He needs to kill to live.
That tells you everything you need to know.
lnstinct. Understand his, but trust yours.
- You were chosen for a reason.
- (Spike groans)
- Are you OK?
- Fine.
Couple of ribs ain't quite set right.
- l'm fine.
- Let me see... Spike.
l'm gonna be OK.
That's hot.
So, we're supposed to, like,
make out with them or something?
Careful, Buffy. Just when you think
it's part of the lesson, he'll... hurt your arm.
Molly, Kennedy, let's go. You're up.
Next lesson.
(Rona) No way.
One-armed push-ups are bull.
- (Kennedy) l can do 'em.
- (Rona) l'm more of a chin-up kinda girl.
- l can do chin-ups till the cows come home.
- l can do the kind where you clap between...
You're all gonna die.
But you knew that already.
That's the cool reward for being human.
Big dessert at the end of the meal.
Don't kid yourselves, you guys.
This whole thing is all about death.
You think you're different
cos you might be the next slayer?
Death is what a slayer breathes,
what she dreams about when she sleeps.
Death is what a slayer lives.
My death could make you the next slayer.
Oh, goody. Rapt attention.
l love that so much.
Now, where was l?
Ah.
lf we go with Anya's resources,
then the First is in remission for a while,
which we think means "advantage us".
What does that mean... about the First?
Best we can tell,
he - or more precisely it -
was putting a lot of stock
in that Übervamp thing, the... Chaka Khan.
Turok-Han?
When l kicked its ass, the whole Firsty circus
decided to back off for a while.
Good news?
Means we probably don't have to worry
about it pulling Spike's strings for a while.
Here's the half-empty.
Time away means time to regroup.
And part of that regrouping
is coming back stronger than ever.
The odds are against us.
Time is against us.
And some of us will die in this battle.
Decide now that it's not going to be you.
l know you're all tired,
far away from home, anxious.
But you're all special.
Most people in this world have no idea
why they're here or what they wanna do.
You do.
You have a mission, a reason for being here.
You're not here by chance.
You're here because you are the chosen ones.
Dawn, you better hurry up and eat something
so you're not late for school.
(bell rings)
Xander, l know. l'm sorry.
lf you're gonna take a shower
at my house, lock the door.
Of course they're curious.
Hey, l gotta go.
Has Giles checked in yet?
l thought he was picking up that
Chao-Ahn girl in Shanghai yesterday.
OK, well... Let me know if he does. Bye.
Amanda, right? l'm all yours.
Do people ever think you're weird?
l guess... Sure.
ln a charming, endearing, lovable...
Yeah.
l feel like people think l'm weird,
and so they pick on me.
But l might be... weird.
Amanda, why do you think that you're weird?
One of the boys who picks on me,
l kind of...
See, if a guy picks on you,
is it weird to think he's cute?
Oh.
lt's just the last few times l've seen him
l've wanted to, you know...
pick on him... extra. More.
Uh-huh.
The thing is... l can't tell.
My mom says when a guy teases you,
it means he likes you.
- Sometimes that's true.
- ls it weird?
We're mean to each other,
and we like each other.
Well, it depends.
Sometimes that's how people relate,
being mean to each other.
Even... mortal enemies.
Then with the...
And that leads to no good -
absolutely no good - and much confusion.
And then it's over.
Absolutely, seriously, definitely over.
And that's confusing too, the over part.
Which it is. Over!
So... maybe.
(girls and Xander shouting)
(Xander) There might be a more appropriate
place to do that, like maybe outside.
Why do we always have to yell?
l was only gone a couple of hours.
Buffy?
Hey, everybody, it's Willow.
Perhaps with a blunt weapon.
Buffy, we just got news.
- And she's sure?
- Positive.
Althenea said the seers located
another potential slayer in Sunnydale.
- Someone that already lives here.
- Oh, God.
All these girls flocking to town,
and this one's already here?
Wait, the seers couldn't find out
her name or her address or anything?
Am l getting the word "seer" wrong?
l was gonna take the girls out for some
show and tell, but maybe l shouldn't.
They were so excited.
You're gonna break their little hearts.
This town is lousy with Bringers.
l don't want them to find this new girl first.
No, you should go.
l can do a spell to find her tonight.
l have to get together a few ingredients.
You shouldn't skip your training.
lt's too important.
- You think you can handle it?
- No problemo.
Yeah. You guys have
more important things to do.
OK, l'll take 'em.
Yes!
Andrew, you're not going.
Ooh, crossbow! Gotta love it.
Feels like l'm stormin' a castle.
- You do a lot of that, do you?
- l might if l had a beauty like this. Halt!
- We don't point weapons in the kitchen.
- lt's not loaded.
That's always under the headline: "Household
Crossbow Accident Claims Teen".
- Oh, a mace!
- Yeah, that's better.
Gotta go with the stake. lt's classic.
- l like the feel of wood in my hand.
- Lost me there.
Hey, are we gearing up already?
Right. You guys are going
on your little group patrol.
More than that, it's an outing.
- Tonight we might actually get to kill things.
- l've killed things.
- l'm not begging.
- You're like a dog dancing for Snausages.
You don't want me to come
cos you think l'm evil.
- He doesn't seem evil, exactly.
- He's not evil.
But when he gets close to it,
he picks up its flavour like a mushroom.
But l'm reformed.
l'm like Vegeta on Dragonball Z.
l used to be a pure Saiyan,
and now l fight on the side of Goku.
- Still not coming.
- lt's not fair.
- Spike just killed people, and he gets to go.
- Spike didn't have free will. You did.
l hate my free will.
This where you're all hiding?
You ready to go, or what?
Let's go, girls. Grab your weapons.
All right, let's do it.
(Rona) l don't know about you guys,
but l'm ready to kick some serious...
You wanna play Dragonball Z?
l got my tumbleweed, my eggs.
Got my chrysalises... chrysali?
My butterfly transformer pods.
Hey, where's my snakeskin?
At your ssservice, Miss Rosenberg, sssir.
Can you imagine if once in a while
people just wriggled out of their skin
and left it behind them, like, on the sidewalk?
Talk about embarrassing.
Hey, do you think this girl -
this potential - goes to Sunnydale?
Hmm. Well, l guess probably.
l mean, she's gotta be about that age.
Could be anybody.
Could be that glamazon in gym class.
What's her name?
Oh, my lab partner, Margo the freak.
l hope not. She fainted right in the middle
of our foetal pig dissection.
l just don't think
she's cut out for the slayage biz.
Killing pigs is just so wrong. And also hard.
We'll know soon enough
who the next potential is.
Somebody's life is about to change.
How long will it take?
Will we find out who it is right away?
Pretty much. The spell will
conjure up this brilliant light.
The light will find the potential
and it'll illuminate her with a glowing aura.
Cool.
l've enchanted this map,
so that we can track her basic location.
We'll have to hotfoot it,
but l'm betting we find her tonight.
lf it is Margo, she's so gonna faint.
To light the aura of the new,
skin of snake and chrysalis too.
To indicate the fresh reborn,
tumbleweed and rosebush thorn.
An egg that means the life to come.
Take this, O spirits, and my spell is done.
Good God! What is that smell?
l'm sure that's a hard-boiled egg
being thrown into a fire.
- Uh-huh.
- The smell will lead us to the potential.
Or someone who ate too many chimichangas.
She'll also be lit with a brilliant aura.
ls it supposed to be
shimmying all over like that?
l don't know. l don't think so.
So you messed up the spell again.
At least it smells... otherworldly.
Oh, look! Pretty!
l suck. l'm sorry, you guys...
Maybe we could figure something out
on the computer?
Good call. l'm gonna open the door
and let this place air out.
Don't worry, Will. lt's really no big.
l just... l was sure that it was gonna work.
Dawn!
l think it worked.
- Dawn!
- Dawn, are you OK?
Maybe you did it wrong?
Was it ambiguous in any way?
Did you maybe say "potential sailors"?
l do like the water.
- l did it right.
- Wow, she...
You're a potential.
You could be the next slayer.
Oh!
Wow, it's like...
One second you're a klutzy teenager with
fake memories and a history of kleptomania,
then suddenly you're a hero
with a much abbreviated life span.
This is huge. We have to think about this.
l can't think about this.
lt doesn't fit in my head.
A slayer. Makes sense, l guess.
Remember that thing about
"they share the same blood"?
Yeah, l never got that.
She has to die.
l mean, if l was ever the Slayer,
it would mean she died.
lt's a lot like being the Pope in that way,
except you don't have to be
some old Catholic.
- We've gotta call Buffy.
- No, we can't. She didn't bring her cellphone.
Well, sure.
All the important people are with her.
- You're important now.
- What happens now?
Well, you could start
by maybe sitting still for a sec.
l can't. l need to know
what happens to my life.
- Well, l guess Buffy trains you.
- Right.
l train with the potentials... other potentials.
Learn to do the stuff they're learning.
We also have to protect you from the eyeless
guys with the sharp, sharp knives.
Bringers.
- lt's OK, we'll protect you.
- What if they saw the spell?
Saw the spell?
Dawn, they can't see flash cards. Big ones.
We did a big orange powerful spell.
What if they sensed it?
What if they're on their way?
Are we gonna replace the microwave?
l was thinking some Orville Redenbacher...
What's going on?
- Dawn's gonna be a slayer.
- Holy crap!
Excuse me.
Plucked from an ordinary life,
handed a destiny...
Say Skywalker, and l smack ya.
- Does Buffy know?
- She didn't take her phone.
lncommunicado.
- We'll tell her as soon as she gets back.
- Let's not.
Dawn, she has to know.
l know, just not right away.
Guys, when Mom appeared to me, she said...
- Dawnie...
- No, please.
She said something about Buffy,
and l'm thinking...
l'm just not so sure
Buffy will be happy for me.
- Of course she will.
- Will she?
l'm not even sure l'm happy for me.
Everything's different now.
That's because you're a part of
something larger. Like being swallowed.
- By something larger.
- This...
This is too much for my head again.
l can't. l need to be...
Nice job with "getting swallowed".
Well, it is a mixed bag. lf she gets to be
the Slayer, then her life is short and brutal,
and if she doesn't,
it smells of unfulfilled potential.
My "swallowed" analogy
looks pretty sweet now.
lt's not like that.
lt's like she's part of this huge power.
l know what that feels like. lt feels wonderful.
Yes, Willow so captured it. lt's like...
lt's almost like this metaphor
for womanhood, isn't it?
The sort of flowering that happens
when a girl realises that she's... part of
a fertile heritage stretching back to Eve...
- l'll pay you to talk about Star Wars.
- This isn't about womanly power.
Dawn just might have
bought herself an early death.
- We don't know that.
- All we know is that everything just changed.
(Willow) Someone should go find Buffy.
She needs to know.
- (Xander) Will, what if she doesn't like it?
- Are you worried about the ghost?
We don't even know
if that really was Joyce.
- We don't know what she meant about Buffy.
- l don't mean that.
What's Buffy gonna do with this information?
Jump up and down, teach Dawn
the handshake? She knows what this means.
Short, brutal life. Sharp, sharp knives.
l covered this.
Right. You think Buffy
really wants that for Dawn?
(Xander) Besides, Dawn doesn't
want us telling her yet.
(Willow) Dawn's freaking out.
Her input - not worth that much now.
(Anya) She's a child. She can't handle this.
(Xander) Something out there said she can
handle this and more. Something chose her.
l'm chosen.
(Willow) ls that why she's hiding?
(Xander) She's just getting used to it.
She doesn't have to rush.
He's right. We shouldn't rush her.
Rushing's only gonna get her killed.
(Rona) This is a bar.
- Best damn field trip l ever took.
- Look, they're all...
They're demons! lt's a demon bar.
lt's like a gay bar, only with demons.
Spike!
Long time. Nice of you to bring snacks.
Touch them, and lose your privates.
- l didn't like him.
- Nice job of blending in, girls.
We're 15-year-olds in a demon bar. How much
blending did you think we were gonna do?
lt's OK. Usually you come to
a place like this, you wanna be seen.
You wanna scare someone or make contact...
- Or have a strong drink?
- Not usually that.
- You don't drink?
- Sure l do.
l mean, no. That would be wrong.
- Do they card?
- Nope, go ahead.
Down all the yak urine shots
or pigs' blood spritzers you like.
- Gross.
- Got that right.
Prices they charge, you should get
human blood straight from the body.
Vampire.
lf l come here, it's to wring information
out of something large, scary, drunk,
with a room full of friends who don't
care for the Slayer. Remember that.
Not a being here
wouldn't gladly rip your throat out.
Buffy?
- Girl, how you been?
- Clem! You look great. So toned.
- He's ripping out her throat.
- My God! lt is so good to see you!
l saw this great show the other night that
l knew you'd love, but my TiVo went flooey.
Can l talk to you for a second over here?
You think she dated him too?
OK, everyone. These are the girls.
Howdy.
So, you girls are gonna
deal with demons, huh?
Just let me tell you this:
l could use a shot of that
yak urine right about now.
Hey.
Hey, Dawn. What you doing?
Just walking. You?
Yeah, just walking too.
Well, have a good walk.
- l guess l'll see you Monday morning?
- Yeah.
You all right?
Sure. Just walking. You know?
Are you all right? You've got a thing.
l guess l... l had a bit of a...
lt's been a bizarre night.
What happened? Who did that to you?
Nobody... exactly.
l don't think you'd exactly believe me.
Try me.
l was at school late
because of, you know, swing choir,
and l tore my sweater -
you know, the striped ones we wear.
So l went to Home Sciences to sew it up.
And by the time l was finished,
the place was empty,
so it was all echoey and lonely and...
Then there was this guy - or thing -
and it was...
lt scratched me, and l kinda dodged it,
and it kinda hit its head.
- What kind of thing?
- l don't know.
lt was messed up, in the face.
Around hereabouts.
And when it scratched at you, did it...
was it scratching with its teeth?
ls it real?
Was it really a vampire?
- l bet you think l'm crazy.
- l... believe you.
Well, cool.
The thing is, after it hit its head,
l kinda freaked out.
l trapped it in a room, and it's still there.
Now l don't know what to do.
- lt's OK. This is totally dealable. Don't worry.
- l was thinking of getting your sister.
- You know something about my sister?
- Well, l've heard people talking.
A lot of 'em think she's some kind
of high-functioning schizophrenic.
But... l also heard that maybe...
she could help with this kinda thing.
- Do you think we should go get her?
- She's out.
l'll take this one.
Phew!
l think l strained something.
Maybe something l'll need later in life.
Come on. The vampire's upstairs.
- Are you spooked out?
- No. l'm all right. l can do this.
lt's mostly instinct... l think.
(Dawn yelps)
So, if he scratched me with a tooth, am l...
l'm not gonna turn into one, am l?
Only if he slashed open one of his veins
and led you to drink deep of his blood.
Nope.
Good. You're lucky
he didn't hurt you way more than that.
Right. He can do that.
So, l was thinking...
we don't have to kill the vampire, do we?
What?
Suppose he got out and was led toward the
gym while the marching band was playing.
The way they look down on the swing choir,
it might be, you know... funny.
l'm just saying.
Well... he didn't break down the door, anyway.
Yeah.
Can they do that?
They're very strong.
Although they feel pain,
they don't hold back because of it.
Guess you're some kind
of monster expert too.
Let's just say it runs in the family.
- l thought you said it was locked.
- lt was.
lt was here.
Amanda...
lt got out.
Where'd it go?
l don't know. But we have to get out of here.
Argh!
What are you doing?
l can't remember! Does it have to be
right side up or upside down to work?
A vampire is an animal. Sometimes
they run in packs, sometimes alone.
- Who can tell us where we are?
- lt's a nest.
- How can you tell?
- Only a vamp could live like this.
Some, yeah. As a group,
we're not known for our decor,
but, in all fairness to race,
this place is seriously lacking in style.
- Thank you, Spike.
- l'm merely saying.
He has a point. Vampires can
live anywhere. Any way they want.
Tastes, fashions, living conditions -
they can vary.
The animal inside, always the same.
- Where'd you live?
- What, you mean before?
A crypt actually, but nicer. A bit more...
l don't know if posh is the right word,
but it was more...
- Comfy.
- Excuse me?
When did you find it comfy?
Moving on.
You wanna stay alive, you have to
spot and identify a nest on sight.
Look around, all of you.
Look for signs that last night maybe a dozen
vampires were right where we're standing.
Go ahead.
Work, work, work. This excursion
was just in danger of being interesting.
You know something, Spike...
lnteresting is not a problem.
Buffy, l think we found something.
lt's a body.
lt's not a body. lt's leftovers.
ln here!
Help! We need to barricade this!
Too small.
Too big!
Stay down.
Think we're safe?
No one's safe. Not here, not ever.
- See this guy?
- He was dead a minute ago.
That was a minute ago. Now...
- Hey!
- ..he's the enemy.
- Amanda?
- Yes?
- Listen.
- l'm listening.
We're gonna get out of this.
Both of us. Alive.
Alive. Do you believe me?
- l believe you.
- Good. Cos l got a plan.
(Buffy) You can't think too much.
Reacting's better.
Could be the difference between
staying alive and that other thing.
This plan of mine...
l'm not guaranteeing it'll work.
Better than mine about the marching band.
Besides, your plan'll work.
l don't know what l'm doing here.
You're getting it done.
The question is never "What do you think?"
lt's always "What do you know?"
You gotta know.
lf you don't, if you make one mistake...
lt takes just one vampire to kill you.
So you've gotta know you can take him.
Know your environment. Know what's
around you, and know how to use it.
ln the hands of a slayer, everything is
a potential weapon, if you know how to see it.
When you're fighting, you have to
know yourseIf, your brain, your body.
Know how to stay calm, centred.
Every move is important.
Every blow has gotta be part of your plan,
cos you make that one mistake, and it's over.
You're not the Slayer. You're not a potential.
You're dead. So what do you know?
Now, the only thing you know for sure...
you got me.
- Come on, sweetie. Open up.
- Want me to kick down the door?
- Anya.
- What? lt'd be funny.
Besides, she's been sulking in there forev...
Oh.
Crap.
- Double crap.
- Gone.
We gotta find her... before the Bringers do.
l can do a locator spell,
but we gotta hurry. And find Buffy.
- Help! Amanda, help me!
- l can't!
Amanda!
No! You don't want her!
You want me.
Amanda!
- What were those?
- Amanda, listen to me.
You remember when you said l was special?
Well, l'm not. But the thing is, you are.
- This is your battle, Amanda.
- No, l can't.
You can! You've got to.
Look, l've got your back,
but this is something you have to do.
lt's something you were born to do.
Here, this belongs to you.
(Xander) Buffy, up here.
Here!
OK.
One minute l'm in swing choir,
and the next...
What the hell's going on?
You tell me to come to you with problems.
Turns out a vampire attacked me. Problem.
So l go to your house,
only then this orange cloud hits me.
She was at the doorway.
l don't know if you're into the drugs,
but that's not my deal.
That cloud hit me, and l got
a little dizzy and discombobulated.
lt was Willow's spell.
She's the potential slayer.
l'm sure the vampire thought
we were, like, four helpless girls.
- Then Vi yells "We're just four helpless girls."
- That was part of my plan.
When it all started going down, it was
like we knew what we were doing, for real.
Like when you dodged that attack,
and cracked him across the jaw.
l couldn't have done that
if you hadn't took his legs out.
l hurt his arm. Yep!
And an arm can be as lethal as a mouth.
When you staked him, the rush was like...
- So, you took one out solo?
- Yeah, what was that like?
l don't know.
l mean, when l saw the vampire... vamp...
Vampire's good too.
Cool. Yeah, when that vampire attacked me,
l felt this kind of charge. You know?
(Kennedy) Like you realise in one instant
that your whole life is different.
(Amanda) Exactly.
lt's that rush you're talking about.
Hi.
- You OK?
- Yeah.
l was thinking of hitting the books.
Do some research on the First.
lt's in retreat mode,
but you still need to know how to fight it.
Great. Sounds good.
Hey, you guys. Wanna head downstairs?
Get our newest arrival up to speed?
What's up?
l'm just thinking about the girls.
lt's a harsh gig, being a potential.
Just being picked out of a crowd.
Danger, destiny. Plus if you act now, death.
- They can handle it.
- Yeah.
They're special, no doubt.
And the amazing thing is,
not one of 'em will ever know. Not even Buffy.
Know what?
How much harder it is for the rest of us.
- No way. They've got...
- Seven years, Dawn.
Working with the Slayer. Seeing
my friends get more and more powerful.
A witch. A demon.
Hell, l could fit Oz in my shaving kit,
but, come a full moon,
he had a wolfy mojo not to be messed with.
Powerful. All of them.
And l'm the guy who fixes the windows.
You had that sexy army training for a while,
and the windows really did need fixing.
l saw what you did last night.
Yeah, l...
l kinda lost my head
when l thought l was the Slayer.
You thought you were all special.
Miss Sunnydale 2003.
And the minute you found out you weren't,
you handed the crown to Amanda
without a moment's pause.
You gave her your power.
The power wasn't mine.
They'll never know how tough it is, Dawnie,
to be the one who isn't chosen.
To live so near to the spotlight
and never step in it.
But l know.
l see more than anybody realises
because nobody's watching me.
l saw you last night.
l see you working here today.
You're not special.
You're extraordinary.
Maybe that's your power.
What?
Seeing. Knowing.
Maybe it is. Maybe l should get a cape.
Cape is good.
Yeah.
Subtitles by Visiontext
Urgh! Argh!
ENGLlSH SDH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org