(# "Charge" by Splendid)
# The way you love
# Have you got a name for it?
# Cos I don't understand
# It
# The language is an annoying necessity
# And I depend on all the regular things
# Got a list tattooed on my memory
# Of how our tryst should unfold
Hey.
# I'm falling from the opposite
I'm Ben. We had
Algebra II together last year?
I'm sorry, I pretty much repress
anything math-related.
Ms. Jackson? Second period?
You sat in the seat three over
and one behind.
Oh! Yeah, I remember now.
It's the one with the
desks, and the chalkboards,
and pencils, and stuff, right?
- That's the one.
- Like a steel trap.
So, I was wonderin',
you know the dance tomorrow night?
- Are you goin'?
- You mean the Sadie Hawkins thing?
- The deal where the girls ask the boys?
- Yeah.
And I thought maybe, you know,
if you're free, you might ask me.
Oh, gosh...
- I...
- Oh, hey, hey, no. Don't, don't worry...
No! No, no, you seem
like a really great guy.
It's... me, I...
I'm not seeing anybody.
- Ever again, actually.
- Oh. That's... that's too bad.
OK, well, I better...
# Fight the map with no key attached
- Sorry.
# My heart's enlarged, and I charge
# I'm falling from the opposite
# What good is it?
# Fight the map with no key attached
# My heart's enlarged and I charge
Hey. You're bailin'?
Yeah. I'm gonna stop by the library
and see if Giles wants me to patrol,
and then... sack it.
You've been doing that a lot -
patrolling and sacking.
In fact, you've, kind of, been
"All work and no play Buffy".
I play. I have big fun.
I came here tonight, didn't I?
You came, you saw, you... rejected.
You mean that guy?
I'm just not in date mode right now.
Maybe you need to date
to get in date mode.
I don't think I'm ready for that, Will.
You're thinking too much.
Maybe you need to be impulsive.
Impulsive? Do you remember
my ex-boyfriend, the vampire?
I slept with him, he lost his soul,
and now my boyfriend's gone for ever
and the demon that wears
his face is killing my friends.
The next impulsive decision I make
will involve my choice of dentures.
OK, the Angel thing went badly.
I'm on board with that.
But... that's not your fault.
And anyways,
love isn't always like that.
Love can be... nice.
Come back here! We're not finished!
You don't care any more, is that it?
It doesn't matter!
It doesn't matter what I feel!
Then tell me you don't love me.
Say it!
Will that help?
Is that what you need to hear?
I don't. I don't! Now, let me go.
No! A person doesn't just wake up one day
and stop loving somebody.
Love is for ever.
"I Only Have Eyes For You"
I'm not afraid to use it. I swear!
- If I can't be with you...
- Hey!
Oh, my God!
Don't walk away from me, bitch!
- What happened?
- What happened?!
You just went O.J. on your girlfriend.
This is nuts. I-I...
I don't know why I got so mad.
- Because you're a jerk?
- He's not.
We weren't even fighting
a few minutes ago.
We weren't. I, I swear to God.
If you weren't fighting,
then why'd you have a gun?
I don't... I don't know.
I don't even know where I got it.
I don't see any gun.
I'm sure you know
why I asked you here.
- To thank me?
- That's right, I wanna thank you.
What would Sunnydale High do
without you around
to incite mayhem, chaos and disorder?
I don't incite! I stopped that boy
from killing his girlfriend.
Ask him. Ask the janitor.
People can be coerced, Summers.
I'm no stranger to conspiracy.
I saw "JFK".
I'm a truth seeker. I've got a missing gun
and two confused kids on my hands.
Pieces of the puzzle.
And I'm gonna look at all the pieces
carefully and rationally,
and I'm gonna keep looking until I know
exactly how this is all your fault.
Mr. Snyder, Billy Crandal chained himself
to the snack machine again.
Pathetic little no-life vegan.
Not so fast, missy.
I'm not done with you yet.
You stink of lies.
So, for next time read the chapters on
information grouping and binary coding.
I bet you'll think
coding is pretty cool. I mean...
if you find two-digit,
multi-stacked conversions
and primary-number clusters a big hoot!
Giles! I made them laugh. Did you hear?
- I did the joke thing!
- Yes, yes, so it seems.
I-I mean, um, uh, you did indeed.
Good, good, good show.
I-I-I just stopped by to, to
see if you needed any assistance,
but you... seem to have things
quite under control.
Well, I had... good lesson plans.
Ms. Calendar had them on her computer.
Yes, yes, she was very, um...
uh, dedicated.
And I found a bunch of
files and Internet sites
on paganism and magic, and stuff.
- Oh?
- Yes. It's really interesting.
And, uh...
I found this in her drawer.
She told me it was a rose quartz.
And it has healing powers.
I thought she'd want you to have it.
Oh, thank you, Willow, that's, um...
that's very thoughtful of you.
Before 1935, the New Deal focused on
revitalizing stricken business
and agricultural communities.
The New Deal also tried to regulate
the nation's financial hierarchy
to avoid another disaster
like the 1929 stock market crash.
Don't forget your assignments
are due on Friday, class.
I told Miss Hall we'd go help
decorate the gym. Who are you taking?
- David said yes.
- Oh, you're kidding! He's so dreamy!
Thank you.
Thank you, James. How are you enjoying
that... book I loaned you?
- The Hemingway.
- I like it.
Very much.
It's honest.
Yes, it's, um...
it's based on a true story, actually.
He fell in love with his...
...hours...
child... labor...
and... collective bargaining.
DON'T WALK AWAY FROM ME BITCH!
- Oh, my God!
- Did you see what he wrote?
I'm telling you,
something weird is going on.
"Something weird is going on" -
isn't that our school motto?
Pretty much. But I don't know.
This time... it bugs me.
I don't wanna pooh-pooh your wiggins,
but a... domestic dispute,
a little case of chalkboard Tourette's?
All sounds like Hellmouth Lite to me.
Xander, what happened?
Did Cordelia win another round
in the broom closet?
You're just a big bucket of funny, Will!
I'll have you know I was just
accosted by some kind of, um...
locker monster.
- Loch Ness Monster?
- 'Locker' monster is what he said.
But it wasn't really a monster. It was
this big arm that came out of the locker.
But then we opened it again,
it was gone. Nothing.
This was right after Buffy's
history teacher starts doing some
freaky channeling thing in class.
Ooh! Sounds like paranormal phenomena.
- A ghost? Cool!
- Oh, no, no. No. No cool.
This was no wimpy chain rattler.
This was: "I'm dead as hell,
and I'm not gonna take it any more."
Well, despite the
Xander-speak, that's a...
fairly accurate definition of a...
poltergeist
I defined something? Accurately?
- Guess I'm done with the book learning.
- So we have some bad boo on our hands?
- Yes.
- Well, why is it here?
Does it just wanna scare people?
Unfortunately, it doesn't know exactly
what it wants. That's, that's the trouble.
See, many times the spirit is plagued
by all manner of worldly troubles,
only being dead, it has no way to...
to make its peace.
So, it lashes out, growing ever more...
confused, ever more...
- angry.
- So it's a normal teenager. Only dead.
What can we do?
Is there any way to stop it?
The only tried and true way is to...
work out what unresolved...
issues keep it here...
and-and-and, um... resolve them.
Fabulous! Now,
we're Dr Laura for the deceased.
Only if we can find out
who the spirit is.
Or was.
- Working late, Ms. Frank?
- My fault. Let myself get behind.
Is it OK to walk here, George?
It is George, right?
- Yes, ma'am. Go ahead.
- Thanks. Have a nice evening.
- You, too. Drive safe. Oh, Ms. Frank?
- Yes?
You can't make me disappear
just because you say it's over.
There's no way we can be together.
No way people will ever understand.
Accept it.
Is that what this is about?
What other people think?
No! I just want you to be able
to have some kind of a normal life.
- We can never have that. Don't you see?
- I don't give a damn about a normal life.
I'm going crazy not seeing you.
- I think about you every minute.
- I know... but...
But it's over.
It has to be.
Come back here! We're not finished yet!
- You don't care any more? Is that it?
- It doesn't matter.
- It doesn't matter what I feel.
- Then tell me you don't love me.
Say it!
Will that help?
Is that what you have to hear?
I don't. I don't!
- Now let me go.
- No.
A person doesn't just wake up one day
and stop loving somebody.
Love is forever.
I'm not afraid to use it.
If I can't be with you...
Don't walk away from me, bitch!
I need you.
Jenny.
Don't! Don't do that, dammit!
Don't talk to me like I'm some dumb...
- What's going on?
- What's going on?!
You just shot a woman.
And this...
This is the garden.
Wow!
Look. Jasmine.
- Night-blooming.
- Like us.
Oh, Angel... it's fairyland.
It's paradise.
Big windows, lovely gardens.
It'll be perfect
when we want the sunlight to kill us.
If you don't like it, Spike,
hit the stairs and go.
Take a stand, man.
Well, our old place was just fine
till you went and had it burned down.
Things change, Spikey.
You gotta roll with the punches.
Well, actually, you pretty much
got that part down, haven't you?
Very funny, mate.
What can I say?
I just love to see you smile, buddy!
Yeah... you're a giver.
It was just as with the, the couple
you encountered the other night, Buffy.
The, the janitor remembered everything.
He, he knew he'd killed this poor woman,
but he had no idea why.
Well, they-they had no...
intimate relationship.
- What about the gun? Did you find it?
- No. No.
No, the police, everybody,
we-we-we-we searched high and low.
I think it's very clear
what's happening here.
Fill me in, then.
'Cause I've read the book,
seen the movie, and I'm still fuzzy
about what's going on.
It's Jenny.
- What?
- You think she's the ghost?
Well, don't you see?
Well, she-she-she died here
under tragic circumstances,
a-a-and now she's trapped.
But... what about the gun?
I mean, Angel didn't shoot Ms Calendar.
The gun is insignificant. It's the
violence of the thing that matters.
I don't know. These fights these couples
keep having, it's sort of... specific.
She's right. It's a pattern that doesn't
fit with the way Ms. Calendar died.
Yes, well, I, uh, I... appreciate
your thoughts on the matter.
I, in fact I... well, I encourage you
to, to always, uh...
challenge me, uh,
when you feel it's appropriate.
You should never be
cowed by authority.
Except of course in this instance,
when I am clearly right
and you are clearly wrong.
This is freaky. I don't remember
ever seeing Giles be this weird.
I know. He's usually "Investigate-Things-
From-Every-Boring-Angle" guy.
Now he's "I-Cling-Onto-My-One-
Lame-Idea" guy. What gives?
He misses her. He can't think.
Just a little more fallout
from my love life.
OK, but this ghost stuff
is something else.
Let me do a crosscheck
on other shootings at the school.
Yeah, we need some alternate
ghost theories. What do we know?
Dog's spit is cleaner than human.
- Besides that?
- Oh, boy! We know plenty.
It says a student murdered a teacher
on the night of the Sadie Hawkins Dance.
The rumor was they were having an affair,
and she tried to break it off.
After he killed her, he went into
the music room and shot himself.
Ladies and gentlemen, we have a ghost.
It is one of those two, right?
It all fits: the gun,
the Sadie Hawkins Dance.
- Which is tonight.
- How come we've never heard about
this murder-suicide thing before?
When did it happen?
1955.
How did you know?
OK, here's the new strangeness.
I dreamt about this woman,
Grace Newman, the other day.
- Her and this guy.
- James Stanley?
He's the one! He did it!
Your dreams are getting
wicked accurate, Buff.
You wouldn't happen to see me
coming across some big cash?
Or possibly knowing the love of a woman?
In a full body sense?
He couldn't make her love him,
so he killed her. Sicko.
He looks so normal on this picture.
He was smart, too. He made the honor roll.
- Smart?
- He killed a person and killed himself.
Those are pretty much two of the
dumbest things you could do.
I know, but...
Well, don't you feel kind of bad for them?
Sure I feel lousy. For her.
He's a murderer and should pay for it.
- With his life?
- No, he should be doing
60 years in a prison, breaking rocks
and making special friends
with Roscoe the weightlifter.
Yikes! The quality of mercy is not Buffy.
Whose ghost do you think
we're dealing with? His or hers?
Well, considering how violent it is,
I'm gonna say his.
That tracks.
Well, I've been browsing on
some of Ms. Calendar's pagan sites.
Maybe I can find a way
to communicate with him, and...
we can find out what he wants.
Who cares what he wants?
We need to shut him down
before some other innocent guy
goes and kills some poor nice girl
and then blows his brains out
all over the music room wall.
OK!
Who's hungry?
Next, please. Move along.
I hope you, guys, aren't going
to the Sadie Hawkins Dance tonight,
'cause I'm organizing a boycott.
Do you realize that the girls have to ask
the guys? And pay and everything?
I mean, whose genius idea was that?
Obviously some hairy-legged feminist.
Really? Well, we need to
nip this thing in the bud.
I mean, otherwise,
things are going to get really scary.
They're everywhere!
Perfect. I'm gonna be scarred and swollen.
Why didn't they just kill me?
- Schoolboy pranks?
- Never sell.
The sewer got backed up.
Better. I can probably make that one fly.
But this is getting out of hand.
- People will talk.
- You'll take care of it.
I'm doing everything I can,
but you people have to realize...
- Snyder, what's going on here?
- Backed-up sewer line!
Same thing happened
in San Diego just last week!
We're on a Hellmouth.
Sooner or later...
people are gonna figure that out.
The city council was told
you could handle this job.
If you feel that you can't,
perhaps you'd like to take that up...
with the Mayor.
I'll handle it.
I will.
Remember the plan to contact the spirit
and talk to it? Scrap that plan.
Buffy, you were right. The time for
touchy-feely communication has passed.
I've done some homework and found out
the only solution is the final solution.
Nuke the school?
- I like that.
- Not quite. Exorcism.
Are you crazy? I saw that movie.
Even the priest died!
- What's the deal?
- OK. See here, the balcony?
That's where the original teacher died
back in 1955, and that teacher last night.
That's the hot spot where
all the bad mojo is coming from.
- We need to create a Mangus tripod.
- A what?
One person chants here on the hot spot.
And the other three chant in other places
around the school, forming a triangle.
It's supposed to bind the bad spirit
and keep it from doing any more harm.
Well, I'll take the hot spot.
If there's trouble, that's where it'll be.
This ghost, this James guy, is fixating
on you, Buffy. The dreams, the yearbook...
You sure you can handle it?
Well, I'm hoping he'll show. I truly am.
OK, we have our places. We do the chant
and light candles at midnight exactly.
- Any questions?
- Yeah. What if this
mangled triangle thingy doesn't work?
Oh! I almost forgot!
I made us all scapulars.
OK. So we can flip the ghost over
when it turns a nice golden brown?
Scapular, not spatula!
Um... you wear it around your neck
for protection.
You expect me to wear this?
It smells like grandpa breath.
Sorry. I didn't have a lot of time.
I had to use sulphur.
- Stinky, but effective.
- OK, let's do this.
No problem.
This will be a piece of cake, right?
Maybe I'll sleep underground.
Dig myself a little burrow.
What about your pretty dress, sweet?
It'll get all dirty.
Then I'll sleep naked.
Like the animals do.
You know?
I'm suddenly likin' this plan.
Fortunately, nobody cares
what you like... mate.
Oh, yeah? Let's ask Dru.
There's a gate!
- It's opening!
- Incoming! I love when she does this.
- What gate, pet? What do you see?
- It's black.
It wants her.
- Wants who?
- The Slayer.
It's time, Angel.
She's ready for you now.
She's... dancing.
- Dancing with death.
- Big deal. He won't do anything.
Our man Angel here likes to talk,
but he's not much for action.
All hat and no cattle.
I don't know about that.
I think this whole Slayer thing
has run its course.
I'm ready to focus my energy elsewhere.
- Really?
- Oh, yeah!
What, with you being Special Needs Boy,
I figure I should stick close to home.
You and Dru can always use
another pair of hands.
God, Willow, what are you doing here?
- You're not supposed to be inside.
- Me? What about you?!
I'm, uh, I'm, I'm trying to, uh...
I think I-I may be close to, uh...
contacting Jenny.
- What's that smell?
- It's my scapular.
- Ah, right. Did you use sulphur?
- Yeah.
That's clever.
Uh, well, uh... run along then.
Th-there may be some, uh, paranormal
ph-phenomena if I contact her.
Y-y-you don't want to be
in the line of fire.
OK. Night.
(# "I Only Have Eyes For You"
by The Flamingos)
# My love must be a kind of blind love
# I can't see anyone but you
Oh, yeah, baby!
It's snake-a-licious in here.
# The moon may
# Be high
# But I can't see a thing
# In the sky
# I only...
- Giles!
- Willow!
Giles! Giles!
- Where are you?!
- Please!
Help! Help me!
Help! Help! Help! Help!
- Stop!
- Just calm down.
Get out!
- Are you all right?
- Giles...
Jenny could never be this mean.
I know.
It's... it's not her, is it?
I'm sorry.
Oh, God. Oh!
Careful up here!
I shall confront and expel all evil...
I shall totally
confront and expel all evil...
out of marrow and bone...
out of house and home -
never to come here again.
Oh, my God!
You all right?
Get back!
Check it. I'd say school's out for good.
The good news is...
none of you girls were shot.
We've, we've established,
based on all the parallels
and-and-and... Buffy's visions that...
- it's James' spirit.
- So what do we do, Giles? About James.
Well, he's obviously reliving
the night of the Sadie Hawkins Dance
when he killed Ms. Newman.
It's, it's common enough for a spirit
to do this - to... recreate a, a tragedy.
Hey! If Sunnydale High School
shuts down forever,
do we automatically graduate?
But why? What does he want?
- Actually, that's an interesting point.
- He's, he's trying to...
resolve whatever issues
are keeping him in limbo.
- W-w-what exactly those are, I'm not...
- He wants forgiveness.
Yes... Yes, I imagine he does!
But when... James possesses people,
they act out exactly
what happened that night.
So he's experiencing
a form of... purgatory instead.
I mean, he's doomed to,
to kill his Miss Newman
over and over and over again, and...
- forgiveness is impossible.
- Good. He doesn't deserve it.
To forgive is
an act of compassion, Buffy.
It's, it's not done
because people deserve it.
- It's done because they need it.
- No.
James destroyed
the one person he loved the most
in a moment of blind passion...
And that's not something you forgive -
no matter why he did what he did.
And no matter if he knows now
that it was wrong and selfish and stupid,
it is just something
he's gonna have to live with.
He can't live with it, Buff.
He's dead.
OK. Overidentify much?
I need you.
So what do we do next?
Do we go in again?
Uh, not now. No, the, uh...
The spirit is too... angry,
too, too powerful.
No, we have to work out...
exactly how and, and if this...
thing can be defeated.
Hey, Buffy, are you...?
Oh, God... Giles!
She went back.
So, what now? Not even a mega-vat
of Raid's gonna do the trick here.
I don't get it. Is she trying to be
a big loner hero or something?
No. I believe
she's under the spirit's thrall.
He's, he's calling her.
But why?
James needs her to re-enact
everything that happened
on the night that he...
he killed Ms. Newman.
He wants to change things,
make... make a happy ending.
But it can't ever happen!
It always ends the same,
which means Buffy just went in there
to get shot, Giles!
Yes.
But the school's deserted.
There's no way for James to...
to play his part. There's, there's
no man inside for him to possess.
So Buffy should be safe
until we find a way to get her out.
In theory, yeah.
Fun fact about wasps.
They have no taste for the undead.
Hey, not that a sting would do me
any damage. It's just... tonight's special.
I wanted to look my best for you.
You're the only one.
The only person I can talk to.
Gosh, Buff. That's really pathetic.
You can't make me disappear
just because you say it's over.
Actually... I can.
In fact...
I just want you to be able to have
some kind of normal life.
We can never have that, don't you see?
I don't give a DAMN about a normal life!
I'm going crazy not seeing you.
I think about you every minute.
I know.
But it's over. It has to be!
Come back here! We're not finished!
You don't care any more? Is that it?
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter what I feel!
Then tell me you don't love me!
Say it!
Is that what you need to hear?
Will that help?
I don't.
- I don't. Now let me go.
- No!
A person doesn't just wake up
and stop loving somebody!
Love is forever.
I'm not afraid to use it, I swear!
If I can't be with you...
Oh, my God!
- Don't walk away from me...
- bitch!
Stop it!
Stop it! Don't make me!
All right. Just...
You know you don't wanna do this.
Let's both...
just calm down.
Now give me the gun.
Don't! Don't do that, dammit!
Don't talk to me like I'm some stupid...
James.
# My love must be a kind of blind love
# I can't see anyone but you
- Grace!
- Don't do this.
But... but I killed you.
It was an accident.
It wasn't your fault.
- It is my fault. How could I...
- Hush.
I'm the one who should be sorry, James.
You thought I stopped loving you...
But I never did.
I loved you with my last breath.
Shh... No more tears.
Angel.
Everything seems normal.
Not a snake, not a wasp.
Yep. School can open again tomorrow.
Explain to me again
how that's a good thing.
I'm drawing a blank.
- Are you feeling any better?
- James picked me.
I guess...
I guess I was the one
he could relate to.
He was so sad.
Well...
They can both rest now.
I still...
Part of me just doesn't understand
why she would forgive him.
Does it matter?
No.
I guess not.
You might want to let up.
They say when you've drawn blood,
you've exfoliated.
What do you know about it?
I'm the one who was freakin' violated.
You didn't have this thing in you.
What was it? A demon?
Love!
Poor Angel.
Let's get out of here.
I need a real vile kill before sunup
to wipe this crap out of my system.
Of course.
We'll find you a nice toddler.
Want to come, pet?
No can do, Dru.
I'm sure he'd be hell on wheels,
but we don't have much time.
Gotta travel light.
Sorry. Try to have fun without me.
Oh, I will.
Sooner than you think.
Subtitles extended and timed by UAR
www.tvsubtitles.net