Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
* All is calm *
* All is bright *
* Round yon virgin... *
- * Mother and child *
- Watch it.
Daniel.
Where were you going?
You... You're not human.
Not of late, no.
Wh... What do you want?
Well, it happens that
I'm hungry, Daniel...
and seeing as that you're
somewhat in me debt...
Please, I can't.
A man playing at cards
should have
a natural intelligence
or a great deal of money,
and you're sadly lacking in both.
So I take me winnings
me own way.
The Lord is my shepherd.
I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie down
in green pastures...
Daniel, be of good cheer.
It's Christmas.
It's gonna be sunny and warm
with temperatures continuing
in the high 70s throughout
the holiday weekend.
* Remember Christ our savior
was born on Christmas day *
* To save us all
from Satan's power *
- * When we had gone astray *
- Merry Christmas.
* Oh, tidings of comfort
and joy *
Hi.
Angel.
So, are you shopping?
You're probably not shopping.
I couldn't sleep.
Vampires probably not that big on
Christmas, now that I think about it.
Not as a rule.
But you're good?
I... I'm all right. You?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm good.
I was just getting some
Christmas gifts for the gang.
Um, I'd better go before
the magic store closes.
Angel?
What is it?
And then he just bailed.
He didn't say anything.
He just took off.
It was so weird.
Angel? Weird?
What are the odds?
Do you think something's wrong?
Maybe you should tell Giles.
No. I don't wanna bug Giles.
He's still kinda twitchy when it
comes to the subject of Angel.
It must be that whole "Angel killed
his girlfriend and tortured her" thing.
Giles is pretty petty
when it comes to stuff like that.
Xander, enough, okay?
Maybe Angel just has
the holiday blues.
Everybody gets them,
especially when they're alone.
It's just so frustrating.
I'm trying to do the right thing
and stay away from him
and get over it,
and then boom, there he is.
I just want a nice,
quiet Christmas vacation.
Xander: So, you doing
anything special?
Buffy: Tree. Nog. Roast beast.
Just me and Mom and,
hopefully, an excess of gifts.
What are you doing for Christmas?
Being Jewish.
Remember, people?
Not everybody worships Santa.
I just meant for vacation.
Nothing fun.
Oz and I had planned...
But I guess that's off.
Well, I'll be enjoying
my annual Christmas Eve camp-out.
See, I take
my sleeping bag outside
and I go to sleep
on the grass.
Buffy: Sounds fun.
Yeah, I like to look
at the stars, you know?
Feel the whole nature vibe.
I thought you slept outside
to avoid your family's
drunken Christmas fights.
Yes, and that was a confidence
I was hoping
you would share with everyone.
Well, I'll be in Aspen skiing...
with actual snow.
I hear that helps.
It must be a drag to be
stuck here in Sweatydale...
but I'm thinking of you.
Okay, I'm not.
She certainly has reverted to form.
It's not her fault.
After what happened,
we gotta cut her some slack.
That's the Christmas spirit.
Hello, stillJewish.
Chanukah spirit,
I believe that was?
Anyway, forgiveness is pretty much
a big theme with me this year
'cause of the...
Hey.
Okay. The thing is...
seeing you with Xander,
it was...
I've never felt that way before
when it wasn't a full moon...
but I know you guys
have a history.
But it's a history
that's in the past.
Well, I... I guess most
history is in the past.
But it's over.
Well, I don't know.
I don't know that it ever
will be between you two.
Oz, please believe me.
This is what I do know.
I miss you...
like, every second.
It's like I lost an arm
or worse, a torso.
So, I think I'd be willing
to give it a shot.
Really?
Yeah.
Do you want us to...
to hug now?
Yeah, I'm good for that.
Woman:
Take the other one then.
Do you wanna get one
with snow on it?
Be very Christmasy.
I think those are just for display.
Oh. You know, honey,
I was thinking
maybe we should invite Faith
to spend Christmas Eve with us.
I don't know.
Faith and I don't really hang out
or talk or make eye contact lately.
Do you really wanna
let her spend Christmas Eve
all by herself in that
dingy little motel room?
You're still number one
with a guilt trip, Mom.
- I try.
- I'll ask her.
- You're a doll.
- What about Giles?
- He doesn't have any fam...
- No, I'm sure he's fine.
We could at least ask him.
He doesn't wanna spend Christmas Eve
with a bunch of girls.
Let's split up.
Bunch of them up and died on us.
Don't know why.
If you want one,
I can make you a hell of a deal.
No, thank you.
Joyce: Oh, honey,
this one's perfect.
[Men Chanting]
[Gasping]
- [Knock At Door]
- TV: Merry Christmas...
- Yeah?
Happy New Year...
Hey, what's up?
Work, damn it!
Hey.
What's going on?
Scary monsters?
No.
We're having Christmas Eve dinner
at my house...
and I thought that if you
didn't have plans...
Your mom sent you down, huh?
No.
Well, thanks, but I got plans.
There's this big party
I've been invited to.
It should be a blast.
Okay, cool.
But if you change
your mind, the offer...
That's nice of you. Thanks.
But I got... I got
that big party
that I've been
invited to, so...
I like the lights.
Yeah. Well, 'tis the season.
Whatever that means.
[Knocking]
Just a minute.
Hello.
Um...
I'm sorry to bother you.
Sorry. Coming from you
that phrase strikes me
as rather funny.
Sorry to bother me.
I need your help.
And the funny keeps on coming.
I understand. I have
no right to ask for it...
but there's no one else.
All right.
I... I can't come in
unless you invite me.
I'm aware of that.
Come in.
I've been seeing...
I've had...
I've had dreams lately
about the past.
It's like I'm living it again.
It's so vivid, I...
I need to know.
I need to know why I'm here.
Here, back on Earth?
I should be in a demon dimension
suffering an eternity of torture.
I don't feel particularly
inclined to argue with that.
But I'm not.
I was freed...
and I don't understand why.
Knowing why you were back
would give you peace of mind?
It might.
You think that's something
you ought to have?
Because, sir, to be blunt...
the last time you became
complacent about your existence...
it turned out rather badly.
What?
There.
Don't you see her?
Who?
I can't!
Sir, please, I should
return to the party.
Margaret, Margaret,
there's no hurry.
Mistress will be wondering...
Shh. The mistress will be
wondering how to get
the good Reverend Chalmers
into bed
and will not notice
the absence of canapés.
Stay with me.
Sir, people might talk.
I'll be put out in the streets.
My little boy would...
I can't lose this job.
Then you best keep quiet.
You're hurting me.
Cry out. Call for help.
I'm sure mistress will believe
your behavior beyond reproach.
Please.
Come, make a scene, huh?
Shall I?
No.
No, no.
We'll be as quiet as mice.
No matter what.
Sir, my son!
He'll make a fine dessert.
[Gasps]
Trouble sleeping?
You're not here.
I'm always here.
Leave me alone.
I can't.
You won't let me.
What do you want?
I want to die in bed
surrounded by fat grandchildren...
but guess that's off the menu.
I'm sorry.
You're sorry?
For me?
Don't bother.
I'm dead.
I'm over it.
If you wanna feel
sorry for someone...
you should feel sorry
for yourself.
Oh, but I guess you've already
got that covered.
I am sorry...
for what I've done.
What else can I say to you?
I don't wanna make you feel bad.
I just want to show you
who you are.
You had a dream about Angel.
I was in Angel's dream.
I'm not sure...
Giles, there was stuff
in this dream
that I couldn't possibly
know about.
It was Angel's past.
He was dreaming it,
and somehow I got sucked in.
There's something wrong with him.
I know. I've seen him.
He wanted to know
why he was back.
Is there a way for us
to find that out?
Possibly. I've been looking.
Well, let me look too.
I'm not seeing him anymore.
I'm trying to put
all this behind me...
and I'm not gonna be able to
as long as we're both doing guest spots
in each other's dreams.
So we'll help him?
Yes.
Where do we start?
Look, I'm aware I haven't been
the mostest best friend to you
when it comes to the whole
Angel thing.
And I don't know. Maybe I
finally got the Chanukah spirit.
Well, we start,
not surprisingly, with research.
Xander, the Black Chronicles.
And, Buffy, the diary
of Lucious Temple.
An acolyte of Acathla,
expert on demons.
You can skip the passages
on his garden
unless you're keen on growing
heartier beets.
Are you sure this is how you
wanna spend your Christmas vacation?
Yeah, this is actually the most
exciting thing I've got planned.
Who else can claim that
pathetic a social life?
Hey, guys.
What are we doing?
He's gonna come over on Christmas Eve
'cause my parents are out of town.
- We're gonna watch videos.
- That's good, right?
You guys are back.
It's good. It's perfect...
in an awkward,
uncomfortable sort of way.
I just don't know how
to make Oz trust me.
Xander has a piece of you
that Oz just can't touch.
I guess now it's just about
showing Oz that he comes first.
I guess.
Thanks.
Hey, he likes beets.
I read that one already.
We're not getting any closer.
The thing I remember most
was thinking how artful it was.
In the dark, they looked
just like they were sleeping.
It wasn't until I bent down
and kissed them good night
that I felt how cold they were.
You grabbed me, and I thought,
"Who would go to so much trouble
to arrange them like that?"
But you see...
that's what makes you
different than other beasts.
They kill to feed, but you took
more kinds of pleasure in it
than any creature
that walks or crawls.
Oh, God.
Yeah, cry out.
Make a scene.
I was to be married that week...
but then, as I recall,
you knew that.
It wasn't me.
It wasn't you?
A demon isn't a man.
I was a man once.
Oh, yes, and what a man you were.
[Singing]
A drunken, whoring layabout...
and a terrible disappointment
to your parents.
I was young.
- I never had a chance to...
- To die of syphilis?
You were a worthless being
before you were ever a monster.
Stop it! Stop.
[Sobbing]
I don't wanna hurt you, Angel...
but you have to understand.
Cruelty's the only thing
you ever had a true talent for.
- That's not true.
- Shh.
Rest.
You mistake it for a curse,
Angel, but it's not.
It's your destiny.
I'll show you.
- You want her?
- No.
Take her.
Take what you want.
Pour all that frustration
and all that guilt into her...
and you'll be free.
No.
You can't live for eternity
with all that pain.
This is what you are, and this is why
we brought you back.
Take her.
And then you'll be ready...
to kill her.
Hey, Buffy, take a look.
These letters contain references
to an ancient power known as the First.
- First what?
- Evil.
Absolute evil,
older than man, than demons.
It could have had the power
to bring Angel back.
These guys...
I saw them in my dream.
I fell asleep up there.
You had another dream with Angel?
What happened?
Oh, we don't need
to get sidetracked.
Who are these guys?
Well, they're known as the...
As the Bringers or Harbingers.
They're high priests of the First.
They can conjure
spirit manifestations
and set them on people
to influence them, haunt them.
These are the guys working
the mojo on Angel?
Xander: We gotta stop them.
Y... You can't fight
the First, Buffy.
It's not a physical being.
Well, I... I can fight
these priest guys.
If we can find them.
Willy: Hey.
It's the slayer.
What brings the slayer down here?
Hey, Willy, how you been?
Keeping out of trouble,
as God is my witness.
So, what can I do for you?
Couple of drinks?
Yeah. Let me get
a double shot of...
Of information, pal.
Three priests.
They call themselves...
The Bringers.
Bringers, Harbingers.
They have a "no eyes"
kind of look.
Doesn't ring a bell.
How about I ring
that bell for you?
Does the threatening come now?
Maybe you shouldn't help.
They would've come
to town recently.
They'd be holed up somewhere
summoning the spirit of the First.
Well, I heard a few things,
you know, from the underground.
The underground?
Yeah, you know, from things
that live under the ground.
Apparently there's been a lot
of migration out of Sunnydale
from the lower inhabitants.
Something's scaring them off...
and these are things that
aren't easily scared.
Could be your priest guys
are underground.
Underground where?
I do not know.
- Okay. Thanks.
- See you around.
Hey. You did great,
by the way.
I was very intimidated by you.
Really?
- Thanks.
- Let's go.
Hey, kid.
Merry Christmas.
Man, is it hot.
It was so nice
and cool in there.
Yeah, a nice cool waste
of time.
We know underground.
That's a start.
Sure, in a town with 14 million
square miles of sewer.
Plus a lot of natural cave formations
and a gateway to hell.
Yeah, this does
resemble square one.
- I don't know what to do.
- I think right now...
the best plan is to deck the halls
with boughs of holly.
Look, we'll catch the bad guys,
sooner or later.
Willow?
I got videos.
Hi.
Why don't you come s-sit down?
* I've heard people say that *
* Too much of anything
is not good for you, baby *
You ever have that dream
where you're in a play...
and you really don't know your lines,
and you kind of don't know the plot?
Well, we're alone...
and we're together.
I... I just wanted it
to be special.
How special are we talking?
Well, you know, we're alone...
and we're both mature
younger people...
and... and so we...
we could...
I... I'm ready to...
w... with you.
We could do that thing.
* I don't know why *
* I can't get enough
of your love, babe *
- Where are you going?
- No, I'm not going.
Just a dramatic gesture.
That's... That's pretty special.
Oz, I... I wanna
be with you first.
I think we should
sit down again.
Oz?
I'm ready.
Okay. Well, don't take
this the wrong way...
but I'm not.
Are you scared,
'cause I thought you had...
I have,
but this is different.
I mean, you look great,
you know.
And... And you got
the Barry working for you...
and it's all...
good.
But when it happens...
I want it to be because we both
need it too for the same reason.
You don't have to prove
anything to me.
I just wanted you to know.
I know.
I get the message.
There we go.
Nothing like a roaring fire
to keep away the blistering heat.
Oh, come on. It's lovely.
Maybe I should turn
the air conditioning on.
So, Angel's on top again?
What?
Angel or star?
Oh, uh, star.
Star.
[Doorbell Ringing]
Hey.
Hi.
Uh, looked like
that whole party thing
was gonna be kind of a drag.
I didn't really have anything...
You know.
I'm glad you came.
Uh, here.
Why don't you come in
from the entire lack of cold?
Mm.
Uh, that one is for your mom.
They're pretty crappy.
Faith, you made it.
Oh, that is so thoughtful.
They're crappy.
You know, I'm gonna go upstairs
and get your gifts.
Excuse me.
Uh, would you like some nog?
Okay, Mom, don't touch
yours, though...
'cause then you're gonna know
what it is.
Angel.
Huh.
Buffy.
What is it?
Uh...
[Agitated Breathing]
I gotta... I...
Look, I, uh,
I had to see you, um...
I don't know, I...
You shouldn't be...
Just tell me what's going on.
She wants you to touch her.
What are you waiting for?
You have to stay away from me.
You came to see me to tell me
that I can't see you?
Angel, something
is doing this to you.
You just have to
control it, okay?
I... I know that you're confused.
I think you're the one
who's confused.
I think you need to...
She wants you to taste her.
Think of the peace.
You'll never have to see us again.
Angel, how can I help you?
Leave me alone!
I just need you to stay with Mom
in case he comes back.
Yeah, I'll play watchdog.
I don't really get it, though.
I'll explain later.
Everything. I promise.
Watch your back.
Giles, we have to do something.
Soon. Now.
I'm still not sure what.
Find me these priest guys.
Find me something I can pummel.
Let's not lose our heads.
Giles, he's slipping.
I think we're losing him.
Look...
you realize if he...
truly becomes a danger...
you may have to kill him.
Again.
Can you do that?
I can't do it.
You have to do it.
What else are you good for?
Get away from me.
Couldn't you just... feel her?
Couldn't you almost smell her skin?
You never were a fighter, Angel.
Don't start trying now.
Sooner or later,
you will drink her.
I'll never hurt her.
You were born to hurt her.
Have you learned nothing?
As long as you are alive...
Then I'll die.
You don't have the strength
to kill yourself.
I don't need strength.
I just need the sun to rise.
You're not supposed to die.
This isn't the plan.
But it'll do.
"A child shall be born of man
and goat and have two heads...
and the First shall speak
only in riddles..."
No wonder you like this stuff.
It's like reading the sun.
Yes. Ah.
Priests?
Um, yes, but, uh,
more posturing, I'm afraid.
"For they are
the Harbingers of Death.
Nothing shall grow
above or below them.
No seed shall flower,
neither in man nor..."
They're rebels, and they'll never,
ever be any good.
- Nothing specific about their haunts.
- Let me see that.
"The Harbingers of Death.
Nothing shall grow
above or below."
What?
[Grunts]
All right, ten more minutes of chanting,
and then you guys have to go to bed.
Uhh!
Hmm. I'm impressed.
You won't get Angel.
Hmm.
You think you can fight me?
I'm not a demon, little girl.
I am something
that you can't even conceive...
The First Evil.
Beyond sin...
beyond death.
I am the thing
the darkness fears.
You'll never see me,
but I am everywhere.
Every being...
every thought...
every drop of hate.
All right, I get it.
You're evil.
Do we have to
chat about it all day?
Angel will be dead by sunrise.
Your Christmas will be his wake.
No.
You have no idea
what you're dealing with.
Let me guess.
Is it... evil?
Dead by sunrise!
Angel!
Angel.
I bet half the kids
down there are already awake.
Lying in their beds.
Sneaking downstairs.
Waiting for day.
Angel, please.
I need you to get inside.
There's only a few minutes left.
I know. I can smell the sunrise
long before it comes.
I don't have time to explain this.
You just have to trust me.
- That thing that was haunting you...
- It wasn't haunting me.
- It was showing me.
- Showing you?
- What I am.
- Were.
And ever shall be.
I wanted to know why I was back.
Now I do.
You don't know.
Some great evil
takes credit for bringing you back,
and you buy it?
You just give up?
I can't do it again, Buffy.
I can't become a killer.
Then fight it.
It's too hard.
Mm-mmm.
Angel, please,
you have to get inside.
It told me to kill you.
You were in the dream.
You know.
It told me to lose my soul in you
and become a monster again.
I know what it told you.
What does it matter?
Because I wanted to!
Because I want you so badly.
I want to take comfort in you...
and I know it'll cost me my soul...
and a part of me doesn't care.
Look, I'm weak.
I've never been anything else.
It's not the demon in me
that needs killing, Buffy.
It's the man.
You're weak.
Everybody is.
Everybody fails.
Maybe this evil
did bring you back...
but if it did,
it's because it needs you.
And that means
that you can hurt it.
Angel, you have the power
to do real good, to make amends.
But if you die now, then all
that you ever were was a monster.
Angel, please,
the sun is coming up.
- Just go.
- I won't.
You think this is simple?
You think there's an easy answer?
You can never understand
what I've done. Now go.
- You are not staying here.
I won't let you!
- Leave!
Oh, my God.
No! No!
Am I a thing worth saving, huh?
Am I a righteous man?
The world wants me gone.
What about me?
I love you so much.
And I tried to make you go away.
I killed you,
and it didn't help.
And I hate it!
I hate that it's so hard...
and that you can
hurt me so much.
I know everything that you did...
because you did it to me.
Oh, God.
I wish that I wished you dead.
I don't.
I can't.
Buffy, please.
Just this once...
let me be strong.
Strong is fighting.
It's hard...
and it's painful...
and it's every day.
It's what we have to do.
And we can do it together.
But if you're too much of
a coward for that, then burn.
If I can't convince you
that you belong in this world...
then I don't know what can.
But do not expect me to watch.
And don't expect me
to mourn for you, because...
TVweatherman:
And while most of Southern California
is enjoying a balmy Christmas...
an extreme cold front
has sprung up out of nowhere
around Sunnydale, where they
are reporting heavy snowfall
for the first time in,
well, ever.
Sunnydale residents shouldn't expect
to see the sun at all today.
That cold front
isn't going anywhere.
With temperatures in the high 30s...
means you better bundle up
if you're planning to go outside
and enjoy the change
in the weather.
Grr. Argh.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org