Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
The First. That's what it wants.
To erase all the slayers-in-training
and their watchers along with their methods.
(Willow) Buffy, he's been feeding...
He really didn't know what he'd done.
lt wasn't in his control.
lt's a trigger. lt's a brainwashing term.
lt's how the military makes sleeper agents.
- Amy.
- Can l come in?
lf you really are my friend,
you better stay away from me.
- Agent Finn, my implant?
- The implant works.
Hostile 17 can't harm any living creature
without intense neurological pain.
Aargh!
You think you can just do that to me?
Tara?
Somebody! Help!
- You wanna do the sleeping arrangements?
- OK.
You, uh... better not hog the covers.
- Are you sure you'll all be all right?
- You'll only be gone for two days.
- l think we've managed a bit longer than that.
- Right.
Oh, Dawn, Vi's left her notebook on the
mantelpiece. Would you run it out to the car?
Sure.
Smack her head with it.
Remind her not to leave it lying around.
On it.
l'm just a bit twitchy
about leaving you alone again here
while things are...
in such a state of flux.
l know. But you should go.
This trip is important for the girls
to understand the source of their power
and know how to use it.
l don't think they appreciate
the gravity of our undertaking.
lt's frightening, and it's difficult.
And then, apparently someone told them
that the vision quest consists of me driving
them to the desert, doing the hokey pokey
until a spooky Rasta-mama slayer arrives
and speaks to them in riddles.
That's not exactly how l put it, l...
Hey, how's Kennedy?
Still fluey.
Bummed about missing the field trip.
She says she wants you to meditate extra
hard for her and bring her back some s'mores.
Ah, yes, s'mores. l'm going to end up
singing campfire songs aren't l?
Oh, yeah.
- Giles, you might wanna get out there.
- God, what?
Molly and Rona are fighting over
who gets to drive the first leg.
Bet you wish you renewed
that California driver's licence.
Rona won. You should probably
let Molly out of the trunk.
l never actually realised
just how compact Molly really is.
- Please be safe while l'm away.
- You too.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
- Hey.
Giles is off... on the retreat.
- Give us all a chance for a breather, eh?
- From Giles?
From the constant pitter-patter
of clomping teenage girlie feet.
- l have no idea what you're talking about.
- Come on.
No, l enjoy my responsibility
as mentor, role model, life guide...
Oh, my God, l cannot believe l have my
bathroom all to myself for two whole days.
lt's like a bloody war zone up there,
and not in a good way.
- Seen the kitchen since they've been here?
- l'm just tryin' to stay out of their way.
l noticed.
This is better. Believe me, it's safer.
OK. But you've been fine.
ln close contact with the girls.
Yeah. With you by my side, yeah.
You wouldn't let me hurt one of them.
And that's the way it's gonna be until we're
sure the First is done making me its bitch.
Either we're together, or l'm on the leash.
We just need to make sure
the trigger's deactivated.
We've got a couple of days,
lack of pitter-patter and all.
Buffy.
What?
- Ow.
- Ow?
Ow, ow, ow!
(groans and yelps)
What's wrong? Spike, what is going on?
The chip. God. God.
Why would...?
No!
Aargh!
(Willow) Hey. How is he?
Oh, in the "goes" part of "comes and goes".
There seems to be a definite lack
of screaming. That has to be good.
You'd think.
- That for the other patient?
- Yeah.
Thought l'd bring her some tea,
help her feel better.
Mm-hm?
- lt's just tea.
- (Buffy laughs)
Will...
how much do you know about the chip?
Spike's chip?
l remember trying to dig up stuff back then,
but, you know, it turns out when a secret
government agency studies vampires
and puts chips in their brains
that keep them from hurting people,
they don't really build websites. Why?
Even with the chip Spike was able
to hurt people when he was brainwashed.
Yeah, but he was
under the control of the First.
- Maybe something's wrong with it.
- The chip is misfiring all on its own, then.
Well, this will be fun.
Remember when things
used to be nice and boring?
No.
Have fun... delivering the tea.
OK, not when you make it
sound all dirty like that.
lt's just tea.
(knock at door)
Hey, l figured the best thing
for a cold is a nice hot cup of...
Boots?
Hey.
For someone who's sick, you look
surprisingly robust and casual dressy.
Well, the lighting in here is good.
- Maybe it's just...
- You were never sick.
No.
- l was never sick.
- Oh, you are so busted.
- Xander's gonna have to drive you to...
- Willow, chill. There's a reason l didn't go.
l have a thing. A separate thing.
- What?
- Something's coming down.
l have my own mission. And l need your help.
(# rock music)
- This is a mission?
- Oh. Yeah.
And the little paper umbrellas
are a signal for what?
- We're not on a mission, are we?
- Hey, trust me.
l told you. l have a thing.
Come on, come on.
Just hang out with me a little.
You're sexy when you pout.
Why do you do that?
To get you to stay.
All right, l'll stay for one drink,
then l'm going home.
OK. One drink. l can work with that.
Let's start with the easy stuff.
How long have you known?
- That you were gay.
- Wait. That's easy?
And, what, you just assume that l'm gay?
- l mean, presume much?
- OK, sorry.
How long have you enjoyed sex with women?
Hey!
What, you think you have some sort
of special lesbidar or something?
OK, you know there's
a better word for that, right?
You really haven't been getting
out there much, have you?
Well, l just...
Can you always tell
just by looking at someone?
No.
No, of course not.
That wouldn't be any fun.
The fun part is the process
of getting to know a girl. lt's like...
lt's like flirting in code.
lt's using body language
and laughing at the rightjokes and...
and looking into her eyes...
and knowing she's still whispering to you,
even when she's not sayin' a word.
And that sense that...
if you can just touch her,
just once...
everything will be OK... for both of you.
That's how you can tell.
Or if she's really hot, you just get her drunk,
see if she comes on to you.
Three years ago. That's when l knew.
And it wasn't women, it was woman.
Just one.
Lucky woman.
(Spike) Popped another blood vessel, l think.
There's gotta be a reason
why the chip is going all wonky.
Maybe it's related to the trigger.
Or maybe it has something to do
with the new soul.
Or maybe l wasn't meant to last this long.
One more thing you and l
have in common, eh, pet?
- We'll fix it. We'll hit serious research mode...
- Good.
Try Behavioural Modification Software
Throughout the Ages.
OK. You're right.
Not a book thing.
- lt's a phone thing.
- Who you gonna call?
God, that phrase is never
gonna be usable again, is it?
Doubt it.
- Do your parents know?
- Yeah.
My mom was all proud like l was
making some political statement.
Then the statement mojo wore off
and l was just gay.
She hardly ever even met Tara.
Classic.
l didn't mind.
Tara and l are kind of private.
l'm sorry. lt must've...
Were, l mean. Private.
Yes, Agent Finn, Riley.
Tell him we're having a problem
with Spike's chip.
No, his chip.
Spike.
- Listen, pet?
- No, no, Finn is his last name.
Yeah.
Well, did he used to work there
and maybe he got transferred?
- Oh!
- Oh.
ls this actually a flower shop,
or is this one of those things
where l'm supposed to play along
to show l know it's secret ops?
Maybe l shouldn't have said that. Um...
OK.
Right. Uh...
Well, if some guy named Finn
shows up to buy flowers...
Yeah. Thanks.
Wrong number. Or a giant
government conspiracy, one or the...
Spike?
This one seemed easier than the others.
See? Probably just gonna fade...
Aargh!
lt was Gone with the Wind.
l saw that, and l knew l wanted
to sweep Scarlett off her feet.
You were five.
Well, l'm not saying the sweeping
would have been easy.
- What?
- l just...
l still don't get it.
Why you like me.
l mean, you don't even know me.
Have you seen you?
And we like the same things.
ltalian, skate punk,
Robert Parker mysteries, fighting evil...
l don't like any of that stuff.
Except the fighting-evil part.
But, even then, l'd prefer a nice foot massage.
OK.
l dig the way you turn off the Moulin Rouge!
DVD at chapter 32 so it has a happy ending.
l like the way you speak. lt's interesting.
And your freckles...
lickable.
l'm not so into the magic stuff.
lt seems like fairy-tale crap to me,
but if it matters to you...
You care about it, so it's cool.
Well, this is my stop.
So...
glad we talked.
Yes.
- Kinda cleared the air, huh?
- Yeah, totally. Air cleared. Check.
You know, in the spirit of air clearing...
Yeah?
l feel like l need to be honest
about something.
- ls something wrong?
- No.
No.
lt's just...
l think you should... know...
(Warren) Well, that was nice.
Are you OK?
l'm not used to literally knocking girls off of
their feet with just the power of my own lips.
- OK, you gonna pick that up, or...?
- l don't...
- What are you?
- ls this a freckle thing, cos...
Oh, God! Oh, God.
- What is that?
- lt's the man that l killed.
(Kennedy) OK, hold up a sec.
- Guys.
- Get Buffy. The First is back.
- l'm not the First.
- We're not interested in your evil lies.
No, guys, it's me. (Warren's voice)
l'm me. l'm Willow. Guys, come on.
- Ask Kennedy, she was there.
- l don't know. l'm not sure.
We were up in Willow's room and we were...
- No, you're back.
- No, l'm not. lt's not... l'm not it.
- Listen to me...
- No more listening.
l know who you are now. l know what you
made me do. Your promises of happy fields
and dancing schnauzers
and being demigods won't work on me.
- Buffy!
- The Bringers are probably coming.
- l'm not the First.
- You made me do things l can't take back.
- What the hell is going on in here?
- Ow!
- Buffy...
- Wait.
- But if he's the First...
- l'm not.
- You're not.
l know.
Oh, my God. You're back.
Hey, bad touching!
- Aargh!
- Everyone please stop it, it's me.
- lt's Willow.
- l'm Willow.
- Are you sure?
- There are other stories from kindergarten.
Non-yellow-crayon stories in which
you don't come out in such a good light.
An incident involving Aquaman underoos.
You want me to start talkin'?
- Hey, Willow!
- What happened?
l don't know. We were... there,
and then l looked like him.
- Oh, like a glamour.
- Maybe, but l probably brought it on myself.
- What makes you think that?
- lt wouldn't be the first time.
l have a history with my subconscious
making things go kerfloofey.
Remember the wacky "l can't see you,
you can't see me" spell?
Guys!
- lt's so real.
- Yeah, all too aware.
Say you did do this to yourself. Why would
your subconscious turn you into Warren?
Obviously because l feel bad...
about killing him.
Look, we'll deal. We'll get help.
- No, l can handle this.
- On your own? Why?
l did it. l'll fix it. l don't want you
seeing me this way, anyway.
lt's kind of a little late for that.
Seriously, l'm not posing any big threat.
Looks like you've got your hands full already.
l'll go, l'll handle it, l'll fix it.
l'll be back before you even know l'm gone.
(Warren's voice) Promise.
Spike?
- Buffy.
- l'm right here.
- The chip fired again.
- l kinda figured.
Maybe they'll call back.
Maybe they'll send help.
Maybe we can't wait.
- Oh!
- OK.
No one will ever accuse you
of being too butch.
- Kennedy, go home.
- Come on.
l mean... you turned into a guy.
lf you take a step back, seriously, there's
a certain element of humour here, right?
Well, a really, really big step.
l killed him. lt's hard to see the chuckles.
- So you got a plan?
- Yeah, gonna get some help reversing it.
- l thought you were gonna try it.
- l did. lt didn't work.
- Something's blocking me.
- All the more reason for me to go with you.
Plus, l was there with you when it happened.
Let me come to try to help too.
- l really think l'm fine with the handling.
- By yourself? Why?
l'm the one that killed him.
- lt's hard to understand.
- Given.
How about l just tag along anyway?
Keep you company.
- l'm taking that as a yes.
- Fine. Come.
But try not to get in the way.
- You know where you're going?
- To see some old friends of mine.
Been a while, but maybe they can help.
Are you sure you still wanna go back
in this place with me?
Uh, nothing good on TV tonight.
- Here we are.
- Yup, here we are.
- You think the stuff's still good?
- l don't know.
Worked pretty good when
the lnitiative held me captive here.
Every time l'd get a little rambunctious,
the chip'd kick in,
and l'd feel like my head was gonna explode.
They'd dope me up, and everything
would be all daffodils and teddy bears.
- For a couple of hours anyway.
- Maybe we should search for files and stuff.
Find out everything we can
about the chip. Shelf life.
l'll take whatever l can get.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
- (phone rings)
- l'll get it.
Supposed to get a call when the League
of Extraordinary Gentlemen comes in.
- See if you can get two?
- Summers residence.
This is Andrew speaking.
How can l help you?
Loser.
Hey, do we know
some British guy named Robson?
He was attacked,
this... Robson guy in England.
And Giles was there helpin' him.
- And there was a Bringer.
- Xander...
Robson blacked out, but the last thing
he remembers is Giles's head...
about to get familiar
with a Bringer's very sharp axe.
- Oh, my God!
- Giles never mentioned any of this.
Robson said by the time he came to...
there was no Giles.
- So, what are we saying?
- Maybe Giles just didn't want to talk about it.
Or maybe he didn't make it.
Look, l'm not saying it's a happy scenario,
but we're dealing with the Big Bad
that can be any dead person.
To infiltrate the inner circle of the Slayer...
You become the one person she trusts
more than anybody else.
- But there's no way that we can know.
- Actually, that's not true.
The First can't take corporeal form,
so it can't touch anything.
Well, it's not like Giles
hasn't touched anything, right?
Has anyone seen Giles
touch anything since he got back?
Hold anything?
Has anybody hugged him?
Think very hard.
- Where're you...?
- The desert, to find Giles.
Oh, good. Let me just get
some tapes for the car.
- (Xander) You're not coming.
- What? Why?
Cos l used to be evil?
No, cos you're annoying,
but that's a good reason too.
Wait, l... Don't leave me here all alone.
l keep getting attacked in this house.
- Actually...
- What if this is part of the plan?
Drive you guys away so it can have
its way with me? Ever think of that?
- l'll risk it.
- OK, well, if you leave me here alone,
l'll do something evil, like...
burning something
or... gluing things together.
For crying out loud, Harris, let's just take him.
At least we can keep an eye on him.
- Xander.
- l know, they're out there all alone.
All of 'em.
(Vaughne) lnstil us, oh, great one,
with peace, with strength,
with compassion,
with hope.
The path we seek is yours.
Keep us on that path.
OK, wow, this is new.
Um, hi, we're...
Oh, hey. l'm sorry. Willow.
We actually met when l was a freshman.
And also not a boy.
- This is Kennedy.
- Hey.
- You're Willow?
- Yeah.
Wow, look at you guys.
Campus Wiccans. l guess you
got past the whole bake-sale phase.
No, we still do that too.
Second Tuesday of every month.
l'm sorry, l'm kind of having a hard time
with the whole guy event thing.
(girl) Um...
lt's actually her. l can tell.
l know her.
OK. Whoa!
Um, OK, here's the thing. Hi.
Here's the thing.
l'll just get this out of the way.
l'm sorta screwed up, but l mean, you already
knew that because you lived it. Gotcha.
- But she's doing so much better now. Amy...
- lt's OK, Vaughne, l wanna do this.
lt took me a long time to really see myself.
But l did. Because that's the crazy thing
about hitting rock bottom,
you get to relive all
the crappy things that you did.
l wanted to come find you and tell you that l
was here working on things with these guys.
That they're good. And that l was sorry.
But you're here. Looking like...
Wow! How did this happen?
That's what we're here to find out.
lf we're done with all the group hugging.
l got hit with this, like, glamour thing,
and l can't seem to shake it myself.
l was hoping that someone here
might be able to help.
Yeah, the thing is we're more about healing
spirits and nurturing our life force here.
Oh.
But we'll try.
- (Amy) Her spirit's true...
- What if she can't handle this?
- You have a better idea?
- Give back the form the soul requires.
- See that the balance is put right.
- Argh!
- lt didn't work?
- No it didn't, you dumb bitch!
Willow!
- You slapped me!
- No, l didn't.
lt wasn't me.
lt was Warren.
Willow.
Willow!
- OK, you're upset.
- Upset? Upset?
Are you just tuning in?
Did you not see that?
l'm turning into him.
lt's not a trick, it's not a glamour.
l'm becoming him.
A murderous, misogynist man.
l mean, do you understand what he did?
What l could do? l killed him for a reason.
Getting angry isn't helping. We can try...
You understand nothing about magic. And in
case you haven't noticed, our date - it's over.
Willow!
Willow, wait!
(Buffy) Be careful.
Oh, God.
They just left 'em.
(Spike) They just sealed the place off.
Left everything as it was.
- (Buffy) l'm thinkin' brief stay.
- Yeah, you're not wrong.
l think l can get us
to the med lab, find the drug.
(creaking)
OK, l'll go. R.
- Ghost is hard to play by yourself.
- How long since they left?
A few hours.
lf it is the First, and l'm not saying it is,
what are we expecting to find?
He didn't bring 'em out there to meditate.
Kinda makes you grateful you weren't
a potential after all, doesn't it? Safer.
- Yeah, well, not so fast with the big "phew".
- He might know we're coming.
Which means we're too late
and heading to the middle of nowhere.
- With no slayer, no powerful witch...
- Just a teenager, a powerless former demon,
and two big geeks.
OK, licence-plate game, maybe?
Look at me. Crying like a little girl.
(creaking)
- (Spike) You hear that?
- (Buffy) Yep.
Think something survived?
Sounds like.
- (Spike) You see where?
- (Buffy) No.
But it sounded like
it was coming from over there.
- Whatever it is, it's not...
- (creaking and growling)
(growling)
(Spike) Buffy!
- Where'd they go?
- They took off.
lt was a little too creepy, even for us.
You're really worried about her.
Look, she's gonna be fine, really.
She's good at this. She's strong.
And she's dealt with a lot worse.
Long before she went out and found herself
a big old potential-slayer bodyguard, OK?
Just have a little faith in her.
- l never said l was a potential slayer.
- Oh. No, l think you did.
- When you first got here, you told us that...
- No, l didn't.
How did you know who l was?
Oops.
(growling)
(Spike) Oh, God, no.
God! No, not now.
(growls)
Spike! Uh!
(growling)
So, same model as last time.
How'd that work out for you?
You'd be amazed.
- (Andrew) Aargh!
- (Xander) Touch him. Touch him.
- Oh, l feel him. l feel him.
- Me too.
- Good. We all feel each other.
lncluding some of us who don't know each
other well enough to take such liberties.
l assume there is a perfectly reasonable
and not-at-all-insane explanation, yes?
- We thought you were non-corporeal evil.
- We can't remember you touching anything.
We had to make sure you were OK.
Oh.
Ah.
That's very... Yes, that's very sweet.
Now wait a minute. You thought...
You think l'm evil if l bring a group of girls
on a camping trip and don't touch them?
Spike?
(growling)
Argh!
Hey.
- Are you still with us?
- Yeah.
Well, that guy was...
- ..just the beginning.
- What's happening?
Miss Summers. Agent Finn reported that you
tried to contact him earlier today.
l knew it. Government conspiracy.
He indicated you might need our assistance.
We're to provide you anything
you need to help assface here.
Those were his exact words, ma'am.
(soldier) Med team tells me
they took a look at the chip.
You were right. lt's degraded.
Leave it as it is much longer,
it'll be fatal to him.
OK. So, how long t...
Now, ma'am.
Right, of course. Um... What do we do next?
Agent Finn said it was your call, ma'am.
My... What was my call?
All decisions regarding Hostile 17
are to be left in your hands.
His chip...
We can either repair it or remove it.
Tell me why you did this to her.
Uh!
- What did you do to her?
- (Amy) What, to Willow?
Oh, just your standard
penance malediction is all.
OK.
And that's magic crazy talk for what?
- l put a hex on her.
- l got that part.
But why Warren?
And why did it happen after we kissed?
Oh!
That's rich.
That must've been some kiss.
- You must be good.
- Answer me.
The hex lets the victim's subconscious
pick the form of their punishment.
Always better than anything
l can come up with. Elegant.
- Undo it. Let her out.
- OK.
Oh, wait, l forgot. No.
Why would you do this to her?
You really hate her that much?
(sighs)
This is not about hate.
lt's about power.
Willow always had the power,
long before she knew what to do with it.
Just came so easy for her.
The rest of us? We had to work
twice as hard to be half as good.
But no one cares about how hard you work.
They just care about cute, sweet Willow.
They don't know how weak she is.
She gave in to evil,
and stuff worse than l can even imagine.
She almost destroyed the world.
And yet everyone keeps on loving her?
So what's wrong with having a little fun,
huh? Taking her down a peg or two?
Fun? She's disappearing.
Fading away in that creep,
and you think it's fun?
lt was just a game.
lt's not my fault if she's losing herself.
- l'm gonna stop you now, you know.
- Hey.
l'm not the bad guy here.
But l wonder where he'd be right about now.
Well, that was a hell of a thing.
Think you can just do that to me?
That l'd let you get away with it?
Do? Get away with...?
OK.
- Let's not get excited.
- lt's too late for that. This is what l am.
l made it happen, and l'll make it stop.
Willow.
- What did you make happen?
- You were there, bitch! You saw it!
l killed her.
- You mean him.
- Her, him... You know what l mean.
But you said "her".
No. That was Warren.
No, no, it wasn't. You said l was there.
- Who did you kill, Willow?
- lt was your fault, slut.
You tricked me.
Got me to forget.
- Tara.
- Shut up!
Shut up! You do not get to say her name.
Offering it up to whoever's there.
Tricking me into kissing you.
l didn't... l didn't mean...
What l'm saying... l...
l can't make... Kennedy...
l can't hold on. He's winning.
No.
l'm being punished.
l kissed you just for a second,
but it was enough.
l let her go. l didn't mean to.
- Kissing me didn't mean...
- No.
She was never gone. She was with me.
We should have been forever.
And l... l let her be dead.
She's really dead. And l killed her.
Willow, no.
Please, baby, l'm so sorry.
Come back. l'm sorry. l'm sorry, come back!
Willow, l don't think you did anything wrong.
This is just magic. And l think
l'm figuring the whole magic thing out.
- lt's just like fairy tales.
- What are you doing?
Bringing you back to life.
Hm.
l am good.
lt's me?
l'm back? Oh, God.
Are you all right?
l have no idea.
l'm so tired.
Yeah.
l'll make you some tea.
Visiontext Subtitles: Abigail Smith
Urgh! Argh!
ENGLlSH SDH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org