- Previously:
- I love you.
Oh, my God.
Here lies the warrior of the people.
Let her cross over!
I think I was in Heaven.
I was torn out of there by my friends.
They can never know.
We can't ignore this behaviour.
Something needs to be done.
I'm glad you're here to take care of it.
We're getting married.
Willow, you're using too much magic.
- Can we not do this now?
- Forget it ever happened.
Forget.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Every single night, the same arrangement
I go out and fight the fight
Still I always feel the strange estrangement
Nothing here is real, nothing here is right
I've been making shows of trading blows
Just hoping no one knows
That I've been going through the motions
Walking through the part
Nothing seems to penetrate my heart
I was always brave, and kind of righteous
Now I find I'm wavering
Crawl out of your grave,
You'll find this fight just
- Doesn't mean a thing
- She ain't got that swing
Thanks for noticing
She does pretty well with fiends from Hell,
but lately we can tell
- That she's just going through the motions
- Going through the motions
Faking it somehow
She's not even half the girl she... Ow!
Will I stay this way for ever?
Sleepwalk through my life's endeavour?
- How can I repay...
- Whatever
I don't want to be
Going through the motions
Losing all my drive
I can't even see
If this is really me
And I just want to be
Alive
- Good morning, Buffy!
- Did Dawn get off to school all right?
What? Oh, yeah. I think so.
Respect the cruller. And tame the doughnut!
That's still funny, sweetie.
So, uh, no research?
Nothing goin' on? Monsters or whatnot?
Good. Good.
So, did anybody...
last night, you know, did anybody...
burst into song?
Merciful Zeus!
- We thought it was just us!
- I had my guitar at the hotel...
- We were talking, then it was like...
- You were in a musical.
That explains the huge backing orchestra
and the dancing room-service chaps.
- We argued, then it rhymed...
- An entire verse about couscous.
- It was very disturbing.
- What did you sing about?
I don't remember.
But it seemed perfectly normal.
But disturbing. Not natural.
Do you think it'll happen again?
We should look into it.
- With the books.
- Do we have any books on this?
We break it down. Look at the factors
before it happens again. I for one...
I've got a theory
That it's a demon
A dancing demon
No, something isn't right there
I've got a theory
Some kid is dreaming
And we're all stuck inside
his wacky Broadway nightmare
I've got a theory we should work this out
It's getting eerie
What's this cheery singing all about?
It could be witches!
Some evil witches
Which is ridiculous
cos witches they were persecuted
Wicca good and love the Earth
and women power and I'll be over here
I've got a theory
It could be bunnies
- I've got a...
- Bunnies aren't just cute
Like everybody supposes
They got them hoppy legs
and twitchy little noses
And what's with all the carrots?
What do they need
such good eyesight for anyway?
Bunnies!
Bunnies! It must be bunnies!
- Or maybe midgets
- I've got a theory we should work this fast
Because it clearly
could get serious before it's passed
I've got a theory
It doesn't matter
What can't we face if we're together?
What's in this place that we can't weather?
Apocalypse?
We've all been there
The same old trips
Why should we care?
What can't we do if we get in it?
We'll work it through within a minute
We have to try
We'll pay the price
It's do or die
Hey, I've died twice
- What can't we face if we're together?
- What can't we face?
- What's in this place that we can't weather?
- If we're together
There's nothing we can't face
Except for bunnies
- See, OK, that was disturbing.
- I thought it was neat.
So what is it? What's causing it?
I thought it didn't matter.
Well, I'm not quaking
in my stylish-yet-affordable boots,
but there's something unnatural going on.
And that doesn't usually lead
to hugs and puppies.
Well, is it just us?
I mean, is it only happening to us?
Cos that would probably mean a spell.
They got
the mustard
- out!
- They got the mustard out!
It's not just us.
Oh, my God. You will never believe
what happened at school today.
Everybody started singing and dancing?
I gave birth to a pterodactyl.
Oh, my God. Did it sing?
- So you guys too, huh?
- So what'd you sing about?
Math.
That's right! The volume. The text.
What text?
- The volumey... text.
- You know.
The mmummrfugh report.
The what now?
There's a few volumes at the house
about mystical chants, bacchanals.
- Might be relevant.
- Yeah, we could...
I'm a hair's breadth from investigating
bunnies, so I'm open to anything.
Great. We'll check it out
and we'll give you a call.
Yeah, this could blow
the whole thing wide open.
Do we have any books at all at home?
Who wants to be cooped up
on a day like this?
The sun is shining, there's songs going on,
those guys are checking you out...
What? What are they looking at?
- The hotness of you, doofus.
- Those boys really thought I was hot?
Entirely.
Oh, my God. I'm cured!
I want the boys!
Do I have to fight to keep you?
Cos I'm not large with the butch.
I'm just not used to that.
They were really looking at me?
And you can't imagine what they see in you?
I know exactly what they see in me.
You.
I lived my life in shadow
Never the sun on my face
It didn't seem so sad though
I figured that was my place
Now I'm bathed in light
Something just isn't right
I'm under your spell
How else could it be
Anyone would notice me?
It's magic, I can tell
How you've set me free
Brought me out so easily
I saw a world enchanted
Spirits and charms in the air
I always took for granted
I was the only one there
But your power shone
Brighter than any I've known
I'm under your spell
Nothing I can do
You just took my soul with you
You worked your charms so well
Finally, I knew
Everything I dreamed was true
You make me believe
The moon to the tide
I can feel you inside
I'm under your spell
Surging like the sea
Go to you so helplessly
I break with every swell
Lost in ecstasy
Spread beneath my willow tree
You make me
Complete
You make me complete
You make me...
- I bet they're not even working.
- Who now?
Willow and Tara. You see the way they were
with each other? The get-a-roominess?
I bet they're...
Singing. They're probably singing right now.
I'm sure they're making every effort.
- Oh, yeah.
- Xander.
Buffy, it's OK. I do know about this stuff.
- Besides, it's all kinda romantic.
- No, it's not.
Come on! Songs, dancing around.
What's gonna be wrong with that?
That's entertainment.
You want some breakfast, baby?
- You don't have to go to work?
- Nah, I shut the crew down for the day.
My guys start dancing around me,
I don't know if I can deal.
It's a flab thing. So, waffles?
Will you still make me waffles
when we're married?
No, I'll only make them for myself, but
by California law you will own half of them.
Hey, how about omelettes?
I could do an omelette...
This man that I plan to entangle
Isn't he fine?
My claim to fame
was to maim and to mangle
Vengeance was mine
But I'm out of the biz
The name I made, I'll trade for his
The only trouble is...
I'll never tell
She is the one
She's such wonderful fun
Such passion and grace
Warm in the night
when I'm right in her tight
Embrace, tight embrace
I'll never let her go
The love we've known can only grow
There's just one thing that...
No, I'll never tell
Cos there's nothing to tell
- He snores
- She wheezes
Say "housework" and he freezes
She eats these skeezy cheeses
that I can't describe
- I talk, he breezes
- She doesn't know what pleases
His penis got diseases
from a Chumash tribe
The vibe gets kind of scary
- Like she thinks I'm ordinary
- Like it's all just temporary
- Like her toes are kind of hairy
- But it's all very well
Cos God knows, I'll never tell
When things get rough, he
Just hides behind his Buffy
Now look, he's getting huffy
cos he knows that I know
She clings, she's needy
She's also really greedy
- She nev...
- His eyes are beady
This is my verse! Hello!
She...
Look at me! I'm dancing crazy!
You know...
- You're quite the charmer
- My knight in armour
You're the cutest of the Scoobies
With your lips as red as rubies
And your firm yet supple... tight embrace!
- He's swell
- She's sweller
He'll always be my fella
That's why I'll never tell her
that I'm petrified
I've read this tale
There's wedding, then betrayal
I know that come the day
I'll want to run and hide
I lied
I said it's easy
I've tried
But there's these fears I can't quell
Is she looking for a pot of gold?
Will I look good when I've gotten old?
Will our lives become too stressful
if I'm never that successful?
When I get so worn and wrinkly
that I look like David Brinkley
- Am I crazy?
- Am I dreaming?
Am I marrying a demon?
We could really raise the beam in
making marriage a hell
So, thank God, I'll never tell
I swear that I'll never tell
My lips are sealed
I take the Fifth
Nothin' to see, move it along
I'll never tell
- It's a nightmare. It's a plague.
- It's like we were being watched.
- I didn't wanna say things but they came out.
- Like a wall was missing from our apartment.
- My toes are not hairy!
- My eyes are not beady!
- You gotta stop it.
- I am looking into some leads...
Of course, our number is a retro pastiche...
that's never going to be
a breakaway pop hit.
- Gimme an axe. Show me where to point it.
- As ever, it's not quite that simple.
- But I have learned some disturbing things...
- ...put that pad away
I'm asking you, please no
It isn't right, it isn't fair
There was no parking anywhere
I think that hydrant wasn't there
Why can't you let it go?
- I think I've paid more than my share...
- Somebody set people on fire? That's nuts!
I don't know. One more verse of our ditty
and I'd have been looking for a gas can.
Well, clearly emotions are running high.
But as far as I can tell
these people burnt up from the inside,
spontaneously combusted.
I've only seen the one. I examined the body
while the police were taking witness arias.
But we're sure the things are related, the
singing and dancing and burning and dying.
We're not sure of much. Buffy's looking
for leads at the local demon haunts.
At least, in theory she is,
but she doesn't seem to...
She's easing back into it. We pulled her
out of an untold Hell dimension.
Ergo the weirdness.
The important thing is to be there for her.
I'm helping her as much as I can, but...
The sun sets and she appears.
- Come to serenade me?
- So you know what's going on.
I've seen some damn funny things
the last two days.
A 600-pound Chirago demon making like
Yma Sumac, that one will stay with you.
I remain immune, happy to say.
Drink?
A world of no.
So any idea what's causing this?
Oh. So that's all. You've just come
to pump me for information.
What else would I wanna pump you for?
I really just said that, didn't I?
Yeah, well, don't wanna
bore you with the small talk.
Don't know a thing.
- What's up? You're all bad-moody.
- It's nothing. Glad you could stop by.
- It's nothing!
- What?
I died
So many years ago
But you can make me feel
Like it isn't so
And why you come to be with me
I think I finally know
You're scared
Ashamed of what you feel
And you can't tell the ones you love
You know they couldn't deal
Whisper in a dead man's ear
It doesn't make it real
That's great
But I don't wanna play
Cos bein' with you touches me
More than I can say
But since I'm only dead to you
I'm saying stay away
And let me rest in peace
Let me rest in peace
Let me get some sleep
Let me take my love and bury it
In a hole six foot deep
I can lay my body down
but I can't find my sweet release
So let me rest in peace
You know
You got a willing slave
And you just love to play the thought
That you might misbehave
But till you do I'm tellin' you
Stop visitin' my grave
And let me rest in peace
I know I should go
But I follow you like a man possessed
There's a traitor here beneath my breast
And it hurts me more
than you've ever guessed
If my heart could beat
it would break my chest
But I can see you're unimpressed
So leave me be
And let me rest in peace
Let me get some sleep
Let me take my love and bury it
In a hole six foot deep
I can lay my body down
but I can't find my sweet release
Let me rest in peace.
Why won't you
Let me rest in peace?
So you're not staying then?
- Lot of homework?
- Math.
It seemed cool
when we were singing about it.
Willow said they have a lead
on the whole musical-extravaganza evil.
This demon that can be summoned,
some sort of lord of the dance.
But not the scary one. Just a demon.
- Do they know who summoned it?
- They don't even know its name.
But Willow will find out.
She's a brainy type.
- I'm glad you guys made up.
- What?
That fight you guys had
about magic and stuff?
It gives me belly rumblings
when you guys fight.
Dawn, Willow and I never fought about...
It's OK. It's just...
You guys are so great together.
I just hate it when you...
But that was the only fight
I've seen you guys have anyway.
But I'm still glad it's over.
Dawn, I...
There's something I need at the shop.
Will you be OK for a little while?
Yes. The 15-year-old can spend
half an hour alone in her locked house.
I won't be gone long.
Does anybody even notice?
Does anybody even care?
Why'd you run away?
Don't you like my style?
Why don't you come and play?
I guarantee a
Great big smile
I come from the imagination
And I'm here strictly by your invocation
So whaddaya say?
Why don't we dance awhile?
I'm the heart of swing
I'm the twist and shout
When you gotta sing
When you gotta
Let it out
You call me and I come a-runnin'
I turn the music on
I bring the fun in
Now we're partyin'
That's what it's all about
Cos I know
What you feel, girl
I know
Just what you feel, girl
So you're, like, a good demon?
Bringin' the fun in?
All these melodies
They go on too long
Then that energy
Starts to come on
Way too strong
All those hearts laid open, that must sting
Plus some customers just start combusting
That's the penalty
When life is but a song
You brought me down
and doomed this town
So when we blow this scene
Back we will go to my kingdom below
And you will be my queen
Cos I know what you feel, girl
No, you see, you and me
wouldn't be very regal
I'll make it real, girl
What I mean, I'm fifteen
So this queen thing's illegal
I can bring whole cities to ruin
And still have time to get a soft-shoe in
Well, that's great, but I'm late
and I'd hate to delay her
Something's cookin', I'm at the griddle
I bought Nero his very first fiddle
She'll get pissed if I'm missed
See, my sister's the Slayer
The Slayer?
Find her. Tell her... tell her everything.
Just get her here.
I wanna see the Slayer burn.
Now we're partyin'
That's what it's all about
Good. Good.
I feel like I should bow, or...
have honour, or something.
It may seem hokey but we need precision
and concentration as much as power.
- We're not sure what we're facing.
- Oh, you'll figure it out.
I'm worried this session's gonna turn into
some training montage from an '80s movie.
Well, if we hear any
inspirational power chords,
we'll just lie down until they go away.
Anyway, I don't think we need
to work that much on your strength.
Yeah, I'm pretty spry for a corpse.
Have you spoken to Dawn
about that incident at Hallowe'en?
I thought you took care of that.
- Right.
- What would I do without you?
OK. I'm ready.
You're not ready for the world outside
You keep pretending, but you just can't hide
I know I said that I'd be
standing by your side
But I...
Your path's unbeaten and it's all uphill
And you can meet it, but you never will
And I'm the reason
that you're standing still
But I...
I wish I could say the right words
To lead you through this land
Wish I could play the father
And take you by the hand
Wish I could stay here
But now I understand
I'm standing
In the way
The cries around you, you don't hear at all
Cos you know I'm here to take that call
So you just lie there
when you should be standing tall
But I...
I wish I could lay your arms down
And let you rest at last
Wish I could slay your demons
But now that time has passed
Wish I could stay here
Your stalwart, standing fast
But I'm standing
In the way
I'm just standing
Did you just say something?
I'm under your spell
God, how can this be?
Playing with my memory
You know I've been through hell
Willow, don't you see?
There'll be nothing left of me
You made me
- Believe
- Believe me, I don't wanna go
And it'll grieve me cos I love you so
But we both know
- Wish I could say the right words
- Wish I could trust that it was
- To lead you through this land
- Just this once, but I must do
- Wish I could play the father
- What I must. I can't adjust to this
- And take you by the hand
- Disgust, we're done and I just
Wish I could stay
Wish I could
Stay
Lookie lookie what I found.
- Is this the demon guy?
- Tara!
Works for him. Has a nice little
story for the Slayer, don't you?
Come on, then. Sing.
My master has the Slayer's sister at the
Bronze because she summoned him.
At midnight he's going to take her
to the underworld to be his queen.
What does he want?
Her.
If that's all you've got to say, then I'm...
Strong.
Someday he'll be a real boy.
So, Dawn's in trouble.
- Must be Tuesday.
- I just left her for a few minutes.
It's not your fault. So what's the plan?
- Plan, schman. Let's mount up.
- No.
Dawn had the wrong idea
in summoning this creature, but...
I've seen some of these underworld
child-bride deals and they never end well.
- Well, maybe once.
- We're not just gonna stay here?
Yes, we are.
Buffy's going alone.
- Don't be a stupid git. There is no...
- If I want your opinion, Spike, I'll...
I'll never want your opinion.
- A little confusion spell could...
- No!
I mean, I don't think it'll help.
Forget them, Slayer. I got your back.
I thought you wanted me to stay away
from you. Isn't that what you sang?
Spike sing a wittle song?
- Was it a pop hit or more of a book number?
- Let it go, sweetie.
Fine. I hope you dance till you burn.
You and the little bit.
You're really not coming?
It's up to you, Buffy.
- What do you expect me to do?
- Your best.
I touch the fire
And it freezes me
I look into it and it's black
Why can't I feel?
My skin should crack and peel
I want the fire back
Now through the smoke, she calls to me
To make my way across the flame
To save the day
Or maybe melt away
I guess it's all the same
So I will walk through the fire
Cos where else can I turn?
I will walk through the fire
And let it...
The torch I bear is scorchin' me
And Buffy's laughin', I've no doubt
I hope she fries
I'm free if that bitch dies!
I'd better help her out
Cos she is drawn to the fire
- Some people never learn
- She will never learn
And she will walk through the fire
And let it...
Will this do a thing to change her?
Am I leaving Dawn in danger?
Is my slayer too far gone to care?
What if Buffy can't defeat it?
Beady-Eyes is right, we're needed!
Or we could just sit around and glare
We'll see it through
It's what we're always here to do
So we will walk through the fire
So one by one, they turn from me
- I guess my friends can't face the cold
- What can't we face
- Why I froze, not one among them knows
- If we're together?
And never can be told
- She came from the grave much graver
- So one by one
- First he'll kill her, then I'll save her
- They come to me
- Everything is turning out so dark
- The distant redness as their guide
- No, I'll save her, then I'll kill her
- That single flame
- I think this line's mostly filler
- Ain't what they had in mind
- What's it going to take to strike a spark?
- It's what they have inside
- These endless days are ending in a blaze
- She will come
- And we are caught in the fire
- To me!
The point of no return
So we will walk through the fire
And let it
Burn
Let it burn
Let it burn!
Showtime.
- I love a good entrance.
- How are you with death scenes?
You got a name?
I've got a hundred.
I ought to know, if you're
gonna be my brother-in-law.
Buffy, I swear I didn't do it.
Don't worry. You're not going anywhere.
- I am.
- What?
Deal's this. I can't kill you,
you take me to Hellsville in her place.
- What if I kill you?
- Trust me. Won't help.
- That's gloomy.
- That's life.
Come, now, is that really what you feel?
Isn't life a miraculous thing?
I think you already know.
Life's a show
And we all play our parts
And when the music starts
We open up our hearts
It's all right
if some things come out wrong
We'll sing a happy song
And you can sing along
Where there's life there's hope
Every day's a gift
Wishes can come true
Whistle while you work
So hard, all day
To be like other girls
To fit in in this glittering world
Don't give me songs
- She needs backup. Anya, Tara.
- Don't give me songs
Give me something to sing about
I need something to sing about
Life's a song
you don't get to rehearse
And every single verse
Can make it that much worse
Still my friends
don't know why I ignore
The million things or more
I should be dancing for
All the joy life sends
Family and friends
All the twists and bends
Knowing that it ends
Well that depends
On if they let you go
On if they know enough to know
That when you've bowed
You leave the crowd
There was no pain
No fear, no doubt
Till they pulled me out
Of Heaven
So that's my refrain
I live in Hell
Cos I've been expelled
From Heaven
I think I was in Heaven
So give me something to sing about
Please give me something...
Life's not a song
Life isn't bliss
Life is just this
It's living
You'll get along
The pain that you feel
You only can heal
By living
You have to go on living
So one of us is living
The hardest thing in this world
is to live in it.
Now that was a show-stopping number.
Not quite the fireworks
that I was looking for...
Get out of here.
Mm, I smell power.
I guess the little missus and I
should be on our way.
That's never gonna happen.
I don't make the rules. She summoned me.
I so did not. He keeps saying that.
You have my talisman on, sweet thing.
Oh, but, no, I...
This... at the Magic Box, on the floor.
I was cleaning, and I forgot...
- But I didn't summon anything.
- Well, now, that's a twist.
If it was in the shop,
then one of us probably...
- Xander?
- Well, I didn't know what was gonna happen.
I just thought there were
gonna be dances and songs.
I just wanted to make sure we'd work out.
Get a happy ending.
I think everything worked out just fine.
Does this mean that I have to...
be your queen?
It's tempting.
But I think we'll waive
that clause just this once.
Big smiles, everyone!
You beat the bad guy.
What a lot of fun
You guys have been real swell
And there's not a one
Who can say this
Ended well
All those secrets you've been concealing
Say you're happy now
Once more, with feeling
Now I gotta run
See you all
In Hell!
Where do we go
From here?
The battle's done and we kind of won
So we sound our victory cheer
Where do we go
From here?
Why is the path
Unclear?
When we know home
Is near?
Understand we'll go hand in hand
But we'll walk alone in fear
Tell me
Where do we go
From here?
When does "The End"
Appear?
- Bugger this.
- When do the trumpets cheer?
The curtains close on a kiss, God knows
We can tell the end is near...
You should go back inside.
Finish the big group sing.
Get your kum ba ya-yas out.
I don't want to.
The day you suss out what you do want,
there'll probably be a parade.
76 bloody trombones.
- Spike...
- Look, you don't have to say anything.
I touch the fire and it freezes me
- I died so many years ago
- I look into it and it's black
- This isn't real, but I just want to feel
- But you can make me feel
Where do we go from here?
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org