This is what happened this year:
Tomorrow night, we're bringing Buffy back.
We're talking about raising the dead.
I think I was in Heaven.
I was torn out of there by my friends.
I'm headed back to England.
And I plan to stay.
So you three have, what,
banded together to be pains in my ass?
We're your arch-nemesis... es.
Willow, you are using too much magic.
I don't think this is gonna work.
Are you saying you're gonna leave me?
Willow has a problem.
I need help.
We kissed, Buffy.
- I'm in love with you.
- You're in love with pain.
Are you afraid I'm gonna...
Things have changed.
The only thing that's different
is that I'm disgusted with myself.
It's over. I'm using you.
- We're getting married.
- Congratulations.
Xander's missing? What do you mean?
I wish we could just go back
to the way things were before.
And I wish you were never born.
You left me, Xander, at the altar.
So you go out and bang
the first body you can find?
- It's good enough for Buffy.
- Shut up and leave her out of...
We can't ignore this behaviour.
Something needs to be done
before it spins out of control.
Can you just be kissing me now?
- Please...
- I'm gonna make you feel it.
Stop!
Ask me again why I could never love you.
Get nice and comfy, Slayer. I'll be back.
You think you can just do that to me?
Tara? Tara?
Bring her back.
- It is done.
- No!
Something terrible has happened.
But you don't have to...
I need power.
What are you doing? She's gonna die.
No, she isn't.
We need to find Willow.
And you want to return to your former self?
Bitch is gonna see a change.
Let me go. Somebody!
Please! God!
Bored now.
Willow, what did you do?
One down.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
- I think I'm gonna be sick.
- Again?
Xander, we don't have time.
I know. It's just...
what happened back there.
The sounds of it.
- The smell.
- I know.
- Willow did that.
- That's why we have to keep moving.
You heard what she said: "One down. "
She was talking about two to go, right?
Jonathan and... the other guy.
Andrew. They're in jail
with no clue she's coming.
You don't think she's gonna
kill them too? She wouldn't.
She has an addictive personality. She just
tasted blood. She may be there already.
No, she couldn't. A witch at her level?
She can only go airborne.
It's a thing. More flashy, impresses
the locals, but it does take longer.
- Longer than what?
- Teleporting.
Right. Vengeance demon.
Well, at least she'll get there first.
I'm counting the ways that can go wrong.
- Anya can handle herself.
- Against Willow tonight? Don't be too sure.
Well, she should come down
at some point, shouldn't she?
I mean, back there she was out of her head.
Running on grief and magics.
It doesn't matter.
Willow just killed someone.
Killing people changes you.
Believe me, I know.
Warren was a cold-blooded killer
just warming up.
- If you ask me, the bastard had it coming.
- Maybe.
Andrew and Jonathan don't.
This is still Willow we're dealing with,
right?
I hope so.
Whatever she's going through,
we must stop her.
Maybe we can actually do that
if we can get to your...
- car.
- Willow.
I guess she wants to finish the job
without us tagging along.
- Meet me at the jail.
- Sure. How are you gonna...
OK, then. I'll just catch up.
She's only my best friend, you know.
No big deal, just...
glad I can help.
Dude, move, like, a foot to your left.
What for?
- I'm trying to hear something.
- Like what?
Signals.
For crying out loud. Signals?
Who from, your probe-happy alien friends?
Say, maybe we can trade
a pack of cigarettes in for tin foil.
- Make you a nice little antenna hat.
- Laugh it up, fuzzball.
I figured it out. Warren never abandoned us.
Well, not me, anyway.
This is like his test. If we can figure out
how he's communicating with us,
then we'll be... you know, worthy.
You're checking for implants?
Lex Luthor had a false-epidermis escape kit
in Superman vs the Amazing Spider-Man.
First of all, those were sonic disrupters.
Second of all, you are sadness personified.
Waiting for Warren?
Yeah, maybe he'll come bust us
outta here in Santa's magic sleigh.
- I'm telling him you said that.
- Why wait? Tell him right now.
- Warren, your girlfriend's pathetic. Over.
- Shut up, Jerkathan.
You see this? This is why we get jet packs
and all you get is left behind.
- So you admit it?
- Why not?
You were out of the trail a long time ago
in a galaxy far, far away.
And you wanna know why, little fella?
No respect for the chain of command.
See how far it's gotten you?
Checking every hole in your sad
little body for transmitters.
I'll find it if I have to check
every hole in my body and yours.
- Get off!
- Make me!
- There you two are.
- You do that?
Listen. We have to get you out of here
or you'll both be killed. Guard!
- What's goin' on?
- Guard!
Stop that. I don't trust her.
Do you trust her? This is major uncool.
Anya, you're gonna have to
break this down for us a little.
Warren shot Buffy. Warren shot Tara.
Buffy's alive. Tara's dead.
Willow found out and,
as the most powerful Wicca in the West,
decided to get the payback, with interest.
What about Warren?
She killed him. Ripped him apart
and bloodied up the forest doing it.
Now she's coming here
and the two of you are next.
- Oh, my God. Warren.
- Oh, my God. Me.
- Guard!
- We didn't do anything.
Guard!
All right, all right. What do you...
- Who the hell are you?
- Something's coming. Something bad.
You have to let these men out of here
or I guarantee there will be hell to pay.
OK. What exactly is coming?
One of the many things in this world
you are not prepared for.
- Is that a fact?
- Yes. We're running out of time.
So believe me when I tell you
these things are real,
they're dangerous, and they're coming.
What the hell was that?
- I don't know what you're doing, but...
- Take a nap.
So please stop looking at me like it's your
first trip to the circus and let them out.
- You three stay here.
- Like we have a choice.
Don't move. You'll be safe here.
Are you listening?
This is the one place they won't be safe.
Back off.
Hold it.
Stop it. Just stop. Why is she doing this?
Tell her we didn't do anything.
Yes, we did. We teamed up. We wanted
to see where our plans would take us.
- Well, take a look. This is it.
- Maybe for you.
Anya, teleport us out of here, please.
Take us with you.
I can't. It doesn't work that way.
Oh, God. Help!
Move!
Buffy.
Willow, just stop for
a second and listen to...
What's that sound? God, it kills.
- We have to make a run for it.
- She's like Dark Phoenix up there.
- You expect us to just outrun her?
- Pretty much.
Get in.
Go, go!
- Is she coming?
- I don't see anything.
Are you guys all right? Are you injured?
- I don't think so.
- Where are you taking us?
We'll keep you someplace safe
until we can stop Willow.
- Run and hide? That's your brilliant plan?
- I don't believe this.
Boys, knock it off, or I will
pull over and you can just...
walk to your painful deaths from here.
I don't get it. Willow's a witch.
Why doesn't she just...
wave her arms and make us dead?
She doesn't want you dead.
She wants to kill you.
But we didn't do anything.
I hate to admit it, Buff,
but Jonathan may have a point.
Why isn't she right here right now?
Maybe she's just getting
her mojo up and running.
Or maybe she hasn't figured out
exactly how much power she really has yet.
- Neither have we.
- Guess we keep running, then.
I still can't believe that was Willow.
I mean, I've known her
almost as long as you guys.
Willow was... you know.
She packed her own lunches and wore floods
and was always... just Willow.
- Jesus.
- What was that?
Just Willow.
- OK, any ideas?
- Drive faster.
This is faster.
She knows you're in this car too, right?
Right?
- She's draining.
- She's what-ing?
Just keep going.
Cool.
Not that I'm knockin' the nacho cheese ones.
I like the taste.
It's just the texture I can't deal with.
So gritty.
Kinda hurts my tongue.
So, I give 'em a seven. Maybe a seven-five.
And you think this is dumb, don't you?
No.
No. As taste tests go, this is definitely
one of the better ones I've been to.
I get it. No biggie.
You wanna play cards? I can be a real
boredom-buster if you just give me a chance.
- It's not you.
- Still, I feel responsible.
It's not fair. A girl your age
cooped up in a crypt.
Tell you what. Let me get my hat and coat.
I'll take you to a movie. We'll go nuts!
PG-13.
Clem, look at me. Do I look
weak to you, or incapable?
- Heck, no.
- So why am I stuck here?
No good reason I can see.
I'm still real sorry about what happened.
If there's anything I can do to help,
just name it.
Anything?
Oh. You're not gonna go and get yourself
in trouble now, are you? Or me?
Cos your sister's the Slayer. I'm a demon.
That's a real good incentive
to get along with her.
I need a demon to help me.
- Spike would have.
- Spike's gone.
You understand, then?
Yeah. It's not like you haven't been
clear about it, O great mysterious one.
This is a test. I don't get what I want
unless I pass it.
That about the size and shape?
Yes.
Since your pad is decked
out gladiator-style,
and no No. 2 pencils have been provided,
I guess we're not starting with the written.
Oh, here we go, then!
Just me and the walking action figure.
I'm venturing this is
a "kill or be killed" situation?
To the death.
Right.
Here we are now. Entertain us.
Son of a...
Rack's place was around here last time.
I don't feel anything.
Oh, not here. Let's go.
You don't feel anything
because his place moves.
Know why Rack moves all the time?
Because he's shady.
- A bad element comes down here.
- I get that.
But Willow's part of it now.
She is the element.
If she isn't around,
Rack may know where she is,
- which is why we need to talk to him.
- We? In a face-to-face way?
- Or me. I'll go in there without you.
- No, it's fine. I'm good. It's just...
Rack's not partial to the floppy-eared.
He has a thing.
But, hey. I'm in, absolutely.
Either way. Just get me there.
Say Rack does know,
he won't tell you for nothing.
- He's gonna want something.
- I have money.
That's not the something he'll want.
He likes little girls.
I am not a little girl.
I don't know if you've thought this through.
I'm supposed to keep you safe,
and this whole thing is...
I mean, even if you find Willow,
you really think you can stop her?
Thanks for getting here so fast. Big help.
Once again, Xander in need of big help.
Whatever. So, can you still sense Willow?
Knowing her location would be
a real big comfort right about now.
No, I can't. Which means she's gone
way beyond simple vengeance.
Did I mention the comfort?
Whatever we got, grab it fast.
This is the first place she'll look for us.
Then why are we here? I could summon
a demon that would kill her.
I could smack your eyes
out of their sockets.
No one is getting killed. Sit down.
We need to find some magics to stop Willow,
or at least slow her down.
She drained the place. Took everything.
- Not everything.
- What is it?
A book of protection spells.
Anti-magic. Our last resort.
You think you can work this stuff?
OK. Well, good news is, the text is intact.
Bad news is, I can't read a word of it.
It's, like, in ancient Sumerian
or something.
- Could I take a look at it?
- Shut up.
Right.
I just thought,
as long as you're protecting us...
I'm not protecting you, Jonathan.
None of us are.
We're doing this for Willow. The only reason
it happens to be your lucky day
is because, if Willow kills you,
she crosses a line, I lose a friend.
- And I hate losing.
- I get that.
It's just... You know she's
running out of power, right? I can tell.
I can practically feel it.
I've dabbled in magics.
I think Willow's in a league
of her own now, dabble boy.
But still, running that hot for that long,
at some time you gotta recharge,
no matter how juiced up you are.
Thank you. Now, remember
that thing we talked about?
About me shutting up?
Right.
Buffy.
Buffy, let's say this works and we stop
Willow working the hoodoo for a minute.
- What then?
- I talk to her.
Great. And say what?
Look, whatever she's gonna do,
she starts with those two.
They're the line she cannot cross.
And if she is running low on magics,
she's probably somewhere right now
trying to get it all back.
Hey, babe.
I've been waitin' for you.
Guess the rehab didn't take, huh?
That's the way it goes sometimes.
But I gotta say,
I could feel you comin' a mile away,
the power you got.
And you know something, sweetness?
I liked it.
When you first came to me,
you were just a little slip of a girl.
Look at you now. So... growed-up.
Just full of dark juice.
And you still taste like strawberries.
Only now...
you're ripe.
You came because
you want something, don't you?
I thought so.
So tell me, strawberry.
What on this earth do you want?
Just to take a little tour.
Yay, Clem. Makin' with the demon senses.
I knew you could find this place.
- It's not very clean.
- Don't wig out on me again.
It's just... I'm still not so sure
you should be here.
- I'm not so sure I should be here.
- It'll only take a minute. Come on.
- You wanna wait here?
- If that works for you.
Be right back.
Willow?
Hey, cutie.
Dawnie, what are you doing here?
Cos if you're lookin' for
me, now's not a great time.
- You look terrible.
- Do I?
- You're back on the magics.
- No, honey. I am the magics.
Did you kill that guy?
It's an improvement, believe me.
I have to go.
Why? So you can run and tell Buffy?
Willow, please just listen to me.
You don't have to talk.
Just think real loud. I can hear you.
- You're freaking me out.
- Don't be like that.
I'm just a little wired.
And I have some things to do.
I thought if anybody'd understand...
I miss Tara, too.
But this? What you're doing here?
This is not the way to go.
You're only going to make things worse.
But I promise, it's not too late...
- You miss her?
- Yes.
Did you cry?
Of course you did. I get that.
I understand the crying.
You cry because you're human.
But you weren't always.
Yes, I was.
No, please. You're telling me
you don't remember?
You used to be some mystic ball of energy.
Maybe that's why you're
crying all the time, Dawnie.
Cos you don't belong here.
Wanna go back? End the pain?
You'll be happier. I'll be happier.
We'll all be a lot happier
without listening to the constant whining.
Willow, stop.
"Mom! Buffy! Tara!"
It's time you go back
to being a little energy ball.
No more tears, Dawnie.
I think you need to get away from her.
- You're too close.
- How am I supposed to read?
I don't know. I'm staring right at
this stuff and I can't read it.
Well, how's the translation coming?
What have we got so far?
So far we've got "the".
Well, either "the" or "towards",
I'm not really sure.
I can't do this. I'm in retail.
Stupid ancient Sumerian.
I'm pretty sure it's Babylonian. The text
is similar, but the dialect is different.
Great. Babylonian. Thanks a bushel.
But, unless you can read Babylonian,
why don't you sit back down?
- Why are you helping them?
- Because they're saving our lives, moron.
And what then? Even if they kill that Wicca
bitch, you think they're gonna let us walk?
- They own us.
- So what do you want me to do?
Look around. You know magic.
We're in a magic shop.
We can take them.
The books are sucked dry, but so what?
There's still tons of supplies
all around us.
This is our best chance we're gonna get
to make it out of here.
- And do what?
- Start over.
We can be a duo. You and me.
You can even be the leader.
I swear I'll take orders.
I like taking orders.
Just tell me what to do.
You want an order?
Grow up.
Play nice or you'll break our concentration.
Which means no protection spell.
And Willow will make
you two boneless chickens skinless too.
And then what?
You think your little witch buddy's
gonna stop with us?
You saw her.
She's a truck-driving magic momma.
We've got seconds before Darth Rosenberg
grinds us into Jawa burgers,
and not one of you bunch
has the midichlorians to stop her.
You've never had
any tiny bit of sex, have you?
The annoying virgin has a point.
What if Willow filets their souls
and comes after us?
- She won't.
- You don't know that.
We're her friends, Anya. Her family.
She would never hurt us.
She tried to use you
for a hood ornament, Xander.
She doesn't care if you live or die.
I guess you two finally
have something in common.
I care if you live or die, Xander.
I'm just not sure which one I want.
Again with the comfort.
Look, we both know things
might get ugly at Wiccapalooza.
- And if it gets really bad...
- Let me guess. You'll propose?
I need to know if you're gonna turn on me.
Use this little shindig as an excuse
for some sweet revenge.
There is nothing in this world
that would give me greater satisfaction
than to wreak bloody vengeance
upon you, Xander Harris.
But I can't. Not officially. Not magically.
So smile. It's your lucky day.
You got away with it. I can't hurt you.
You varnishing the table with Spike,
how could that possibly have hurt?
- It may have chafed.
- That wasn't vengeance.
It was solace.
Look,
I really can't hurt you, so I'm just gonna
have to settle for hating you.
- If that's what you need to do.
- Don't play the martyr.
- I'm not.
- This wouldn't be happening but for you.
You think I don't know that?
You think I'm the hero of this piece?
I saw the gun.
Before Warren raised it,
I saw it and I couldn't move.
He shot two of my friends...
before I could even...
You want me to know how useless I am?
That it's my fault?
Thanks. I already got the memo.
I was talking about us.
You need to back down a minute
and think, Will.
I wasn't gonna hurt her, buzzkill.
She tried to turn me back.
You're attacking the people
who love you now?
Only the ones in my way.
That's not... You need help.
I'm doing fine on my own, thanks.
Dawn, get out of here. Go.
Don't. We're all friends.
Willow, I know what you wanna do,
but you have to listen to me.
The forces inside you
are incredibly powerful.
They're strong, but you're stronger.
You have to remember you're still Willow.
Let me tell you somethin' about Willow.
She's a loser, and she always has been.
People picked on Willow
in junior high school,
high school, up until college,
with her stupid, mousy ways.
And now... Willow's a junkie.
- I can help.
- The only thing Willow was ever good for...
The only thing I had going for me...
were the moments...
just moments when Tara would
look at me and I was wonderful.
And that will never happen again.
I know this hurts... bad.
But, Willow, if you let loose
with the magics, it'll never end.
- Promise?
- You don't want that.
- Why not?
- Because you'll lose everything.
Your friends. Yourself.
Willow, if you let this control you, then
the world goes away, and all of us with it.
There's so much to live for.
Will, there's too much...
Please! This is your pitch?
Buffy, you hate it here as much as I do.
I'm just more honest about it.
- That's not true.
- You're trying to sell me on the world?
The one where you lie to your friends
when not trying to kill them,
you screw a vampire just to feel,
and insane asylums
are the comfy alternative?
This world? Buffy, it's me.
I know you were happier
when you were in the ground.
The only time you were ever at peace
in your whole life was when you were dead.
Until Willow brought you back,
you know... with magic.
Sorry, the trip can be kinda rough
if you're, you know... not me.
Dawn.
Jonathan. Andrew.
You boys like magic, don't you?
Abracadabra.
OK. Didn't see that coming.
- What was that?
- We're alive.
You guys wanna take it slow?
I can do that too. Ask Warren.
Don't.
Let's get outta here.
No, no. Stay.
I mean, we're just getting started.
I've got big party plans.
- Will.
- No, don't.
Guys, come on. I'm just getting
the wood for the violence here.
And you know what they say:
If at first you don't succeed...
Had enough?
Bad move, bad move, bad move.
Looks like local boy loses.
So it would appear.
Good on me, then.
I get what I came for. I passed, right?
Indeed. You have passed
the first stage of the test.
Right. I get it.
Wait. First stage?
Bugger.
Damn, that is one effective counterspell.
- Won't keep you alive, though.
- Will, stop. You need to give this up now.
I get it. You boys put a spell
on yourselves, didn't you?
Protecting you from harm,
from magics. That's cute.
Will, back off before somebody gets hurt.
How about I back off right after?
So, which one of you boys worked the mojo?
Doesn't matter really.
I just... I'm curious.
Just because I can't do magics to you
doesn't mean I can't do them on myself.
Now I'm pretty sure I'm strong enough
to beat you to death.
I don't wanna hurt you.
Not a problem.
I said I didn't want to.
Didn't say I wouldn't.
- Let's go.
- What about Willow?
- Buffy can handle her.
- Are you sure?
No. That's why we're leaving. An.
I can't. I have to keep
the spell going on Willow.
- No, but...
- Go. Do something right.
No.
So, here we are.
Are we really gonna do this?
Come on. This is a huge deal for me.
Six years as a sideman,
now I get to be the Slayer.
A killer isn't a slayer. Being a slayer
means something you can't conceive of.
Oh, Buffy.
You really need to have
every square inch of your ass kicked.
Then show me what you got,
and I'll show you what a slayer really is.
- Where are you taking us?
- Someplace safe.
- Like where?
- Xander?
I don't know.
Get off, superbitch.
I can help you stop.
You were gonna show me what a slayer was.
I can't run any more.
Need to... breathe.
If you wanna keep breathing,
you gotta keep moving.
This is bogus.
We've gotta get out of this town.
Mexico. We should go to Mexico.
Hey, you're not goin' anywhere.
We've gotta hide you until
we get the all clear from Buffy.
What if the Slayer's dead already? We just
wait for Sabrina to come and disembowel us?
- You do what I say to do.
- I don't think so.
Well, hey. Isn't that interesting?
Anya's still here.
Looks like I've been beatin' on
the wrong gal.
OK, Andy. Let's just put the sword down.
No way. I'm not gonna die
because of something I didn't even do.
You're not gonna die.
Leave him alone.
Let him go, Andrew.
You heard me.
- You let me go first.
- Him.
- It's your move.
- No. Yours.
I'm not moving.
I'm not gonna budge till...
right now.
Xander's right. We're not leaving Sunnydale.
When this is over, you and I
are going back to jail to do our time.
Help me!
You can't block my spells
if you can't chant.
And you can't chant if you're sleeping.
Buffy, I gotta tell ya, I get it now.
The Slayer thing
really isn't about the violence.
It's about the power.
And there's no one in the world
who has the power to stop me now.
I'd like to test that theory.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org