Freeze! Put your hands up.
Back away from the girl, slowly.
- Look, I didn't do anything.
- Do it! Now.
- This one's dead.
- What about up there?
- Xander!
- Get her out of here!
Wait. Just see if he's OK! Please!
Please, you don't understand.
You'd do well
to keep your mouth shut, missy.
- But I didn't do anything!
- Why do I find that
- so very hard to believe?
- In there!
- You know this girl?
- Buffy Summers.
If there's trouble, she's behind it.
You stupid little troll. You have no idea.
Attitude problems. Serious.
I just wanna know
if my friends are OK.
All right, that's enough.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can...
Stop! Get down!
All units, we have a fugitive on foot
at the high school.
Homicide suspect. Female, blond,
approximately sixteen years old.
Suspect is very dangerous.
"Becoming"
Part 2
Dr. Michaels,
report to 9-1, please.
Xander! Oh!
I was so worried. I didn't know
if you were OK. The... The cops were...
Yeah... I heard 'em chase you out.
I was just comin' out of it.
- Souvenir.
- What about the others?
Are they OK?
OK. That was about
equal parts protecting me
and copping a feel, right?
What is it?
The doctor said it was head trauma.
She can wake up any time, but, um...
the longer it lasts, the...
less likely it is.
I never should have let her
try to do that curse.
Angel must have known.
- Where are her parents?
- With relatives in Phoenix.
I gave them a call. They're...
- They're getting on a plane back.
- Does Oz know?
Oh, man...!
I didn't even think. I'll...
I'll call him.
- Hey!
- Hey.
How is she?
- The doctor told me that...
- Yeah. We're, uh... still waiting.
- You OK?
- I ran.
I think I made it through
three counties before I realized
nobody was chasing me.
- Not too brave.
- It was the right thing to do.
- Did Giles keep up with you?
- I didn't see Giles.
- You mean he's not in the hospital?
- No.
Hi, Rupert. I wasn't sure
you were gonna wake up.
You had me worried.
What do you want?
I wanna torture you.
I used to love it
and it's been a long time.
I mean,
the last time I tortured somebody,
they didn't even have chain saws.
Oh, yeah. Acathla.
He's an even harder guy
to wake up than you are.
I mean, I performed the ritual,
said all the right phrases...
Blood on my hand. Got nothing.
Big doughnut hole for my troubles.
I figure you know the ritual.
You're pretty up on these things.
You could probably...
tell me what I'm doing wrong.
But honestly,
I sort of hope you don't.
'Cause I really wanna torture you.
No. I-i-it's impossible. There...
There's been some terrible mistake.
And you have no idea
where your daughter is?
She said was going to her friend,
Willow's house. Maybe she slept over.
- Is that Willow Rosenberg?
- Yes.
- Second victim.
- What?
Your daughter has
a history of violence,
doesn't she, Ms Summers?
Well...
You call us, OK?
If she decides to stop by.
Be best if she just comes in.
Giles! Giles?
I don't think he's here.
- Who are you?
- Whistler.
- What are you doing here?
- Waitin' for you.
- Why?
- 'Cause I...
I need a date to the prom.
I have had a really bad day, OK?
If you have information worth hearing,
then I am grateful for it.
If you're gonna crack jokes,
then I'm gonna pull out your ribcage
- and wear it as a hat.
- Hello to the imagery! Very nice.
It wasn't supposed
to go down like this.
Nobody saw you coming.
I figured this for Angel's big day.
But I thought
he was here to stop Acathla.
Not to bring him forth.
Then you two made with the smoochies,
and now he's a creep again.
And what are you gonna do?
- Or what are you prepared to do?
- Whatever I have to.
Maybe I should ask
what are you... prepared to give up?
You don't have anything useful
to tell me, do you?
What are you,
just some immortal demon
sent down to even the score
between good and evil?
Wow! Good guess.
Well, why don't you try
getting off your immortal ass
and fighting evil once in a while? 'Cause
I'm sick and tired of doing it myself.
In the end, you're always by yourself.
You're all you've got.
That's the point.
- Spare me.
- The sword isn't enough!
You gotta be ready.
You gotta know how to use it!
Hold it right there!
Put your hands on your head! Do it!
Hello, cutie.
Ugh! Will you hold on a second?!
Hey! White flag here. I quit.
Let me clear this up for you.
We're mortal enemies.
- We don't get time-outs.
- You wanna go a round, pet,
I'll have a gay old time of it.
You want to stop Angel...
we're gonna have to play this
a bit differently.
- What are you talking about?
- I'm talking about your ex, pet.
I'm talking about putting him
in the bloody ground.
This has gotta be the lamest trick
you, guys, have ever thought up!
He's got your watcher.
Right now,
he's probably torturing him.
- What do you want?
- I told you.
I want to stop Angel.
I want to save the world.
OK, you do remember
that you're a vampire, right?
We like to talk big. Vampires do.
"I'm going to destroy the world."
It's just tough-guy talk.
Struttin' around with your friends
over a... pint of blood.
The truth is, I like this world.
You've got...
dog racing, Manchester United...
and you've got people.
Billions of people walking around
like Happy Meals with legs.
It's all right here.
But then, someone
comes along with the vision.
With a real...
passion for destruction.
Angel could pull it off.
Goodbye Piccadilly,
farewell Leicester bloody Square.
You know what I'm saying?
OK, fine. You're not down with Angel.
Why would you ever come to me?
I want Dru back.
I want it like it was
before he came back.
- The way she acts around him...
- You're pathetic.
I lost a friend tonight!
- I wasn't in on that raiding party!
- And I may lose more!
The whole Earth
may be sucked into Hell,
and you want my help
'cause your girlfriend's a big ho?
Well, let me take this opportunity
to not care.
I can't fight them both alone
and neither can you!
- I hate you.
- And I'm all you've got.
All right. Talk.
- I just need to kill this guy.
- Ahem!
- Oh, right.
- Let's get inside.
- Do you want some coffee?
- I don't wanna leave.
She might, uh...
- I'll get it.
- Thanks.
Come on, Will.
Look, you don't have a choice here.
You gotta wake up.
I need you, Will.
I mean, how am I gonna
pass trig, you know?
And who am I gonna call every night...
and talk about
everything we did all day?
You're my best friend.
You've always...
I love you.
Willow?
Oz?
I'm here.
She's just starting to wake up.
- Hey, baby.
- Hi.
I'm gonna go get a doctor.
How're you feelin'?
My head... feels big.
Is it big?
No, it's head-sized.
Is everybody else OK?
Rupert, buddy...
I'm here to tell you, I'm impressed.
Hey. Uh...
How you holdin' up?
Never... better!
Glad to hear it.
Now...
Tell me when it hurts.
Buffy?
Where have you been? Are you OK?
The police were here!
I've been looking for you!
You know, Mom, let's,
let's go inside and I can explain.
Who is this man? Who are you?
- Are you OK?
- Mom! I'm, I'm OK.
Buffy, terrible things have happened.
What were you doing?!
- What? Your mom doesn't know?
- Know what?
That I'm, uh... in a band.
A-a rock band with Spike here.
- Right. She plays the, the triangle.
- Drums.
Drums, yeah. She's, uh,
hell on the old skins, you know.
- Mm. And, uh, what do you do?
- Well, I sing.
You know what? Why don't we go inside,
and, and we can talk about this?
I'm, I'm not sure
how I feel about this.
- One of Angel's boys.
- Yeah, probably watching me. Or you.
Yeah, he won't get a chance
to tattle on us now.
Buffy...
What is going on?
Mom...
I'm a vampire slayer.
I'm OK, Buffy. Really.
I mean, I don't feel good, but...
I'm awake and I know my name, and
who's President, and how many fingers.
So, they don't think my brain
got mushed at all.
Thank God.
I'm so sorry I can't be there.
I know.
I'm sorry I didn't get to cure Angel.
Don't be. It just wasn't meant to be.
I know I'm never gonna get him back
the way he was.
- It just makes it easier.
- I guess.
- Any luck finding Giles?
- Yep.
- I got a lucky break.
- What?
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
Xander, Angel and the others
are holed up outside town.
You remember that funky-looking mansion
you showed me that time?
On Crawford Street, sure.
That makes sense. What's the drill?
- I'm gonna hit it come daybreak.
- You'll need backup.
No. You stay there. I'm covered.
Do you, um...
Do you think Giles is still alive?
I think he is.
I just wish he was here
to tell me what to do.
Have we met?
Er... You hit me with an axe one time.
Remember, uh,
"Get the hell away from my daughter"?
Oh.
So, do you, uh... live here in town?
- Is Willow all right?
- Yeah, she's fine.
- All right, talk. What's the deal?
- Simple.
You let me and Dru skip town,
I help you kill Angel.
- Angel, your boyfriend?
- Forget about Drusilla.
- She doesn't walk.
- There's no deal without Dru.
- She killed Kendra.
- Dru bagged a slayer?!
She didn't tell me! Hey, good for her.
Though not from your perspective,
I suppose.
I can't believe
I invited you into my house.
- So, you didn't kill that girl?
- Of course not.
Did she explode
like that man out there?
She was a slayer, Mom.
Like what you are?
Look... this deal works only one way.
Full stop. Me and Dru, for Angel.
Honey, are you sure
you're a vampire slayer?
I'll take her out of the country.
You'll never hear from us again,
I bloody well hope.
Fine. Get back to the mansion,
make sure Giles is all right.
I, I mean, have you tried
not being a slayer?
Mom!
Be ready to back me up
when I make my move.
If Giles dies...
she dies.
It's because you didn't have
a strong father figure, isn't it?
It's just fate, Mom.
I'm the Slayer. Accept it.
- We should call the police.
- No! We're not calling the police.
Well, now that we know
that you're innocent,
- it's...
- What? You thought I was guilty?
- Jeez, feelin' the love in this room.
- No, I didn't think that. It's just...
- now we have proof.
- We have my word, Mom, not proof.
Look, I am sure
that they will understand.
Get them involved,
you'll get them killed.
Well, you're not gonna
hurt them, are you?
I'm a slayer, not a postal worker.
Cops can't fight demons.
I have to do it.
- Do what? Buffy, what is happening?
- Just have another drink.
Don't you talk to me that way!
You don't get to just dump something
like this on me and pretend it's nothing!
I'm sorry, mum,
but I don't have time for this.
No, I am tired of
"I don't have time" or...
"You wouldn't understand".
I am your mother
and you will make time to explain yourself.
- I told you. I'm a vampire slayer.
- Well, I just don't accept that!
Open your eyes, Mom. What do you think
has been going on for the past two years?
The fights, the weird occurrences.
How many times have you
washed blood out of my clothing,
and you still haven't figured it out?
- Well, it stops now!
- No, it doesn't stop! It never stops!
Do... do you think
I chose to be like this?
Do you have any idea how lonely it is?
How dangerous?
I would love to be upstairs watching TV,
or gossiping about boys, or...
God, even studying!
But I have to save the world. Again!
No, this is insane.
Buffy, you need help.
I'm not crazy!
What I need is for you to chill.
I have to go!
No. I am not letting you
out of this house.
- You can't stop me.
- Oh yes, I...
You walk out of this house,
don't even think about coming back!
So, Buffy's going
for the big showdown, huh?
Wish we could help.
You know, without dying.
- I don't see how.
- I wanna try again.
- Try what?
- The curse. We never got to finish it.
- Maybe we can restore Angel's soul.
- I don't like it.
You're talking about messing
with powerful magic, and you're weak.
- I'm OK.
- You don't look OK. Does she?
You should listen to him.
The hair, it's so flat. And the lips...
- Could we stay on topic here, honey?
- What?
- Look, it's not a good idea.
- There's no use arguing with me.
Do you see my resolve face?
You've seen it before -
you know what it means.
This can help Buffy.
If we turn Angel back soon enough,
we can stop him
from ever awakening Acathla.
OK, I pretty much missed out
on some stuff, didn't I? Because...
this is all making a kind of sense
that's... not.
Go with Cordy to the library
and get my things. She'll fill you in.
Sure.
I'll drive.
Xander, go to Buffy.
Tell her what we're doing.
- Maybe she can stall.
- But I...
Resolve face.
Be careful.
You know, I can stop the pain.
You've been very brave...
but it's over.
You've given enough.
Now let me make it stop.
Please.
Just tell me what I need to know.
In order to...
to be worthy...
you must perform the ritual...
in a tutu.
Pillock!
All right. Someone get the chain saw.
Now, now, don't let's lose our temper.
Keep out of it, Sit 'n' Spin.
Look, you cut him up,
you'll never get your answers.
Since when did you become
so level-headed?
Right about the time
you became so pig-headed.
You have your way with him,
you'll never get to destroy the world
and I don't fancy spending the next month
trying to get librarian out of the carpet.
- There are other ways.
- Enlighten me.
Drusilla? Sweetheart?
Do you want to play a game?
You do know this is a crime scene,
don't you?
But then, you're a criminal,
so that pretty much works out.
You know I didn't do it.
The police will figure it out.
In case you haven't noticed,
the police of Sunnydale
are deeply stupid.
It doesn't matter anyway.
Whatever they find...
you've proved too much
of a liability for this school.
These are the moments you savor.
You wish time would stop,
so that you could live them
over and over again.
You're expelled.
You never ever got a single date
in high school, did you?
Your point being?
It's Snyder.
Tell the mayor I have good news.
Is that better?
Poor thing.
Let's see what's inside.
Of course.
Look at me.
Be... in me.
Mmm... See with your heart.
Jenny!
- I thought I'd lost you.
- Shhh
I'll never leave you.
- We have to get out of here.
- No, no, no, no, no. Slowly.
It can't be you.
Did you tell Angel?
About the ritual?
No.
We have to get...
him away from Acathla.
- Why? Is he close to figuring it out?
- Later.
Tell me what to do.
It's all right.
We'll be together.
Finally.
We'll have everything
we never got to have.
Never got to feel.
Just tell me what to do.
We have to get Angel
away from Acathla.
Angel himself?
- He's the key?
- His... his blood.
- He... he mustn't...
- Shhh.
Blood. Of course! The blood
on my hands must be my own.
I am the key that will open up the door.
My blood. My life.
- OK, kill him.
- But what if he's lying?
Yeah. Good point.
All right, don't kill him.
You know?
I kinda like having you watch my back.
It's kinda like old times.
Uh, Drusilla?
- Honey?
- We are finished here, ducks.
Sorry.
I was in the moment.
Whistler.
What did you mean,
"The sword isn't enough?"
You know, raidin' an Englishman's fridge
is like dating a nun.
You're never gonna get the good stuff.
Tell me how to use it.
Angel's the key.
His blood will open the door to Hell.
Acathla opens his big mouth,
creates a vortex.
Then only Angel's blood will close it.
One blow'll
send 'em both back to Hell.
But I strongly suggest that
you get there before that happens.
'Cause the faster you kill Angel,
the easier it's gonna be on you.
Don't worry about me.
- It's all on the line here, kid.
- I can deal.
I got nothin' left to lose.
Wrong, kid.
You got one more thing.
- Xander?
- The cavalry's here.
The cavalry's a frightened guy
with a rock, but it's here.
- That's better.
- You're not here to fight.
You get Giles out and run like hell.
Understood?
I can't protect you.
I'm gonna be too busy killing.
- You know, that's a new look for you.
- It's a present for Angel.
Willow, uh...
She... told me to tell you...
Tell me what?
Kick his ass.
Acathla, mundatus sum.
(Acathla, I am cleansed)
Pro te necavi.
(Before you, I have killed)
Sanguinem meum pro te effundam...
(My blood flowing before you)
quo me dignum... esse demonstram.
(which shows I am worthy)
- Are we ready?
- Stinky herbs are go!
Did I mention I didn't take Latin?
Y-you don't have to understand it.
You just have to say it.
- I hope.
- Right.
Now, Acathla...
you will be free.
And so will we all.
- Hello, lover.
- I don't have time for you.
You don't have a lot of time left.
Coming on kinda strong,
don't you think?
You're playing some deep odds here.
Do you really think
- you can take us all on?
- No. I don't.
Painful, isn't it?
I don't wanna hurt you, baby.
Doesn't mean I won't.
Quod perditum est...
(What is lost...)
invenietur!
(let it be restored!)
Not dead, nor not of the living.
Spirits of the interregnum, I call.
Giles! Giles!
Xander?
- Can you walk?
- You're not real.
- Sure I'm real.
- It's a trick.
They get inside my head,
make me see things I want.
Then why would they make you see me?
You're right. Let's go.
Come on.
Ooh! Here he comes.
Gods, bind him, cast his heart...
from the...
evil...
realm.
- You almost made it, Buff.
- It's not over yet.
My boy, Acathla here, is about to wake up.
You're going to Hell.
Save me a seat.
In return...
I call on...
- Willow?
- Are you OK?
Te implor Doamne,
(I call on you, Gods,)
nu ignora accasta rugaminte!
(do not ignore this supplication!)
- Is this a good thing?
- Nici mort, nici al fiintei...
- Hey... speak English!
- Lasa orbita sa fie vasul care-i
va transporta, sufletul la el.
(...carry his soul to him.)
Sorry, baby.
I wish there was another way.
God, he's gonna kill her.
That's everything, huh?
No weapons...
no friends...
no hope.
Take all that away...
and what's left?
Me.
Asa sa fie! Asa sa fie! Acum!
(So shall it be! So shall it be! Now!)
Acum! (Now!)
Buffy?
What's going on?
Where are we?
I... I don't remember.
Angel?
You're hurt.
Oh, Buffy! God...
I... feel like
I haven't seen you in months.
Oh, God, everything's so muddled, I...
Oh, Buffy.
- What's happening?
- Shh.
Don't worry about it.
- I love you.
Close your eyes.
Buffy?
(#"Full of Grace" by Sarah McLachlan)
# The winter here's cold
# And bitter
# It's chilled us to the bone
# We haven't seen the sun for weeks
# Too long, too far from home
# I feel just like I'm sinking
- Buffy?
- # And I claw for solid ground
# I'm pulled down by the undertow
# I never thought I could feel so low
# Oh darkness, I feel like
# letting go
# If all of the strength
and all of the courage
# Come and lift me from this place
# I know I can love you
- Willow,
are you sure
you should be out of bed?
- Look who's talking.
- Yes.
- Any word?
- You guys haven't seen her, either?
- No.
- But we know the world didn't end,
'cause... check it out.
Well, we, uh...
we went back to the mansion.
It... it was empty.
Um... and Acathla was, was dormant.
I think the spell worked.
I felt something... go through me.
Plus, the orb did that...
cool glow thing.
Well, maybe it wasn't in time.
Maybe she had to kill him
before the cure could work.
Well, then, she'd wanna be alone,
I guess.
Or maybe Angel was saved
and they want to be alone together.
- Perhaps.
- Well,
she's gotta show up sooner or later.
- We still have school.
- Yeah.
She'll be here in a while.
# Everything we say and do
# Hurts us all the more
# It's just that we stayed
# Too long
# In the same old sickly skin
# I'm pulled down by the undertow
# I never thought I could feel so low
# And, oh, darkness,
# I feel like letting go
# If all of the strength
and all of the courage
# Come and lift me from this place
# I know I could love you
much better than this
# Full of grace
# I know I could love you
much better than this
# It's better this way
Subtitles corrected and extended by UAR
www.tvsubtitles.net