Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
[Glass Crunching]
- There's nobody here, sir.
- No.
No, she'd take
the fight outside.
My Faith doesn't like
to be cooped up.
We have to find them.
Put everyone on it.
Do it now.
- But, sir, the ascension...
- Find them!
Faith's a good girl.
She can take anything
they'll throw at her.
She's gonna be all right.
She'll be all right.
- Any word from Buffy?
- Not yet.
Here's your coffee.
Brewed from the finest
Colombian lighter fluid.
Thank you.
Horrible.
Aren't you supposed to be
drinking tea, anyway?
Tea is soothing.
I wish to be tense.
Okay, but you're destroying...
a perfectly good
cultural stereotype here.
Look through the, um...
Kippler volumes.
Uh, any reference
to the demon Olvikan...
um, powers,
weaknesses, hat size.
- There's got to be something.
- Still battin' zero?
But I mean, uh, in Cricket.
- Cordy, what's up?
- I demand an explanation.
- For what?
- Wesley.
Uh... inbreeding?
So very funny. Any minute,
I'm sure to laugh.
I just got off the phone
with him. He could hardly
speak, he was so upset.
He said that there was
something about a fight...
and he's leaving the country.
Shall I assay remorse?
Just tell me
what's going on.
Buffy's quit the Council.
She'll not be working
with Wesley from now on.
- But he's her watcher.
- Buffy no longer
needs a watcher.
Well, does he have
to leave the country?
I mean, you got fired,
and you still hang around
like a big loser.
Why can't he?
Cordelia! We're trying
to stop a massacre here.
Want to give us a hand?
Sure.
That's just such
a Buffy thing to do.
She's always
thinking of herself.
You're awake.
You... You've been
watching over me?
[Kissing]
Well, we've been taking turns.
I thought... I thought
I'd never see you again.
I can't leave you.
I... I... I was wrong.
I need you.
Oh.
You mean you need Buffy.
- Willow?
- Yes. Right. Willow.
- Where is she?
- She'll be back soon.
Any change?
He's delirious.
- He thought I was Buffy.
- You, too, huh?
I hope she gets here soon.
She'd better, if...
Yeah.
I feel so...
- I feel so guilty.
- Guilty?
Well, things are so terrible...
and everything's coming apart...
and I'm just...
In some ways, it's
the best night of my life.
- The best?
- The best.
I just checked on him
just now. We're watching.
Did you find Faith?
You didn't...
She's not here?
How is he?
He comes in and out.
I think the pain
is less... now.
Would you guys...
I'd like to be alone with him.
Of course.
We'll try to find
another cure.
Thanks.
Buffy...
it's you?
It's me.
I didn't want to go
without seeing you.
- Angel, I can cure you.
- It's okay.
- I'm ready.
- Angel, listen to me. Sit up.
You're gonna live.
You have to live.
- What do I...
- Drink.
Drink me.
- No.
- It's the only way.
Get away.
- It'll save you.
- It'll kill you.
Maybe not, not if you
don't take it all.
You can't ask me to do this.
I won't let you die.
I can't.
Angel, the blood of a slayer
is the only cure.
Faith.
I tried.
I killed her.
Then it's over.
It is never over!
I won't let you die. Drink.
Please.
Buffy?
Buffy.
I need some help!
She's lost a lot of blood!
- What happened?
- She needs blood!
Try to stay calm.
We're gonna take care of her.
Something bit her.
She needs a transfusion now.
- You found her?
Was she conscious?
- Yes. Yes.
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure.
Okay. I need a type
and a cross-match.
Get her on 2 lines of
ringer's lactate and watch
for hypovolemic shock.
- Tell me, what happened?
- Something bit her.
I don't know what.
I need a rabies shot treatment.
Any allergies?
No. Just...
Just help her.
You two been doing drugs?
You want her to live,
you're gonna have
to be straight with me.
She's clean.
All right. Wait outside.
Let us work.
A phone.
Right out there.
[Man] Bones are set...
and the damage to
the kidneys is repairable...
but the head trauma, it's...
Well, it's simply too severe.
You know, it's a wonder she's
alive at all with the blood loss.
I'm sorry, sir.
There's almost no chance...
that she's ever going
to regain consciousness.
It's your day.
[Nurse] We have another
young girl, severe blood loss.
Dr. Powell wants you to prep to
assist on an anticubital cutdown.
I'll be right there.
Oh, my God! Sir! No!
Somebody call security!
Don't do that!
I will.
I'll do that and worse.
Murderous little fiend!
Did you see what
she did to my Faith?
Hadn't made plans
to weep over that one.
Well, I'd get set for
some weeping if I were you.
I'd get set
for a world of pain.
Misery loves company...
and I'm looking to
share that with you
and your whore!
Heh heh heh heh!
Well, heh heh!
Looks like somebody's
been eating his spinach.
[Chuckles]
No, it's okay, folks.
It's all right.
The show's not over,
but there will be
a short intermission.
Don't want to miss
the second act.
All kinds of excitement.
I'll be there.
- How is she?
- She's fine.
- She's asleep.
- Well, you seem all right, too.
- Yeah.
- What happened?
When we left her,
she was fine. Did Faith...
Faith's out of the picture.
Buffy put her in a coma.
- And?
- Buffy cured me.
- Made me...
- You fed off her.
- Yes.
- How much?
- She's going to be fine.
- She won't be a vampire?
No. She didn't feed off me.
Well, it's just good to know
that when the chips are down
and things look grim...
you'll feed off the girl who
loves you to save your own ass.
You better go, Angel.
We'll watch over her.
- I don't want to...
- The sun will be up soon.
Gosh, I'm really gonna
miss him when he leaves town.
Let's find out
how Buffy's doing.
[Meows, Purring]
Who's gonna look after him?
It's a she.
And aren't these things...
supposed to take care
of themselves?
A higher power guiding us?
I'm pretty sure
that's not what I meant.
There's something
I'm supposed to be doing.
Oh, yeah. Miles to go.
Little Miss Muffet
counting down from 7-3-0.
Great. Riddles.
Sorry.
It's my head.
A lot of new stuff.
They're never gonna
fix this, are they?
What about you?
Scar tissue.
It fades. It all fades.
You want to know the deal?
Human weakness.
It never goes away. Even his.
Is this your mind or mine?
Beats me.
Getting towards that time.
How are you gonna
fit all this stuff?
Not gonna. It's yours.
Oh, I can't use all of this.
Just take what you need.
You ready?
- Buffy!
- Are you okay?
How do you feel?
- Is Angel here?
- He had to go.
It got kind of sunny.
Get him.
Get everyone.
- What exactly is up?
- Buffy, are you sure
you're all right?
I'm ready.
Ready for what?
War.
That's the basic plan.
So, am I crazy?
- Well, "crazy"is
such a strong word.
- Let's not rule it out, though.
- You don't think it can be done?
- Uh, I didn't say that.
I might, but not yet.
I personally don't think
it's possible to come up
with a crazier plan.
We attack the mayor
with hummus.
- I stand corrected.
- Just keeping things
in perspective.
Thank you.
My point, however is,
crazy or not...
it's pretty much
the only plan.
Besides, it's Buffy's,
and she's slay-gal...
you know, little
Miss Likes-To-Fight, so...
I think there was
a "yea" vote buried
in there somewhere.
I'm gonna need every
single one of you on board,
especially you, Xander.
You're sort of
the key figure here.
Key? Me?
Okay, pride, humility...
and here's
the mind-numbing fear...
what do I have to do?
Do you remember any of your
military training from when
you became soldier guy?
Ooh! Rocket launcher?
Rocket launcher
not gonna get it done.
I mean, it took a volcano to kill
one of these things last time.
Um, Buffy, uh,
all this is rather dependent...
on your being able
to control the mayor.
- Faith told me to play
on his human weakness.
- Faith told you?
Was that before or after
you put her in a coma?
- After.
- Oh.
- His weakness?
- Right.
Which is?
You know, I do
all this planning...
I'm in charge here, even though
I'm really not at my best...
Well, uh, let's-let's,
um, let's think.
Well, Angel, you hung
with him the most.
Was there something
that he's... afraid of?
Well, he's not crazy
about germs.
Of course. That's it!
We'll attack him with germs!
Great! We'll get him cornered,
and then you can sneeze on him.
No! No, we'll get
a container of Ebola virus...
and-and, uh... or it doesn't
even have to be real.
We can just get a box
that says "Ebola" on it...
and, um... chase him.
With the box.
- I'm starting to lean towards
the hummus offensive.
- He'll never see it coming.
- Faith.
- Faith?
At the hospital, he was
grieving, seriously crazed...
and not just in a homicidal,
"I want to be a demon" way.
She's his weak link.
Faith. I can work that.
You haven't an enormous
amount of time.
Hey, it's Mr. States-The-Obvious.
The Council
is not welcome here.
I have no time for orders.
If I need someone
to scream like a woman,
I'll give you a call.
I'm not here
for the Council.
Just tell me how I can help.
That is so classy.
Isn't he just so classy?
It's a start.
So there is something
I can do?
Besides scream like a woman.
There's plenty.
There's chores for everyone.
- Okay, this is how it's...
- It's gonna lay out.
The transformation
should begin at exactly 3:28.
I'll just be
finishing my speech...
You know, it's too bad you fellas
are gonna have to miss that...
'cause I think it speaks
to every one of us.
I mean, heck, I've been working
on it for a hundred years.
Better be good.
[Chuckles]
They'll try to run,
of course...
and that's when I need
you boys in flanking position.
- But, sir, the sun.
- Not a problem.
"Darkness will follow.
The day becomes night."
- An eclipse.
- Standard procedure
for an ascension.
- That puts me
back in the game.
- Yeah, it does.
You and Xander are gonna
have to work together now.
Can you guys handle that?
- I'm still key guy, right?
- Right.
Great. Then Angel, in his non-key
guy capacity, can work with me.
- What fun.
- Hey, key guy's still talking.
That's good. Start bickering.
That's gonna work great for us.
You guys are like
little old ladies.
You'll come up
through the sewers here.
The important thing is
containment. I'll need to feed.
It's crucial,
in the first few minutes,
to sustain the change.
What does that mean? No snacking.
I see blood on your lips...
it's a visit to the woodshed
for you boys.
Kill. Don't feed.
So how are we
on volcano detail?
- I think we can work it out.
- Fun with chemistry.
Xander said he should be
able to get the materials.
- Who's gonna stoke it up?
- You feel up to it?
I suppose it should be I.
Strangely fitting,
in a grotesque fashion.
Okay, guys, start reaching out.
Giles... weapons,
weapons, weapons.
- What about you?
- There's something
I need to get.
Remember... fast and brutal.
It's gonna be a whole
new world come nightfall.
Don't want to weaken now.
And, boys...
let's watch the swearing.
Harmony, listen, I need
to talk to you for a sec.
You mean, in front
of other people?
- Are they serious?
I'm gonna look stupid in this.
- Percy.
Do I look stupid in this?
Be honest.
You look great.
You got a sec?
- Cordelia.
- Yes?
- You know that
when this is over...
- Yes?
Well, should we prevail...
I'll be going back to England.
I know.
With Buffy no longer
working for the Council...
there's really no place
for me here.
I guess not.
No... reason to stay.
- No.
No cause to hope that...
- I might be needed.
- Needed.
- Or wanted.
- Wanted.
- Good luck in England.
- Yes, thank you.
I'll drop you
a line sometime.
- That'd be neat.
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay, put these with the others.
- You got it.
- Don't touch anything.
- What do we do then?
- Nothing.
- Just relax. Have a good time.
Uh... okay.
Okay, it's clear.
Let's move.
I guess that's it.
Won't be long now.
- You nervous?
- Only in a terrified way.
- We're gonna make it through this.
- Are you sure?
- I sound pretty sure, don't I?
- Yeah.
Well, then I must be sure.
Is that just a comforting way
of not answering the question?
How long till graduation?
Little while.
- You get what you needed?
- Yeah, I did.
This isn't gonna be enough.
Giles is on it.
How are you?
I heal fast... like you.
- So, are we sure
that everyone's good with...
- I'm not gonna say good-bye.
If we get through this...
I'm just gonna go.
You understand?
There's just too much to...
**[Processional Music]
Congratulations
to the class of 1999.
You all proved
more or less adequate.
This is a time
of celebration...
so sit still and be quiet.
Spit out that gum.
Please welcome our
distinguished guest speaker...
Richard Wilkins III.
I saw that gesture.
You see me after graduation.
Am I late?
Did we fight?
[Clears Throat]
Well.
What a day this is.
A special day.
Today is our centennial...
the 100th anniversary of
the founding of Sunnydale...
and I know what that
means to all you kids.
Not a darn thing.
Because today, something
much more important happens.
Today, you all graduate
from high school.
Today, all the pain,
all the work...
all the excitement
is finally over.
Now, what's 100 years of
history compared to that?
My God.
He's gonna do
the entire speech.
- Man, just ascend already.
- Evil.
Maybe you have a place
in Sunnydale's history,
whether you like it or not.
It's been a long road getting
here for you, for Sunnydale.
There's been achievement,
joy, good times...
and there's been grief.
There's been loss.
Some people who should
be here today... aren't.
But we are.
Journey's end.
And what is a journey?
Is it just distance traveled?
Time spent? No.
It's what happens on the way.
It's the things that shape you.
At the end of the journey,
you're not the same.
Today is about change.
Graduation doesn't just mean
your circumstances change.
It means you do.
You ascend...
to a higher level.
Nothing will ever be the same.
Nothing.
[Groans]
And so, as we look back on...
On the events that have
brought us to this day...
- Come on.
- We...
We must all...
[Yells, Groans]
It has begun... my destiny.
It's a little sooner
than I expected.
I had this whole section
on civic pride...
but I guess we'll just
skip to the big finish.
[Roaring]
[Crowd Screaming]
Now!
Flame units!
First wave!
Fire!
Go! Go! Go!
This is... This is
simply unacceptable.
- Xander!
- Bowmen!
Fire!
- Fall back!
- Fire!
This is not orderly.
This is not disciplined.
You're on my campus, buddy...
and when I say
I want quiet, I mean...
Fall back!
Get back!
- Go.
- Good luck.
Xander, take 'em down.
Everyone, hand-to-hand!
Go! Go! Go!
Move! Move!
Get the kids!
[Screams]
- [Yells]
- Right flank, close that up!
Close!
Jason and Doug, you guys
are the right flank.
Get some help here?
[Buffy] Hey!
You remember this?
I took it from Faith.
Stuck it in her gut.
Just slid in her
like she was butter.
You want to get it
back from me... Dick?
Well, gosh.
[Wesley Moaning And Gasping]
If... If I could just
get something for the pain.
It-It's rather a lot
of pain, actually.
An aspirin? Anyone? Ohh.
Perhaps I could just
be knocked unconscious.
Ohh. Ohh!
- Got off pretty cheap, considering.
- Seems like we did.
He made it through the fight.
Guess maybe he...
he took off after.
Good job.
- Are you all right?
- I'm a little tired.
I should imagine so.
It's quite a couple of days.
I haven't processed
everything yet.
My brain isn't really
functioning on the higher levels.
It's pretty much,
"fire bad, tree pretty."
Understandable.
Well, when it's working
again, congratulate it
on a good campaign.
- You did very well.
- Thank you. I will.
I, uh, I ferreted this
out of the wreckage.
It may not interest you,
but, uh...
I'd say you earned it.
There's a certain, um...
dramatic irony
attached to all this...
synchronicity that borders on
predestination, one might say.
Fire bad. Tree pretty.
Oh, yes. Sorry.
I'll go and attend to Wesley.
See if he's still,
um, whimpering.
Well, that was
the most fun you can have
without having any fun.
What about the part where
we kicked some demon ass?
- I didn't hate that.
- Hear, hear.
You guys want to take off?
- I think we've pretty much
done everything we can.
- I'm for it.
Are you okay?
Yeah. I'm okay.
- I could use
a little sleep, though.
- Yeah.
If someone could just wake me
when it's time to go college,
that'd be great.
Guys, take a moment
to deal with this.
We survived.
It was a hell of a battle.
Not the battle.
High school.
We're taking a moment.
And we're done.
Why do demons
even come here?
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org