Get nice and comfy, Slayer.
I'll be back.
Previously
on Buffy the Vampire Slayer:
And you want to return
to your former self?
Bitch is gonna see a change.
You think you can just do that to me?
- How did this happen?
- Warren, he had a gun.
We need to find Willow.
She's off the wagon big time.
Warren's a dead man if she finds him.
Willow.
- What about Warren?
- She killed him. The two of you are next.
- Get in.
- Go.
Willow, just stop for a second.
- Is she coming?
- I don't see anything.
I get it now. It's about the power.
- Let's go.
- What about Willow?
- Buffy can handle her.
- Are you sure?
No. That's why we're leaving.
And there's no one in the world
who has the power to stop me now.
I'd like to test that theory.
Giles?
Giles.
- Daddy's home. I'm in wicked trouble now.
- You have no idea.
You have to stop what you're doing.
Sorry. Can't do that.
I'm not finished yet.
Neither am I. Stay down.
How'd you do that?
That's borrowed power.
No way is it gonna be strong enough...
I'm here to help you.
Thanks, but I can kill
a couple of geeks all by myself.
But, hey, if you'd like to watch...
And that's what you watchers
are good at, right? Watching.
Butting in on things that don't concern you.
You concern me, Willow.
Stay on this path and you'll wind up dead.
Willow, listen to him.
I don't wanna fight you any more.
I don't wanna fight you either.
I wanna fight him.
- Stay down.
- No.
Remember that little spat we had
before you left?
When you were under the delusion
that you were still relevant here?
You called me a rank, arrogant amateur.
Well, buckle up, Rupert.
Cos I've turned pro.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Asmodea, bring forth...
No! Get off!
What did you do?
Contained her and her powers
within a binding field.
It puts her in a kind of stasis,
for the time...
You cut your hair.
I'm blonde.
I coloured my hair. Again.
Yes, I noticed.
I'm very sorry about Tara.
This... won't hold me... for ever.
I came as soon as I heard.
The Council?
The Council haven't a clue.
About much of anything, really.
No, there's an extremely
powerful coven in Devon.
They sensed the rise of a dangerous
magical force here in Sunnydale.
A dark force fuelled by grief.
Willow.
I'd so hoped it wasn't her.
And then a seer in the coven
told me about Tara.
That's when the coven
imbued me with their powers.
And sent you here to bring Willow down?
Buffy, what's happened here?
God, I don't even know where to start.
Well, Willow's clearly
been abusing the magics.
She has.
She was. And I barely even noticed.
Giles, everything's just been so...
Xander left Anya at the altar,
and Anya's a vengeance demon again.
Dawn's a total klepto.
Money's been so tight that
I've been slinging burgers...
at the Double Meat Palace, and...
and I've been sleeping with Spike.
Sorry.
Anya.
Willow?
I need you, Anya.
I need you to do something for me.
I know what you're trying to do.
But that mind-control mojo doesn't work on
vengeance demons, so why don't you just...
- Stop talking and listen.
- OK.
You need to free me.
No.
You don't wanna call out to them.
You wanna take away this binding spell.
- I don't know how.
- I do. Do you want me to tell you?
- Duct tape?
- On their mouth! So the demon, he said...
Because they were figments!
All of it. You, Sunnydale...
And I was just some nutcase in LA.
Of course. Why didn't we see it before?
Can you forgive me?
- For what?
- I should never have left.
No. You were right to leave.
We're just... stupid.
I know you're all stupid.
I should never have abandoned you.
No.
Giles, you were right about everything.
It is time I was an adult.
Sometimes the most adult thing you can do
is ask for help when you need it.
Nowyou tell me.
I guess... I wasn't ready before.
It took a long time for that feeling
to go away.
The feeling that I wasn't really here.
It was like...
when I climbed my way out of that grave,
I left something behind.
Part of me.
I just...
I don't understand why I'm back.
You have a calling.
But it was my time, Giles.
Someone would have taken my place.
So why?
Right.
What's gonna happen to Willow?
Well, the coven's working on a...
way to extract her powers without...
killing her.
And, should she survive...
You ought to know, Buffy, that there's
no guarantee she'll... be as she was.
Willow's killed a human being.
How will she be able to live with herself?
I wouldn't worry about that.
Willow doesn't live here any more.
Fool me once...
Willow.
Shame on you.
- Where are we going?
- I have no idea.
- What?
- I don't know, OK?
I can't even run away well.
That's something I'm usually good at.
Maybe we should go back and help.
Yeah, cos I've been such a big help already.
Standing around like a monkey
while Buffy gets shot.
Tara's dead, and Willow's... losing it.
Well, feeling sorry for yourself
isn't helping either, Xander, OK?
You know, if Spike were here,
he'd go back and fight.
Sure - if he wasn't too busy
trying to rape your sister.
What?
Forget it.
- I don't believe you.
- Fine.
He wouldn't do that.
Is this blind spot a genetic trait
with the Summers women?
The only useful thing Spike ever did
was finally leave town.
Well, that was a bloody doddle
and a piece of piss.
You got any more ruddy tests for me,
you ponce?
I'll take anything you can throw at me.
If it'll get me what I need
to take care of the Slayer.
Give her what's coming to her.
You just bring it on.
Bring on the whole...
Bloody hell.
That all you got, Jeeves?
Cos I could stand to go another ten rounds.
Whereas... you can barely stand.
Your powers may be undeniably greater,
but I can still hurt you if I have to.
Boy, you just don't get it, do you?
Nothing can hurt me now.
This...
is nothing.
It's all nothing.
I see.
If you lose someone you love,
then the other people in your life
who care about you
become meaningless.
I wonder what Tara would say about that.
You can ask her yourself.
You're always saving everyone.
It's kinda pesky.
You probably even think you're buying
escape time for Jonathan and the other one.
Well, I got a little secret for ya.
I can kill them from anywhere I want.
With this.
It'll find them. It'll bury them.
Along with anyone else
helping those dead men walking.
Don't.
Unless somebody, somehow,
can get there in time to save them.
Oh, well.
Fly, my pretty, fly.
- See what I did there?
- Go.
Good luck.
Thought she'd never leave.
Now I finally have you all to myself.
You're such a hypocrite.
Waltzing in here
with your borrowed magics...
So you could tell me what?
"Magic's bad. Behave. Be a good girl."
Well, I don't think you're in any position
to be telling me what to do.
Do you?
I used to think you had all the answers.
That I had so much to learn from you.
Willow.
You were jealous. Still are.
Just couldn't bear
that I was the one with power.
That's why you ran away.
That's why you...
That was rude.
Now I forgot what I was saying.
Perhaps you're not as strong as
you think you are.
You're expending way too much of your
mystical energies to maintain your powers.
At this rate you're going to
burn out and...
Blah, blah, blah.
Willow, you need to stop.
What I need is a little pick-me-up.
Head rush.
Who's your supplier?
This is...
It's incredible.
I'm so juiced.
Giles, it's like...
no mortal person has ever
had this much power - ever.
It's like I'm connected to everything.
I can feel...
It feels like...
everyone.
Oh, my God.
All the emotion and the pain.
No, it's too much.
It's just too much.
Willow.
It doesn't have to be like that.
You can stop it.
Yeah. I can.
I have to stop this.
I'll make it go away.
No.
You poor bastards.
Your suffering has to end.
No.
- Son of a bitch.
- Buttwipe.
- I wasn't talking to you.
- Oh. Reflex.
Man, they've really
tightened security up here.
One too many squatters from the Hellmouth.
Hide out in the cemetery -
what a fantastic idea.
I'm working on a "shut the hell up" pitch
you might like too.
Xander.
I've had just about as much as I can stand
babysitting a couple of social retards
- who don't appreciate...
- Xander.
- What?
- What is that?
Get out of there!
Move!
Dawn. Dawn.
Hold on.
Mexico, huh?
Giles.
Giles!
Anya.
I'm so sorry. Willow forced me to free her
with her brain. Are you OK?
I can see.
It's a... miracle.
Willow.
I can see her.
She took the magic I had and...
I know where she is.
I can feel what...
Oh, God.
Giles, you have to rest.
Silly girl. I'm dying.
No, you're not.
It was... it was the only way.
I thought we...
there'd be a chance, but now...
I know where Willow is.
She's going to finish it.
Finish what?
The world.
No!
Buffy!
- Are you OK?
- We have to get outta here.
- Xander!
- I think I saw him hit his head.
Xander!
This looks a little like Spike's place.
You know, under his crypt?
- What are you doing?
- If we can pull these out,
we can use the coffins for height
and maybe get outta here.
Maybe one of the tunnels Spike uses
is around here. We could get to his place.
That's the last place on earth
we need to be.
But it was good enough for you
to take me there after what he did to you?
- What he...?
- Tried to do. Whatever.
- Xander.
- So it's true.
Dawn, you may not have noticed,
we are in really big trouble here.
Why did you not tell me?
- Because you didn't need to know.
- Yes, I do.
I need to know. I'm not a kid any more.
- Dawn, I am trying to protect you.
- Well, you can't.
Look around, Buffy. We're trapped in here.
Willow's killing,
and people I love keep dying.
And you cannot protect me from that.
- Dawn...
- Hello?
Xander?
Buffy, are you OK?
- Where's Dawn?
- Here.
Are Jonathan and Andrew
up there with you?
No. They must've skedaddled
when I was out. Weasels.
Xander, you've gotta find a rope
or something and get us out of here.
Right.
OK, I'll... I'll take a look around.
And hurry up, before...
- Holy frijole.
- What are you doing here? Where's Giles?
- Giles?
- He's at the magic shop.
- Giles is back? You didn't tell me that.
- Did he stop Willow?
- No. And things just got a whole lot worse.
- How worse?
End-of-the-world worse.
Willow's going to destroy it.
She can do that?
She can and will
when she gets where she's going.
- Where is she going?
- Big old satanic temple. Kingman's Bluff?
There's no temple on Kingman's Bluff.
Proserpexa? Who's she?
Way up there in the hierarchy of she-demons.
Her followers intended to use
her effigy to destroy the world.
They all died when the temple got
swallowed up in the big earthquake of '32.
So now, 70 years later, Willow's
gonna make their dreams come true?
She's going to drain
the planet's life force,
and funnel its energy
through Proserpexa's effigy
and burn the earth to a cinder.
- Not if I can help it.
- You can't.
Something else Giles said -
no magic or supernatural force can stop her.
- What does that mean?
- I don't know.
He said "The Slayer can't stop her",
then a bunch of other stuff.
He really wasn't too clear.
Anya, what do you...
I should get back to him. He's alone.
Is he OK?
I don't think he has a lot of time left.
I'm sorry.
Xander! Where is that rope?
- Buffy...
- Xander!
Where is he?
You heard what Anya said.
You heard what Giles said.
I heard, and I don't care. I have to try.
From the pit of forgotten shadows...
I'm not sitting here while Willow
incinerates what I'm chosen to protect.
- I have to stop her.
- Always the Slayer.
Right to the last.
- Willow?
- And it is the last, you know?
For all your fighting,
thinking you're saving the world.
Buffy?
And, in the end,
I'm the only one that can save it.
By killing us?
It's the only way to stop the pain.
I can't take it any more.
But I know you, Buffy.
You're a warrior.
You won't go out without a fight.
I don't really have time for one.
But you should go out fighting.
- Willow, what are you...
- It was me who took you out of the earth.
Well, now...
the earth wants you back.
Buffy!
They just keep coming. I can't take 'em all.
Dawn... Will you help me?
I got your back.
Proserpexa,
let the cleansing fires from the depths
burn away the suffering souls
and bring sweet death.
Willow.
Giles. Giles!
Don't die. Not yet.
There are things I wanna tell you.
Thanks a lot for coming.
It was good of you to teleport all this way.
Though in retrospect it probably
would've been better if you hadn't come
and given Willow all that magic that
made her, like, ten times more powerful.
That would've been a plus.
Hey, black-eyed girl. Whatcha doin'?
- Get out of here.
- Oh, no.
You're not the only one with powers.
You may be a hopped-up über-witch,
but this carpenter can dry-wall you
into the next century.
I'm not joking, Xander.
Get out of my way - now.
There.
What?
It's not over.
Dawn! I'm coming!
What? You think I never watched you?
You can't stop this.
Yeah. I get that.
It's just, where else am I gonna go?
You've been my best friend my whole life.
World gonna end,
where else would I wanna be?
Is this the master plan? You're gonna
stop me by telling me you love me?
I was gonna walk you off a cliff and hand
you an anvil, but it seemed kinda cartoony.
Still making jokes.
I'm not joking.
I know you're in pain.
I can't imagine the pain you're in.
I know you're about to do something
apocalyptically evil and stupid.
And, hey, I still wanna hang.
- You're Willow.
- Don't call me that.
The first day at kindergarten, you cried
because you broke the yellow crayon
and you were too afraid to tell anyone.
You've come pretty far.
Ending the world - not a terrific notion.
But the thing is... yeah, I love you.
I love crayon-breaky Willow
and I love scary, veiny Willow.
So if I'm goin' out, it's here.
If you wanna kill the world,
well, then start with me.
I've earned that.
- You think I won't?
- It doesn't matter.
- I'll still love you.
- Shut up.
I love you.
I... love you.
Shut up.
I love you, Willow.
Stop.
- I love you.
- Stop.
I love you.
What happened?
Giles.
- You're not dead!
- No.
However, I am still in some pain.
Well, why aren't you dead?
Why aren't I dead?
The threat's gone. Willow's been stopped.
- You mean she's...
- No, she's alive.
It... The magic she took from me,
it did what I hoped it would do.
You dosed her.
You knew she'd take your powers all along.
The gift that was given me by the coven
is the true essence of magic.
Willow's magic came from
a place of rage and power.
And vengeance. Don't forget vengeance.
How could I?
In any case, the magic she took from me
tapped into the spark of humanity
she had left.
Helped her to feel again.
Gave Xander the opportunity to reach her.
Xander?
Yes.
It was he who got to her in time.
He saved us all.
I think it's over, Buffy.
The world's still here.
Sorry to disappoint you.
Wait. Is... is that happy crying?
Yes, dummy.
You think I wanted the world to end?
I don't know.
Didn't you?
Dawn.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
It's OK, Buffy. It's OK.
No. It hasn't been.
It hasn't been OK.
But it's gonna be now. I see it.
See what?
You.
Things have really sucked lately.
That's all gonna change.
And I wanna be there when it does.
I wanna see my friends happy again.
I wanna see you grow up.
The woman you're gonna become.
Because she's gonna be beautiful.
And she's gonna be powerful.
I got it so wrong.
I don't wanna protect you from the world.
I wanna show it to you.
There's so much that I wanna show you.
You have endured the required trials.
Bloody right I have.
So you give me what I want.
Make me what I was
so Buffy can get what she deserves.
Very well.
We will return your soul.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org