Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
- Robson! Dear God, l thought you...
- Gather them.
l understand.
l saw Mom.
lt's the Big Bad, Dawn.
The one we knew was coming.
l did what you told me.
lt's not my fault it didn't work.
- l would do this stuff if l could.
- l don't think l can kill anybody else.
lt's my fault the ritual didn't work.
l don't have enough blood.
Look who l found, buying
mass amounts of blood at the butcher shop.
- Just tell us what... you... know.
- Ow!
l believe in you, Spike.
They were after Spike all along.
l'm getting tired of subtle.
lt's about time we bring
some authority to our presence.
Now, Spike, you wanna see
what a real vampire looks like?
lt's a loop, like the mummy hand. l'm doomed
to replace these windows for eternity.
We should board these up
until things are less Hellmouthy.
Nothing, and nothing.
Cliffs Notes to nothing. Nothing abridged.
Yeah, my search
isn't turning anything up either.
Are you sure this thing called itself the First?
Pretty sure. lt claimed to be the original evil,
the one that came before anything else.
How many times
have l heard that as a demon?
"l'm so rotten, they don't have a word for it."
"l'm bad. Baddy bad bad bad.
Does it make you horny?"
- Or terrified. Whatever.
- (Buffy) lt wasn't a line.
When l came up against this thing, l felt it.
lt was... ancient and enormous.
lt nearly got Angel to kill himself.
lf we don't rescue Spike soon,
God knows what the First'll get him to do.
l wish Sleeping Ugly would come to.
He's been out all night.
Yes, he was just starting to squeal
when the spooky SWAT attacked.
Said the First was held up
at the Seal of... Danzar something?
Maybe he's just faking so he doesn't
have to answer any more questions.
- Hm. Or maybe he's in a fugue state.
- (Buffy) Dawn.
- What?
- He'll come to when he comes to.
Keep reading. lf we're gonna rescue Spike,
we need to figure out how to fight this thing.
Anya gets to hit him.
Hey! Here, the First! Bank of Delaware. Sorry.
Hand me the Watchers' Codex again.
(Joyce) Can l get you anything else, baby?
How about some tea?
Mom?
You're not real.
OK, is that slang, like you're not for real, or...
You're the First.
Oh, baby, you're so tired,
you're not making sense.
- Maybe you should get some sleep.
- No.
You can't win against this thing.
- Not if you don't rest.
- Stop.
Stop being like this.
lt's a lie.
l don't want to scare you,
but l want you to take care.
You need to wake up.
- What?
- (Xander) You're dreaming.
Buff, wake up.
- Did you see it?
- There's nothing to see.
You were just doing
a little dream-talking, that's all.
Oh.
You OK?
- What'd you see?
- Nothing.
lt was nothing.
(chanting in Latin)
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
(Spike's voice) Go on. Give him a kick, then.
You always liked that, didn't you?
Kick a dolly when he's down.
That was always your style.
Has buckets of energy, poor dear.
He's been laying in wait for his moment
since before the bug walked.
There, there, pet. Soon as the moon comes,
you'll have your carnage.
Little girls tear so easily, like pink paper.
Till then, we'll have our way with this one.
Got it coming, he does.
- (thud)
- Aargh!
That was something.
Maybe if you threw hot water on him.
Good thinking.
- Whoa, hey.
- Hi.
- Nothing.
- What?
Oh, l thought you were gonna ask us
what we were doing.
- No, l was going to ask...
- (coughs)
Oh! Look who's awake.
Silly Andrew, you drooled all over yourself.
l'm... l was about to be dead.
You saved me.
For the time being.
But if you don't tell us what we need to know,
then l'm gonna offer you to the First on a
platter and let him chop you into tiny pieces.
The first what?
The evil thing posing as Warren
to get you to kill Jonathan.
- Not very ominous-sounding.
- lt is if you understand the context.
No, an evil name should be
like Lex or Voldemort or...
Hey, l was intimidating here.
Oh, sorry. Go ahead.
Forget it. Where's the seal?
lt's around this corner, l think.
- You'd better be right this time.
- l told you, l'm not sure.
Maybe you should get sure.
l'm sick of all the run-around with you.
Whoa. Check out the goat-headed badness.
- What's it do?
- l don't know. Something not good.
lt didn't work cos...
there wasn't enough blood.
OK.
There's blood on this. Lots.
Looks like the First made
another sacrifice. Or a music video.
The seal could've been activated.
- Maybe that's what it needed Spike for.
- That wasn't there before.
- l had nothing to do with that.
- Thanks for clearing that up.
We thought you were up to no good
at this satanic manhole cover.
You killed your best friend!
He's in a place ofjoy and peace. He told me.
No, nobody told you.
You got tricked by a fake ghost.
Can we save the encounter session?
We need to cover this thing up.
Whatever it does,
we can't leave it exposed like this.
This place gives me the creeps.
lt's like in Wonder Woman, issue 297-299.
- "Catacombs". Yeah, with the skeletons.
- (both) That was cool.
Move it. This way.
So what next?
We found the seal, but no Spike.
l don't know. The First was camped
underground last time l found him...
Buffy?
- Hey!
- Hey.
l... thought that you were...
Sick? She was. Vomiting and oozing
from various places and...
Yeah, l remember, so please don't go on.
Oh, but now it's amazing.
- The doctor gave her some cream.
- Some pills.
And a cream. And l'm all better.
Oh, yeah. Um...
Apparently somebody left this
in the courtyard, and l was just returning it.
That's some full-service principalling.
l try.
Oh!
l was down here helping Dawn
with a school project.
- For science.
- We buried a... time capsule.
"Hello, people of the future.
Kids today like Red Bull and Jackass!"
- We'd better go.
- Buffy?
lf you are feeling better,
l could really use you back at work.
l've been waitlisting kids
who really wanna see you.
Oh, yeah. l'm sorry, you know,
l just... l've been ill and stuff.
No, it's fine, and l understand.
lt's just... things are starting to back up.
Well, l'll be there tomorrow.
No problem. 100% ooze-free.
Good.
OK.
How's it going?
Dawn's trying to find out
about the Seal of Danzalthar.
Will's about to do a locator spell,
see if we can find the First.
Why don't you go get some rest?
You haven't slept for two days.
- We'll call you if we find anything.
- Nah, l couldn't sleep. Too much going on.
lt'll be OK, Buff.
We've faced this kind of stuff before.
You didn't see the First. l did.
l felt it. lt was like...
Aargh!
Will!
(demonic voice) You only make me stronger!
- lt's still in me, l feel it!
- No, it's not. lt's gone. You're OK.
l don't wanna hurt anybody.
Please don't let it make me!
We won't, l promise. We won't use magic
to fight this until we know what we're doing.
l can't. l can't. l'm sorry.
- Let me come with you.
- l'm going alone.
You don't know how
to fight the First, or where it is.
lt's out there.
lt's hurting my friends. l'll find it.
- Buffy.
- Giles!
Nice place. Bit of a mess.
This is the Slayer?
Huh!
Sorry to barge in.
l'm afraid we have a slight... apocalypse.
- They're all slayers?
- (Giles) Potential slayers.
Waiting for one to be called. There were
many more like them all over the world, but...
now there's just a handful,
all on their way to Sunnydale.
The others were murdered.
(Giles) ln cold blood.
As well as their watchers.
We always feared this day would come,
when there'd be an attack against
not just one slayer, but the whole line.
lt's started.
The First. That's what it wants.
Yes, to erase all the slayers-in-training
and their watchers, along with their methods.
And then Faith, and then me.
And with all the potentials gone
and no way of making another, it's the end.
No more Slayer.
Ever.
But we haven't found any information
on the First. No documentation...
That's because it predates any written history.
And... it rarely shows its true face.
The only record l know
was in the Council library.
What about the Council?
What do they say about this?
Gone.
- (Willow) What?
- Obliterated.
They were in session,
and there was an explosion.
That means all the Council's records
are destroyed?
Annabelle?
That's what's left of
the mystic secrets of the watchers.
And whatever l could find on the First.
When l learned what was happening, l...
- l stole them.
- And you blew the Council up!
This is what happens when you're
stuffy and repressed. You overreact.
Not... l didn't.
Must've been an agent of the First,
after my little burglary session.
The knowledge contained in these files
had to be protected,
and there wasn't time
for bureaucracy or debate.
- The Council knows no other way.
- And it cost them their lives!
Go on.
Can we gag him?
But what do these records
say about the First?
(Giles) Very little. lt can change form.
lt only appears in the guise
of someone who has passed away.
- Our ghosts.
- Also it's not corporeal.
lt can't touch or fight on its own.
lt only works through those it manipulates.
And its followers, the Bringers.
- Those freaks in the black robes.
- With the hoodies and crazy alphabet eyes.
- l never saw 'em, l just heard...
- Sh! Molly.
Mr Giles doesn't need us prattling on.
The First is unlike
anything we've faced before.
There's evil and then there's...
the thing that created evil.
- The source.
- That's what this thing claims to be?
That's what it is.
lt has eternities to act, endless resources.
How to defeat it, l...
Honestly, l don't know.
But we have to find a way.
lf the slayer line is eliminated,
then the Hellmouth has no guardian.
The balance is destroyed.
l'm afraid it falls to you, Buffy.
Sorry. l mean, we'll do what we can.
But... you're the only one who has
the strength to protect these girls -
and the world - against what's coming.
But no pressure.
(Kennedy) That's it? That's the plan?
l don't see how one person,
even a slayer, could protect us.
l saw what those Bringers can do.
They tore apart my watcher.
- We'll use all our resources...
- lf this thing is the root of all evil,
isn't the Hellmouth
its number-one vacation spot?
Shouldn't we be hiding
on the other side of the globe?
- Kennedy!
- No, she's not wrong.
We need more muscle.
That's why we need to find Spike.
Yeah, he'll help. lf he's not crazy or...
off killing people or... dead.
Or, you know, all of the above.
That's why our kind make such good dollies.
Hard to kill.
Tried to enlighten little Buffy, didn't you?
Spilled, spilled, spilled our secrets like seed.
But you forgot.
l say what you tell and what you know.
l say when this is over.
And l'm not done with you yet.
Not nearly.
(clicks tongue)
This place you originally saw the First,
you say it was... a Christmas tree lot?
Under it. There was a hidden cavern.
Just happened to be under a tree lot.
The Bringers were doing some kind of ritual.
- Giles, this is bad, isn't it? A new kind of bad.
- Just in time for Christmas.
You know, l didn't even realise
it was December.
Maybe when we get home,
we should decorate the rubble.
Think you'll ever show up for a real visit?
The kind where the world isn't about to end?
lf we survive this, l promise.
Good. Cos l miss you.
l miss you too.
So, how long have you followed Buffy?
l don't "follow" her. She's my best friend.
Huh.
She seems like a good leader.
Her hair is shiny.
Does she make you stab things?
OK, so Annabelle can sleep down here,
- Molly can sleep in Dawn's room...
- Not if Dawn actually wants to sleep.
- Molly will talk her ear off.
- OK, then Molly down here,
you with Dawn, and Annabelle in my room.
Bad idea. Annabelle snores.
- You wanna do the sleeping arrangements?
- OK.
You... better not hog the covers.
- Does she wanna eat?
- What?
Oh, she's... she's new.
Annabelle and Molly are starved.
l burnt the mac and cheese.
l'll put hot sauce on it, tell 'em
it's an American thing. Say it's blackened.
lt's not blackened so much as ruined.
Or we can order pizza.
- As long as it's plain. l'm veggie.
- Cracked, you mean.
- Just because you'll eat any kind of trash.
- Oh, brill! Biscuits!
You don't mind, do you? l got a case
of the nerves after Mr Giles' lecture.
Knock yourself out.
l feel a cookie problem coming on myself.
(Giles) So the entrance to the cave...
was above ground here?
Yeah, l'm pretty sure
it was around here somewhere.
Well, we'll just keep...
- Argh!
- (crash)
(Buffy) Found it!
- Good lord, are you all right?
- Peachy.
Except my knees bend backwards now.
Giles, stay up there.
l'm gonna check it out.
Right.
(growls)
..the others just yet. lt'll give us a chance to...
- Sorry about the British invasion.
- We've been up for hours.
4pm, London time.
Are you all right? You look...
Oh. Yeah, l'm OK.
l just... got into a fight is all.
You wanna tell me with what?
Yes, Buffy, but don't you think
we should discuss this privately?
You mean, not in front
of the next generation?
No time to coddle them, Giles.
Welcome to the war room, guys.
What you fought was a vampire,
but it was more than that.
lt was a... Turok-Han.
As Neanderthals are to human beings,
the Turok-Han are to vampires.
Primordial, ferociously powerful killing
machines, as single-minded as animals.
They are the vampires that vampires fear.
An ancient and entirely different race.
Until this morning,
l thought they were a myth.
So, the First shows up, and now this.
You think it's a coincidence?
l think it's more likely that the Turok-Han
is here as an agent of the First.
Erm...
Did you slay it?
No, it's still out there. Somewhere.
What's it want?
All of us dead.
For now it looks like sunlight's
keeping this Ubervamp away.
(Giles) So, until sunset,
l suggest you get some rest.
A few hours sleep
will do a world of difference.
No sleep today. Can't.
- Oh, come on, you're exhausted.
- lt comes with the gig.
Somehow l don't think taking on
prehistoric evil comes with nap time.
Sorry, potential guys. l know you came
a long way, and you wanna get into it,
but the best thing you can do now
is just sit tight. Wait it out.
l'm gonna go to work, see what l can find out.
l'll be back before sunset.
How do you plan to research
something as ill-defined as the First?
l have the best plan ever.
l already rechecked the basement.
Wait, you know, hold on,
l'm gonna try something.
Maybe the First isn't ready
for modern technology.
"Displaying results 1 through 10 of... 900,517."
OK, l gotta narrow this down.
l'll call you back?
Yeah.
"Manifestations of evil"?
"..in... the... movies."
You're searching for evil movies?
l know it's not the all-time
most kosher use of my office hours,
but, you know, looking at some downtime.
What can l say?
l just love those evil, evil movies.
Like Exorcist, you know, Blair Witch...
As opposed to, say, Rob Schneider's oeuvre.
- Different kind of evil.
- Yeah.
Buffy, l'm not that big a fan of scary movies,
even the hokey ones.
Sometimes they go to a place
that l think kids could stand to avoid.
- Well, it's not for the kids.
- Yeah.
Yeah, l'm only saying
that once you see true evil,
it can have some serious afterburn,
and then you can't unsee what you saw.
Ever.
That's just one opinion.
l better get back to work.
What kind of movies do you like?
Oh, me? Mysteries.
l love finding out
what's underneath it all at the very end.
(Drusilla) Think of it as a game.
A fun, funny game.
Without all the rules,
or any of the bothersome winning part.
But still, there are sides.
You have to choose a side, Spike.
Then we can fly.
Be free and visit all our friends
as they come squirming up
from out the earth.
l know you like a good wriggle
and a giggle and a squiggle.
You're not Drusilla.
- No, l'm really not.
- She was crazier than you.
Mmm, daddy.
No kicking. lt's almost Christmas Day today
and you've gone spoiling it.
l've been so very good all year.
(growls)
But l could be bad if you like.
Bad daddy. Needs a caning.
Never learned his headmaster's lesson
while all the school bells ring
and ring and ring
and ring and ring.
Choose a side. Choose our side.
You know that it's delicious.
What do you say?
- Dru, love...
- Hm?
Get bent.
Stupid, stubborn... daddy.
And ring and ring...
(bell)
Ow.
Buffy, what happened?
- lt's OK, Mom.
- l tried to warn you, but...
Right. The last thing you need now
is one of helpful Mom's guilt trips.
- l'll get you some ice.
- No.
Mom, l can't.
- Buffy, you have to heal.
- l don't have time.
Are you worried about the sun going down?
There's some things you can't control.
The sun always goes down,
the sun always comes up.
- Everyone's counting on me.
- They do that.
l'm sorry, but these friends of yours put too
much pressure on you. They always have.
- Something evil is coming.
- Buffy, evil isn't coming, it's already here.
Evil is always here.
- Don't you know? lt's everywhere.
- And l have to stop it.
- How are you gonna do that?
- l don't know yet, but...
Buffy, no matter what your friends
expect of you, evil is a part of us. All of us.
lt's natural. And no one can stop that.
No one can stop nature, not even...
(bell)
Oh, l'm sorry. What were we talking about?
- Only my life. You're just like all the others.
- No. No, no. l'm different.
l'm hip, l relate to the young people.
No, don't go...
- Roger.
- Roger! See? l knew that!
Oh!
This day's almost over.
And the sun will go down in 17 minutes.
Hey, junior slayers, don't look so worried.
We don't know where Spike is
or how to fight the First,
or if and when the superstyle vampire
is gonna attack us.
However, house - boarded up.
Now all we gotta do is trap this Ubervamp
in the pantry, and it's game over.
Xander, newbies. Let's ease them in to
the whole "jokes in the face of death" thing.
Who's joking? That pantry thing could work.
Are you saying
M Night Shyamalan lied to us?
You'll be OK.
OK, or even better. lt's like our guarantee.
Buffy, l just... l want you to know
that l'm really sorry for letting you down.
You know, here before, with the magic
going all "argh" and me going all "eee"
and everything getting all "rrr".
l wish l could help out.
No one expects you to make everything right.
l can't do everything, but l should
at least be able to do something.
l have so much power,
but when l try to use it...
- Don't, OK?
- OK.
But... you need help, Buffy.
l know you, and l know you'll
never admit it, but you need help.
l'll be OK. OK, or better.
lt's like my guarantee.
Hey, are we getting weapons?
Trained fighters? Patton is coming?
l've heard worse ideas.
We'll be armed
when the Slayer feels we're ready.
l feel ready.
You're frightened.
You must learn to control your fear.
You know what would help with that?
Weapons.
- l don't know.
- We're sitting ducks without them.
We're with the Slayer. Safe as houses.
Do you see the house we're in?
lt'll come straight for us, won't it?
We should load them up, Giles.
Listen to me.
l've got a bad feeling about this.
Of course you've got a bad feeling.
You're tied to a chair.
No. Yeah, but above and beyond that,
l'm telling you my Spider-Sense is tingling.
This is gonna get hairy. l'm talking
weird with a beard. Better untie me.
And that'll help us how?
OK, l know what you're thinking.
"Andrew, bad guy."
You think l'm a super-villain like
Dr Doom or Apocalypse or The Riddler.
l admit l went over to the dark side,
butjust to pick up a few things,
and now l'm back. l've learned.
- l'm good again.
- And when were you good before?
OK, technically, never. Touché.
But l'm like Vader in the last five minutes
of Jedi, with redemptive powers, and...
mine is a redemptive struggle... of...
epic redemption which chronicles...
These ropes itch.
How are we doing on time?
Sunset should be any minute now.
Done everything we can.
And don't worry, everyone here
understands that you're calling the shots.
- l just hope l'm calling the right ones.
- You have all my faith.
And they're depending on you.
That's not exactly what l needed to hear.
Guys?
Annabelle split.
(Xander) Buffy!
Oh, God almighty.
(Drusilla) Do you know why you're alive?
Never figured you for...
existential thought, love.
l mean, you hated Paris.
You're alive for one reason,
and one reason only.
Because l wish it.
Do you know why l wish it?
- Because l'm not done with you.
- Give it up.
Whatever you are,
whatever you get away with, l'm out.
You can't pull this puppet's strings any more.
And what makes you think
you have a choice?
What makes you think you will ever
be any good at all in this world?
She does.
Because she believes in me.
(Giles) We could make plans
as we always do, but Buffy was our plan.
- There is no backup.
- (Willow) Giles, she looks bad.
(Giles) She does.
l'm afraid there may be internal bleeding.
- (Willow) What does that mean? Will she...
- (Giles) Die? l don't think so. l don't know.
(Willow) What do we do if she can't fight?
If she can't beat this thing?
- We're back at square one.
- Which square would that be, exactly?
l'm not sure.
The First predates
everything we've ever known.
Or can know. lt's everywhere, it's pure.
l don't know if we can fight it.
You're right.
We don't know how to fight it.
We don't know when it'll come.
We can't run, can't hide.
Can't pretend it's not the end, cos it is.
Something's always been there
to try and destroy the world.
We've beaten them back.
But we're not dealing with them any more.
We're dealing with the reason they exist.
Evil. The strongest.
The First.
Buffy, um...
- l know you're very tired...
- l'm beyond tired.
l'm beyond scared.
l'm standing on the mouth of hell,
and it is gonna swallow me whole.
And it'll choke on me.
We're not ready?
They're not ready.
They think we're gonna wait
for the end to come, like we always do.
l'm done waiting.
They want an apocalypse?
Well, we'll give 'em one.
Anyone else who wants to run, do it now.
Cos we just became an army.
We just declared war.
From now on, we won'tjust face
our worst fears, we will seek them out.
We will find them
and cut out their hearts one by one,
until the First shows itself
for what it really is.
And l'll kill it myself.
There is only one thing on this earth
more powerful than evil, and that's us.
Any questions?
Visiontext Subtitles: David Van-Cauter
Urgh! Argh!
ENGLlSH SDH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org