In every generation, there is a Chosen One.
She alone will stand against the vampires,
the demons and the forces of darkness.
She is the Slayer.
No.
Oh, great. A book.
Oh, I haven't gone through the new arrivals.
Put it in... that pile.
- Here, I'll get it.
- Oh. Thanks, Dave. Willow pile.
When I've examined it,
you can... er... skim it.
- "Scan" it, Rupert. That's "scan" it.
- Of course.
Oh, I know our ways are strange to you.
But soon...
you will join us in the 20th century,
with three whole years to spare!
Ms Calendar,
I'm sure your computer-science class is
fascinating. But I happen to believe
that one can survive in modern society
without being a slave to the...
- idiot box.
- That's TV. The idiot box is TV.
- This... is the good box.
- I still prefer a good book.
The printed page is obsolete.
Information isn't bound up any more.
It's an entity.
The only reality is virtual.
If you're not jacked in,
you're not alive.
Thank you, Fritz, for making us all
sound like crazy people.
Fritz comes on a little strong,
but he does have a point.
You know, for the last two years
more e-mail was sent than regular mail.
More digitized information went
across phone lines than conversations.
That is a fact that I regard
with genuine horror.
I'll bet it is.
Alright, guys, let's wrap it up for today.
I've just got a few more.
I'll hang for a bit.
Cool. Thanks.
Xander, you wanna stay and help me?
- Are you kidding?
- Yes. It was a joke I made up.
Willow, I love you but... bye!
- See you tomorrow!
- Buffy, wait up!
I'm just going to stay
and clean up a little.
I'll... I'll be back in the Middle Ages.
Did you ever leave?
"I Robot... You Jane"
Willow! Willow, hey, wait up!
Oh, Buffy. I didn't even see you.
Or hear me! What was up last night?
I tried your line like a million times.
- Oh, I was... I was talking.
- Talking to...?
Okay, that's it, you have a secret,
and that's not allowed.
- Why not?
- 'Cause... there's a rule.
Well... I sort of met someone.
I knew it! This is so important!
When did you meet?
Last week, after we did
the scanning project in the library.
Does he go here? What's his name?
Have you kissed him? What's he like?
No. Malcolm. No. And very nice.
You are a thing of evil
for not telling me this right away!
Well, I wasn't sure
there was anything to tell.
But last night, oh! We talked all night.
It was amazing. He's so smart, Buffy,
and... and he's romantic,
and we agree about everything.
- What's he look like?
- I don't know.
Yes, I will. I promise.
So... you've been seeing a guy
and you don't know what he looks like.
OK, this is a puzzle.
No, wait, I'm good at these.
Does it involve
a midget and a block of ice?
- I met him on line.
- On line for what?
Oh!
Morning, kids.
- Buffy, are you supposed to be somewhere?
- No, I have a free.
Cool. But this is lab time,
so let's make it a nice, short visit, OK?
- Sure.
- You have mail.
It's him.
- He's so sweet!
- He's a sweetie.
What should I write back?
Willow, I think it's really great
that you have this cool pen pal, but...
don't you think you're kind of
rushing all into this?
- You know what I mean?
- "I'm thinking of you, too."
No. That's incredibly stupid.
Will, down, girl. Let's focus here, OK?
What do you actually know about this guy?
Oh, see? I knew you'd react like this.
Like what? I just wanna make sure
you're careful, that's all.
Buffy...
He could be different than you think.
His name is Malcolm Black. He's 18.
He lives is Elmwood, which is about
80 miles from here. And he likes me.
Short? Tall? Skinny? Fat?
Why does everything have to be about looks?
Not everything, but... some stuff is.
I mean, what if you guys
get really, really intense,
and then you find out that he...
has... a hairy back?
Well... No. He doesn't talk like
somebody who would have a hairy back.
And anyways, that stuff doesn't matter
when you really care about each other.
Maybe I'm not his ideal either.
Hey, I'm just trying to make sure
that he's good enough for you.
I think it's great that you met someone.
Hey, Fritz.
I'm... looking at the logs.
You and Dave are clockin'
a scary amount of computer time.
- New project.
- Ooh! Will I be excited?
You'll die.
This isn't my report. "Nazi Germany
was a model of a well-ordered society"?!
I didn't write that! Who's been in my files?
- Guess who.
- Uh... Xander?
Yeah, but keep guessing anyway.
- Xander.
- Aw, I can't fool you.
You see right through my petty charade.
Are we going to the Bronze tonight?
Not me. I think
I'm gonna call it an early night.
Oh. Malcolm, right?
Yeah, I heard.
But you're gonna be missing out.
I'm planning to be witty.
I'm gonna make fun of
all the people who won't talk to me.
That's nice. Have a good time.
She certainly looks perky.
Yeah. Color in the cheeks,
bounce in the step.
I don't like it. It's not healthy.
So, are you going to the Bronze tonight?
Oh, probably not,
you probably have some vampire slaying
or some lame endeavor
like that, don't you?
Everyone deserts me.
- Check out the jealous man!
- What are you talking about?
- You're jealous.
- Of what?
Willow has a thang,
and Xander's left hanging.
Oh, that's meaningless drivel.
I'm not interested in Willow like that.
Yeah, but you got used to
being the Belle of the Ball.
No, it's just... this Malcolm guy?
What's his deal?
I mean, tell me
you're not slightly wigged.
OK, slightly. I mean, just
not knowing what he's really like.
Or who he really is. I mean,
sure, he says he's a high-school student,
but I can say I'm a high-school student.
- You are.
- OK, but I can also say that I'm
an elderly Dutch woman. Get me?
I mean, who's to say I'm not
if I'm in the elderly Dutch chat room?
I get your point.
Oh, this guy could be anybody.
He could be weird, or crazy, or old, or...
He could be a circus freak.
He's probably a circus freak!
Yeah. we read about it all the time.
Y'know, people meet on the 'Net,
they talk, they get together,
have dinner, a show...
Horrible ax murder.
Willow, axe-murdered by a circus freak?
OK, OK, what do we do?
What are we doing? Xander!
You get me started!
We are totally overreacting.
But it's fun, isn't it?
I'm jacked in.
Whoa. You're a little late, girl.
- I overslept.
- Till fifth period?
- Talkin' to Malcolm last night?
- Yeah.
- What?
- Nothing.
You're having an expression.
I'm not.
But if I was, it'd be saying:
this just isn't like you.
Not like me to have a boyfriend?
He's boyfriendly?
I don't understand why
you don't want me to have this.
I mean, boys don't chase me around
all the time.
- I thought you'd be happy for me.
- I just want you to be sure.
To meet him face to face.
In daylight, in a crowded place,
with some friends.
You know, before
you become all... obsessive.
Malcolm and I really care
about each other.
Big deal if I blow off
a couple of classes.
I thought you said you overslept.
Malcolm said you wouldn't understand.
Malcolm was right.
Dave?
Hey there, Dave. Anybody home?
Oh, what do you want?
I wanted to ask you something
if you have a minute.
- What is it?
- Well, you're a computer geek...
genius...
and I sort of have a technical problem.
If I wanted to find out
something about someone,
if-if someone e-mailed me,
could I trace the letter?
Well, you could pull out
somebody's profile
based on their user name.
But they write
the profile themselves, right?
And so they could say
anything they wanted.
- True.
- Wow. I had knowledge.
Well, is there a way to find out exactly
where a letter - an e-letter - came from?
I mean, the actual
location of the computer?
That's a challenge.
'Cause, you see, Willow's got
this boyfriend, Malcolm,
- and to tell you the truth, I think...
- Leave Willow alone.
What do you mean?
That's none of your business.
- Dave, are you Malcolm?
- Of course not.
Dave, what's going on?
Look, I'll talk to you later, OK?
I've got work to do.
So do I.
I'm telling you, something is going on.
It's not just Willow.
Dave, Fritz... they're all wicked jumpy.
Those boys aren't
sparklingly normal as it is.
- Giles, trust me.
- I do.
I-I-I really don't know
how to advise you.
Things involving the computer
fill me with a childlike terror.
Now, if it were a nice ogre or some such
I'd be more in my element.
I suppose you could "tail" Dave.
See if he's up to something.
Follow Dave? What, in dark glasses
and a trench coat? Please.
I can work this out myself.
She's too close. What do I do?
Party.
Whatever Dave is into, it's large.
- What was the name of this place?
- It said CRD.
But, I couldn't get close enough
to see what it was.
Calax Research and Development.
It's a computer research lab.
Third largest employer in Sunnydale
till it closed down last year.
What, I can't have information sometimes?
It's just somewhat unprecedented.
Well, my uncle used to work there...
in a floor-sweeping capacity.
- But it closed?
- Uh-huh.
Looked pretty functional
from where I stood
I don't have a clue
what they were doing.
And what do they need Dave for?
Something about computers, right?
I mean, he is off-the-chart smart.
We still don't know an enormous amount.
Whatever is going on there
may be on the up and up.
No, if CRD opened,
it would've been on the news.
Besides, I can just tell
something's wrong.
- My spider sense is tingling.
- Your... spider sense?
Pop-culture reference. Sorry.
Yes, well, ahem,
I think we're still at a standstill.
- Short of breaking into the place...
- Breaking in. This is the plan.
- I'm free tonight.
- Tonight it is.
A moment, please, of quiet reflection.
I did not suggest
that you illegally enter the...
data into the file so the book will be
listed by title as well as author.
I just came by to check
your new data base,
make sure your
cross reference table isn't glitching.
'Cause I'm guessing
you haven't gone anywhere near it.
No, I'm still sorting through
the chaos you left behind you.
Hmm.
You here again? You kids
really dig the library, don't you?
We're literary.
To read...
makes our speaking English good.
- We'll be going now.
- We-we...
will continue this conversation
at another time.
I think, we're done.
- "Makes our speaking English is good"?
- I panicked, OK?
I've never felt this way
about anyone before, Willow.
I know what you mean.
I feel like you know me
better than anyone.
- I do.
- Do you think we should... meet?
I think we should, soon.
I'm nervous.
I'm not. Isn't that strange?
That's what Buffy doesn't understand.
How comfortable you can make me feel.
Buffy just makes trouble.
That's why she got
kicked out of her old school.
How did you know that?
It's on her permanent record.
You must have mentioned it.
I guess.
Let's not worry about her any more.
I have to sign off.
I'll talk to you later.
Don't.
- You're a snob.
- I am no such thing.
Oh, you are a big snob.
You, you think that
knowledge should be kept
in these carefully guarded
repositories where only
- a handful of white guys can get at it.
- Nonsense!
I simply don't adhere
to a knee-jerk assumption...
that because something is new,
it's better.
This isn't a fad, Rupert.
We are creating a new society here.
A society in which human interaction
is all but obsolete?
In which people can be
completely manipulated by technology?
Well, well... Thank you, I'll pass.
Well, I think you'll be very happy here
with your musty old books.
These musty old books
have a great deal more to say than
any of your... fabulous web pages.
This one doesn't have
a whole lot more to say.
What is it? Like a diary?
How odd.
I... haven't... looked through
all the volumes yet and I didn't...
What is it?
Er, nothing.
A diary, yes.
I imagine that's what it is.
Well, it's been so nice talking to you.
- We were fighting.
- Must do it again sometime.
Bye now.
I checked the computer,
and there's nothing
in his file about
being allergic to penicillin!
- Buffy.
- Dave.
- How are you doin'?
- OK.
Look, I'm sorry about yesterday. I haven't
been getting much sleep lately, y'know?
Don't sweat it.
- Willow was looking for you.
- Good. I need to talk to her.
Do you know where she is?
She said she'd be in the girls' locker room.
Great.
Thanks.
Will?
Willow?
Will? Are you taking a shower?
I guess not.
This is how droughts get started.
Buffy! Get out!
I can't do it!
I'm not gonna do it.
But you promised.
Buffy isn't a threat to you!
It's not worth it.
The project is almost complete.
You won't have to do it again.
I can't.
I've shown you a new world, Dave.
Knowledge, power...
I can give you everything.
- All I want is your love.
- No.
This isn't right. None of it is.
I'm sorry. I've been a terrible person.
I'm a coward and
I can't go on living like this.
Forgive me, Mom and Dad.
At least now I'll have some peace.
Remember me.
Love, Dave.
- I'm gonna kill Dave!
- He tried to warn me.
Warn you that he set you up?
Is she gonna be OK?
She was only grounded
for a moment. Still...
If you'd been anyone but the Slayer...
Tell me the truth. How's my hair?
It's great. It's your best hair ever.
Oh. Yes.
I just... I don't understand
what would make Dave do a thing like that.
I think perhaps I do.
Does this look familiar to either of you?
Yeah, sure.
- It looks like a book.
- I knew that one.
In the Dark Ages, the souls of demons
were sometimes trapped in certain volumes.
They remained locked
within the book, harmless,
unless the pages were read aloud.
Unless I'm mistaken,
this is Moloch, the Corrupter.
A very deadly and seductive demon.
He draws people to him with promises
of love, power, knowledge.
- Preys on impressionable minds.
- Like Dave's.
Dave and who knows how many others.
- And Moloch is inside that book?
- Not any more.
- You released Moloch?
- Way to go!
I didn't read it!
That dreadful Calendar woman
found it and it was already blank.
OK, so a powerful demon with horns
is walking around Sunnydale,
and nobody's noticed?
I-if he's so big and strong,
why bother with Dave?
Why didn't he just attack Buffy himself?
I don't know.
And I don't know who could've read
that book. It wasn't even in English.
Where was it?
Uh, in a pile with others
that were, um, uh, scanned.
That released the demon?
No, he's not out here. He's in there.
The scanner read the book.
It brought Moloch out as
information to be absorbed.
He's gone binary on us.
OK, for those of us
in our studio audience who are me,
you guys are saying
that Moloch is in this computer?
And in every computer
connected to it by a modem.
- He's everywhere.
- What are we gonna do?
Willow scanned him into her file.
It may be...
a futile gesture,
but I suggest we delete it.
Solid.
Don't get too close.
OK.
So which file do you think it is?
Willow?
That's... probably it, right?
I'll just... delete the whole thing.
Stay away from Willow!
It is none of your business!
So that's what Malcolm looks like.
- So much for "Delete file".
- This is very bad.
Are we overreacting?
He's in a computer. What can he do?
You mean, besides convince
a perfectly nice kid to try and kill me?
I don't know. How about mess up
all the medical equipment in the world?
Randomize traffic signals.
Access launch codes for nuclear missiles?
Destroy the world's economy.
I think I pretty much capped it
with that nuclear missile thing.
Right. Yours was best.
OK, he's a threat.
I'm on board with that now.
But what can we do about it?
I think the first thing we do
is find Willow.
She's probably talking to him right now.
God, that creeps me out!
- What does he want with Willow?
- Let's never find out.
OK. I'm gonna check the computer lab...
and you guys... call her home.
Willow?
- No answer.
- Damn it.
Well, it wasn't busy either,
so she's not on-line.
- She's not home.
- What did you find?
- Willow isn't...?
- Dave.
- He's dead.
- How?
Well, it looks like suicide.
With a little help from my friends?
I'd guess Fritz.
Or the other zomboids from CRD.
OK. You and I are going to Willow's house.
Giles, you need to come up with a way
to get Moloch out of the Net.
I, I have records of the ceremonies, but,
but that's for a creature of the flesh.
This could be something
completely different.
Then get Ms Calendar.
Maybe she can help you.
Well, even if she could,
how am I gonna convince her
that there's a demon on the Internet?
OK, fine, then you can stay here
and come up with a better plan.
Come on.
Mom?
Dad?
You have mail.
Dad, did you forget your keys again?
No more waiting.
A spokesman for the archbishop
denied the allegations,
blaming computer error
for the apparent financial discrepancy.
Binding ritual...
In Washington D.C., the FBI today reported
that all of its serial killer profiles
have been mysteriously downloaded
from its central computer.
- I got your message. What's so urgent?
- Thank you for coming.
Er... I need your help.
But before that, I need you to believe
something that... you may not want to.
Er, there's...
Something's got into the... inside, erm...
There's a demon in the Internet.
I know.
Willow?
This isn't good.
OK, any thoughts?
"No more waiting. I need you to see me"?
See him how? Where?
- What about CRD?
- The research place?
- I'm guessing that's Moloch Central.
- I'm guessing that's our best lead.
Let's just hope Giles can back us up.
You already know? How exactly is that?
Come on.
There have been portents for days.
Power surges, on-line shutdowns...
You should see the bones I've been casting.
I knew this would happen sooner or later.
I mean, it's probably a, a mischief demon,
y'know, like Kelkor, or...
It's Moloch.
The Corrupter? Oh, boy.
- I should have remembered.
- You don't seem exactly surprised.
Who are you?
I teach computer science
at a local high school.
A profession that hardly
lends itself to the casting of bones.
Wrong and wrong, snobby.
You think the realm of the mystical
is limited to ancient texts and relics?
That bad old science
made the magic go away?
The divine exists in cyberspace,
same as out here.
Are you a witch?
I don't have that kind of power.
"Techno pagan" is the term.
There are more of us than you think.
Well, er... you can definitely help me.
What's in cyberspace at the moment
is less than divine.
I have the binding rituals at hand,
but I'm completely out of my idiom.
Well, I can help - I think.
I hope. I mean, this is my first real...
D-d'you know how he got in?
He was...
"scanned" is the term, I believe.
And you want him back in the book.
- Buffy?
- Yeah.
- Willow?
- Not at home.
Looks like she was taken somewhere.
- Where are you?
- CRD.
Whatever Moloch wants Willow for
is probably in there.
Ms. Calendar and I are, uh,
working to get Moloch offline.
Here's a tip: hurry.
Welcome, my love.
I can't tell you how good it is to see you
with my own two eyes.
- Willow.
- Malcolm.
This world is so new, so exciting.
I can see all of it.
Everything flows through me.
I know the secrets of your kings,
but nothing compares
to having form again.
To be able to walk. To touch.
To kill.
- Back way?
- Back way.
Here they come.
The first thing we have to do
is form the Circle of Kayless.
- Right?
- Form a circle?
But there's only two of us.
It's really more of a line.
You're not getting it, Rupert.
We have to form the circle inside.
I'm putting out a flash.
I just hope enough of my group responds.
Won't Moloch just shut you down?
Well, I'm betting he won't figure out
what we're doing until it's too late.
Hoping and betting,
that's what we've got.
Wanna throw in praying? Be my guest.
I don't understand.
What do you want from me?
I want to give you the world.
- Why?
- You created me.
I brought these humans together
to build me a body.
But you gave me life.
Took me out of the book that held me.
- I want to repay you.
- By lying to me?
By pretending to be a person?
Pretending you loved me?
I do.
Buffy!
- It's her.
- Yeah. Who's the other guy?
Don't you see? I can give you everything.
I can control the world.
Right now a man in Beijing is transferring
money to a Swiss bank account
for a contract on his mother's life.
Good for him.
- I can't bust it. It's heavy steel.
- Then let's find another way in.
What's goin' on?
The building security system
is computerized.
Whoops.
Almost there.
Couldn't you just stop Moloch
by entering some computer virus?
You've seen way too many movies.
OK, we're up.
- You read, I type. Ready?
- I am.
By the power of the divine,
by the essence of the word,
I command you.
- Let me leave.
- But I love you.
Don't say that.
That's a joke. You don't love anything.
You are mine.
I'm not yours. I'm never gonna be yours.
Never.
Pity.
By the power of the Circle of Kayless,
I command you.
Kayless with a K.
I'll miss you.
Demon, come!!!
I command you!
Ow! The guy's made of metal.
No! I won't go back!
Demon, come!
Whoa!
Hey! I got to hit someone!
He's out of the Net.
He's bound.
He's not in the book.
Where is he?
- Let's go this way.
- Wait!
I was omnipotent. I was everything!
Now I'm trapped in this shell.
Malcolm!
Remember me - your girlfriend?
I think it's time we break up!
But maybe we can still be friends!
This body is all I have left,
but it's enough to crush you.
Take your best shot.
Well, look who's here.
Welcome to my world. You scared?
I'm... remaining calm, thank you.
I just wanted to return this.
I found it among the new books
and naturally I thought of you.
Cool. Thanks.
Uh, well, I'll, I'll see you anon.
Can't get out of here
fast enough, can you?
Truthfully, I'm even less anxious
to be around computers than I used to be.
Well, it was your book that started
all the trouble, not a computer.
Honestly, what is it about them
that bothers you so much?
The smell.
Computers don't smell, Rupert.
I know.
Smell is the most powerful
trigger to the memory there is.
A certain flower or a whiff of smoke
can bring up experiences long forgotten.
Books smell
musty and rich.
The knowledge gained from a computer is...
It has no... no texture, no context.
It's there and then it's gone.
If it's to last, then-then
the getting of knowledge should be...
tangible.
It should be...
smelly.
Well, you really are
an old-fashioned boy, aren't you?
Well, I-I don't dangle a corkscrew
from my ear.
That's not where I dangle it.
Are we going to the Bronze tonight?
We three?
It'll be fun.
Yeah, Willow. Fun?
Remember fun? That thing where you smile?
Oh, I'm sorry, guys.
I'm just thinking about...
Malcolm?
Malcolm... Moloch...
Whatever he's called.
The one boy that's really liked me
and he's a demon robot.
What does that say about me?
It doesn't say anything about you.
I mean, I thought I was really falling...
Hey, did you forget? The one boy I've
had the hots for since I've moved here...
turned out to be a vampire.
Right. And the teacher I had a crush on?
Giant praying mantis?
That's true.
- That's life on the Hellmouth.
- Let's face it.
None of us are ever gonna have
a happy, normal relationship.
- We're doomed.
- Yeah.
Subtitles by: Doreen Trenerry
Corrections and timing: UAR
...
www.tvsubtitles.net