Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
l'm Faith.
(Giles) We have a rogue slayer.
l can't think of anything more dangerous.
Faith, no!
- You killed a man.
- l don't care.
She's unstable, Buffy.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
l'm not a demon, little girl.
l am something that you can't even conceive.
The First Evil.
lt's not a happy scenario,
but we're dealing with the Big Bad
that can be any dead person.
You know the rules.
l can't take corporeal form.
- They're all slayers?
- (Giles) Potential slayers.
There were many more like them all over
the world, but now there's just a handful.
That's what it wants.
(Giles) To erase all the slayers-in-training
and their watchers, along with their methods.
And then Faith, and then me.
lt's the end. No more slayer.
Spike has a soul now. That's what's
gonna stop him from hurting people.
- Buffy...
- He can be a good man, Giles. l feel it.
Willow, call for you from LA.
Somebody named Fred.
l'm gonna have to take off for a while.
We're on the verge of war.
You need to make difficult decisions
regardless of cost.
You're stalling me.
l've been searching for you
for a very, very long time.
Ever since you killed my mother.
You try anything again, he'll kill you.
More importantly, l'll let him.
l think you've taught me
everything l need to know.
Stop! Stop! Stop, please!
Get me out of here!
ls someone hurt? What is it?
Drive!
Well, that was...
Are you all right?
Thank you. Thank God you were there.
Well, let's not give him credit for everything.
l'm funning you.
l don't believe it was a coincidence.
l also don't believe young girls should be
in the woods at night. Should be in bed.
- Wish l was.
- l expect you do at that.
Look, l don't mean to pry,
but those boys... they looked like...
You didn't happen to fall in
with devil worshippers, did you?
No, l'm sorry.
You look like you've been
travellin' a while. l didn't think that...
ls there someplace you'd like me
to drop you? You heading someplace?
- Sunnydale.
- l'm going there myself.
l ain't never been,
but we can find a police station...
l just need to get to Robello Drive.
But thanks, Father...
Call me Caleb. Never was nobody's daddy.
l'm Shannon.
Well, Shannon, you feel like telling me
why those freaky joes were after you?
l'm not sure.
Do you ever think that maybe they were
chasin' you because you're a whore?
- What?
- l know what you're thinkin'.
Crazy preacher man spouting off at
the mouth about the Whore of Babylon.
That ain't me. l'm not here to lecture you.
What's the point?
My words would just curdle in your ears.
Wouldn't take in a thing.
Head filled with so much filth that...
ain't no room for words of truth.
You know what you are, Shannon?
- Dirty.
- l'm not!
Now, now, now. There's no blame here.
You were born dirty. Born without a soul.
Born with that gapin' maw that wants
to open up, suck out a man's marrow.
Makes me puke to think too hard on it.
Yeah, that there door's problematical.
l couldn't recommend steppin' out at this
speed. You're like as much to tumble some.
Of course, there's my boys back there.
They hate to miss a mark.
Your boys?
They ain't exactly my blue-eyed boys,
but they're hard workers.
And they don't truck with Satan.
That was just me having fun.
Satan is a little man.
l don't like back-seat drivers.
Please... don't hurt me.
ls this the part
where you offer to do anything?
Because l tried to make it clear to you,
you got nothin' l want to explore.
- Argh!
- Oh, yeah! That's it.
That's a cleansin' fire. Hallelujah!
lf l'm not mistaken,
there's a car a little ways behind us.
l do believe there's some folk in it
goin' the same place you are.
l want you to deliver a message for me,
but it's not for them.
lt's for the other one. The one and only,
the original, accept-no-substitutes Slayer.
- Would you tell her somethin' for me?
- Yes.
Thank you, Shannon.
(whispers)
Now, let's see what we can't do
about that door.
Are you OK?
Can you hear me? Can you talk?
This girl's bleeding badly.
We have to get her to the hospital.
Yep. Guess l'm back in Sunnydale.
l know it's hard.
l haven't been able to sleep
the last few nights.
Listen. lt's gonna be OK.
Buffy knows what she's doing.
She won't send you into battle
until she's sure you're ready for action.
That's just it, though.
How will l know l'm ready... for action?
- You have to trust us.
- l'm so scared, Xander. And l'm so young.
Believe it or not, l was younger
than you when l started all this.
There's just so much l haven't done,
so much l need to do.
lt's like... l never had
a real boyfriend, you know?
Yeah?
l never been with a man.
l could die tomorrow,
and l never been with a man.
Well...
l've never been with a man before either.
Colleen.
l've never been with her
in front of a man before.
in front of a man either.
Um...
Xander...
- We can't.
- We're so scared.
- The others might hear us.
- No, they won't.
They're OK.
(Rona) Xander! Xander!
- Wha...?
- Goddamn it!
What's going on? l was sleeping.
Dominique has a stomach flu,
and the toilet bowl is backed up.
l'll be right out. Got a... a leg cramp.
(Faith) You sure she's one of us?
She don't look like much now.
Not a potential slayer, l mean.
Don't know. Seems to fit, though. We'll know
more when she regains consciousness.
lf she regains consciousness.
Girl's been gutted like a catfish.
Yeah.
Something's killing girls all over the world,
trying to end the slayer line.
Thing like that, figure l might get a heads-up.
Faith...
Guess it doesn't matter
as long as you got the true Slayer intact.
You were in prison.
We figured you were safe there.
Yeah, that's prison. Safe as a kitten.
Sorry. l... don't know much
about the big house. Was it...
l mean, did something happen in there?
Someone came at me
with a nasty-looking knife.
Didn't really know why until now.
- Faith, we didn't...
- Forget it. lt's cool. l get by.
What are we gonna do about her?
l guess we should find Buffy,
tell her what's going on.
l tried calling home.
Dawn says she's out patrolling.
Let's look for her.
Cemetery's more fun anyway.
Somebody should wait here
in case she wakes up.
- Fine. Sit tight. l'll be back.
- Wait.
Maybe you meeting Buffy alone
isn't the best idea.
You told her the sitch, right?
She knows l'm coming.
Probably been up all night hangin' streamers.
Yeah, but it's not like
you're study buddies, exactly.
Maybe it'd be better if l...
eased her into the whole thing.
l can't stay here, Willow. Spent way
too much time in hospitals. We don't click.
Don't worry.
l'm sure we'll get along just fine.
(growling)
What you want to do to her, vamp?
Something like this?
Nice punch you got there. Let me guess.
Leather pants, nice right cross,
doe eyes, holier-than-thou glower.
You must be Faith.
- Oh, goody. l'm famous.
- Told you were coming.
- Bit of a misunderstanding here. l'm...
- Spike. We've met before.
We have? l don't think we...
Bloody hell. What are you doing?
l'm on your side.
Yeah? Maybe you haven't heard.
l've reformed.
So have l. l reformed way before you did.
Stop... hitting... me!
We're on the same side.
- Please! You think l'm stupid?
- Well, yeah.
You were attacking that girl.
Sorry, Faith. l didn't realise that was you.
lt's all right, B.
Luckily you still punch like you used to.
- You OK?
- Yeah. Terrific.
You're protecting vampires?
Are you the bad slayer now?
Am l the good slayer now?
He's with me. He has a soul.
- He's like Angel?
- No.
- Sort of.
- l'm nothing like Angel.
He fights on my side.
Which is more than l can say for some of us.
lf he's so good, what's he doing
chasing down defenceless...
- That's one of the bad guys.
- You should make 'em wear signs.
May l?
Thanks.
Angel's dull as a table lamp,
and we have different colouring.
OK, catching up. Anything else l gotta know?
Nice to have you back.
Whoa. Memory lane. Same old house.
All the furniture's been destroyed and
replaced since you left, so... new house.
Buffy?
We have a new house guest.
Hey. Got a spare bed for a wanted fugitive?
Hello, Faith.
- l guess "wanted" wasn't really accurate.
- (Dawn) Does she have to stay here?
There's hotels for
tried-to-kill-your-sister types.
Check it out. Brat's all woman-sized.
l need to get to the hospital.
A girl was attacked on her way into town.
- She might...
- We know. Willow's been calling.
She's still there.
She's gonna call if the girl wakes up.
Fine.
Well, Faith, we'd better...
see if we can find someplace
to squeeze you in for the night.
Not all that tension was about you.
Giles was part of a plan to kill me...
for Buffy's own good.
Well, that makes me feel better about me,
worse about Giles,
kinda shaky about you.
Drink of this,
for it is my blood.
You know, l always loved
the story of the Last Supper.
The body and blood of Christ
becomin' rich, red wine.
l recall, as a boy, though,
l couldn't help but think
"What would happen if you were at
the Last Supper, and you ordered the white?"
A nice oaky Chardonnay or White Zin.
Would he make that
out of his lymph or somehow?
Never did bring it up.
Suppose there was a reason
why l never spent too long in one parish.
Just lookin' for answers.
Just lookin' for the Lord
in the wrong damn places.
Then you showed me the light.
Do you think l'm God?
l certainly do not.
l am beyond concepts like that.
But you still wear the outfit.
Man can't turn his back
on what he come from.
Besides, black is slimmin'.
Everyone knows that.
How do you like what l'm wearing?
Just another dirty girl.
And since you only dress up in dead folk,
l'm guessin' one who's already
been paid her wage.
Look hard.
What do you see?
Strength.
And... the loneliness
that comes with real strength.
Nothing about my pert and bouncy hairdo?
- You're her.
- The Slayer.
At long last.
All this time.
All the work l've done for you.
Blowin' up the Council,
organisin' the Ray Charles brigade,
and... stickin' all them splits.
- You never showed me.
- Well, you've earned it.
And you'll be meeting her soon. Am l right?
Oh, yeah. She'll get the message.
- And what makes you so sure she'll come?
- Curiosity. Woman's first sin.
l offer her an apple.
What can she do but take it?
l'll see you soon.
(Andrew) Faith. Her name alone invokes awe.
Faith. A set of principles or beliefs upon
which you are willing to devote your life.
The dark slayer. A lethal combination
of beauty, power, and death.
For years and years -
or, to be more accurate, months -
Faith fought on the side of good,
terrorising the evil community.
But like so many tragic heroes, Faith
was seduced by the lure of the dark side.
She wrapped evil around her
like a large, evil Mexican serape.
She became a cold-blooded killer.
Nobody was immune to her trail
of destruction. Not friends, not family,
not even the most pacifist
and logical of races.
What the hell are you talking about?
l thought Faith killed a volcanologist.
(Andrew chuckles)
Silly, silly... Amanda.
Why would Faith
kill a person who studies Vulcans?
He studied volcanoes. He was a professor.
Ah... yes.
Well, regardless...
l thought you weren't supposed to be
doing this any more, making up stories.
l'm not. This is true.
Except for that... possible...
word misunderstanding.
There are things you need to know about.
Faith... has a history not to be taken lightly.
She's a killer. Never forget that.
You must stay on guard around Faith
at all times. Your lives may depend on it.
(bell rings)
- You look better.
- No, l don't.
- No, you don't.
- l'll be OK.
Unless, of course,
you start beating up on me now.
l won't.
Well, l thought about it.
l made some doodles.
As far as l'm concerned,
we're on even ground.
l meant what l said.
l don't have time for your vendetta.
But l need you in this fight.
l want you on my side.
Thanks. That means a lot.
- So we're good?
- Absolutely.
- You're fired.
- What?
Effective immediately.
You're firing me?
l just refrained from kicking your ass.
Buffy, there's nothing here for you.
People are leaving town,
half the kids don't even show up any more.
You've got much worse things to deal with.
- Look at the big picture.
- Right.
The big picture. The one with the big war
and all the dead little girls.
Not dead. Not dead,
not if you get them ready.
l don't wanna lead them into war.
lt can't be the right thing.
Most wars aren't, you know.
Some of these girls
haven't even been tested in battle.
Then, l guess, maybe you should test them.
Couldn't l come to work part-time?
l could make fliers for encounter groups.
And you're fired again.
Remember, Buffy,
the mission's what matters.
(girls giggling)
You craving a moment alone in the dank,
or can l bum one?
Well, l guess you can smoke all you want.
The big C not really an issue.
Teeth get yellow... after an eternity.
- Gotta watch that.
- Huh.
- Right. lt's not what it looks like.
- Hey, to each his own, man.
One guy l ran with, he liked me to dress
up like a schoolgirl and take this bullwhip...
l got dangerous... for a while.
- This before the soul or after?
- After, but l got over it.
ln case you're feeling all dust-happy
after your incarceration.
Not if you're all repenty.
Takes the fun out of it.
(clattering from upstairs)
No more Starbucks for the wannabes, man.
They've been spazzing for hours.
- Yeah. Does get a bit much up there.
- They're good girls. Just green is all.
- So why aren't you up there... imparting?
- That's Buffy's thing.
Anyway, l just spent a good stretch
locked away with a mess of females.
- Kinda had my fill.
- Hm.
But you waited until Angel
needed your help to bust out.
Three squares, nice weight room, movie
every third Sunday. Could've been worse.
- What movie?
- Last one was Glitter.
l guess it couldn't have been worse.
You had the power to walk away any time.
Nothing to stop you.
l stopped me.
l got dangerous for a while.
You over it?
More or less. l pull for the good guys now.
- What's the less?
- The usual stuff.
Such as?
l was thinking about looking up
the guy with the bullwhip.
Long incarceration.
You could do better.
Schoolgirl thing's old hat.
lt's all old hat, man.
Every guy's got some whack fantasy.
Scratch the surface
of any granola-type dude -
naughty nurses and horny cheerleaders.
- l figure, if you can't beat 'em...
- Join 'em.
- Just don't forget who's on top.
- That, l suspect, would be you.
You got that right.
l've met you before, you know.
Yeah, you made
a great impression on my chin.
Not in the graveyard. Before that.
- l was kinda wearing a different body.
- Pity.
You seemed OK with it.
The body swap... with Buffy.
- She fill you in on that whole deal?
- She told me it went down.
Failed to mention who was driving her skin.
l may have said a few things.
You could ride me at a gallop
till my knees buckled,
squeeze me till l pop like warm champagne.
lt's not the kind of thing a man forgets.
Should've known it wasn't Blondie.
She'd never throw down like that.
Oh, you have been away.
Don't tell me little Miss Tightly-Wound's
been getting her naughty on?
- Not of late.
- Wow.
Everybody's just full of surprises.
Hey, B.
Well, it's nice to see you two
getting along so well.
Yeah. You just know all the cool vampires.
Yeah.
- Aren't you usually at work about now?
- l decided to cut back on my hours.
- (Dawn) Buffy? ls that you?
- Down here.
Figured l'd better focus on
what's going on around here.
Buffy, Willow just called from the hospital.
The girl's awake.
He was a minister, or something.
At least, he dressed like one.
l thought he was trying to save me... at first.
He picked you up on the side of the road?
Bringers were chasing me.
He said they were his boys.
Right before he burned me.
He wanted to tell you something.
Before he... cut me...
he told me to give the Slayer a message.
- What is it?
- He said...
"l have something of yours."
We've got a new player in town.
Dresses like a preacher.
Calls himself Caleb.
Looks like he's working for the First.
He's taunting us, calling us out.
Says he's got something of mine.
Could be another girl.
Could be something else.
Don't know. Don't care.
l'm tired of talking. l'm tired of training.
He's got something of mine? Fine.
l'm getting it back,
and you guys are coming with me.
You're searching for somethin', girl.
What would that be now?
Oh... You, l was looking for you.
That right?
l heard you speakin' tonight. Preachin'.
l felt your words go straight to me.
Well, the truth is like a sword,
isn't it, girl? Cuts deep.
Yeah.
The words l use got a power to 'em.
Power, now. They're notjust words.
They're truth.
- They brought me here.
- They called you.
Know why? Because you're human.
You got your urges.
A woman's got hers. A man's got his.
Our whole race can be so damnably weak.
That's why we seek the strength, the power.
lt's not wrong to be drawn
to the power, is it, preacher?
Oh, no, child. lt's not wrong.
(girl gasps)
Just human.
Most people don't like visits
from their dead, you know.
Heathens. No appreciation for life's pleasures.
- Do it again.
- l take requests.
- One of those potentials you killed, perhaps?
- No. Save them for later.
l'm in more of an old
memory lane kinda mood.
Back before l met you, there was a choirgirl
in Knoxville l gave singing lessons to.
She even screamed on key. Show me her.
All these girls. They followed you willingly.
- You tricked them.
- l only told them the truth.
As for following, well...
that seems to be what they do best.
We need to arm the girls.
l wanna be ready when we find him.
- We don't know where we're going.
- We're gonna do some recon.
- You up for it?
- Point me where you want me.
You're certain about this? You don't know
what this man has of yours, if anything.
lt could be a girl,
a potential trying to get to us.
Could be a stapler.
- l'm going in anyway.
- With the girls?
Most of whom have yet to be in the field,
let alone a life-or-death situation.
lt's time we test them. l'll take the ones that
have been here longest. The rest can stay.
Could be that's what he wants.
The old bait-and-switch.
He lures us away
and then kills the girls we leave behind.
l know. That's why l need you
to stay here with them.
You're my most powerful weapon, Will.
You can keep them safe if anything happens.
An unknown man breezes into town,
says he has something of yours.
Buffy, this has "trap" written all over it.
He won't be expecting a full attack.
That's why we have to move.
We know nothing about this man.
We cannot go into battle unprepared.
We need more time.
Giles, we don't have time.
And you're not going into battle.
l need you to stay behind with the others.
Help the girls who still need a teacher.
No eyes, but look at him go.
He got sonar or somethin'?
Or something, l guess.
Pretty good when they attack.
They just roam free around town?
Normally they show up out of nowhere,
and either stab or get stabbed, then run off.
- Looks like this guy wants to be found.
- Lends weight to the "it's a trap" theory.
l am through waiting for people to attack us.
l'm with you. Drop me in
the hornet's nest, what the hell?
You got a rough sitch here, trying to turn
a bunch of little girls into an army.
They're potential slayers, just like we were.
- Right. Maybe they'll do as good as us.
- They're getting better.
l'll work with them.
Some of 'em seem real eager.
Fashion disasters, yeah,
but they're ready to fight.
- Why did you come back?
- Willow said you needed me.
Didn't give it a lot of thought. Do you...
- Am l getting you want me to be not here?
- No, that's not what l meant.
(sighs) l'm... glad that you're here. lt's good.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
You know me. All about the good deeds.
Willow said you helped out Angel.
Yeah. He says "Hi."
- Really?
- Sure.
- How is he?
- Better.
l had to do this magical mind-walk with him.
- You were in Angel's mind?
- Buffy...
- What is this place?
- Look, there's more of 'em.
- l think we just found our hornet's nest.
- Let's get the cavalry.
Now remember, we're looking for
killing blows only, people.
So, chest and throat if it's a vampire.
Stomach, chest and face if it's a bringer.
- What if it's something else?
- Could happen.
Something otherworldly.
Here's a handy rule:
don't go for the tentacles just because
they wave 'em about for attention.
Go for the centre. Brain, heart, eyes.
Everything's got eyes.
- (Dawn) Except the Bringers.
- Except the Bringers.
l don't want there to be tentacles.
l'm not good with squishy.
l don't care if it's Godzilla.
l wanna get in this thing.
Godzilla's mostly Tokyo-based,
so he's probably a no-show.
Besides, if Matthew Broderick
can kill Godzilla, how tough is he?
- Xander!
- Matthew Broderick did not kill Godzilla.
He killed a big, dumb lizard
that was not the real Godzilla.
You people are even crazier than her.
- Than who?
- Buffy, man.
l mean, taking us right into the bad guy's lair.
That's where, generally speaking,
you'd go to find the bad guy.
- l don't think you came here to fight plaque.
- No, l came here for protection.
- Well, you signed on to fight with...
- Look, l know...
This plan is trouble.
Buffy doesn't care if she puts us in danger.
Let me tell you something about Buffy.
You should all listen to this.
We kinda were.
l've been through more battles with Buffy
than you all can ever imagine.
She's stopped everything
that's ever come up against her.
She's laid down her life, literally,
to protect the people around her.
This girl has died two times,
and she's still standing.
You're scared? That's smart.
You got questions? You should.
But you doubt her motives, you think Buffy's
all about the kill? Then take the bus to battle.
l've seen her heart,
and this time not literally.
l'm telling you right now, she cares more
about your lives than you will ever know.
You gotta trust her.
She's earned it.
Damn! l never knew you were that cool.
- Well, you always were a little slow.
- l get that now.
All right. Saddle up.
OK. Set up a perimeter, guard the door.
l don't want anything getting in behind us.
My team goes in first, we check it out.
You guys are our safety net.
lf it's a trap, we give the signal,
you guys come in, guns a-blazing.
- What's the signal?
- l'm thinkin' lots and lots of yelling.
Got it.
Shall we?
- What is this place?
- Looks like an old vineyard.
- An evil vineyard, huh?
- Like Falcon Crest.
Stay alert, you guys.
The Bringers are here somewhere.
- Just need to find out where.
- Shouldn't be too hard.
Well, now! You girls are just burnin'
with righteousness, aren't you?
But you think you're blazing like suns,
when really you're burning like matchsticks
in the face of the darkness.
You havin' fun?
l hope my boys haven't worn you out.
l need you fit for when l purify you.
Save the sermon, padre.
l heard you have something of mine.
Well, l do now.
You liked my message, did you?
l ruined a perfectly good knife on that girl.
Got her soiled blood all over the place.
l may need to get a new truck.
So you're the Slayer.
The Slayer. The strongest, the fastest,
the most aflame with that
most precious invention of all mankind -
the notion of goodness.
The Slayer must indeed be powerful.
So, what else you got?
(Kennedy) Let's go!
Kennedy!
Miss, you have your own problems
you should be worried about.
(Caleb) Oh, good. There's more of you.
Buffy!
You're the other one, aren't you?
Your Cain to her Abel.
No offence meant to Cain, of course.
- Never was much for the Good Book.
- Oh, it has its moments.
Paul had some good stuff,
but overall l find it a tad complicated.
l like to keep things simple.
Good folk, bad folk.
Clean folk, dirty folk.
No!
Yes.
Xander, get them outta here.
We have to retreat. Do it.
What can l say? l work in mysterious ways.
Also some fairly straightforward ones.
We are leaving.
Are you OK?
Let's go. Come on.
Let's go! Come on!
You're the one who sees
everything, aren't you?
Let's see what we can't do about that.
Argh!
Xander!
Come on.
(Caleb) Now, it's a simple story.
Stop me if you've heard it.
l have found and truly believe
that there is nothing so bad
it cannot be made better with a story.
And this one's got a happy endin'.
There once was a woman,
and she was foul, like all women,
for Adam's rib was dirty,
just like Adam himseIf,
for what was he but human?
But this woman, she was filled
with darkness, despair...
And why? Because she did not know.
She could not see.
She didn't know the good news,
the glory that was comin'.
That'd be you.
For the kingdom, the power,
and the glory are yours, now and forever.
You show up, they'll get in line,
cos they followed her.
All they have to do is take
one more step, and l'll kill them all.
See? l told you it had a happy endin'.
Visiontext Subtitles: Claire Bates
Urgh! Argh!
ENGLlSH SDH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org