Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
Why didn't your chip go off?
We were at the lnitiative...
- There was a choice.
- Right. Either repair the chip, or remove it.
- You removed the chip?
- Yeah.
Spike has a soul now. That's what's
gonna stop him from hurting people.
- Buffy...
- He can be a good man, Giles. l feel it.
How do you know about slayers?
My mother was one.
She was killed when l was four.
- Something got her? A demon...?
- A vampire.
- How do you two know each other?
- He works with me.
You know, in the struggle against evil.
He's a vampire.
- Nice coat. Where'd you get it?
- New York.
(thunder)
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Well, all right!
Got the moves, don't you? l wanna ride you
hard before l put you away, love.
You sure about that?
You actually look a little wet and limp to me.
And l ain't your love.
l spent a long time trying to track you down.
Don't really want the dance
to end so soon, do you... Nikki?
The music's just starting, isn't it?
By the way...
love the coat.
Mama!
You did a good job, baby boy.
You stayed down just like mama told you.
- Can we go home now?
- Uh-uh. lt's not safe there any more.
How about l take you to Crowley's house?
You can play with those spooky doodads.
No, l wanna stay with you.
Yeah, l know you do, baby.
But remember, Robin honey,
what we talked about.
Always gotta work the mission.
Look at me.
You know l love you, but l got ajob to do.
The mission is what matters. Right?
That's my boy. Come on.
Robin?
Spike!
Little tip, mate.
Stake's your friend.
Don't be afraid to use it.
What?
Just waiting for my moment.
(bell rings)
Situation still normal.
Or as normal as this school ever sees.
So it appears.
No fires, no one's head's going kablooey,
and the swing choir and marching band are
back to their normal, seething resentment.
Yeah, it's been pretty quiet
since you shut down that seal.
- You just may have stopped this thing, Buffy.
- No, it can't be that easy.
You call that easy?
Any apocalypse l avert without dying,
those are the easy ones.
You know, you're something else,
Ms Summers.
l've been watching you
when we're out patrolling, and you're...
You remind me of my, um...
- Your mother?
- Yeah.
What l remember of her, anyway.
Gotta say, not a line every girl likes to hear,
but in this case compliment taken.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe everything is fine.
Everything's terrible. Total catastrophe.
- Giles, what's wrong?
- Have you seen the new library?
There's nothing but computers.
Not a book to be seen.
l don't know where to begin, Buffy.
Who do we speak to?
That would be me. Hi.
- l'm Robin Wood.
- Oh, sorry. Rupert Giles. Sorry.
Buffy tells me you're something
of a freelance demon-fighter.
Oh, yes.
l'm relieved.
We're running dangerously low on allies.
So we didn't stop it, then?
No, the seers at the coven are certain
the First is continuing to gather its forces.
l'm afraid war is inevitable.
- So we should go before the school board.
- What?
Well, l can have my backup library
sent from home in the meantime.
- lt's not much, but...
- Giles.
Knowledge comes from crafted bindings
and pages, Buffy, not ones and zeros.
- Did you bring back any potentials?
- No.
Actually, my trip was about
something else. lt's regarding Spike.
Spike? What about him?
l told you my concerns when you recklessly
chose to remove the chip from his head.
- Wait, sorry. Chip?
- lt's a long story.
The military put a chip in his head
so he couldn't hurt anyone.
The abridged version.
But he wouldn't hurt anyone any more
because he has a soul now.
- Unless the First triggers him.
- The chip?
No, the trigger's a posthypnotic thing.
The First put it in his head. lt... made him...
- He was killing again.
- So he has a trigger, a soul and a chip?
- Not any more.
- lt was killing him, Giles.
- The trigger?
- The chip. The trigger's not active.
Because the military gave him a soul?
Sorry.
We don't know that the trigger is inactive.
What l brought back may help us to disarm it,
and to ascertain exactly what it is
that causes Spike's behaviour.
lt was that song, Giles.
lt was that song that Spike was singing.
He has no memory of it.
ls there part of it that you remember?
lt didn't have a catchy hook, like "l'm coming
up, so you better get this party started."
Boring, old, and English.
Just like yo... ul... Brynner.
Yul Brynner.
A British Yul Brynner.
This thing you brought to keep Spike
from killing again. How's it work?
lt will require a bit of magic.
We couldn't have
put these chains back up a week ago.
No, we gotta work on Spike now of all times.
What?
Nothin'.
What are you doing here?
You came to see the show?
- l thought you might need support.
- Uh-huh.
Let's get this over with.
What are you gonna do?
Some hypno-beam? A disarming spell?
Not exactly. The First has brainwashed you.
There's something in your subconscious
that it's using to provoke a violent reaction.
So...
we have to put this in your brain.
Bugger that!
The prokaryote stone will move within your
mind to reveal the root of the trigger's power.
lt can unleash ideas, images, memories.
Hopefully, once you understand
what it is that's... setting you off,
you can break its hold on you.
Hopefully? So it might not work?
The stone's just a catalyst for the process.
The rest is up to Spike.
And how do you get
that hunk of rubble into my cranium?
- Willow?
- OK.
l just hope my pronunciation
is in the ballpark.
(reads spell)
Oh, you have got to be joking? What now?
lt has to access the cerebral cortex
via the optic nerve.
Oh, bollocks.
All the rubbish people keep sticking in my
head, it's a wonder there's room for my brain.
l don't think it takes up
that much space, do you?
Ow!
- Ow, ow!
- Spike!
- Spike, listen to me.
- Yeah.
Are you all right?
How do l know if this bug-ugly's doing its...
(William) "Yet her smell, it doth linger,
painting pictures in my mind,
Her eyes, bowls of honey,
Angels' harps, her laugh."
"O lark, grant a sign
if crook'd be Cupid's shaft."
"Hark, the lark, her name it hath spake."
"'Cecily' it discharges
From 'twixt its wee beak."
- Oh, William!
- lt's just scribbling.
Nonsense. lt's magnificent.
l wonder, though.
This Cecily of whom you write so often...
Would that be the Underwood's eldest girl?
No, no. l do not presume.
She's lovely.
You shouldn't be alone.
You need a woman in your life.
l have a woman in my life.
But you ne...
Well, do not mistake me.
l still have hopes that one day
there will be an addition to this household.
l will always look after you, Mother.
This l promise.
Should l send the coach for Doctor Gull?
l'll be all right.
Oh, it's passed.
- Just sit with me a while, will you?
- Of course.
# Early one morning
# Just as the sun was shining
# l heard a maid sing
# ln the valley below
# "Oh, don't deceive me"
# "Oh, never leave me"
# "How could you use a poor maiden so?"
(roars)
Dawn!
Get these sodding things off me. l'm fine.
Shouldn't you take a little time? Calm down?
l am calm.
This stone of yours is out, right?
Did its job, so l'm de-triggered, right?
Spike, what do you remember
about the song?
Oh, yeah, the song.
lt's called "Early One Morning". Old folk ditty.
- What's it mean to you?
- Mean?
Nothing. lt's just... my mum.
lt was her favourite. She used to
sing it to me... when l was a baby.
- And?
- No "and". That's it.
Shouldn't you check on Dawnie?
l clocked the niblet pretty fierce.
She'll be OK. She's tough.
Ow!
- Sorry.
- (phone rings)
- lt doesn't look like anything's broken.
- Did you use a magic x-ray?
That's just what people usually say.
So Spike's trigger's been active all this time.
How can Buffy take this for granted?
He lives in our house, we train with him.
Don't waste your time.
Spike's got a "Get Out of Jail Free" card
that doesn't apply to the rest of us.
He could slaughter a hundred frat boys and...
Forgiveness makes us human.
Blah-dee-blah-blah-blah.
Willow, call for you from LA.
Somebody named Fred.
The guy sounds kind of effeminate.
Spike, listen to me.
What is it about your mother?
l don't know. l got along fine with her.
She was a nice lady.
- There has to be more than that.
- Well, there bloody well isn't!
- What are you doing?
- l'm going to unchain him.
This is pointless, Giles.
He doesn't know anything.
- Your prophylactic stone didn't work.
- He's not cooperating. This takes time.
He's blocking what's in his consciousness.
And while he does, he's endangering us all.
- So the trigger's still working?
- Much as ever.
Ooh! Such a pretty house
you have, sweet Willy.
Smells of daffodils... and viscera.
Don't get too attached, now.
Won't be here for long, love.
Well then...
shall we give it a proper goodbye?
You're a saucy one, aren't you?
Dru... we'll bring this world to its knees.
lt's ripe and ready, my darling.
Waiting for us to devour its fruit.
We'll ravage this city together, my pet.
Lay waste to all of Europe.
The three of us will teach those snobs
and elitists with their falderal just what...
- Three?
- You, me and Mother.
We'll open up their veins and bathe in their
blood as they scream our names across...
- What?
- You... wanna bring your mum with us?
Well, yeah.
You'll like her.
To eat, you mean?
- William?
- Uh... Mother.
Where have you been?
l've been beside myself for days.
You needn't have worried, Mother.
You'll never have to worry
about anything again.
Something has happened.
- l've changed.
- l don't... Who's this woman?
- l'm the other that gave birth to your son.
- l beg your pardon?
lt's true, Mother.
Drusilla... she...
She has made me what l am.
l am no longer bound to this mortal coil.
l have become a creature of the night.
A vampire.
Are you drunk?
A little bit.
Think of it.
No more sickness.
No more dying.
You'll never age another day.
- Let me do this for you.
- What are you talking about?
- And why are you acting so strangely?
- lt's all right, Mother.
lt's only me.
We'll be together... forever.
William...
lt only hurts... for a moment.
(Willow) Buffy?
l just got a phone call. l'm gonna have to
take off for a while. Maybe a day or two?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing you need to worry about.
l'll give you the full scoop later.
Maybe l'll even bring back some good news?
Could use a little of that.
OK. l guess now is as good a time
as we're likely to see for a while.
- Just hurry back.
- Will do.
Think about what you're doing.
l have.
- Buffy...
- Don't.
Mr Giles.
You got a moment?
- What's on your mind?
- The same thing that's on yours.
We got ourselves a problem.
- Spike.
- Yeah. lf that trigger's still working,
then the First must be waiting
forjust the right time to use it against us.
lt does seem doubtful the First simply
forgot it had such a powerful weapon.
A while back, it slipped up.
lt told Andrew it wasn't time yet for Spike.
So, whatever the First's ultimate plan is,
Spike must play an integral part in that.
Something needs to be done.
Buffy would never allow it.
Buffy would listen to her watcher,
wouldn't she?
l don't think you have much of an idea
of the watcher-slayer dynamic.
- Actually, l was raised by a watcher.
- You what?
Bernard Crowley. Took me in
when l was a young kid, trained me.
Crowley.
l remember the name.
New York-based watcher.
Resigned shortly after his slayer was...
You're Nikki Wood's son.
Yes.
Spike killed your mother.
Does Buffy know this?
She knows my mother was a slayer.
She... doesn't know about Spike.
And this has nothing to do
with personal vengeance?
Does it matter?
He's an instrument of evil.
He's gonna be our undoing
in this fight, Buffy's undoing,
and she will never, never see it coming.
Now, l'm talking about
what needs to be done.
For the greater good, Giles.
And you know l'm right.
What exactly do you propose?
l just need you
to keep Buffy away for a few hours.
l don't know, Giles. ls this really
a primo time for a training session?
l'm still your teacher, Buffy.
As adept as you are as a slayer,
there are always new things to learn.
Now more than ever it's crucial
to maintain focus on your calling.
ln case you haven't noticed,
our plates are kinda full right now.
Plus, l'm not sure how l feel about leaving
Spike at Robin's house to watch over him.
For what it's worth, everyone at your house
seemed quite relieved at the arrangement.
Buffy...
While l'm not technically
your watcher any more,
the fact that your life is such chaos
only underscores the importance
of the lessons l can impart to you.
Fine. lmpart away.
We're on the verge of war.
lt's time you looked at the big picture.
Hello! All l do is look at the big picture.
The other day, l gave an inspirational speech
to the telephone man.
lt takes more than
rousing speeches to lead, Buffy.
lf you're gonna be a general, you need to
make difficult decisions regardless of cost.
Have you seen me with those girls?
The way l've treated my friends
and my family and Andrew?
Believe me. l know
how to make hard decisions.
That's what we're here to find out.
While we work on the basics.
You live in a garage?
This is just a workroom.
Kind of my... sanctuary.
A little place to unwind, eh?
A hard day's principalling got you down, you
need a place to cut loose, let your hair down.
So to speak.
- What the bloody hell is this?
- l told you. lt's my... sanctuary.
lt's the Hellmouth, Spike.
You can never be too careful.
Just... stay away from the walls,
you'll be all right.
lt's a bit much, isn't it?
(typing)
What's your story, Wood?
No story, really.
Just... trying to do what's right.
Make a difference.
How about you?
What kind of man are you, Spike?
Sorry. Not much for self-reflection.
Yeah, makes sense.
See, you strike me as the kinda guy
who just careens through life.
Completely oblivious of the damage
he's doing to everyone around him.
That right?
l know more about you
than you think, Spike.
l've been searching for you
for a very, very long time.
Ever since you killed my mother.
- l've killed a lot of people's mothers.
- Yeah.
You'd remember mine.
She was a slayer.
So that's it, isn't it?
Brought me here to kill me?
No. l don't wanna kill you, Spike.
l wanna kill the monster
who took my mother away from me.
# Early one morning
just as the sun was rising
# l heard a young maid sing
in the valley below
# "Oh, don't deceive me"
# "Oh, never leave me"
# "How could you use..."
There he is.
Mother?
(music box plays "Early One Morning")
Hello, William.
- Look at you.
- Mm, yes. All better.
- You're glowing!
- Am l?
Well, l suppose l have you to thank for that.
How ever will l repay you?
Seeing you like this is payment enough.
Oh, William. You're so...
tender.
This is as it should be, Mother.
You and l together.
- All of London laid out before us.
- Ah, yes. Us.
First we'll feast. Then the night is yours.
Theatre, perhaps. Dancing?
- Tell me. What's your pleasure?
- Pleasure?
To take my leave of you, of course.
"The lark hath spake
from 'twixt its wee beak."
You honestly thought l could bear
an eternity listening to that twaddle?
That's right, dog. Fight back!
l feel extraordinary.
lt's as though l've been given new eyes.
l see everything.
Understand... everything.
- Mother...
- l hate to be cruel.
No, l don't. l used to hate to be cruel in life.
Now l find it rather freeing.
Nothing less will pry your greedy little
fingers off my apron strings, will it?
Stop, please.
Ever since the day you first
slithered from me like a parasite.
- What are you s...?
- Had l known better,
l could have spared myself
a lifetime of tedium and just...
..dashed your brains out when l first saw you.
(growls)
God! l prayed you'd find
a woman to release me,
but you scarcely showed an interest.
Who could compare
to your doddering housebound mum?
A captive audience for your witless prattle.
Whatever l was, that's not who l am any more.
Darling...
lt's who you'll always be.
A limp, sentimental fool.
Hurts, don't it?
This what it felt like
when you beat the life out of her?
Toyed with her?
When you snapped her neck?
- Don't kill him yet.
- What? Why not?
Because l'm asking you not to.
Would you let this vampire live
if it would save the world?
Sure. Seems like a nice enough guy.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
- My name's Richard.
- Hi, Rich.
We talked about this. l wouldn't sacrifice
Dawn to stop Glory destroying the world.
Yes, but things are different now.
After what you've been through.
Faced with the same choice now...
- you'd let her die.
- lf l had to.
To save the world. Yes.
- Can l kill this guy yet?
- No.
So you really do understand
the difficult decisions you'll have to make?
That any one of us is expendable in this war?
Have you heard my speeches?
That we cannot allow any threat that
would jeopardise our chances of winning?
Yes, l get it.
And yet there is Spike.
An animal like you
never cared for anyone but yourself.
No one else mattered.
Just... all about the hunt.
Yeah.
You wanna run, don't you?
Scamper off and cry to your new little trollop.
Do you think you'll be able to love her?
To touch her without feeling me?
All you've ever wanted was to be back inside.
You finally got your wish, didn't you?
Sank your teeth into me. An eternal kiss.
No. l only wanted to make you well.
You wanted your hands on me.
Perhaps you'd like a chance
to finish what you started?
l loved you. l did.
- Not like this.
- Just like this.
This is what you've always wanted.
Who's my dark little prince?
No!
Get out.
Get out!
There, there, precious.
lt will only hurt for a moment.
l'm sorry.
What?
Sorry? You think sorry's
gonna make everything right?
l wasn't talking to you.
l don't give a piss about your mum.
She was a slayer. l was a vampire.
- That's the way the game is played.
- Game?
- She knew what she was signing up for.
- l didn't sign up for it.
That's the rub, isn't it? You didn't
sign up for it and somehow it's my fault.
You took my childhood.
You took her away.
She was all l had. She was my world.
And you weren't hers.
Doesn't that piss you off?
Shut up. You didn't know her.
l know slayers.
No matter how many people
they've got around them, they fight alone.
Life of the Chosen One.
The rest of us be damned.
Your mother was no different.
No. She loved me.
But not enough to quit, though, was it?
Not enough to walk away... for you.
l'll tell you a story about a mother and son.
See, like you, l loved my mother.
So much so l turned her into a vampire.
So we could be together forever.
She said some nasty bits to me
after l did that.
Been weighing on me for quite some time.
But you helped me figure something out.
You see, unlike you,
l had a mother who loved me back.
When l sired her, l set loose a demon,
and it tore into me.
But it was the demon talking, not her.
l realise that now.
My mother loved me... with all her heart.
l was her world.
# Early one morning
just as the sun was rising
# l heard a young maid sing...
That's a nice little song you got there.
Thanks, doc. You cured me after all.
l got my own free will now.
l'm not under the First's
or anyone else's influences now.
l just wanted you to know that...
before l kill you.
Spike's a liability, Buffy.
He refuses to see it, and so do you.
Angel left here because he realised
how harmful your relationship with him was.
Spike, on the other hand,
lacks such self-awareness.
Spike is here because l want him here.
We need him.
- l'm in the fight of my life.
- Really?
Not you, Richard.
You want Spike here even after
what he's done to you in the past?
lt's different now. He has a soul.
And the First is exploiting that
to his advantage.
Oh, my God.
You're stalling me. You're keeping me away...
lt's time to stop playing the role
of general, and to start being one.
This is the way wars are won.
Spike?
What happened?
- Oh, my God.
- l gave him a pass.
Let him live, on account
of the fact l killed his mother.
But that's all he gets.
He even so much as
looks at me funny again, l'll kill him.
l lost my mom a couple of years ago.
l came home
and l found her dead on the couch.
l'm sorry.
l understand what you tried to do,
but she's dead.
Because he murdered her.
l'm preparing for a war, and you want revenge
on a man that no longer exists.
Buffy, don't delude yourself.
That man still exists.
Spike is the strongest warrior we have.
We are gonna need him
if we're gonna come out of this thing alive.
lf you try anything again, he'll kill you.
More importantly, l'll let him.
l have a mission.
To win this war. To save the world.
l don't have time for vendettas.
The mission is what matters.
Buffy...
l...
l understand your anger.
- Please believe me, we did what we...
- He's alive.
Spike's alive. Wood failed.
Well, that doesn't change anything.
What l told you is still true.
- You need to learn...
- No.
l think you've taught me
everything l need to know.
Visiontext Subtitles: Claire Bates
Urgh! Argh!
ENGLlSH SDH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org