So this is what it is.
We're talking about communication.
We're talking about language.
Not the same thing.
It's about inspiration. Not the idea, but
the moment before the idea when it's total.
When it blossoms in your mind
and connects to everything.
It's about the thoughts and experiences
that we don't have a word for.
A demonstration. Buffy Summers.
Come on down to the front here.
A typical college girl, one assumes.
Lie down on my desk.
- What?
- Go ahead, you're perfectly safe.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Riley, if you could oblige.
- A demonstration, right?
- Be a good boy.
This feels very strange.
Don't worry. If I kiss you,
it'll make the sun go down.
See?
Fortune favours the brave.
Do you hear that?
Can't even shout, can't even cry
The Gentlemen are coming by
Looking in windows, knocking on doors
They need to take seven
and they might take yours
Can't call to Mom, can't say a word
You're gonna die screaming
but you won't be heard
So I'll see you all Monday
for a final review session.
Man, that was an exciting class, huh?
- Oh, yeah, well...
- And the last 20 minutes was a revelation.
Just laid out everything
we need to know for the final.
- I'd hate to have missed that.
- Just tell me I didn't snore.
- Very discreet. Minimal drool.
- Oh, yay.
- So were you dreaming?
- Yeah. And it was kind of intense.
Intense? Really?
Cos you seemed so peaceful.
- Of course, it was only for a moment.
- Right. You guys headed over toward Judd?
- Student centre.
- Oh, great. So this dream...
You know, you guys go.
I'm gonna do the thing.
- So I'll see you after Wicca group.
- OK. Bye.
Bye.
So tell me about your dream.
As a psych major, I'm qualified to go "hm".
I don't really remember it.
Well, did I appear at all in this dream?
- There might have been a cameo.
- Is that right?
Maybe more like a featured role.
- Romantically?
- I'm not saying a word.
- So what have you got goin' on tonight?
- Patrolling.
- Patrolling?
- Petroleum.
Petroleum?
Tonight you have crude oil?
And homework.
What about you?
You know, grading papers.
- That'll be fun.
- Not petroleum fun, but it passes the time.
- So I...
- Yeah.
I guess I won't see you until...
Yeah.
- What papers?
- Papers?
Grading what papers? We only have the final.
Yeah...
No, I... Late papers I gotta look at.
OK. Neat.
- So...
- Class.
- I'll see you then.
- Yeah.
Fortune favours the brave.
"Can't even shout, can't even cry.
The Gentlemen are coming by."
It sounds vaguely familiar. You're sure it's
nothing you heard when you were a child?
All right. Nothing else?
Well, it could definitely be
one of your prophetic dreams,
or it could just be
the eternal mystery that is your brain.
I'll check it out
and I'll let you know if I find something.
All right. Bye-bye.
- You heard of a group called the Gentlemen?
- Group of what?
- The Gentlemen.
- Don't know.
- You certain?
- No. We're out of Weetabix.
We are out of Weetabix because you ate it all.
- Again.
- Get some more.
I thought vampires
were supposed to eat blood.
Yeah, well, sometimes I like to
crumble up the Weetabix in the blood.
Gives it a little texture.
Since the picture you just painted means that
I will never touch food of any kind again,
- you'll just have to pick it up yourself.
- Sissy.
- Where is this coming from?
- What am I supposed to think?
- How could you say I'm using you?
- You don't care about what I think.
- You don't ask about my day.
- You did turn into a real girl.
See? And you make jokes during my pain.
You don't care about me at all.
- I care about you.
- How much?
- What do I mean to you?
- I...
We, you know, we spend...
We'll talk about it later.
- I think we should talk about it now.
- Thank you for knocking.
- If you don't know how I feel about...
- I don't.
This isn't a relationship. You don't need me.
All you care about is lots of orgasms.
OK. Remember how we talked
about private conversations?
How they're less private
in front of my friends?
- We're not your friends. Go on.
- Please don't.
- This is important.
- But why is it here?
Mom said you wanted me to swing by.
Oh, yes. Well, I meant after sunset.
I need you to take Spike for a few days.
- What?
- I'm not staying with him.
I've a friend who's coming to town,
and I'd like us to be alone.
You mean an orgasm friend?
Yes, that's exactly the most
appalling thing you could have said.
- If he stays with me, he'll get tied up.
- What about our romantic evening?
I'm not having them shag
while I'm tied to a chair.
- Hardly my fantasy either.
- You're blowing off our evening...
I don't want him to come.
We come together, daughters of Gaea,
sisters to the moon.
We walk with the darkness,
the wolf at our side,
through the waterfall of power
to the blackest heart of eternity.
I think we should have a bake sale.
- I don't know.
- You guys like a bake sale, right?
We need money for the dance recital,
and I do an empowering lemon Bundt.
The most important thing
is the Gaea newsletter.
We need to get the message
of blessing out to the sisters.
Also, who left their scented candles
dripping all over my woman-power shrine?
Well, this is good.
I mean, this is all fun, you know.
But there's also other stuff that we might
show an interest in, as a Wicca group.
Like what?
Well, there's the wacky notion of spells.
You know, conjuring, transmutation.
Yeah, then we could get on our broomsticks
and fly around on our broomsticks.
You know, certain stereotypes
are not very empowering.
- I think that...
- One person's energy can suck the power
from an entire circle. No offence.
- Well, maybe we could...
- Yeah, Tara?
Guys, quiet. Do you have a suggestion?
OK, let's talk about the theme
for the bacchanal.
- So not stellar, huh?
- Talk. All talk.
Blah, blah, Gaea. Blah, blah, moon.
Menstrual life-force power thingy.
After a couple of sessions, I was hoping
we would get into something real, but...
No actual witches in your witch group?
No. Bunch of wanna-blessed-bes.
You know, nowadays every girl
with a henna tattoo and a spice rack
- thinks she's a sister to the dark ones.
- I'm sorry it was a bust.
I know you wanna go further
in that department.
I'd just like to float something
bigger than a pencil someday.
Hey, how's with you and Riley?
You two seemed pretty snuggly after class.
See above, re talk. All talk.
- Do I have to tie you two together?
- We almost, but...
Well, get with it.
I need my vicarious smoochies.
I don't know. I get nervous
and I start babbling.
And he starts babbling and it's a babblefest.
Plus, every time we talk, I have to lie.
The Slayer thing comes up one way
or another. I wish I could just come clean.
- Well, you can't.
- Yeah, I know I can't.
- But it bugs me this time.
- This is the burden we bear, brother.
We have a gig that would inevitably cause
any girl living to think we are cool upon cool.
Yet we Clark Kent our way through the dating
scene, never to use our unfair advantage.
- Thank God we're pretty.
- But it's just Buffy's special.
You think she's special? Wow. The first
486 times you told me, it didn't register,
but now I see that you think she's special.
See, you're naturally inclined
to talk too much. I don't have that.
Then get with the kissin'.
- Riley Finn.
- Initiative vocal-code match complete.
- Don't see why I have to be tied up.
- It's just while I'm sleepin'.
Like I'd bite you anyway.
- Oh, you would.
- Not bloody likely.
I happen to be very biteable, pal.
I'm moist and delicious.
All right, yeah, fine. You're a nummy treat.
And don't you forget it.
Xander, don't you care about me?
- Shut up.
- We never talk.
Shut up.
- Xander.
- Shut up.
"They need to take seven."
Take seven what?
- Olivia.
- Sorry I'm so late.
- The flight was a horror.
- Oh, no.
- Bad weather?
- Baseball movie.
- So sorry.
- Yeah.
That's enough small talk, don't you think?
Retinal scan accepted.
Vocal code not accepted. Please state
your name for vocal identification.
Vocal code not accepted. Unauthorised
beings will be considered hostile.
Please commence vocal identification in the
next 20 seconds to avoid countermeasures.
Override code incorrect.
Lethal countermeasures engaged.
..news from Sunnydale, California.
Apparently the entire town has been
quarantined, due to an epidemic of-
as strange as this may sound- laryngitis.
It seems the town has been
rendered unable to speak.
There's no word yet what might have caused
this or what other effects might be seen.
Local authorities have issued
a written statement
blaming recent flu vaccinations.
A few sceptics call it a citywide hoax.
Sunnydale has effectively
shut down all schools.
Businesses will be closed for the time being.
Residents are advised
to stay home and rest up.
The Centers for Disease Control
have ordered the town quarantined.
No one can go in or out until the syndrome
is identified or the symptoms disappear.
We'll bring you more on that as it develops.
Because there will be chaos.
You will help keep order. Dress as civilians.
A military presence
would only increase panic.
We are looking into it. Go.
Help maintain order. We will find an answer.
You were there looking for me?
I thought maybe we could do a spell.
Make people talk again?
I'd seen you in the group, the Wicca group.
You were different than them.
I mean, they didn't seem to know...
What they were talking about.
I think if they saw a witch,
they would run the other way.
- How long have you been practising?
- Always.
I mean, since I was little.
My mom used to. She...
She had a lot of power. Like you.
Oh. I'm not...
I don't have much in the way of power.
Really, I mean,
most of my potions come out soup.
Besides, spells going awry,
friends in danger...
- I'm definitely nothing special.
- No, you are.
So would you say this was
your best visit ever?
All the time you used to talk to me
about witchcraft and darkness and the like,
- I just thought you were being pretentious.
- Oh, I was.
I was also right.
So everything you told me was true?
Well, no, I wasn't actually one of
the original members of Pink Floyd, but...
But the monster stuff, yes.
Scary.
Too scary?
I don't know.
Hi.
Well...
I guess we have to talk.
I guess we do.
Subtitles by Visiontext
ENGLISH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org