In every generation, there is a Chosen One,
She alone will stand against the vampires,
the demons and the forces of darkness,
She is the Slayer,
- Come on, Mom. Please?
- I'm sorry, honey.
Don't you understand
how important this is?
It's an outfit.
An outfit that you may never buy.
- But... I looked good in it.
- You looked like a streetwalker.
But a thin streetwalker.
That's probably not gonna be
the winning argument, is it?
You're just too young to wear that.
Yeah, and I'm gonna be too young to wear it
until I'm too old to wear it.
That's the idea!
The stores are closing and I still need
to order the flyers for the opening.
OK. I'll go to the printers,
and then get our food.
You go to the tailor and pick up my outfit
from Everyday Woman.
- "Everyday Woman"?
- Mm-hm. There's the receipt.
Why didn't you
just go to Muumuus R Us?
Do now. Make fun of your mother later.
Turn around, baby.
I've somethin' to show ya.
Wait a sec. This is my high score.
Well, ain't you just got
the prettiest little neck I ever did see?
Boy! You guys really never come up
with any new lines, do you?
Do you mind? We were talking here.
But you promised
you'd never cheat on me again, honey.
- Um... I'd better go.
- But I ain't done yet.
All right, sugar lips.
Giddy up.
Oh, you're a rough one,
ain't ya? I like that.
You must be that slayer
I've been hearin' so much about.
Lyle Gorch. Pleased to meet ya.
The pleasure's mine.
This ain't over.
Oh, sure. They say they'll call...
Oh, bliss. Mall food.
- Buffy?
- Mom?
- Where's my dress?
- Your dre...
- Oh... Oh, God.
- Let me guess.
- You were distracted by a boy.
- Technically.
- Buffy!
- Look, I can go get it right now.
They're closed.
I'll just have to fit it in tomorrow.
- Sorry.
- A little responsibility is all I ask.
Honestly, don't you ever think about
anything besides boys and clothes?
Saving the world from vampires?
I swear, sometimes I don't know
what goes on in your head.
"Bad Eggs"
- Xander?
- Shhh-sh-sh.
It's just that... I'm worried
we're gonna miss class.
You know what? This would work
a lot better for me if you didn't talk.
Well, it'd work a lot better for me
with the lights off.
Are you saying that you can't look at me
when we... do... whatever it is we do?
No, it's not that I can't.
It's just more... I don't want to.
That's great! That's just dandy.
We're repulsed by each other.
- We... we hide from our friends...
- Well, I should hope so. Please!
All in all this is not what I'd call
a big self-esteem booster.
Tell me about it. Just look at you!
And those clothes.
Where did you get those shoes?
- OK. You know what? I don't need this.
- Ditto. Like a hole in the head.
S-E-X. Sex.
The sex drive
in the human animal is intense.
How many of us have lost
countless productive hours
plagued by unwanted
sexual thoughts and feelings?
- Yes.
- That was a rhetorical question,
- Mr. Harris, not a poll.
- Oh.
Of course, for teenagers
such as yourselves,
these feelings are
even more overwhelming.
With all sorts of hormones surging through
your bodies, compelling you to action,
it's often difficult to remember
that there are negative consequences to...
having sex.
Would anyone care to
offer one such consequence?
Well, that depends.
Are you talking about sex
in the car, or out of the car?
Because I have a friend - not me -
that was in a Miata parked on top of
the hill and she kicked the gearshift...
Yeah, I was thinking of something
more commonplace, Ms Chase.
You wanna talk negative consequence?
What about the heartbreak of halitosis?
I mean, a girl may seem spiffy,
but if she ignores her flossing,
the bloom is definitely off the rose.
Like that compares to
kissing a guy who thinks
the Hoover technique is a big turn-on!
What about having to feign interest in
her vapid little chitchat
- just so you can get some touch?
- Now!
Another consequence
of sexual activity? Anyone?
Uh, else?
How about pregnancy?
That would be a major one, right?
Thank you, Ms Rosenberg.
Among teens,
unwanted pregnancy is the No.1
negative consequence of sexual activity.
So, as discussed last week,
I present you with...
your offspring.
You will split into parenting teams,
You and your partner will share equally
in the daily task of raising your egg.
Now, please choose a partner
and come pick up your children.
You wanna have a baby?
Hey. I know we just met,
but isn't that Xander Junior
you're holding?
Buffy! How come you weren't in class?
Vampire issues.
Did Mr. Whitmore notice I was tardy?
I think the word you're
searching for is "absent".
- Tardy people show.
- Right.
And yes, he did notice,
so he wanted me to give you this.
As far as punishments go,
this is fairly abstract.
No! It's your baby.
OK, I get it even less.
Well, you know, it's the
"sex leads to responsibility" thing,
which I, personally, don't get.
You gotta take care of the egg.
It's a baby.
You gotta keep it safe
and teach it Christian values.
- My egg is Jewish.
- Then teach it that Dreidel song.
I can't do this.
I can't take care of things!
I killed my Giga Pet.
Literally. I sat on it and it broke.
You'll do fine.
Yeah. The only thing that stresses me is,
when do we tell them they're adopted?
I'll just lay that one off
on my partner. Who'd I get?
Well, there were an uneven number
of students, and you didn't show, so...
- I'm a single mother?
- No man of her own.
Do you know what this says about me?
That I'm doomed to lead my mother's life.
- How deeply scary is that?
- How about this?
It says nothing, it means nothing.
This whole egg experiment
is completely pointless.
Success! At last!
Your playmate is
a fellow of repute, it seems.
It's, erm, Lyle Gorch.
And that one's his brother, Tector.
They're from Abilene. They, uh,
they made their reputation by
massacring an entire
Mexican village in 1886.
- Friendly little demons.
- That was before they became vampires.
But, um... the good news is
that they're...
not amongst the great thinkers
of our time.
I doubt if they're up to much.
They're probably just
drawn here by
the Hellmouth's energy.
Enough said. I propose
Buffy slays them. All in favor?
- Aye.
- I don't think you should
underestimate them. I mean,
you may need to have some help if-if...
Why do you all have eggs?
Hey, maybe you can have
Angel help you find the Gorches.
Yes, yes, that's not a bad idea.
Strength in numbers.
All right. I see a lot of hunting
getting done in that scenario.
Please. Like Angel and I are just
helpless slaves to passion.
Grow up.
- We really...
- I know.
You know, this isn't hunting
in the classical sense. We should...
You're right.
- OK.
- You see anything?
- No.
- OK... Enough hunting.
- Yeah.
- That the Slayer?
- Yep.
- Ain't that Angelus with her?
Well, how come she ain't slayin'?
And how come
he's about to make me blush?
Well, I don't know, Tector. And how come
you're always askin' me
so many stupid questions?
So, you wanna take him,
or, uh... you want me to, Lyle?
I say we leave it.
Wait till she's alone.
Why? You scared?
No. I could whip 'em both
right now if I wanted to.
Then why don't ya?
'Cause I got me a plan.
I'm the one that does the thinkin',
remember?
Yeah. You do the thinkin', Lyle.
That is definitely your department.
So why don't you tell me again
why we can't kill 'em now?
OK, little egg dude. Let's see...
Feeding... Check.
Burping... Ugh. Check.
Diapers... Sort of. In theory, I guess.
OK.
Good night, Egbert.
I'm tired of rat. How come
we can't stay in a nice place?
A motel or somethin'. Maybe, uh...
maybe one with an ice machine.
'Cause we got to keep a low profile till
we get this slayer business taken care of.
Well, how come Angelus is
gettin' all cuddly with her, Lyle?
I mean, does the man have no code?
Tector?
Are you gonna be pestering me
with these questions all damn day?
I just don't like it here. There ain't
a decent whore in the whole city limits.
So this is the thanks I get?
Well...
Don't I take care of ya?
Didn't I near raise you myself?
Hm? Burden that you were,
maybe I shoulda left you on that doorstep
- when Momma blew town.
- Don't say that, Lyle.
- Now I'm takin' care of this.
- You afraid of the girl?
I'm just playin' it safe.
We're just gonna follow her around
a little while, find our time.
- 'Cause this ain't over.
- I think you are afraid of the Slayer.
All right. I'm gonna beat you
like a redheaded stepchild.
Throw your ass out
in that sunlight. C'mon.
- You think you can?
- Giddy up, son.
Yippe-ki-yay, matey!
Oh... Oh, God.
At least eat something
if you're gonna drink that.
Not that hungry.
- How's the parenting going?
- Fine.
Are you sure your egg is secure in that?
Did I ask for back-seat mommying?
- Are we a little touchy this morning?
- No. I just feel all funky.
Hm... You don't have a fever.
Oh, no, it's not that.
I just... I didn't sleep well.
What's the matter?
Your egg keep you up all night?
You're killing me. Parenting's a pain.
Wait till it starts dating.
Oh! Why are you three hanging about?
- Don't you have classes to go to?
- Teen Health got cancelled.
Mr. Whitmore is ab. He couldn't
find an egg-sitter or somethin'.
- Well, then. Can you give me a hand?
- No.
Sure.
How did the, um...
hunt go last night, Buffy?
No go.
Er... no, you didn't go,
or... or you were unsuccessful?
- No Gorches.
- Apparently Buffy has decided
the problem with the English language
is all those pesky words.
You... Angel... big... smoochies?
- Shut... up.
- It-it's true, Buffy.
You and Willow do seem a little sluggish.
Are you quite sure everything's alright?
- Maybe something we ate.
- Or perhaps it's the burden of parenthood.
Notice how seriously
you two have taken this egg thing.
While I, in turn, have, uh,
well, chosen a...
more balanced approach.
- Xander! Maybe you shouldn't...
- That's what I'm talkin' about.
You can't stress over every little thing.
A child picks up on that.
Which is a one-way ticket to Neurotic City.
It didn't break. How come it didn't break?
Which is another secret to
conscientious egg care.
Pot of scalding water and about 8 minutes.
- You boiled your young?
- Yeah! I know it sounds cruel,
but sometimes
you gotta be cruel to be kind.
I mean, you can bet that little Xander here
is thick-skinned now.
Technically, that would be cheating, yes?
No. It's like a shortcut.
You know, when you run a race?
- That would also be cheating.
- You should be ashamed.
I suppose there is a sort of...
Machiavellian ingenuity
to your transgression.
I resent that!
Or possibly thank you.
Figures you three would all be
hanging in the dungeon
while something major's going on
at Sunnydale High.
And what would that be, Cordelia?
Barrette Appreciation Day?
- Mr. Whitmore didn't show today.
- That news is of the past.
He's missing.
- Presumed dead.
- Presumed by whom?
Well, me.
I think we should give him a few hours
before we give up on him completely.
Well, I think we should look around.
Don't you, Xander?
- It can wait.
- Well, his body
could fall out of a closet somewhere.
So we should check some closets
to see if he's in... a closet?
You're right.
There could be a closet. Let's go.
You guys look for more clues.
We'll meet back here.
- We'll get right on it.
- Are they getting weirder?
Have you noticed the weirdness of them?
They're weird. Should I have guilt
about not looking for Mr. Whitmore?
I'd rather you conserve your strength
for hunting the Gorches.
I'll be fine by tonight.
Maybe I'll sweep the cemetery.
Well, be careful. If you're still
feeling a little sluggish...
No worries.
- And Angel's helping you, right?
- He does what he can.
As much as I hate to say this,
we should really go kill bad guys.
It's late. You should get home.
- What about the Gorches?
- I'll hunt.
Really? You'd do that?
Not like I have an early day tomorrow.
True. I still have to go home
and fill out my egg diary.
- Your what?
- Oh, I told you that.
Faux parenting gig
we're doing at school.
Like I'm really planning
to have kids anytime soon.
Maybe... someday in the future,
when I'm done having a life.
But... right now, kids would be
a little too much to deal with.
I wouldn't know.
I don't...
Well, you know, I, I can't.
Oh... That's OK. Um...
I... I figured there were all sorts
of things vampires can't do.
Like... work for the telephone company,
or volunteer for the Red Cross,
or... have little vampires.
So you don't think about the future?
- No.
- Never?
No.
You really don't care
what happens a year from now?
Five years from now?
Angel, when I look
into the future, a-a...
all I see is you.
All I want is you.
I know the feeling.
Hello? Is anybody in here?
- Come on, pick up.
- Hello?
- Willow, are you OK?
- Why shouldn't I be?
- Your egg. Is it doing anything?
- Doing what?
Break it. Right now. I want you to
smash it with something heavy.
- Buffy, what...
- My egg. It went... went postal on me!
The thing hatched, and it, it sprung this
creepy-crawly thing, and it attacked me!
- Are you OK?
- Yeah. No, I'm fine. But-but your egg...
Is totally normal.
I... I put it in the fridge.
Oh...
Maybe it's a trap. Something
the Gorch brothers planted for you?
Maybe. Yeah. Uh...
I'm sorry. I shouldn't've
woken you. Go, go back to sleep.
- You sure?
- Yeah! Yeah, I'm, I'm better.
I'm, I'm fine.
OK. I'll see you tomorrow.
What's going on in here?
Buffy, who are you talking to at this...
Why are you dressed?
Where exactly do you think you are going
at this hour of the night?
- Nowhere.
- Who was that on the phone?
Um... Willow.
She wasn't feeling well today,
so I was calling to make sure
she was feeling better.
You're gonna have to do
much better than that, young lady.
- I had a bad dream?
- Oh, no,
you're about to have a bad dream -
a dream that you're grounded
for the rest of your natural life.
Which means...
no after-school socializing,
no Bronze, no nothing.
Not until I say so. Do you understand?
- Yeah, but I think you...
- Now, school ends at 2:30 -
I want you to go to the library at 2:33,
and study until I pick you up there
at 5:30. Understood?
- Yeah.
- Good. Have a nice day.
- Nice bear. Listen, is your...
- Hey, I'll have you know
that my father brought this bear
back from Gstaad years ago.
Then all of a sudden these trendoids
everywhere started sporting them.
So I'm totally not wearing it.
Then I thought "Hey,"
"I'm the one who started this
nationwide craze. What am I ashamed of?"
OK, Soliloquy Girl.
I just wanted to ask about your egg.
- My egg?
- Yeah, your egg.
- The one Mr. Whitmore gave you.
- It's in my bear.
So... your egg isn't acting
odd or anything?
It isn't "acting" anything.
It's an egg, Buffy. It doesn't emote.
- Shanice! Is that your real hair?
- Yeah...
- Hey.
- Hi.
Mm. Cardboardy!
Sorry, Junior, but a man's gotta eat.
So was there any more
hatchling activity last night?
No. You were probably right.
It was just a trap the vamps set for me.
And... everyone else's eggs
seem perfectly normal.
Did you bring the thing
that attacked you?
Yeah. Giles wants to see it.
He's in full research mode.
OK. Well, bring it to the science lab,
and I'll get Giles and we'll analyze it.
Great. You know, I always say
that a day without an autopsy
is like a day without sunshine.
Hey.
Can I just say... "gyugh!"
I see your "gyugh"
and raise you a "nyagh!"
- What is it?
- We don't know what it is, Cordelia.
That's why we're here. Capeesh?
"Capeesh"? What are you -
world traveler now?
Hey, where's Giles?
I know he won't wanna miss this.
He said to get started.
He'll be by as soon as possible.
So, OK. Get started, Buffy.
Dissect it or something.
- Me? Why do I have to dissect it?
- Uh, because you're the Slayer.
And I slayed. My work here is done.
Oh, no! I almost ate one of these things.
I think I fulfilled my gross-out quota
for the decade.
- Guys!
- Do we even know what to look for?
I mean, how are we supposed
to figure out what this thing is?
Turn it over.
Maybe we missed its ID bracelet.
So, now I guess, uh, we know
what happened to Mr. Whitmore.
- He saw this and ran away?
- Try "best-case scenario".
It's possible that
Mr. Whitmore wasn't harmed.
Maybe the offspring simply used him
to return to the mother bezoar.
Yeah. Maybe he... What?
- What's a bezo...
- Cordy! What...
Buffy?
- Hello?
- Hello.
Oh! Mr. Giles. Hi.
I was looking for Buffy.
She was supposed to wait for me here.
Well, sh-she hasn't been in.
I-I've been waiting to talk to her myself
about, uh, uh... h-history texts.
- That is just the last straw.
- I'm sure she didn't mean to, uh...
She never means to, but somehow
she always manages to anyway.
- Do you have children, Mr. Giles?
- Um...
- Should I be whispering?
- No!
A-a-and, uh, no,
I, I haven't any children.
A-although, uh, sometimes I feel
as though I do, uh, working here...
They can be such a... Oh,
I don't want to say "burden", but, uh...
Actually, I kind of
do want to say "burden".
Feel free.
- Oh, they're just so irresponsible.
- Sometimes.
"Bristow's Demon Index"?.
"Hell's Offspring"?.
A hobby of mine. But having
nothing to do with Buffy in any way.
Um... you say Buffy told you
that she'd be here - all afternoon?
Well, yes. Is something wrong?
No. I'm sure it's nothing.
- What was that?
- Probably the janitor.
Hey! Xander. Hey!
You all right?
Last time Cordy dragged me
in here, it was a lot nicer.
- What?
- Huh? Nothing. Uh...
Crazy talk. Head trauma.
Tell me about it.
I'm gonna have a big bump.
Uh, I'm gonna have a peninsula... here.
What... What the hell's goin' on?
Cordy and Willow...?
Something to do with
the hatchlings, I'm sure of it.
What, are they possessed?
I don't know.
But they sure wanted us out of the way.
Why not kill us? Why, uh...
why drag us in here?
Oh!
Bad now.
Thank you. Oh!
- Giles!
He must be out somewhere.
Well, he picked a hell of a time
to get a life.
- What do we do?
- We can't fight these things
- till we know something about 'em.
- Willow said something - a name.
- What was it?
- A bozo!
- Not bozo.
- A bezoar!
That's it! OK. So now... we look it up?
- In what?
- A book?
Giles said he was gonna
try to find something...
And I'd say he found something.
I'd say something found him.
"Pre-prehistoric parasite. The mother
hibernates underground, laying eggs."
"The offspring then
attach themselves to a host,"
"taking control of their motor functions
through neural clamping.'
"Neural clamping"?
That sounds skippable.
So, our people are taking orders
from the mamma bezoar.
- Which begs the question...
- What does Momma want?
Somebody help me! Get this thing
off me! Get this thing off me!
Help!
Are you OK?
I'm fine. I slipped.
- I think I hear Mommy calling...
- Uh-huh.
- Do we really wanna go in there?
- We really don't.
Careful.
What are they diggin' up?
Oh, boy.
We can't let them spread those eggs.
I'll handle it. Um, can you,
uh, hold down the fort?
I'm gonna need a weapon.
I'm gonna need a big weapon.
Yeah.
- I told you this weren't over.
- She's so cute, and little.
Think we can keep her?
Guys, this really isn't a great time.
Oh, it's gonna be.
Hey! That's my brother!
What the hell is this?
Mom?
Kill them.
What the hell is goin' on?
Long story.
Cordelia! I don't want to hurt you...
some of the time.
That's my bump!
Well, all right!
Well, lookee there!
Well, hello!
Tector!
Tector?
- This is all your fault.
- How?
All right. It's over.
Yes, yes, uh, i-i-it was a-a,
a gas leak, everyone.
But just, er... get some air...
and, er... a good night's rest, you know.
You'll be fine. These gas things...
do happen, actually.
- W-w-what was it really?
- Stick with the gas thing.
- I'll fill you in tomorrow.
- Right.
How you guys doin'?
- Did I really hit you?
- You knocked me out.
- Did I hit you?
- Yes! Everyone hit me.
Good. Well, I don't mean
"good" because I hit you,
but I didn't want to be left out.
- How is she?
- She's a bit confused, but...
It's going around.
- Are you OK?
- Buffy, I was worried.
you'd gotten caught in the building.
There, there was a gas leak.
Yeah, I just heard. I was in the gym.
- I went looking for you in the library.
- Oh, well, I was on my way there when I...
I thought I made it pretty clear that
you weren't to leave the library
- till I came.
- The other side of that is
- there was a gas leak...
- I'm not really interested
in the other side right now.
Young lady, you have to learn
some responsibility, OK?
- Once and for all.
- I'm grounded?
- You're already grounded!
- Oh, yeah.
Until further notice,
you are confined to your room.
You will not leave your room at any time
except to go to school or the bathroom.
- Am I making myself clear?
- You're clear.
I... won't leave my room.
You're damn right, you won't.
- You sure you're not gonna get in trouble?
- Hey. I earned this.
'Sides, I'm not breaking any rules.
Buffy? Are you going to bed?
In a minute!
Subtitles extended & timed by UAR
www.tvsubtitles.net