Come on, Mom! She's always late.
Are you lost?
No.
My mom's just supposed
to pick me up, is all.
Do you want me to walk you home?
No, thank you.
My mummy used to sing me to sleep at night.
# Run and catch
# The lamb is caught
in the blackberry patch
She had the sweetest voice.
What will your mummy sing
when they find your body?
I'm not supposed to talk to people.
Oh. Well, I'm not a person, see?
So that's just...
Run home.
My Angel!
Hello, Drusilla.
Do you remember the song
Mummy used to sing me?
Pretty.
I remember.
- Yes, you do.
- Drusilla, leave here.
I'm offering you that chance.
Take Spike and get out.
Or you'll hurt me?
No. No, you can't. Not any more.
If you don't leave,
it'll go badly... for all of us.
My dear boy's gone all away, hasn't he?
To her.
Who?
The girl. The Slayer.
Your heart stinks of her.
Poor little thing.
She has no idea what's in store.
This can't go on, Drusilla. It's gotta end.
Oh, no, my pet.
This is just the beginning.
"Lie to Me"
- It's a secret.
- What kind of a secret?
Uh, the kind that's secret. You know,
where I don't actually tell you what it is.
I think it's customary that when
two people are going out on an evening
that they, they both have an idea
of where they're going.
Come on!
Where is your sense of adventure?
How will I know what to wear?
Do you own anything else?
- Er, well, not as such, no.
- Rupert, you're gonna have to trust me.
- All right. I'll put myself in your hands.
- That sounds like fun.
- OK, tomorrow night, 7:30, right?
- Yes.
- Hey.
- Hello. Um...
- Did we... hunt last night?
- I did a couple of quick sweeps downtown.
- Any encounters?
- Nothing vampirey.
I've been researching our friend Spike.
The profile is fairly unappetizing.
But I-I still haven't got a bead
on why he's here.
You'll figure it out.
You all right? You seem a little glum.
- I'm fine.
- Why don't you take the night off?
OK. That'd be nice.
Yes. You could
spend some time with Angel.
I don't know.
He... might have other plans.
Well, it seems like Louis XVI
was just sort of a weak king.
That's fair enough.
Uh, any other impressions?
I just don't see why everyone's
always picking on Marie Antoinette.
I can so relate to her. She worked
really hard to look that good
and people just
don't appreciate that kind of effort.
And I know the peasants were all depressed.
I think you mean "oppressed".
Whatever. They were cranky.
So they're like
"Let's lose some heads!"
That's fair. And-and
Marie Antoinette cared about them.
She was gonna let them have cake.
Yes, well. That's
a very interesting perspective.
Um... Would anyone else like to comment?
I don't know. I don't think so.
- They seemed pretty friendly.
- Who's friendly?
- No one.
- Angel and a girl.
Willow, do we have to be
in total share mode?
Hey, it's me! If Angel's doing
something wrong, I wanna know.
- 'Cause it gives me a happy.
- I'm glad someone has a happy.
Oh, you just need cheering up.
And I know just the thing.
- Crazed dance party at the Bronze!
- I don't know.
Very calm dance party at the Bronze?
Moping at the Bronze?
I'd suggest a box of Oreos
dunked in apple juice,
but maybe she's over that phase.
- Ford?
- Hey, Summers. How you been?
- Oh, my God! What are you doing here?
- Uh, matriculating.
Huh?
I'm finishing out
my senior year at Sunnydale High.
- Dad got transferred.
- This is great!
Why d'you think so?
Didn't think you'd remember me.
Remember you? Duh! We only went
to school together for seven years!
- You were my giant fifth-grade crush.
- So! You two know each other?
Oh, I'm sorry. Um, this is Ford. Uh...
- Billy Fordham, this is Xander and Willow.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- Nice to meet you.
Uh, Ford and I went to
Hemery together in LA.
- And now you're here. For real?
- Dad got the transfer and... boom!
He just dragged me out of Hemery
and put me down here.
- So you two were sweeties in fifth grade?
- Not even!
- Ford wouldn't give me the time of day.
- I was a manly sixth-grader.
Couldn't be bothered
with a girl that young.
It was terrible.
I moped over you for months.
Sitting in my room listening to
that Divinyls song 'I Touch Myself'.
Of course, I had no idea
what it was about!
Hey, are you busy tonight?
We're going to the Bronze.
It's the local club and you have to come.
I'd love to, but if... you guys
already had plans, would I be imposing?
- Oh, only in the literal sense.
- OK, then!
I gotta find the admissions office,
uh, get my papers in order.
Well, you know? I'll take you there
and I'll see you guys in French.
It's good to meet you.
This is Ford,
my bestest friend of all my friends!
Jeez, doesn't she know any fat guys?
Oh, that's what that song is about?!
- Ford, you made it.
- It wasn't hard to find.
Buffy, Ford was just telling us
about the ninth grade beauty contest
and the, uh, swimsuit competition.
Oh, my God, Ford, stop that!
The more people you tell,
the more people I have to kill.
You can't touch me, Summers.
I know all your darkest secrets.
- Care to make a small wager on that?
- I'm gonna go get a drink.
Ford... try not to talk.
- Oh.
- Hey. I was hoping you'd show.
- That's Angel.
- He's Buffy's beau.
Her special friend.
He's not in school, right?
He looks older than her.
You're not wrong.
So...
- What did you do last night?
- Nothin'.
Nothing at all? You ceased to exist?
No, I mean I stayed in, read.
Oh.
- Didn't want that soda after all?
- Not thirsty.
- Hey, Angel.
- Hi.
This is Ford.
We went to school together in LA.
- Nice to meet you.
- Whoa! Cold hands.
You're not wrong.
- So, you're here visiting Buffy?
- No, I'm actually here to stay.
- We've just moved down.
- Hey, Angel, do you wanna play?
You know, it's getting really crowded
in here tonight. Um, I'm a little hot.
- You wanna take a walk?
- Um, sure. That'd be nice.
OK, then. I'll... see you tomorrow.
- Good night.
- Take care.
- OK, once more, with tension.
- He just moved here?
Yeah, and boy, does he move fast!
Well, Angel, we could still play.
See? You made him do
that thing where he's gone!
So... that was your boyfriend?
No... Uh, yeah. Maybe.
Could we lay off
the tough questions for a while?
Sorry.
So... What else
do you do for fun around here?
Um... My purse! I... I left my purse at
the Bronze. Uh, could you get it for me?
- Uh, OK.
- Good.
Run! Thanks!
No!
- What's goin' on?
- Um...
There was a... cat. A cat, here.
And, um, then there was... another cat.
And they fought. The cats.
And... then they left.
Oh. I thought you were
just slaying a vampire.
What? Whatting a what?
I know, Buffy. You don't have to lie.
I've been trying to figure out
the right time to... to tell you.
I know you're the Slayer.
- Just like that, he told you?
- Just like that.
Said he found out right before
I got booted from Hemery.
Wow! It's neat!
Is it neat?
Yeah, I guess it is.
I don't have to constantly worry
that he's gonna find out my dark secret.
And it just makes everything... easier.
(# "Never Land" by The Sisters of Mercy)
- Ford? Hi, Ford.
- Hey.
- Well, how did it go?
- It went good.
Good? That's it? That's all we...?
- Well, when are we...?
- Soon.
Oh, soon, OK. You know, you could
give me more information here.
I'm trusting you.
I'm out on a limb here.
Not to mention, the lease is almost up
on this place. Who's gonna cover that?
- Marvin...
- Diego!
Come on, man, it's Diego now.
Diego. Ritalin.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Just make sure
you're ready when I say.
True believers only.
- I can't wait.
- Right. Whatever.
I still think
I should be in on the plan.
Diego, you gotta trust me.
All right,
A couple more days
and we'll get to do the two things
every American teen
should have the chance to do:
Die young...
and stay pretty.
So...
you play your wits against mine.
Me, who commanded armies
hundreds of years before you were born,
Fools!
- Oh! Angel, what are you doing here?
- I wanted to talk to you.
Oh, well...
- Well?
- I can't.
Unless you invite me, I can't come in.
Oh! Well, OK...
I... invite you... to... come in.
- If this is a bad time, I...
- No! I just...
I'm not supposed to have boys in my room.
I promise to behave myself.
OK. Good.
- I guess I need help.
- Help? You mean, like, on homework?
No, 'cause you're old
and you already know stuff.
I want you to track someone down...
on the Net.
Oh! Great! I'm so the Net girl.
I just wanna find everything I can:
records, affiliates...
I'm not even sure
what I'm looking for yet.
- Great, what's the name?
- Billy Fordham.
Uh, Angel, if I say something
you really don't wanna hear,
do you promise not to bite me?
- Are you gonna tell me that I'm jealous?
- Well, you do sometimes get that way.
You know, I never used to.
Things used to be pretty simple.
A hundred years...
just hanging out, feeling guilty.
I really honed my brooding skills.
Then she comes along.
Yeah, I get jealous.
But I know people,
and my gut tells me this is a wrong guy.
OK, but if there isn't anything weird...
- Hey, that's weird.
- What?
I just checked the school records
and he's not in them.
I mean, usually they
transfer your grades and stuff,
but he's not even registered.
He said he was in school
with you guys, right?
- Let me just see if I can...
- Willow?
- Are you still up?
- Ack! Go!
Uh, I'm just going to bed now, Mom!
Come by tomorrow at sunset.
I'll keep looking.
Don't tell Buffy
what we're doing, all right?
You want me to lie to her?
It's Buffy!
Just don't bring it up
till we know what's what.
- OK. It's probably nothing.
- That'd be nice.
Willow!
- What's up?
- Nothing.
Do you wanna hang?
We're cafeteria bound.
I-I'm gonna do work in the computer lab...
on schoolwork that I have.
- So I cannot hang just now. Hi, Ford.
- Morning.
- OK, Will, fess up.
- What?
Are you drinking coffee again?
'Cause we've talked about this.
It makes me jumpy.
I... have to go... away.
- Nice girl.
- There aren't two of those in the world!
Buffy! Erm... Yes, er...
Ms. Calendar and I are going...
somewhere tonight.
And she's given me
the number of her beeper thingy,
er, in case you need me...
for, erm, study help... suddenly.
- He knows, Giles.
- What?
- Ford knows I'm the Slayer.
- I know.
Oh. Er, very good, yes.
Buffy? Excuse me.
You're not... by any chance
betraying your... secret identity...
just to impress cute boys, are you?
I didn't tell him. He knew.
Oh. Er, right then.
Just remember, if you...
Go! Experience this thing called fun.
I'll try not to have a crisis.
And on your right, once again,
the beautiful campus.
I think you've now seen
everything there is to see in Sunnydale.
Well, it's really...
- Feel free to say "dull".
- OK. Dull is good.
Or maybe not so dull.
Is that more vampires?
It must be the weather.
Stay close to me.
- Maybe they were just passing through.
- I don't think so.
You got one chance to live.
Tell me what I wanna know
and I'll let you go.
- Where's the other one?
- I killed her.
I-I killed her and she just...
turned to dust. It was... amazing.
The only thing I could track down
was this address. The Sunset Club.
Still didn't find anything incriminating.
He leaves no paper trail, no records.
That's incriminating enough.
Yeah, I'm gonna have to go
with Dead Boy on this one.
Could you not call me that?
We're friends of Ford's.
Boy, we blend right in.
In no way do we stick out
like sore thumbs.
Let's look around.
You guys check out downstairs.
Sure thing, Bossy the Cow!
- OK, but do they really stick out?
- What?
Sore thumbs. Do they stick out?
I mean, have you ever seen a thumb
and gone "Wow! That baby is sore"?
You have too many thoughts.
(# "Reptile" by Creaming Jesus)
# The one hungry life
# My life with the other
Hi.
Are you probably noticing a theme here?
As in "vampires, yay"?.
That's the one.
- You guys are newbies, I can tell.
- Oh, no. We come here all the time.
Don't be ashamed.
It's cool that you're open to it.
We welcome anyone
who's interested in the lonely ones.
- The lonely ones?
- Vampires.
Oh, we usually call them
the nasty, pointy, bitey ones.
So many people have that misconception.
But they who walk with the night
are not interested in harming anyone.
They are... creatures above us, exalted.
You're a fool.
You don't have to be
so confrontational about it.
Other viewpoints than yours
may be valid, you know.
Nice meeting you.
- You really are a people person.
- Now nobody's gonna talk to us!
I've seen enough.
I've seen this type before.
I mean, they're children making up
bedtime stories of friendly vampires
- to comfort themselves in the dark.
- Is that so bad?
These people don't know
anything about vampires!
What they are,
how they live, how they dress.
You know, I love a good diatribe,
but I'm still curious why Ford,
bestest friend of the Slayer,
is hangin' with a bunch of
vampire wannabes.
Something's up with him.
You're right about that.
Sorry to beep you guys
in the middle of... stuff,
- but it seemed really weird.
- No. You did the right thing. Absolutely.
- You hated it that much?
- No, but-but, uh...
Vampires on campus
could have implications.
- Very, very grave.
- You could've just said something.
Uh, honestly, I, I've always, I've always
been interested in, in,
uh, monster trucks.
- You took him to monster trucks?
- I thought it would be a change.
- It was a change.
- Look, we could've just left.
Wha-what, and miss the nitro-burning
funny cars? No, couldn't have that.
OK, can we get back
on the vampire tip here?
These guys were here with a purpose.
Yes, yes, and, uh, we must, uh,
ascertain what that purpose is.
- Where's your friend?
- I sent him home.
Good. The less he's involved
in all this, the safer he'll be.
He did bag a vamp his first time out.
Gotta give him credit for... that.
Something wrong?
- Who's this?
- Erm, she's called... Drusilla.
A sometime paramour of Spike's.
She was killed by an angry mob in Prague.
Well, they don't make angry mobs like
they used to, 'cause this girl's alive.
- I saw her with Angel.
- With Angel?
Isn't he supposed to be a good guy?
Yeah. He is.
I think maybe we need to
read up on this nice lady.
Well, some of my...
newer volumes may be more helpful.
My own research has...
Are you guys OK?
A book! It took one of my books!
Well, at least
someone in this school is reading.
He said he killed it.
That's the vampire Ford said he killed.
You sing the sweetest little song...
Won't you sing for me, hm?
Don't you love me any more?
Darling. I heard a funny thing just now.
Lucius tells me that you
went out on a hunt the other night.
My tummy was growly... and you were out.
Come on.
- I'll pout if you don't sing.
- You, um, meet anyone?
Anyone interesting? Like Angel?
- Angel...
- Yeah.
So...
What might you guys
have talked about, then?
Old times? Childhood pranks?
It's a little off, you two so friendly,
him being the enemy and all that.
- I'll give you a seed if you sing.
- The bird's dead, Dru.
You left it in a cage
and you didn't feed it
and now it's all dead,
just like the last one.
Oh, I'm sorry, baby.
I'm a bad, rude man.
I just don't like you goin' out,
that's all. You are weak.
Would you like a new bird?
One that's not dead?
This is so cool!
- I would totally live here!
- Do I have anyone on watch here?
It's called security, people!
Are you all asleep?
Or did we finally find
a restaurant that delivers?
- I know who you are.
- Yeah, I know who I am too. So what?
I came looking for you... Spike.
You've got a real death wish.
It's almost interesting.
Oh, this is great!
This'll be very useful.
- So, how did you find me?
- That doesn't matter.
I've got something to offer you.
I'm pretty sure this is the part
where you take out a watch
and say I've got 30 seconds to
convince you not to kill me?
It's traditional.
Well, I don't go much for tradition.
Wait, love.
Well?
Oh, come on. Say it!
It's no fun if you don't say it.
What?! Oh...
You've got 30 seconds
to convince me not to kill you.
Yes! See, this is the best.
I wanna be like you. A vampire.
I've known you for two minutes
and I can't stand you.
I don't really feature you livin' forever.
Can I eat him now, love?
Well, feature this.
I'm offering you a trade.
You make me a vampire...
and I give you the Slayer.
Buffy. May I come in?
Sure.
I thought once you'd been invited,
you could always just walk in.
I can. I was just being polite.
- We need to talk.
- Do we?
It's about your friend, Ford.
He's not what he seems.
- Who is these days?
- Willow ran him down on the computer.
- Willow?
- We found this address,
- We checked it out with Xander and it...
- And Xander?
Wow! Everybody's in.
It's like a great big, exciting conspiracy.
- What are you talkin' about?
- I'm talking about the people I trust.
Who's Drusilla?
And don't lie to me. I'm tired of it.
- Some lies are necessary.
- For what?
Sometimes the truth is worse.
Live long enough, you find that out.
I can take it. I can take the truth.
Do you love me?
What?
Do you?
I love you.
I don't know if I trust you.
- Well, maybe you shouldn't do either.
- Maybe I'm the one who should decide!
I did a lot of unconscionable things
when I became a vampire.
Drusilla was the worst.
She was... an obsession of mine.
She was pure and... sweet and chaste.
And you made her a vampire.
First I made her insane.
Killed everybody she loved.
Visited every mental torture
on her I could devise.
She eventually fled to a convent.
And on the day
she took her holy orders...
I turned her into a demon.
Well...
I asked for the truth.
Ford's part of some society
that reveres vampires.
Practically worships them.
I don't know what he wants from you.
But you can't trust him.
Buffy!
- Ford.
- I had a great time last night.
Well, an interesting time.
- I'm glad.
- Do you wanna go out again tonight?
- Not busy.
- I sort of had an idea.
It's, uh... it's a secret.
I kinda wanna surprise you.
- I like surprises.
- Can you meet me here?
- Sure.
- At nine?
At nine.
It's gonna be fun.
Buffy!
Did, uh, Angel...
He told me everything.
When Angel came to my room,
he was just really concerned for you.
We didn't wanna say anything
in case we were wrong.
Did you find out what Ford is up to?
I will.
Angel was in your bedroom?!
Ours is a forbidden love.
- Chanterelle, is everything ready?
- Of course! It's ready. Hi.
I took care of it.
I always take care of it.
Is it time? Tonight?
- Are you nervous?
- Yes.
No. I'm... ready for the change.
D'you really think they'll bless us?
I know they will.
What about your friends?
Are they comin'?
- What are you talkin' about?
- Your friends. They came last night.
- Two guys and a girl.
- One was mean.
- Why didn't you tell me about this?
- I have to do everything around here.
Sorry, Mr. Flawless Plan Guy.
It slipped my mind.
It's gonna be all right, isn't it?
They're not gonna let us down?
- It's gonna be fine.
- I need them to bless me.
- No.
It's really not.
It's kinda draughty in here.
I'm sorry, Ford.
I just couldn't wait till tonight.
- I'm rash and impulsive. It's a flaw.
- We all have flaws.
I'm... still a little fuzzy
on exactly what yours is.
I think it has to do with
being a lying scumbag.
Everybody lies.
What do you want, Ford?
What's this all about?
- I really don't think you'd understand.
- I don't need to understand.
I just need to know.
I'm gonna be one of them.
- You wanna be a vampire?
- I'm going to.
You know, vampires are a little picky
about who they change ov...
You were gonna offer them a trade!
I don't think I wanna talk any more.
Yeah, well I still feel awfully chatty.
You were gonna give them me - tonight!
- Yes.
- You had to know I'd figure it out.
Actually, I was counting on it.
What's supposed to happen tonight?
This is so cool! It's just like
it played in my head.
You know the part where you ask me what's
supposed to happen? It's already happening.
Rigged up special. Once it's closed
it can only be opened from the outside.
As soon as the sun sets, they'll be comin'.
Ford, if these people are still around
when they get here...
We'll be changed. All of us.
We're going to ascend
to a new level of consciousness,
become like them -
like the lonely ones.
This is the end, Buffy.
No one gets outta here alive.
- There's gotta be another way out of here.
- This is a bomb shelter, Buffy.
I knew I wasn't gonna
be able to overpower you,
but this is three feet of solid concrete.
- At least let the other people go.
- Why are you fighting this?
- It's what we want.
- It's a chance for immortality.
This is a beautiful day.
Can't you see that?
What I see is that
right after the sun goes down,
Spike and all of his friends
are going to be pigging out
at the all-you-can-eat moron bar.
OK, that's it.
I think we should gag her.
- I think you should try.
- She's an unbeliever. She taints us.
I am trying to save you!
You are playing
in some serious traffic here.
Do you understand that?
You're going to die, and the only hope
you have of surviving this
is to get out of this pit right now and...
My God! Could you have a dorkier outfit?
You gotta back her up, D.
You look like a big ninny.
6:27. Sunset.
When we get there,
everybody spread out.
Two men on the door.
First priority is the Slayer.
Everything else is fair game,
but let's remember to share, people.
Are you sure you're up for this?
I want a treat. I need a treat.
And a special one you'll have.
Lucius, bring the car around.
- Hey, you never give up, do you?
- No, I don't.
It's a good quality in a person.
Too many people just take it, but us...
- Us? We have something in common now?
- More than you think.
Yeah, well, let me explain
something to you.
You're what we call "the bad guy".
I guess I am.
These people aren't
gonna get changed, are they?
The rest of them, they're just fodder.
Technically, yes. But... I'm in.
I will become immortal.
Well, I've got a newsflash
for you, brain trust.
It's not how it works. You die and
a demon sets up shop in your old house.
And it walks and it talks and it
remembers your life, but it's not you.
- It's better than nothin'.
- And your life is nothing?
Ford, these people don't deserve to die!
Well, neither do I!
But apparently no one took that
into consideration, 'cause I'm still dyin'.
I look good, don't I?
Well, let me tell you somethin'.
I got maybe six months left,
and by then, what they bury
won't even look like me.
I'm gonna be bald and
shriveled and I'll smell bad.
Now I'm not goin' out that way.
I'm sorry, Summers.
Did I screw up your righteous-anger riff?
Does the nest of tumors
liquefying my brain kinda spoil the fun?
I'm sorry.
I had no idea.
But what you're doing is still very wrong.
OK, well, you try vomiting
for 24 hours straight,
because the pain in your head
is so intense, and then...
we'll discuss the concept
of right and wrong.
These people are sheep.
They wanna be vampires
'cause they're lonely...
miserable...
or bored.
- I don't have a choice.
- You have a choice.
You don't have a good choice,
but you have a choice.
You're opting for mass murder here,
and nothing you say
is gonna make that OK!
You think
I need to justify myself to you?
I think this is all
part of your little fantasy drama!
Isn't this exactly how you imagined it?
You tell me how you've suffered,
and I feel sorry for you.
Well, I do feel sorry for you, and if those
vampires come in here and start feeding,
I'll kill you myself!
You know what, Summers?
I really did miss you.
Ford... help me stop this.
Please.
People, listen to me!
This is not the mother ship, people!
This is ugly death come to play...
Take them all. Save the Slayer for me.
Spike!
Everybody stop!
Good idea. Now you let everybody out
or your girlfriend fits in an ashtray.
Let them go.
Down the stairs.
Uh, where's the doorknob?
- You guys are just in time.
- Are there vampires?
They're contained.
They'll... get out eventually, though.
We should probably go.
We can come back when they're gone.
Come back for what?
For the body.
- What happened?
- We're stuck in a basement.
Buffy?
She's not stuck in the basement.
Hey, well... I delivered.
I handed her to you.
Yes. I suppose you did.
So? What about my reward?
I don't know what I'm supposed to say.
You needn't say anything.
Be simpler if I could just hate him.
I think he wanted me to.
I think it made it easier for him
to be the villain of the piece.
Really he was just scared.
- Yes, I suppose he was.
- Nothing's ever simple any more.
I'm constantly trying to work it out.
Who to love or hate, who to trust.
It's just like the more I know,
the more confused I get.
Well, I believe that's called growing up.
- I'd like to stop, then. OK?
- I know the feeling.
Does it ever get easy?
You mean life?
Yeah. Does it get easy?
What do you want me to say?
Lie to me.
Yes, it's terribly simple.
The good guys are always
stalwart and true.
The bad guys
are easily distinguished by
their pointy horns or black hats.
And, uh, we always defeat them
and save the day.
No one ever dies and...
everybody lives happily ever after.
Liar.
Subtitles extended & timed by: UAR
...
www.tvsubtitles.net