We haven't been properly introduced.
I'm Buffy, and you're... history!
Poor technique. Prioritising, sub-par.
Execution was adequate,
but a bit too... bloody for my taste.
Giles, don't mention it. It was my pleasure
to make the world safe for humanity again.
I'm not saying that
your methods are without merit.
It's... You're spending
too much time and energy.
It should simply be
plunge and move on, plunge and...
Hello.
Oh, that's great!
I kill 'em, you fence their stuff.
- What is it?
- I don't know.
- But it bothers you.
- Yes. I...
I thought this vampire
was just on a random kill,
- but it may be something else.
- Something big?
Yes. I'd best consult my books.
"And there will be a time of crisis."
"Of worlds hanging in the balance."
"And in this time shall come...
..the Anointed."
"The Master's great warrior."
"And the Slayer will not know him,
will not stop him,
and he will lead her into Hell."
"As it is written,
so shall it be."
"Five will die,
and from their ashes
the Anointed shall rise."
"The Brethren of Aurelius shall greet him
and usher him to his immortal destiny."
"As it is written,
so shall it be."
And one of the Brethren
shall go out hunting
the night before and get himself killed,
because he couldn't wait
to finish his job before he ate.
Oh, wait.
That's not written anywhere.
The Anointed will be
my greatest weapon against the Slayer.
If you fail to bring him to me,
if you allow that girl to stop you...
Here endeth the lesson.
That symbol on the ring.
I believe it's the rune for fidelity but...
it doesn't connect with any
of the sects that I've studied.
What about this? On the inside
it's a sun and three stars.
- Haven't we seen that somewhere?
- Let me see.
No, I don't think this represents any...
Wait. It's right here. "Sun and three stars."
Ugh. Check these guys out.
I told you it looked familiar.
"By the Order of Aurelius." Yes, you're right.
Ooh! Two points for the Slayer
while the Watcher has yet to score.
Oh. Owen. Hi.
- What do you want?
- A book?
See, this is a school and we have students
and they check out books
and then they learn things.
I was beginning to suspect that was a myth.
I lost my Emily... Dickinson.
It's dumb but... I like her around.
Kind of a security blanket.
I have something like that.
Well, it's an actual blanket.
And I don't really
carry it around any more.
So! Emily Dickens, huh? She's great.
- Dickinson.
- She's good also.
Poetry.
I didn't think I'd find you here.
- Why not?
- I didn't mean...
I mean... I think you can read.
Oh, thanks.
But... you don't seem bookwormy.
The type of person to lock themselves
in a dark room with a lot of
musty, old books.
Oh, and I've offended you.
No!
No, I'm just surprised
you gave any thought to what I'm like.
You shouldn't be.
Oh, well, I love books.
I mean, I really love books.
- What's this?
- Oh... Not this one.
This one she doesn't love.
Oh! Emily Dickinson.
- We're both fans.
- Yes. She's quite a good poet.
I mean, for a...
- A girl?
- For an American.
I'll see you in math
if I open my eyes at some point.
Cool.
The Order of Aurelius
is a very old and venerated sect.
If they're here, it's for a good reason.
- That was Owen.
- Yes, I remember.
Do you have any more copies
of Emily Dickinson? I need one.
Buffy, while the mere fact of you
wanting to check out a book
would be grounds for a national holiday,
I think we should focus
on the problem at hand.
Right. I'm sorry. You're right.
Vampires.
Oh. Does this outfit make me look fat?
Owen Thurman was talking to you?
It's all true.
Wow! He hardly talks to anyone.
He's solitary, mysterious.
He can brood for 40 minutes straight.
I've clocked him.
He was so nice, it was eerie.
- What did you guys have to talk about?
- Emily Dickinson.
He reads Emily Dickinson?
He's sensitive, yet manly.
But wait. You've never even read her.
You vixen!
Has anybody given any thought
to what this green stuff is?
I'm avoiding the subject.
I think it's kale.
Or possibly string cheese.
So, Buffy, how'd the slaying go last night?
Xander!
I mean... how'd the laying go?
- No, I don't mean that either.
- It went fine, thank you.
There's some new hoity-toity
vampire sect in town.
That's bad.
Hey, they're bringing in
much-needed tourist dollars.
Ooh. Look at Mr Excitement.
Owen. He's all alone.
Maybe somebody should sit with him.
Mm, just to be polite.
Good luck.
OK, what just happened?
Look! An empty seat.
- Let me get that.
- Thanks.
Boy, Cordelia's hips are wider than I thought.
At least you don't have to eat
your Soylent Green.
Owen, a bunch of us are loitering
at the Bronze tonight. You there?
- Who else's going?
- Well, I'm gonna be there.
- Who else?
- You mean besides me?
- Buffy, what about you?
- What?
No, no, no.
She, uh... She doesn't like fun.
How about we meet there at eight?
Yeah. Eight.
There.
It's not a big deal. It's just
a bunch of people getting together.
- It's a very big deal!
- It's not.
It is! Tell her.
- I'm afraid it's very big.
- Thank you.
Wait. What are you talking about?
- What are you talking about?
- Boys.
Yes, well, I'm talking about trouble.
A violent and disturbing
- prophecy is about to be fulfilled.
- The Order of Aurelius.
You were spot-on about the connection.
I've looked at the writings of Aurelius himself.
He prophesied that the brethren of
his order would come to the Master and...
bring him the Anointed.
- Who's that?
- Well, I don't know exactly. A warrior.
But it says "He will rise
from the ashes of the five...
..on the evening of the 1,000th day
after the advent of Septus."
Well we'll be ready, whenever it is.
- Which is tonight.
- Tonight, OK.
- Not OK! It can't be tonight!
- My calculations are precise.
They're bad calculations! Bad!
- Buffy has a really important date.
- Owen.
All right.
I'll just jump in my time machine,
go back to the 12th century
and ask the vampires to
postpone their ancient prophecy for a few
days while you take in dinner and a show.
OK, at this point you're abusing sarcasm.
Buffy, this is no ordinary vampire.
We have to stop him
before he reaches the Master.
But... cute guy!
Teenager! Postpubescent fantasies!
Those will just have to be put on hold.
The Dark Forces are aligning against us,
and we have a chance to beat them back.
Tonight we go into battle.
- Perhaps I miscalculated.
- I'm thinking yes.
Well, you know what they say: 90 percent
of the vampire-slaying game is-is waiting.
- You couldn't have told me 90 percent ago?
- We've certainly waited here long enough.
Besides, there aren't any fresh graves.
Who's gonna rise?
Apparently no one, tonight.
Then I can bail? I can go
to the Bronze and find Owen?
Very well. Follow your hormones if you want.
But I assume I don't have to
warn you about the...
hazards of becoming
personally involved with someone
who's unaware of your unique condition.
- Yeah, yeah, I read the back of the box.
- If your identity as a slayer is revealed,
it could put you and all those
around you in grave danger.
Well, in that case, I won't wear my button
that says "I'm A Slayer. Ask Me How."
Good night.
"Five shall die, and from their ashes
the Anointed shall rise."
I was sure it was tonight.
I went on an airplane.
A pale horse emerged
with Death as its rider.
You will be judged.
(# Rotten Apple by Three Day Wheely)
# ...is real
# Then you wake up shouting
some familiar name
#  It's not the same
# You're just a girl
# Just a girl who knows no shame
# Whose desperate pace has lost its taste
# A never-ending darkness weighs
# I can't avoid, I can't complain
# I know exactly who's to blame
# The girl who shares my...
That day's gonna bring fire.
Fire comin' down. Judgment.
Don't think you're ready.
Ready to look upon him.
If there's sin in there,
there's sin all around. It's a liquid.
On that day there won't be anybody
tellin' us what to do
or why we're doin' it.
You can't prepare.
- On that day...
- You gotta sit down.
OK?
Are you willing to stand
with the righteous?
Is everyone OK?
Are you all right?
Can you move?
- So you just went home?
- What was I supposed to do?
Say to Owen: "Sorry, I was late.
I was sitting in a cemetery
with a librarian waiting
for a vampire to rise
so I could prevent an evil prophecy
from coming to pass"?
Or... flat tyre?
I can't take this any more.
I feel like everyone is staring at me.
The big, hideous, dateless monster.
What? Yeah, that's right, I have no life.
C'mon, nothin' to see here, pal.
Move it along!
You're acting a little overly, aren't you?
I mean, you could have any guy in school.
He's not "any guy". He's more... Oweny.
Sure, he's got a certain Owenosity,
but... that's not hard to find.
I mean, a lot of guys read.
I can read.
- Hey, Buffy.
- Owen.
Oh, look. It's Owen.
Buffy and Owen. And Xander. That'd be me.
- Where were you last night?
- Oh.
Well, um, my watch broke and
we don't have any... clocks in our house
so I didn't know what time it was
or even what day it was.
I thought I was the only one
that happened to.
How about we try it again for tonight?
I'll even lend you my watch.
Tonight? You and me?
Well, we could invite the Chess Club
but... they drink and start fights.
Oh, no, it's just... Well, I sort of heard
that... you and Cordelia were somewhat...
all over each other. A little.
I danced with her a couple of times.
She's... kinda grabby.
Well, let's see.
If I rearrange that and I push that to
Sure! Tonight'll work.
- Great. I'll pick you up at seven?
- Um...
- Seven.
- That's when the little hand's there.
Oh. Between the six and the eight.
I'll see you then.
Tonight. Isn't that so...
- What?
- Me and Owen.
Yeah. "So" it is.
It sure is "so".
- Hey! How's it goin'?
- All right.
That's great. I see we're still
workin' on that Anointed One problem.
That'll probably take you a few days,
right? I mean, that's one obscure prophecy.
Yes. Well, there are
quite a few interpretations.
So, tonight's lookin' pretty slow, right?
Probably best to relax and regroup.
No big disasters coming. That is so good!
I will see you tomorrow, then. Bye!
She is the strangest girl.
You have done well.
Everything is in place.
When this night's work is done,
I will have a mighty ally.
I'll be one step closer to freeing myself
from this... mystical prison.
I've been trapped down here so long,
I've nearly forgotten
what it's like on the surface.
Well, there'll be time enough to remember
when I rule it.
If she tries to stop you,
kill her.
Give your own lives,
but do not fail to bring the Anointed.
I know you won't disappoint me.
Bug.
- Pick.
- OK.
Do I want to appear shy, coy and naive
or unrestrained, insatiable and aggressive?
You know, Owen is a little homespun.
He probably doesn't like
that overly assertive look.
Oh, hey. Here's something.
A nice, comfy overcoat and a ski cap.
The earflaps'll bring out your eyes.
Maybe I should mix-and-match.
OK, guy's opinion.
Which do you think Owen will like better?
The red or the peach?
Oh, you mean for kissing you and then
telling all his friends how easy you are
so the whole school loses respect for you
and then talks behind your back?
- The red's fine.
- Thanks. I'll go with the peach.
Here. Put this on.
You're not botherin' me.
- So where is he taking you?
- Oh, I don't know.
Where do you suppose
young kids go on dates these days?
Well, I read somewhere once
that sometimes they go to movies.
Movies? Interesting.
And I saw on TV once
a bunch of people our age went to a party.
Wow! I never knew being a teenager
was so full of possibilities.
That's Owen.
- That's Giles.
- We need to talk.
Buffy's not home.
My calculations may not've been
as far off as I thought.
"Five die in van accident"?
"Out of the ashes of five
shall rise the one"
That's the prophecy. Five people have died!
In a car crash.
I know it doesn't quite follow,
but-but it's worth investigating. Look!
"Among the dead was Andrew Borba,
whom the police sought for questioning
in a double murder."
He may be the Anointed One.
The bodies were taken to
Sunnydale Funeral Home. We can...
- Giles, why do you want to hurt me?
- I beg your pardon?
Hey.
Uh... Hi.
- You have a date?
- Yes, but...
I'll return those
overdue books by tomorrow.
- You're not getting off that easily.
- Man, you really care about your work!
Uh... Owen?
Yeah, a couple of things about tonight.
Another date?
Don't you ever do anything else?
This is the first date! There's never been a date.
OK? This is my maiden voyage!
What, she doesn't like to dance?
Well, it's a little too late
to do anything about that.
Uh, you should probably know
that Buffy doesn't like to be kissed.
- Actually she doesn't like to be touched.
- Xander...
As a matter of fact,
don't even look at her.
- We don't even know if this is anything.
- No, we don't.
- And I haven't had a day off for a while.
- True.
And a cranky slayer is a careless slayer.
Buffy, maintaining
a normal social life as a slayer
is problematic at best.
This is the '90s -
the 1990s, in point of fact -
and I can do both. Clark Kent
has a job. I just wanna go on a date.
Well, I suppose it was a fairly slim lead.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
And I won't go far, OK?
If the apocalypse comes, beep me.
- Is everything cool?
- All set.
Yes, and you'll face
a pretty hefty fine in the morning.
Well, bye. Don't wait up.
Is something going on?
Probably not, no. I...
I suppose I'll just...
go to the funeral home in case.
Just see if anything comes up.
This is bad.
I wish it was just bad.
We should go along.
Yeah, you're right.
I don't trust that Owen guy.
It's the eyes. They're crazy.
Xander, we should go with Giles.
He could get in trouble.
Oh, he's gone! He's gonna be all right.
He's, like, Super Librarian. You know?
Everyone forgets, Willow,
that knowledge is the ultimate weapon.
(# Strong by Velvet Chain)
# I'll be right along
# 'Cause, baby, you're so strong
The thing about Emily Dickinson I love
is that she's just so incredibly morbid.
A lot of loss, a lot of death.
It gets me.
And a lot about bees, for some reason.
Did she have a tragic
and romantic life with a lot of bees?
Quiet. Kind of sequestered and uneventful.
Which I can really relate to.
I don't get out much.
- I don't get that.
- It's my fault.
I just find most girls pretty frivolous.
I mean, there's a lot more important
things in life than dating. You know?
Did I say something wrong?
No.
Come on.
# Baby, baby, I know
# it's always been so
# Physical love is, oh,
# so meaningful for you
It's weird.
- What is?
- You.
One minute you're right there.
I got you figured.
The next, it's like you're two people.
Really?
Which one do you like better?
I'll let you know.
# So strong
# Baby, I'm yours
# You know
# Because you're so
# So strong
Aren't there laws
against this sort of thing?
Owen?
Look at you here, all alone.
Cordelia, I'm here with Buffy.
Oh. OK. You wanna dance?
No, I'm still here with Buffy.
You are so good to help the needy.
Cordelia, Owen and I would like to be
alone right now, and for that to happen,
you would have to go
somewhere that's away.
Well, when you're ready
for the big leagues, let me know.
# You would suffer, suffer for me
Damn.
(# Treason by Velvet Chain)
# I have a window in my mind
# I can turn to look right through you
Are you having fun?
- Yeah. I almost feel like a girl.
# Won't cost you anything but time
# To see me feel...
Giles, it's us!
- What are you doing here?
- We saw two guys going in after you.
- Are they...?
- They are.
Listen, you should get to safety.
- Can you get out this window?
- I'm afraid not.
Look, I hate to state the obvious,
but this looks like a job for Buffy?
She has a beeping thing.
No phone, of course.
Look, we'll get her.
Just... hang in there.
Do hurry.
- You want something to eat?
- Sure. Just make it something fattening.
What a disgusting display!
Is that really appropriate behaviour
in a public forum?
I mean, I've never seen a girl
throw herself at a guy like that.
Oooh! Hello, salty goodness!
Pick up that phone. Call 911.
That boy is gonna need some serious oxygen
after I'm through with him.
- Buffy.
- Angel.
Why is this happening to me?
I was hoping I'd find you here.
- You were?
- There's serious stuff happening tonight.
- You need to be out there.
- No. Not you, too?
- What do you know?
- Prophecy, Anointed One, yada-yada-yada.
So you know. Fine.
I just thought I'd warn you.
Warn me?
See that guy over there at the bar?
- He came here to be with me.
- You're here on a date?
Yes! Why is it such a shock to everyone?
Here you go.
Oh.
Owen, this is Angel.
Angel, this is Owen,
who is my date.
Hey.
So, where do you know Buffy from?
Work.
- You work?
- Buffy!
Look at this. They show up everywhere.
- Interesting.
- You don't know the half of it.
- What's he doing here?
- I guess the same thing you're doing here.
Excuse me. What are any of you doing here?
Look, we gotta get to... Uhhhh.
We thought it'd be fun
if we made this a double date.
I didn't know you guys
were seeing each other.
Oh, yeah. Well, We knew
it would happen eventually.
So we figured, hey, why fight it?
And you guys are thinking double...?
'Cause of... the fun!
And you're here because of work?
Hey, maybe we should all
go somewhere together.
Gee, that's so nice of you to ask, but Owen
and I were, well, sort of... Owen and I.
You know what would be cool?
The Sunnydale Funeral Home.
I've always wanted to go there.
The funeral home?
Actually, that sounds kinda cool!
Do you think we could all sneak in?
We saw some guys in there before.
They seemed to be having fun.
Bite me.
Owen, I gotta go.
I thought we were going
to the funeral home.
No, you can't. I'll tell you what.
I'll be back in a little while.
Buffy...
What's the deal?
- D'you want to bail on me?
- No! No, no.
Remember when you said
I was like two different people?
Well, one of them has to go.
But the other one is having
a really, really good time
and will come back. I promise.
She's the strangest girl.
- Which way?
- The room's around back.
Damn it!
This is so cool!
Owen! You can't be here.
Oh, and you guys are allowed?
- Are we gonna see a dead body?
- Possibly several.
Guys, watch him.
Is she mad?
Oh, she just wants to make sure there are
no guards, so we don't get in trouble.
- Good thinkin'.
Giles?
- Giles!
- It is you. Oh, good.
What happened?
Two more of the Brethren
came in here. They came after me.
But I was more than a match for them.
- Meaning...?
- I hid.
But this chap was good enough
to bunk with me till they went away.
But were they here after you,
or was it that prophecy thing?
That's what we have to find out.
I don't know what these...
Brethren mean to do exactly.
Find the Anointed?
Or-or give him something, perhaps?
It's all very vague.
And the Anointed may be long gone.
- But he may not be.
- We must find out.
OK. I just need to get Owen and
the others out of harm's way first.
- Owen? You brought a date?
- I didn't bring him. He came.
Buffy, when I said you could
slay vampires and have a social life,
- I didn't mean at the same time.
- I know.
- I'll get rid of him.
- You can't make him go out there alone.
We don't know where the Brethren are.
- I'll just...
- No! No, Giles.
If he sees you, he's gonna have more
questions than he already does right now.
I'll... take care of it.
- Is everything OK?
- It is.
- And we'll be leaving?
- We're not done lookin' around yet.
No, he's right. So let's find a nice,
safe, fun room to look around in.
We tried the office here but it's locked.
No, it's not.
I don't think we'll find much in here.
- That's the plan.
- OK.
- What?
- I have to go now.
Um, to the bathroom.
I have to go to the bathroom.
If you hear anything, like a security guard
or something, just be really quiet.
And barricade the door.
- Eugh. Parts.
- Keep looking.
He must be here somewhere.
What are you guys doin'?
Uh, just in case.
Oh, my.
- Nothing.
- The Anointed must be gone.
I guess.
I mean, this is where they keep
all the dead bodies, right?
I read a lot about death, but
I've never really seen a dead body before.
Do they usually move?
I have been judged.
What's goin' on?
Oh, no.
He is risen in me!
He fills my head with song!
Pork and beans.
- Pork and beans!
- Gimme that!
I can smell you.
You're the chaff, unblessed.
I'll suck the blood from your hearts.
He says I may!
- He's in there!
- Go! Get out!
She'll be OK. Come on.
I think he's coming this way.
Oh, God, this is too much!
- What have you got?
- What?
- What did you bring? D'you've a stake?
- Oh, uh...
- Thank you.
- What should I do?
Buffy!
Somebody's gotta help Buffy.
Owen!
They told me about you
while I was sleeping.
Why does he hurt me?
Buffy?
No!
Did you see that?
He tried to bite me! What a sissy!
No!
Dead!
He was found wanting.
You killed my date!
- Buffy, Owen's...
- Just give her a sec.
You killed my date!
Your turn!
Does anyone have an aspirin, or sixty?
Owen.
What happened to that guy?
Oh.
We scared him away.
- Oh, good. 'Cause, y'know, I would've...
- I know.
Here.
I'm sure this isn't exactly
what you had in mind for our first date.
Yeah.
I was hoping maybe
we'd finish up at Ben & Jerry's.
- We still could.
- No. I think I'll just walk home.
Uh... Which way is home?
I'll get you there.
No. I'll go it alone.
We'll make sure he gets home safely.
- Buffy, if I might...
- Don't.
(# Let the Sun Fall Down by Kim Richey)
Did Owen say anything about me
on the way home?
You mean specifically about you?
Or generally in the area in the ballpark.
- Any sort of indication?
- Well, in that case, no.
But he was pretty incoherent
so we might have missed it.
- You think?
- No.
I knew it. I totally blew it last night.
No, see, what you need is a guy who
already knows your deepest, darkest secrets
and still says, 'Hey! I like that girl!'
- Someone like...
- Owen.
Well, this is our stop.
Hi.
This is going well.
I don't really know how to say this but
- about last night...
- You don't even have to.
- I'm sure you were pretty freaked out.
- Totally.
And I was wondering
when I could see you again.
That was my hopeful ear.
Could you repeat that?
I think you're the coolest.
- Really?
- Last night was incredible.
I never thought nearly getting killed
would make me feel so... alive!
So that's why you want to be with me?
Absolutely. When can we do
something like that again?
- Something like...?
- Like...
Walk downtown at three in the morning,
and pick a fight in a bar.
- How about tonight?
- Tonight would... be...
not a workable thing. Did I just say that?
Tomorrow then?
I'm free any night this week.
I'm not.
Please don't take this personally.
It's not you. It's me.
Right. It's you.
And I was kinda hoping
that maybe you and I could still be...
I get it.
You just wanna be friends.
That'd be nice.
Friends.
Yeah.
Great.
# The world will keep on turning
# It'll all be there
# come morning
- Yeah. Great.
# So tonight...
# Let the sun fall down
# all around you
- I was ten years old when my...
father told me
I was destined to be a watcher.
He was one, and his mother before him,
and I was to be next.
Were you thrilled beyond all measure?
No, I had very definite plans
about my future.
I was going to be a fighter pilot.
Or possibly a grocer.
But my father...
gave me a very tiresome speech
about... responsibility and sacrifice.
Sacrifice, huh?
He seems like a nice lad.
Yeah.
But he wants to be Danger Man.
You, Xander, Willow... You guys...
You guys know the score. You're careful.
Two days in my world
and Owen really would get himself killed.
Or I'd get him killed.
Or someone else.
I went to the funeral home
of my own free will.
- I should have been there.
- Buffy...
- I blew it.
- I have volumes of lore,
of prophecies, of predictions.
But I don't have an instruction manual.
We feel our way as we go along.
And, I must say,
as a slayer, you're doing...
pretty well.
Well, at least I did stop
that prophecy thing from coming true.
You did, handily.
No more Anointed One.
And I would imagine the Master,
wherever he is,
is having a fairly bad day himself.
"And in this time will come the Anointed,
and the Slayer will not know him."
"She will not stop him."
"And he will lead her
into Hell."
Welcome, my friend.
Subtitles by: Doreen Trenerry
Corrections by: UAR
...
www.tvsubtitles.net