Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Thanks for the relocate.
I perform better without an audience.
You were thinking, what,
a little helpless co-ed before bed?
You know very well, you eat this late...
you're gonna get heartburn.
Get it? Heartburn?
That's it?
That's all I get?
One lame-ass vamp with no appreciation
for my painstakingly thought-out puns.
I don't think the forces
of darkness are even trying.
I mean, you could make
a little effort here, you know?
Give me something to work with.
Watch your mouth, little girl.
You should know better
than to tempt the Fates that way.
Cos the Big Bad is back. And this time...
The Bronze is more fun this year, isn't it?
Cos of the gloating factor alone, you know.
We're all about college now.
We've got heady discourse.
No curfews, mom-and-popless hootenanny.
Co-ed dating prospects
who find townies sexy and dangerous.
- What, I can dream.
- Right.
So if college is so great, why are
we here and why is it more fun?
Because the Bronze is nice and familiar.
It's like a big, comfy blanky.
I was under the impression
that I was your big, comfy blanky.
You're my person blanky.
This is my place blanky.
With all the shock of the new,
it's nice to have one place
that you can come back to
where everything's predictable.
- Hello, all.
- Giles, trouble?
Oh, no, Buffy. Don't get up. Nothing like that.
I just, you know, I thought I'd drop by.
Latte, anyone? On me?
So much for your
"predictable blanky" theory, Will.
Sorry.
Splendid. Well, it's ages
since I've been to a gig.
Well, don't look that way.
I'm down with the new music.
And I have the albums to prove it.
Yes, but it's your cutting-edge
eight-tracks that keep you ahead.
Don't scoff. I've seen Giles' collection.
- He was an animal in his day.
- Thank you.
OK, why not? If the Stones
can still keep rolling, why can't Giles?
Exactly. I think it's brave that you're here.
Well, thank you, all.
You've made me feel right at home.
Well, isn't home that empty place
you're trying to escape?
Dip a finger in me
And paste my word...
- Oh, yeah. Veruca's playing tonight.
- Yeah, every Wednesday. I told you.
Let me be distraction
Let me be dream
So, Oz, what about Dingoes?
When are you guys here again?
Oh, we're up next Friday.
Dip a finger in me
They're good, aren't they?
Nothing special.
Yeah. She's quelle Fiona. Colour me bored.
Really? I think she's rather remarkable.
Such presence for someone her age.
I can feel you twist
I can feel you writhe
Because you're with me
It's in the sandblaster.
What's in the sandblaster, Will?
It's a dream. Come back to me.
All Geminis to the raspberry hats.
- Now you're fakin'.
- Am not.
Just a little.
- Morning.
- Bad dream?
- I guess.
But the waking-up part makes up for it.
It's always so busy in there.
Not always.
A few things shut my brain up completely.
Anything I can help you with?
I gotta get to class right now
but... tonight for sure.
I don't know about tonight, unless
the extreme Jerry Garcia look turns you on.
Night before the full moon.
Oh, that's right. And I have a thing.
There's this Wicca group on campus
I wanted to check out.
They have orientation
on the three nights you're wolfy.
And it's probably totally silly, but...
Well, go. Show 'em how it's done.
Are you sure? You can lock yourself up?
It's only this one month. After orientation
they meet on different nights.
I'll be fine.
OK. As long as you don't mind.
The only thing I mind
is being away from you for three nights.
Ms Summers, I want you to prepare
to lead a discussion group
next class on the paper topic.
- That was smart work.
- What do I have to do?
If you have any questions,
bring them up with one of the TAs.
Are you OK? How'd you do?
This is good. I mean, this is excellent.
You did better than me. This is so unfair.
You made me jealous of you
academically. Buffy!
I know. Can you believe it?
Wow. I guess Professor Walsh
isn't so ogrey after all.
And she wants me
to lead a discussion group next class.
That means more work, right?
Shouldn't she have a better reward system?
You know, like a cookie
or a toy surprise, like at the dentist?
She wants you to lead a discussion group?
OK. Jealous again.
Jealous, jealous... OK, I'm back.
Hey, I'm meeting Oz at the café.
You wanna come?
I'll buy you that celebratory cookie.
Great. I'm TA-bound now
and then I will catch up with you guys.
Cool.
What are you gonna do, sit on the ground?
- My girlfriend's comin'.
- There's room.
Big lunch.
I like to eat. I hate chicks who are, like,
"Does it have dressing on it?"
Agreed.
- You guys were tight last night.
- I guess.
- The amps still sound dirty to me.
- What are you using? 50 or 120?
- Hey.
Hey.
You wanna sit down?
So you should be using a 50. Blue Voodoo -
not your best bet unless you dig the distort.
Music talk, huh? Cool.
I love to listen to Oz talk about the biz.
What do you like again? I know you told me.
There's a couple of good ones.
The Johnson Mil.
- The No.1 is Redbone.
- No.1? No. I gotta go with Hound Dog.
Me too. That's a great song.
I mean, Elvis, what a guy.
- You a big Elvis fan?
- The biggest.
Well, I mean, after Dingoes, of course.
We're actually talking amps. But it's easy
to get confused, the names they give 'em.
You know, I gotta bail. I'll call you later.
I should go, too.
Good shirt.
Check out the rapid exits. Was it me?
Me. I don't speak musicianese.
How come you didn't tell me I look like
a crazy birthday cake in this shirt?
- I thought that was the point.
- He thinks she's sexy.
He gets this blushy thing
going on behind his ears.
- That's for me only.
- It doesn't mean anything.
So Oz checks out another girl. He loves you.
I know. I know. And I don't
wanna be the kind of girl
who freaks every time
my boyfriend notices somebody else.
I mean, I have wrong feelings
about other guys sometimes,
but I feel guilty and I flog and punish.
Exactly. I'm sure Oz
is flogging and punishing himself...
This is sounding wrong before I even finish.
Look, I promise you, in a couple of days
it's gonna be like "Veruca who?"
- You think?
- Absolutely.
Oz just isn't the type to stray.
Not tonight, anyways.
He'll be locked in a cage.
Hello?
Oh, God!
Morning.
That was some night.
So it appears.
Right. You don't remember.
It's like that at first, but then little bits
and pieces'll start coming back to you.
- So you're a...
- Werewolf groupie.
Nobody else gets it done for me.
- What?
- Kidding.
You know what I am.
You've known
since the first time you saw me.
Now, you...
need to relax.
Not a possibility.
So what do you wanna do?
God!
The kids in this dorm
need Fashion 101 in a big way.
Or we could start right here at home.
I'm not making a statement.
Just wanna get back to my place,
figure out why we got out of our cages.
- You have a cage?
- Don't you?
Yeah. It has a little wheel with
a plastic ball and a cute little bell in it.
God! Somebody's domesticated
the hell out of you.
It's my choice. I don't wanna hurt anybody.
Maybe. Or maybe you just don't
wanna admit what happened to you.
Maybe you just wanna pretend
like you're a regular guy.
Well, I am.
I'm only a wolf three nights a month.
You're the wolf all the time,
and this human face is just your disguise.
You ever think about that, Oz?
I'm going to check the paper,
see if we did any damage last night.
We did.
But only to each other.
I know some part of you remembers that.
It doesn't take a full moon.
We could do it again...
right here.
We aren't going to.
This ends right now.
I can help you, Oz.
You're scared. I was, too.
But then I accepted it, the animal.
It's powerful.
Inside me all the time. Soon you just
start to feel sorry for everybody else
because they don't know what
it's like to be as alive as we are.
As free.
Free to kill people?
I won't do that.
You shouldn't.
You don't understand.
But you will.
You'll see that we belong together.
No. I know where I belong.
See ya tonight.
Two of them. It was unbelievable.
The fact that I survived at all is a miracle.
Excuse me, Ms Walsh.
Be careful when you walk
around campus after dark.
- I was attacked by wild dogs last night.
- Wild dogs?
- Two.
- Biggest things I've ever seen.
The first one was... well, for a moment
I thought it was a gorilla.
Did you have a question, Buffy?
No. No, I was just sayin' howdy.
Fine. See you in class.
Yeah?
- Hey.
- New look.
- You too.
Laundry day kinda came and went.
Hey, I'm sorry if I was weird yesterday
with you and Veruca.
I didn't notice anything.
Really? Cos I felt all spazzy.
No.
Good. Guess it was just me
worrying for nothin' again.
Me and my busy head,
always thinkin', thinkin', thinkin'.
Well, now you can stop. Everything's fine.
Maybe you could help me stop.
I'd really, really appreciate
anything you could do.
What? What's wrong?
Sorry, I...
- You don't want to?
- It's not that. I do. I just...
I didn't get any sleep, I guess.
I'm really beat.
Right.
Busy wolf night. I get it.
It's totally OK.
- Willow, you don't have to...
- No, I should. I don't have much time.
I'll see you later.
..treaty of 1648
that ended the Thirty Years' War?
- Peace of Westphalia.
- Yalta?
- You moron!
- That's incorrect.
That dinette set should be mine.
Buffy! Excellent! Come in.
- Hi.
- Can I get you anything? Tea?
I made a very interesting moussaka
last night, if you're hungry.
Pass on the tea. And the... moose, thank you.
- You come on business, I hope?
- Yes. Lucky you, people may be in danger.
- I only meant that I'm at the ready.
- Here's the deal.
One of my professors said that she was
almost attacked by two wild dogs last night
under the light of a nearly full moon.
- Werewolves. Two of them?
- Could be.
Well, I've not seen anything about
the attacks in the newspapers or on the news.
- Have you spoken with Oz?
- My next stop.
Right. Get right on it.
I'll see what I can find out.
- And you report back to me.
- ASAP. Promise.
- Hey, Will. Mom let you in?
- She seemed cranky.
Yeah. We're having a little landlord-tenant
dispute, so I'm withholding rent.
An effective, and might I add, thrifty tactic.
- Why?
- She won't let me put a lock on my door.
I suspect she's afraid
I'll start having "the sex".
Yeah. Parents wait
till you're out of the house.
- Or under it.
- Or under it,
to start worrying about stuff like that.
It's mostly too late.
So, I know why I'm sitting in a dank,
sunless little room. But why are you?
Well, things with Oz are weird.
And I talked to Buffy about it,
but I think we're in guyville here.
I need a translator from the "Y" side of things.
Well, last time I checked,
I had the creds. Hit me.
What does it mean
when a girl wants to... you know...
If you're doing it,
I think you should be able to say it.
- Make love.
- Wild monkey love
or tender Sarah McLachlan love?
Any kind. But what if the girl wants to
and the guy doesn't?
- That's a bad sign, right?
- Could be.
Or she caught him in one of the seven
annual minutes he's too preoccupied to do it.
- Well, say the girl's been noticing...
- Will, I've deciphered your ingenious code.
OK. Say I've been noticing
Oz notice someone else.
- A woman.
- And is this chick noticing back?
Most definitely.
Well... have you asked Oz about it?
Well, I thought about it, but then
he'll think I'm all jealous and worry.
But you are. And odds are, he feels it.
I'll bet that's all there is
to the weird you're feeling.
You guys should talk things out, Will.
You'll both feel better.
Hey.
- Got out, huh?
- Yeah.
- Any news about attacks?
- No.
But I did hear about a woman
being chased by two wild dogs.
Two? Really?
You don't remember anything
like that, do you? Another wolf?
No. When the change comes,
it's like... I'm gone. Total blackout.
Well, if I find werewolf No.2 out on patrol
tonight, you might have a roomie in there.
Oz?
Oz, are you OK?
And if it's possible,
you seem more monosyllabic than usual.
I'm OK. Thanks.
I step out of my skin
You wouldn't know me now
Couldn't you go away?
Shouldn't I?
Leave me the hard part
It's all I want
I need
I won't be
Your soft one
I won't be encircled
You might become
Something I need
To destroy
So this is why you called me here?
To see your Habitrail?
Right before sunset,
I get a little buzzed, you know?
Come here.
I'm not getting in that stupid cage with you,
if that's what this is all about.
We belong outside.
You can't run loose tonight. And not
just because you might hurt somebody.
I know people that'll be
out there, hunting for us.
So you're saying I should spend
the whole night with you.
Alone. Locked in a cage.
You'll be safe.
Not from you.
Isn't that the point
of this cosy little arrangement?
It's coming. Do you feel it?
- It's like blood boiling.
- I feel it.
I've wanted you even before I ever saw you.
I sensed you. Did you sense me?
- Come in here.
- Did you?
- Willow.
- Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
I know what you saw. It wasn't...
I had to. I had to lock her in there with me.
I bet.
She's like me. A wolf.
Well, I knew you two
had a lot in common, but...
Don't touch me!
She was gonna hurt somebody.
I didn't have a choice.
But you did. You could've told somebody.
Your solution... just put you two
together in a room all night?
- Girl's got a point.
- Leave.
- I'm just sayin'...
- Now!
- I'm sorry.
- I knew.
I knew, you jerk.
And you sat there
and you told me everything was fine?
And that's as bad as... as...
I know how it feels. I remember.
So, what, this is payback? I had this coming?
- No, it's not...
- Because I thought that was behind us.
And you know, what happened with Xander,
it doesn't compare.
Not with what you and I had. Not with
whatever you've been doing with her.
I don't know what Veruca and I have done.
When I change, it's like...
it's like I'm gone and the wolf takes over.
But before this, when you were regular Oz,
you had feelings for her, didn't you?
No. I could sense something, but...
But you wanted her.
Like, in an animal way?
Like, more than you wanted me?
Willow!
- Willow, are you OK?
- Thank you. I was too far away.
It was lucky. She almost got hit.
Willow, what's the matter?
Maybe you should take her home.
Whatever it is,
it's not worth hurting yourself over.
I have to go.
I have to find Veruca before the sun sets.
I will, though.
When I do, this thing stops. She's bad news.
Do you want me to get you
something before I take off?
Kleenex?
Chocolaty... chocolate anything?
No.
I'll come back as soon as this is finished.
I just want you to take it easy, OK?
Riley was right.
The main thing is
put the blame where it belongs.
- Don't hurt yourself.
- OK.
OK.
- You're OK?
- I'm fine. I promise.
I love you.
"Put the blame where it belongs."
So you haven't seen her around?
OK. Thanks, man.
- Where is she?
- I don't know. I checked all the usual haunts.
But I know the areas we're drawn to.
I'm sure I can follow her scent.
- We'll try that, then.
- Look, Buffy, you should know that...
Oz. Now might be a good time
for your trademark stoicism.
I conjure thee...
by Borabis, by Satanis and the devil.
As thou art burning, let Oz and Veruca's
deceitful hearts be broken.
This way!
I conjure thee, by the Saracen Queen
and in the name of Hell.
Let them find no love or solace.
Let them find no peace as well.
She's near here.
I can smell her.
Or the dirty pile of clothing
she left on the ground.
They could be from the other night
when she turned into a werewolf.
Unless she wanted to throw you off the scent.
Willow!
Let this image seal his fate.
Not to love, only hate.
For a minute I thought
you might actually play rough.
Sometimes you have to, you know?
To keep what's yours,
sometimes you have to kill.
Well, how about that?
The sun's almost down.
Can't say I'm surprised
you didn't go through with your little hex.
- You don't have the teeth.
- You don't know what I have.
- You don't know anything about me.
- I know what you love.
I have his scent on me right now.
- Don't touch her again.
- Come stop me.
I like it rough, remember?
You wanna hurt me, hurt me.
You leave her out of this.
How can I? She's the reason
you're living in cages.
She's blinding you. When she's gone,
you'll be able to admit what you are.
You don't wanna find out what I am.
You're an animal.
Animals kill.
You're right.
We kill.
Oz?
I'm not quite sure I understand.
There was just so much
going on with Oz and Willow.
There still is.
But I just thought you should know.
This fellow in the woods,
he was in military garb?
And he was toting some serious weaponry.
The thing is, I saw some guys dressed
exactly like him on Halloween night.
I just assumed they were in costume.
- But maybe they were working.
- I wanna know what's up.
The guy got in my way.
I almost didn't catch up with Oz in time.
- And as it was, I was too late to...
- You saved Willow.
Right now she wishes I hadn't.
Giles, I've never seen her like this.
It's like it hurts too much to form words.
You've felt that way yourself
and you got through it.
Yeah. I ran away and went to hell
and then got through it.
- I'm hoping she doesn't use me as a model.
- Fair enough.
I just don't know
how they're gonna deal with this.
Hello.
Hi.
What are you doing?
I'm going.
Now?
- That's your solution?
- That's my decision.
- Don't I get any say in this?
- No.
Veruca was right about something.
The wolf is inside me all the time.
And I don't know where that line
is any more, between me and it.
And until I figure out what that means,
I shouldn't be around you.
Or anybody.
Well, that could be a problem.
Cos people... kind of a planetary epidemic.
I'll find someplace.
Well, how long?
I don't know.
Oz,
don't you love me?
My whole life...
I've never loved anything else.
Oh, God. Oz.
Visiontext Subtitles: Julie Clayton
ENGLISH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org