- Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
- We had to hide the Key.
Made it human and sent it to you.
Dawn? Did you know your sister took
my Key? And she won't give it back.
- I bet you know where she put it.
- She doesn't know.
OK, let's see who you are.
The Knights of Byzantium, an ancient order.
And now your enemy.
So long as you protect the Key,
the brotherhood will never stop
until we destroy it and you.
Look at you. All afraid I'm hot for your honey.
- Because you are.
- Well...
yeah.
- Tell me what kind of demon I'm fighting.
- Glory isn't a demon.
- What is she?
- She's a god.
Mom wants to make with the merry tomorrow
night, but with everything that's going on...
This is exactly what you need:
a 20th-birthday party with presents,
and funny hats,
and those candles that don't blow out.
- Those used to scare me.
- Me too.
I don't think this is
the best time for the party pinata.
We need to stay focused to stop Glory.
We're goin' up against a god,
an actual mightier-than-thou god.
- Well, the bigger they are...
- The faster they stomp you into nothing.
She's right. I've thrown everything I've got
at her. She just shrugs it off.
- Then find something heavier to throw.
- That might pose some difficulty.
From what the Council's discovered
from the Book of Tarnis and other sources,
Glory and two fellow Hell gods
ruled over one of the more seriously
unpleasant demon dimensions.
- There's more than one?
- There are thousands. All different.
All pushing at our reality,
trying to find a way in.
I guess Glory found one.
The question is, why?
There's nothing to indicate that here. Just
vague references to chaos and destruction.
OK, so we know where Glory's from.
What do we know about her?
She's tough,
but no bolts of lightning, no blasts of fire.
- Shouldn't a god be able to do that?
- Usually, yes.
But being in human form must
be severely limiting her powers.
No, all we have to worry about right now
is she's immortal, invulnerable and insane.
A crazy Hell god?
And the fun just keeps on leavin'.
From what I can gather, her living in this
world is seriously affecting her mental state.
She's only been able to keep her mind
intact by extracting energy from us.
Well, from the human brain.
She's a brain-sucker?
She "absorbs the energies that bind
the human mind into a cohesive whole."
- Once drained, all that's left is...
- Crazy people.
Which is why there's been an increase in the
ranks of the mentally unstable in Sunnydale.
At least vampires just kill you.
We have to find a way to stop her.
Well, Tara and I can work
on some tactical spells.
I can do some research. I know way more
about demon dimensions than Giles does.
Well, I do.
This is great long-term-planny stuff, but what
about this Key thingy Glory's lookin' for?
Yeah. Shouldn't we try
to find it before she does?
I don't think we should worry about that.
They've got a point. Whatever Glory's
planning on opening with the Key,
I'm guessing it won't be filled
with candy and flowers.
So where should we look? Do we know
where it used to be kept? Who saw it last?
We did. Giles and me.
We know where it is.
- You what?
- You know, and you didn't tell us?
There were reasons.
Look, if Glory knew that
you guys knew where it was...
I didn't wanna put you in that kind of danger.
As opposed to the other kind
we're always in?
- You should've said something.
- Will, there...
You're right.
- It's time.
- Are you sure?
They'll be risking their lives.
They deserve to know.
Know what?
There's something that you
need to know... about Dawn.
The link must be severed.
Such is the will of God.
The Key is the link. The link must be severed.
You really think He is going to help you?
I fear your faith is gravely misplaced.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Shall we test your faith now?
Never send a minion to do a god's work.
Hey, nice sword.
Bet it hurts.
- You guys doin' a spell?
- Dawn, hey.
Yeah, we're doing
an early-warning incantation.
If anything Hell-godishly powerful
comes within 100ft of the shop,
then screechy siren things
will, you know, screech.
This should give us a heads-up
so we can hide the... Key.
We already put one up around your house.
Cool. Can I help?
I don't think Buffy would like the black arts
bumpin' auras with the littlest Summers.
Yeah. Whatever.
How can she not be real?
She's real. She's just kinda... new.
Hey. We on the case?
Yeah. Right on top, perched, ready for action.
How's my sweet fancy Dawn doin'?
Fine.
What's up with you?
Did you get into the sugar again?
You make a very pretty little girl.
- Anya, you wanna help me with that thing?
- Xander needs help with his thing!
I'm not sure our regular workout
is challenging you any more.
- Perhaps we should make it harder.
- You always think harder is better.
Maybe next time I patrol I should carry a load
of bricks and use a stake made of butter.
Very amusing. I'm sure Dawn feels
that way about her schoolwork sometimes.
That true? How was school today?
The usual: big square building
filled with boredom and despair.
Just how I remember it.
So, what's the homework sitch?
We imagine what we'll be like in ten years
and write a letter to our future self.
The teacher's so out of ideas. Wanna help?
Maybe later.
I have some stuff I have to do first.
- About the weird girl that came to the house?
- Glory. And no, it's not.
Like you'd tell me anyway.
Dawn's too young and too delicate.
Right. A young, delicate pain in my butt.
I think you're freakin' out cos you have to
fight someone prettier. That's the case, right?
Glory is evil and powerful.
And in no way prettier than me.
I think you're getting soft in your advanced
age. She didn't look that tough to me.
OK. One more time.
Just between me and you,
our itsy-bitsy little secret.
Where is the Key?
Even if I knew, I'd die
a thousand deaths before I'd tell you.
Well, you won't need a thousand, sweetie.
I'll make the first one last. Long time.
What is it with you religious types?
It's intimacy, isn't it?
You're just scared of letting someone in!
It's OK.
I know how difficult the first time can be.
You don't have to be afraid.
Just relax.
You may not have the info I want...
but you still got somethin' I need.
- Prezzies!
- See? Just what you needed.
You are very, very wise.
Now gimme, gimme, gimme.
This is extremely suspenseful.
I want the presents.
It's beautiful. Thank you, guys.
We thought you'd get
crossbows and killy stuff.
So we figured, less killy, more frilly.
It's just so lovely!
Oh, I wish it was mine!
Like you weren't all thinking the same thing.
I'm fairly certain I wasn't.
I've got one just like it.
Here. Open mine.
It's not gonna explode, is it?
It's when we visited Dad
that summer in San Diego.
I put the shells on it myself.
We picked them off the beach.
I remember.
Well, jeez, don't get all movie-of-the-week.
I was just too cheap
to buy you a real present.
Thank you.
It still seems there's a lot you don't know
about this. I mean, is she dangerous?
No.
I assume you're talking about her existence
rather than her intentions?
Exactly.
Dawn? What are you doing in there?
Party getting slow?
We need plates. It's cake time.
Why does everybody act
all weird when I'm around?
Me? Me not weird.
I'm not an idiot.
I know you're talking about me.
- No. No, we really weren't.
- We were talking about sex.
They were talking about me, like everybody.
Again, not so much. In fact, none.
We were talking about sex. You know us -
sometimes we like to pretend stuff.
- Anya...
- Like, there's a fireman, or a shepherd...
You know what? Let's not have
this exchange of images now.
Oh, right. Of course.
Can't let Dawn hear anything.
Fine. I'm just gonna go to bed. That way,
I won't accidentally get exposed to... words.
Cake?
- Jeez! Lurk much?
- I wasn't lurkin'.
I was standin' about.
It's a whole different vibe.
What is...
Are you giving Buffy a birthday present?
Oh, my God. Weird.
And chocolates? Lame.
And the box is all bent. And, well, you know
she'd never touch anything from you anyway.
Shouldn't you be tucked away
in your beddy-bye?
All warm and safe
where nothing can eat you?
Is that supposed to scare me?
- Little tremble wouldn't hurt.
- Sorry, it's just...
Come on, I'm badder than you.
- Are not!
- Am too.
You're in the bushes hugging
a bent box of chocolates, and I'm...
What? Sneaking out to braid hair
and watch Teletubbies with your mates?
No.
I'm breaking into the magic shop.
To steal things.
Magic shop, eh?
All number of beasties
between here and there.
Bet they'd really go for
a Little Red Riding Hood like you.
That wouldn't sit too well with big sister.
I can take care of myself.
- You wanna come steal some stuff?
- Yeah, all right.
- Do you know how to do that or not?
- Give us a sec.
I usually just burst through doors.
That's right! Who's bad now?
Girl with a mission, eh? What's the caper?
Jewels? Ancient artefacts? Orjust
plain hard cash liberated from the till?
A book.
All this for a book?
I don't want the book, just what's inside.
I think it was Giles's notes.
He was standing here,
and when I turned around it was gone.
Where did he learn to write
so bloody small? From a fruit fly?
Wait. Here's something.
"Tarnis, 12th century."
"One of the founders
of the Monks of the Order of Dagon."
"Their sole purpose appears
to have been as protectors of the Key."
Brown-robe types always protect something.
It's the only way
they can justify giving up girls.
Troll hammer.
Didn't go with my stuff anyway.
"The Key is not directly described in
any literature, but all research indicates
an energy matrix vibrating at a dimensional
frequency beyond human perception."
"Only those outside reality
can see the Key's true nature."
"Outside reality." What's that mean?
Second-sight blokes, mostly.
Or even just your run-of-the-mill lunatics.
You don't belong here.
- There! There's no one in there.
- I know what you are.
What else does it say about this Key?
Is it made out of gold?
Maybe we can hock it, split the take.
"The Key is also susceptible
to necromanced animal detection,
particularly those of canine
or serpent construct."
"The monks possessed the ability
to transform energy, bend reality."
Blah, blah, blah.
Good Lord, Giles writes
as dull as he talks, doesn't he?
"They started work,
but the Council has suggested
to us that they were interrupted."
"Presumably by... Glory."
"They obviously did manage
to accomplish the taste..."
"accomplish the task."
"They had to be certain the Slayer
would protect it with her life,
so they sent the Key to her in human form."
"In the form of a sister."
I guess that's you, niblet.
- Not even a card, huh?
- I wasn't really expecting one.
No contact with civilians.
There's probably a code name for it.
You know, like "radio silence".
It's "greeting-card silence".
- Sorry.
- Maybe it's time to start a new tradition:
birthdays without boyfriends.
It could be just as much fun.
- Preachin' to the choir here, baby.
- Yeah. Some of my best...
Oh, my God.
Is this blood?
- Dawn!
- Oh, baby.
- What did you do?
- This is blood, isn't it?
It can't be me. I'm not a key.
- I'm not a thing.
- Oh, sweetie, no. What is this all about?
What am I?
Am I real? Am I anything?
- If you need anything...
- Thanks.
Perhaps I should stay.
You know, just in case.
This is a family thing.
We should deal with this.
OK.
Why didn't you tell me?
We were going to. I just...
We thought it would be better
if we waited until you were older.
- How old am I now?
- You're 14, sweetheart. You know that.
No. The monks, when did...
When did...
Six months ago.
I've only been alive for six months, huh?
You've been alive a lot longer than that to us.
You don't know that.
You don't know anything.
I'm just a key, right?
Everything about me is made up.
Dawn...
Mom and I know what we feel.
I know I care about you.
I know that I worry about you.
You worry about me because you have to.
I'm yourjob. Protect the Key, right?
I worry because my sister is cutting herself!
Yeah? How do you know? Maybe this is just
another fake memory from my fake family.
Sweetheart.
- Get out.
- Dawn.
Get out, get out, get out!
We need answers, Giles.
We need to find out
everything we can about the Key.
- What's it for, who created it...
- And why Glory has a girl-god jones for it.
This isn't about her. It's about Dawn.
She deserves to know where she came from.
She needs to know, or it will eat away at her.
How did she find these?
How did she get in here in the...
Who's been using
the Urn of Ishtar as an ashtray?
Morning, sunshine. If you've come round
for eggs and sausage, I'm fresh out.
Hey, careful! These are wet.
How could you let her find out like that?
From books and papers?
You hate me that much?
I was just along for the ride. Not like
I knew she was mystical glowy Key thing.
Nobody keeps me in
the bloody loop, do they?
- You could have stopped her.
- Oh, yeah, here it comes.
Something goes wrong in your life,
blame Spike.
News flash, blondie.
If kid sis wants to grab a midnight stroll,
she'll find a way sooner or later.
I just thought she'd be safer
with Big Bad lookin' over her shoulder.
She shouldn't have found out like that.
You didn't think you could
keep the truth from her for ever?
Maybe if you had been more honest with her,
you wouldn't be trying to make yourself
feel better with a round of Kick The Spike.
Honey?
You're gonna be late for school.
I'm not going.
Blobs of energy don't need an education.
You want me to make some soup?
I think there's some chicken and stars.
I'm not sick!
- I'm not anything.
- Honey, calm down, OK?
Don't tell me what to do.
You're not my mother.
I changed my mind. I'd rather be at school.
All right, fellas.
Today we've got blues, greens and...
Oh, hey, chartreuse. It's a party.
It won't stick.
The birds have been pecking too hard.
- Byzantium.
- Yes, they've arrived.
Unfortunate, but not completely unexpected.
- How many?
- Their numbers are few for the moment.
But they'll grow.
The Knights of Byzantium are like ants:
first you see one, then two...
then the picnic's ruined.
No matter how many we kill,
they'll keep coming. Wave after wave.
It's time to set old animosities aside.
Your fate is directly linked
to Her Magnificently-Scented Glorificus.
She's been extremely forgiving of
your considerable foibles up until now,
but if you persist in your defiance,
she'll be forced to...
To what? What is she going to do?
Send a six-pack of minions to bore me
to death? Glory can't lay a finger on me.
You know it, I know it, she knows it.
So save the threats, or I'll finish
the job I started on your head.
We can'tjust let her sit up there all alone.
She needs time.
We can't force her to be all right with this.
That's your answer? Just leave her alone
and hope that everything works itself out?
No. But if I were her,
I'd want a little bit of time right now.
I wouldn't want my mother and
my sister coming at me from all sides.
Her school called today. She was suspended.
She yelled at a teacher. The things she said,
Buffy. She's never used language like that.
She probably feels like she can
say or do anything right now.
She's not real. We're not her family.
We don't even know what she is.
- How can you talk as if she's a thing?
- I'm not!
I'm just saying
that's probably how she feels.
Then we have to show her that it isn't true.
She needs to know
she's still a part of this family.
It's not that simple!
We're not gonna be able to fix this
with a hug and a kiss and a bowl of soup.
Dawn needs to know where she came from.
She needs real answers.
What she needs is her sister,
Buffy, not the Slayer.
The Slayer is the only thing standing between
Dawn and this god from the bitch dimension
that wants to shove her in a lock
and give her a good twirl!
Mom, I need to be out there...
Oh, my God. Glory. It's Willow's spell.
Wait. It's not Glory.
Damn it.
Dawn!
- Buffy.
- No! She could've burned the house down!
Buffy, she's gone.
She tore up her room.
She burned all of her diaries.
The Dawnmeister Chronicles?
She's been keeping those since...
I mean...
Since she was seven. I remember too, Will.
We have to find her. Fast.
Before Glory or the Knights
of Hack and Slash figure out what...
who she really is.
Mom will stay at home in case she shows up.
I figure we split up and sweep the city.
Anya, stay here in case she shows up.
Xander, Giles, take the centre of town.
Willow, Tara, west side.
Spike, you and I'll get the east side.
Just find her. Please.
- Bet you can't push me all the way around!
- Oh, yes, I can!
No, you can't!
There are so many things I remember.
Seeing Dawn. Hangin' with her.
Listening to Buffy complain about her.
Mostly that last one.
- How could all that never really happen?
- It takes some getting used to,
the idea of a bright 14-year-old actually
being living energy thousands of years old.
I'm guessing some kind
of super-powerful in her raw form.
People have killed, died for it,
summoned armies to control the Key.
You know,
she kinda has a crush on me.
Your point being?
Oh, nothing, no.
Just sayin'. Powerful being,
big-energy gal digging the Xan-man.
Some guys are just cooler, you know?
Dawn!
- Dawn!
- That should do it.
- Shut up.
- She scampered off to get away from you.
She hears you bellowing, she'll pack it in
the opposite direction. Can't say I blame her.
You were right.
This is my fault. I should've told her.
She probably would've skipped off
anyway, even if she never found out.
She's notjust a blob of energy.
She's also a 14-year-old hormone bomb.
Which one's screwing her up more
right now, spin the bloody wheel.
You'll find her, just in the nick of time.
That's what you hero types do.
You'll find her.
And then what?
It's here. It's here. It's here.
Can't stop.
It's here. It's here.
Make it stop. The skin's too tight.
Can't hear it. What's the frequency?
Empty. All spilled out.
Please.
You see me, right?
- Look at me.
- Can't stop!
You know what I am, don't you?
You all know.
- Can't hear it, can't hear it, can't hear it...
- Tell me!
- Can't hear it, can't hear it, can't...
- What am I?
The Key.
I found it. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Thank...
You know what the Key is?
Where did I come from?
Who made me? What am I?
Thank you. Thank you.
- Please!
- Destroyer! Cracked earth and bones.
The sun bleeding into the sky!
The Key is the link. The link must be severed.
Such is the will of God.
Two cups of chocolate goodness, courtesy of
whoever I swiped it from out of the cupboard.
Couldn't find marshmallows.
I'll try to steal some for next time.
- Don't like 'em anyway.
- What? Is that even possible?
Too squishy. When I was five, Buffy
told me they were monkey brains and I...
Dawn, was your mom brought back in?
Is that why you're here?
No. My mom's just fine.
- Is there anybody I can call? Your sister?
- I don't have a sister.
You two have a fight?
It's OK, I know how that goes.
I got a sister, too.
They can be a real pain sometimes, huh?
I tell you, there have been a lot
of nights I wish she didn't exist either.
It's not Buffy. It's me.
I'm the one that doesn't exist.
I know it feels that way sometimes,
but when you're older...
No. You don't understand.
- It's not real, none of this. They made it.
- Dawn...
I'm nothing! I'm just a thing the monks made
so Glory couldn't find me. I'm not real.
- You're the Key?
- How do you know about the Key?
Go! Before she finds you. Don't ask me how
she knows, cos she always knows. Just go.
- Calm down.
- You don't understand, you're a kid.
You stay, she'll find you.
She finds you, she'll hurt you.
- What's wrong with you?
- You're what she's been searching for. Run.
You don't know. You...
Oh, no. Oh, God, no. She's coming.
I can feel it. You've gotta get out. No...
Oh, no, she's here!
She's here!
Hey, don't I know you?
Cotton!
Could a fabric be
more annoyingly pedestrian?
Now, this is what I'm talkin' about.
Makes your skin sing.
You're... You're Ben.
It's an eensy more complicated than that.
Family always is, isn't it?
You'd never make it. I'd rip out
your spine before you got half a step.
And those little legs? They wouldn't
be much good without one of those.
Would they, Dawnie?
Now, what I'm trying to noodle,
is what in the world was the Slayer's
little sis doin' here with Gentle Ben?
- You don't remember?
- Remember what?
You were talking to him, not me.
Oh, he wasn't being naughty, was he?
Excuse me, ma'am.
This area's for hospital personnel.
Rude. I was talking.
What do you say
we find a nice place off the beaten
where you and I can have
a long uninterrupted chat?
- We looked, but no Dawn.
- What about the carousel?
- Checked there, too.
- Nothing?
Sorry, Buff.
Anything could have happened to her.
Notjust Glory.
I better check the hospital.
OK. Small talk over. I'm in a bit of a crunch,
so let's cut right to the ooey-gooey centre.
Your sister, the Slayer, has my Key.
It's mine, I want it.
Do you know where she squirrelled it away?
There's ice cream and puppy dogs
in it for you if you start singin'.
I'm not sure. What does it look like?
Well, the last time I caught a peep...
it was a bright green swirly shimmer.
Really brought out the blue in my eyes.
But then those monks pulled an abracadabra,
so it could be anything. See my predicament?
Maybe.
Yes?
Well, maybe if you told me more about it...
I'd know if I've seen it.
OK.
- She wasn't brought in.
- Which is a happy thing, right?
- I don't know, I...
- ..in the break room.
You guys gotta see him.
His head's almost twisted clean off.
Glory.
So this Key thing...
it's been around for a long time?
Well, not as long as me,
but yeah, just this side of for ever.
- Is it evil?
- Totally.
Well, no, not really.
I guess it depends on your point of view.
What's it for? I mean...
if it's a key, there's gotta be a lock, right?
Yes. We have a winner.
So what does it open?
I smell a fox in my hen house.
Is that why you were playing with Uncle Ben,
to get a peek at Glory's unmentionables?
No. I...
I kinda wanna hear me talking right now.
Me talking.
You know what I'm starting to think?
I'm thinking that maybe you...
don't have any idea where my Key is.
Very irritating, irrational. You know
what I mean, tiny snapdragon? Like...
Like bugs under my skin.
And say... I'm feeling a little...
What's wrong with you?
Hey, this doesn't have to be
a complete waste of my precious time.
I've been meaning
to send the Slayer a message.
And I could use a little pick-me-up.
Two birds, one stone, and...
boom!
You have yummy dead birds.
Get away from my sister.
- Hey, we were just talking about you!
- Conversation's over, hell bitch.
I thought you said this skank was tough.
If he wakes up,
tell your boyfriend to watch his mouth.
He is not my boyfriend.
Hey, those are really nice shoes.
Giles, now!
Oh, please. Like that's gonna...
Watch the hair.
Time to start the dying.
Start with the whelp.
Dawn!
- Buffy!
- Get back!
Nice catch. Is that the best
you crap-gnats can muster?
Cos I gotta tell you, so not impressed.
Look what you did to my dress, you little...
Discede!
Willow!
Dawn.
- What did you do to her?
- Teleportation spell.
- Still working out the kinks.
- Where'd you send her?
Don't know. That's one of the kinks.
Oh, sh...
That was an incredibly dangerous
spell for an adept at your level.
Yep. Won't be trying that one again soon.
Are you OK? Did she hurt you?
Why do you care?
Because I love you. You're my sister.
No, I'm not.
Yes, you are.
Look, it's blood.
It's Summers blood.
It's just like mine.
It doesn't matter where you came from,
or how you got here.
You are my sister.
There's no way you could
annoy me so much if you weren't.
I was so scared.
Me too.
Come on.
Wait.
Ben. He was here.
He was trying to help me. He...
I...
I think he might have left before Glory came.
I can't remember.
It's OK. Don't worry about it.
Next time we see him, we'll thank him.
I have to get you back home, though.
Mom's freaking out.
Is she mad about the whole fire thing?
I think you sorta have a "Get Out of Jail Free"
card on account of big love and trauma.
Really?
OK. Good.
- You think she'd raise my allowance?
- Don't push it.
Visiontext Subtitles: Adrian Isaac
ENGLISH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org