In every generation, there is a Chosen One,
She alone will stand against the vampires,
the demons and the forces of darkness,
She is the Slayer.
Come on, Stephan, rise and shine. Some
of us have a ton of trig homework waiting.
Hey.
- Is this a bad time?
- Are you crazy?
You don't just sneak up
on people in a graveyard.
You make noise when you walk.
You stomp or... yodel.
- I heard you were on the hunt.
- I'm supposed to be, but...
lazybones here
doesn't wanna come out and play.
When you first wake up,
it's a little disorienting. He'll show.
It's weird to think of
you going through that.
It's weird to go through.
So, uh, you're here alone?
Yeah. Why?
I just thought you'd have
somebody with you.
- Xander, or someone.
- Xander?
- Or someone.
- Nope.
Why? Are you jealous?
- Of Xander? Please! He's just a kid.
- Is it 'cause I danced with him?
"Danced with" is a pretty loose term.
"Mated with" might be a little closer.
Don't you think
you're being a little unfair?
It was... one little dance, which...
I only did to make you crazy.
By the way, behold my success.
- I am not jealous!
- You are not jealous.
- What, vampires don't get jealous?
- See? Whenever we fight,
- you always bring up the vampire thing.
- Well, I didn't come here to fight!
Oh, right, I did!
- Where's my stake? I know I had a stake!
- I didn't see a stake.
What d'you mean, he's just a kid?
Does that mean I'm just a kid, too?
Look, obviously I made
a mistake coming here tonight.
Oh, no, you don't. You can't just turn
and walk away from me like that.
It takes more than that to get rid of me!
You OK?
I'm fine.
I wish people wouldn't leave
open graves laying around like this.
So... another vampire has risen tonight.
I don't think so. Look at those tracks.
Whoever was buried here
didn't rise from this grave.
She was dragged from it.
"Some Assembly Required"
W-w-what I'm proposing is,
and I don't mean to appear indecorous...
is-is, um, a-a social engagement,
a-a date, if you're amenable.
You idiot!
Boy, I guess we never realized
how much you like that chair.
- I-I was just working on...
- Your pickup lines?
Um... in a manner of speaking, yes.
Then if you wouldn't mind
a little Gene and Roger,
you might wanna
leave off the "idiot" part.
Being called an idiot tends
to take people out of the dating mood.
It actually kinda turns me on.
I fear you.
You also might wanna avoid words like
"amenable" and "indecorous",
you know? Speak English,
- not whatever they speak in...
- England?
Yeah. You just say "Hey,
I got a thing. You maybe have a thing.
Maybe we could have a thing".
- Oh, thank you, Cyrano.
- I'm not finished.
Then you say
"How do you feel about Mexican?"
- About Mexicans?
- Mexican. Food.
You take her for food,
for which you then pay.
- Oh, right.
- So this chair-woman?
- We are talking Ms Calendar, right?
- What makes you think that?
Simple deduction.
Ms Calendar is reasonably dollsome,
especially for someone in your age bracket.
She already knows that
you're a school librarian,
so you don't have to worry about
how to break
that embarrassing news to her.
And she's the only woman we've
actually ever seen speak to you.
Add it up, it all spells "Duh!".
Now, is it time to have a talk
about the facts of life?
You know, I'm suddenly deciding
this is none of your business.
You know, 'cause that whole
stork thing is a smoke screen.
So, how did things go last night?
Did Mr... Korshak show up on schedule?
More or less.
Angel and I took care of him.
- Angel.
- There's something else, though.
We found an empty grave.
- Another vampire?
- No.
No, this one was dug up
and the body was taken out.
Grave robbing? That's new. Interesting.
I know you meant to say:
"gross and disturbing".
Yes, yes, of course. Terrible thing.
Must-must put a stop to it... Damn it.
So, why does someone
want to dig up graves?
Well, I'll collate some theories.
It would help if we knew
who the body belonged to.
- Meredith Todd. Ring a bell?
- No.
- She died recently. She was our age.
- Drawin' a blank.
Why don't we ask Willow to fire... this
"thing" up, and... track Meredith down?
- Smile.
- Hey!
- Oh, look at those legs.
- No, thank you.
Eric, will you knock it off?
- Hey, Chris.
- Hey.
Oh, I was just wondering
what you were gonna do this year.
- Why?
- 'Cause every year you win
and I place second, so I just thought
I'd see what I'm up against.
You know what the key is? If Dr Clark
doesn't understand your experiment,
he gives you higher marks so it looks like
he understands your experiment.
"Effects of Subviolet Light
Spectrum Depravation...
on the Development of Fruit Flies"?
That should do the trick!
OK, I'm doing this under protest.
It is not fair they're making participation
in this year's science fair mandatory.
I don't think anyone should have to do
anything educational in school,
- if they don't want to.
- "The Tomato: Fruit or Vegetable?"
I wanted to do something
I could finish in a weekend, all right?
Stop it! What are you doing?!
We are under
- fluorescent lights for God's sake!
- The camera loves you.
I didn't think yearbook nerds
came out of hibernation till spring.
- It's for my private collection.
- Eric, will you quit it?
Coming through. Sorry.
Sorry to interrupt, Willow,
but it's the Batsignal.
OK, sure.
See you later, Chris.
- Thanks for the tip.
- OK.
Cordelia's so fine.
You know, she'd be just perfect for us.
Don't be an idiot. She's alive.
This shouldn't take long.
I'm probably the only girl in school
who has the coroner's office
bookmarked as a favorite place.
Hi. Sorry to interrupt
your little undead playgroup,
but I need to ask Willow if she'll help me
with my science fair project.
- It's a fruit.
- I would've asked Chris to help me,
but then that would've brought back
too many memories of Daryl.
I found it! Meredith Todd died
in a car accident last week.
Of course, I have learnt
to deal with my pain.
- How was her neck?
- Fine, except for being broken.
Hello! Can we deal with my pain, please?
There, there.
It says that Meredith and two other girls
in the car were killed instantly.
They were all on the Fondren High
Pep Squad, on the way to a game.
- You know what this means?
- That Fondren might actually
beat Sunnydale in the cross-town
body count competition this year?
She wasn't killed by vampires.
Somebody did dig up her corpse.
Eww! Why is it that every conversation
you have has the word "corpse" in it?
OK, so we've got a body snatcher.
What does that mean?
Here's what I've come up with.
Demons who eat the flesh of the dead
to absorb their souls.
Or it could obviously be
a voodoo practitioner.
- You mean, making a zombie?
- Uh, zombies, more likely.
For most traditional purposes,
a voodoo priest would require
more than one.
So, we should see if the other girls
in the accident are AWOL, too.
Maybe we can figure out what this creep
has in mind if we know whether or not
- he's dealing in volume.
- So we dig up some graves tonight?
Oh, boy, a field trip!
You gonna call Angel?
- I don't think so.
- Yeah, why bother him, huh?
Angel and I have been, um...
Never mind.
As far as Angel's concerned,
I'm taking the night off, OK?
So we're set then.
Say nine-ish? BYO shovel.
And I'll pack some food. Who else likes
those little powdered doughnuts?
- Hey!
- Cordelia?
Darn, I have cheerleader practice tonight.
Boy, I wish I knew we were gonna be
digging up dead people sooner.
- I would've canceled.
- All right. But if you come across
the army of zombies, can you
page us before they eat your flesh?
- Xander?
- Huh?
Zombies don't eat the flesh of the living.
Yeah, I knew that.
But did you see that look on her face?
I couldn't believe Angel.
He was acting all jealous
and he wouldn't even admit it.
- Jealous of what?
- Of Xander.
Because you did that
sexy dance with him?
- Am I ever gonna live that down?
- Nope.
- Anyway, he was being totally irrational.
- Love makes you do the wacky.
- That's the truth.
- You know, this might go a lot faster
if you femmes actually
picked up a shovel, too.
- Here, here.
- Sorry, but I'm an old-fashioned gal.
I was raised to believe that men dig up
the corpses and women have the babies.
So, speaking of the wacky,
what was Cordelia's whole riff
about painful memories? Who's Daryl?
Daryl Epps. Chris's older brother.
He was a big football star.
All-state two years ago.
He was a running...
Someone who runs and catches.
- Was he a studly?
- Big time.
- All the girls were crazy for him.
- And he broke Cordy's heart?
Thus possibly proving its existence.
He died. Rock climbing,
or something. He fell.
Man, that's lousy. Poor Chris.
Ever since then,
Chris has been real quiet.
Kind of in his own world.
I heard their mother doesn't even
leave the house any more.
I think we're there.
By the way, are we hoping
to find a body, or no body?
Call me an optimist, but I'm hoping
to find a fortune in gold doubloons.
Um, body would mean flesh-eating demon.
No body would point towards the army
of zombies thing. Take your pick, really.
Right then, go on.
- You're closer.
- Pathetic much?
Move over.
Guys, if we don't
get this down by tomorrow,
no one's gonna be led by our cheers.
- Practice.
- OK.
See you later.
Hello?
Xander Harris,
if this is some kind of joke...
Cordelia. This is the last place
I expected you to hang out.
Oh, God.
- God, it's you. Why were you following me?
- I wasn't sure it was you at first.
- I'm looking for Buffy.
- Buffy?
Well, she's, uh, big shock,
she's at the graveyard.
- She said she'd be home.
- Well, she lied. Isn't she a rascal?
Well, you're in luck.
It just so happens that my night is free.
Oh, hold on. My skirt is caught.
There.
So, both coffins are empty. That makes
three girls signed up
for the army of zombies.
- Is it an army if you just have three?
- Zombie drill team then.
You're back.
- Angel.
- Xander.
- I thought you were taking the night off?
I, I was, um, but something came up.
- Cordelia told me the truth.
- That's gotta be a first.
Um, as long as you're here,
perhaps you could be of some help. Hm?
We were investigating. Somebody's
been digging up the bodies of dead girls.
I know. We found some of them.
You mean, like, two of the three?
I mean, like, some of them. Like parts.
It was horrible.
Angel saved me from an arm.
God, there were so many parts.
They were everywhere.
Why are these terrible things
always happening to me?
- Karma.
- So much for our zombie theory.
- So much for all our theories.
- I don't get it.
Why go to all the trouble
to dig up three girls,
only to chop them up and throw them away?
It doesn't make any sense!
Especially from
a time-management standpoint.
What I saw didn't
add up to three whole girls.
- I think they kept some parts.
- Could this get yuckier?
They probably kept the other parts to eat!
Question answered.
Why dispose of the remains five miles from
the cemetery, at a school, of all places?
Maybe because whoever did it
had some business in the neighborhood.
- Like, say, classes?
- Oh. Ah.
This was no hatchet job.
Whoever made those incisions
really knew what they were doing.
Yes, really. What student here is gonna be
that well versed in... physiology?
Well, I can think of five or six guys
in the science club. And me.
So, Will, come clean.
Promise to never do it again,
and we'll call it a night.
He joked!
Willow, why don't you get these guys'
locker numbers so we can do some checking?
No. I have to go home now.
I have to take a bath and burn my clothes.
You have to go?
Ah, too bad. Keep in touch. Bye-bye.
I don't wanna go alone. I'm still fragile.
Can you take me?
Great. I'll drive.
How about that? I always pegged him
as a one-woman vampire.
I'm going out, Mom.
I'll be back later, OK?
Mom?
Daryl! Daryl! Daryl!
You understand, in my capacity
as school official,
this search is completely unauthorized,
and I, I cannot condone it.
Fine, your butt's covered.
Wanna grab a locker?
Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
OK, Eric, let's see
what's on your annoying little mind.
Nothing in here but back issues
of Scientific American,
Ooh, I haven't read this one.
Nothing remarkable here.
Guys.
Your friend Chris Epps' locker.
Grey's Anatomy,
Mortician's Desk Reference,
Robicheaux's
Guide to Muscles and Tendons,
I think it's fair to say
Chris is involved.
He's into corpses, all right,
but we still don't know why.
Yes, we do.
# I guess you say
# What can make me feel this way?
# My girl
# Talkin' 'bout my girl
# My girl!
- How's my baby?
- She's not your baby.
She's not gonna be anybody's baby
if we don't finish her soon.
- I'm working on it!
- So am I, friend. So am I.
- Any sign of our suspects?
- Not yet.
I don't get it. Why would
anybody wanna make a girl?
You mean when there's so many
pre-made ones just laying around?
- The things we do for love.
- Love has nothing to do with this.
Maybe not, but I'll tell you this:
people don't fall in love with
what's right in front of them.
People want the dream.
What they can't have.
The more unattainable, the more attractive.
And for Eric, the unattainable
would include everyone that's alive.
Eric's sick enough
to do something like this, but
what about Chris?
He seems like a "human" person.
I don't know. That thing
with his brother was really hard on him.
And he talked about death a lot.
Maybe he just wanted
to get one-up on it.
But it's not doable.
I mean, making someone from scraps,
actually making them live.
If it is, my science project's
definitely coming in second this year.
And speaking of love...
We were talking about
the re-animation of dead tissue.
Do I deconstruct your segues? Huh?
Hey.
Oh, yes. Hello.
- Still no sign of our mad doctors?
- What?
Oh, corpses. Yes, evil. Very good.
- Did you bring it? Tomorrow...
- Very good.
OK, Giles, just remember. "I feel a thing.
You feel a thing." But personalize it.
- Personalize it?
- She's a technopagan, right?
Ask her to bless your laptop.
- Have fun.
- What? Oh, don't...
- Best of luck.
- ...leave.
- Good morning, Rupert.
- Ms Calendar?
Oh, no, please, call me Jenny.
"Ms Calendar" is my father.
Jenny, then.
You know, uh, Jenny,
um, would it appear indecorous...
No, not indecorous. Uh...
Yeah?
Well... Oh, dear. I-I, um...
Rupert, look, I've got to get inside
and set up the lab.
- What I'm proposing is...
- Ah!
I gotta go! Sorry.
Idiot!
Hey. Listen, if it's important,
why don't you just tell me at the game?
Game? Oh, you're going
to the football game?
- Yeah. You seem surprised.
- No, no, uh...
I-I-I-I-I just assumed that
you-you-you spent your evenings
downloading incantations
and, and casting bones.
On game night? Are you nuts?
- You're going too, right?
- Oh, of course.
- Always. Always do.
- So we should just go together.
Look, I could pick you up after school,
and we'll grab a bite to eat
on the way if you like.
How do you feel about Mexican?
Good! OK! And whatever it is you wanna
tell me, you can just tell me then.
- OK?
- OK.
Uh, tonight, then.
That went well.
I think.
I still don't get how Chris could do it.
I mean, arresting cell deterioration
is one thing, but...
"Hello. I wanna get ahead,"
Maybe an electrical current
combined with an adrenaline boost.
"For the love of God,
can somebody scratch my nose?"
Well, it's official. Chris and Eric
didn't come to school today.
- That's no coincidence.
- Maybe they finished their project.
God. What if it worked? What if
that poor girl is walking around?
- Poor girls, technically.
- What could she be thinking?
And... what are they gonna... do with her?
I don't think we have
to worry about that just yet.
I spoke to a press person this morning
about the remains.
The police have finished
sorting through them and
apparently, they found
three heads in the dumpster.
- They only had three girls.
- Precisely.
So they don't have the whole,
uh, package?
Heads must be no good.
Huh. I found 'em attractive enough.
Well, obviously
I'm not as sick as Chris and Eric.
Based on what the police have put together,
I would say they're one step short
of completing their masterpiece.
One step...
We're running out of time.
If we wait too long, the onset of atrophy
in the limbs will be irreversible.
We can turn up the current.
That'll buy us a day at least.
We will lose the body
if we don't attach a head soon!
- We have time.
- We don't!
The crash with the girls was lucky.
But we can't just keep waiting around
for another lucky accident
to drop a head in our laps.
You know what we have to do.
- Hell, it's just one lousy girl.
- I won't do it.
I...
I can't... kill anyone.
Please... understand.
I-I can't do that.
- Please don't make me.
- But you gave me your word.
You promised me, little brother,
that I wouldn't be alone.
The body is perfect. And if we harvest
a head tonight, she'll be ready by sunrise.
When you brought me back,
you promised you'd take care of me.
I need this, Chris.
I need someone.
Please don't ask me to do this.
Don't ask me to take a life.
I tried to tell him. If you take a life
in order to make a life,
the whole thing is a wash.
No harm, no foul.
Maybe you could... you could go out.
- No!
- Let people know.
They can't see me!
Chris, you've always been smarter than me.
You were always the brains.
You're the only one who can help me now.
Third and long, seconds to go.
Where do you throw?
Number five.
Daryl's gonna drive.
Help me, brother.
Thank you.
Show me!
- This one!
- Ha-ha.
A man of taste.
# My girl
# Talkin' 'bout
I checked the obits. Nothing
that would make a likely candidate.
They seem kinda picky for guys
who had three heads to begin with.
Formaldehyde.
- Come again?
- Formaldehyde. Oh, yes, yes, yes,
yes, of course! It accelerates
neural decay in the brain cells.
After a couple of days they're useless.
They're gonna need something really fresh.
- How fresh?
- As fresh as possible.
Buffy, you don't think that they would...
I think anyone who
cuts dead girls into little pieces
does not get the benefit of any doubt.
I wanna end this thing now.
- I second that.
- OK, fine. You guys go to Eric's,
- we can go to Chris', and meet up.
- I'm supposed to be at the...
- "big game". I-I believe it's called.
- Fine. Go ahead. We'll take care of this.
- Yes, but shouldn't I... I'm...
- OK, then why don't we all meet there?
Fine. Yes.
Buffy?
Don't be too hard on Chris.
I mean, he's not a vampire.
No, he's just a ghoul.
Hi. Um, I'm a friend of Chris's.
I kinda need to talk to him.
D'you know if he's home?
So, is he home?
Westbury game. November 17th, '95.
Daryl rushed 185 yards that night.
Four TDs.
He was MVP and he made
all-city that season.
Yeah, that was a great one.
But is Chris home?
I don't know. Is today a school day?
Oh, watch! Watch this move!
Daryl takes a kick-off.
He sheds one, two, three defenders.
And he breaks into the open field
for a 95-yard touchdown.
He would have been 19 next week.
Cordelia.
- Cordelia, 'you coming?
- Yeah, I'll be right out.
Oh, God. Chris, you scared me.
What are you doing in here?
Is something wrong?
- Joy, Lisa, where's Cordelia?
- Cordelia has a game to think about.
She doesn't need losers like you.
I'm sorry. What did you say?
- Are you OK?
- Oh, my God, Buffy.
Don't worry. He's gone.
I was on my way down to the field
when Chris came in
- and all of a sudden someone jumped me.
- Shh! Quiet down. Relax. Take it easy.
That's the fight song. Oh, my God,
it's time for the cheerleader pyramid
at mid-field. I've gotta go.
- Are you sure you're OK to go out there?
- Yeah, you don't understand.
I have to go. I'm the apex!
Chris?
I know what you're trying to do.
You and Eric.
I know about the bodies from the cemetery.
But you haven't hurt anyone yet.
Look, I know what it's like
to lose someone that you're close to.
But that's no excuse.
- What you're doing is wrong.
- I have to do this for him.
- He needs someone.
- Who? Eric?
He needs industrial-strength therapy!
He always... looked out for me.
Stood up for me.
He's all alone.
Everybody loved him...
and now he's all alone.
Who are you talking...
Oh, my God.
You promised me!
You promised!
I wouldn't have to be alone!
It's not too late.
Nothing's changed.
We can still do this, you and me.
Your brother's not the only one
who can create life.
What d'you say?
Let's go scare you up a date.
Daryl!
Daryl?
Daryl! What...
He's not here. Where else could he be?
But... he would never go out.
- Unless...
- He's gonna pick up where you left off.
Go, Greenbacks, go! Go, team, go!
Go, team, go!
I don't know what it is
about football does it for me.
I mean, it lacks the grace of basketball,
the, uh, poetry of baseball.
At its best, it's unadorned aggression.
It's such a rugged contest.
- Rugged? American football?
- And that's funny because?
No, I just think it's rather odd that
a nation that prides itself on its virility
should feel compelled to strap on
40lbs of protective gear
just in order to play rugby.
Is this your normal strategy
for a first date:
dissing my country's national pastime?
Did you just say... "date"?
- You noticed that, huh?
- Hi, Ms Calendar. Hi, Giles.
- Hey. What's up?
- Eric's was a bust. Nothing there.
Nothing much but computer equipment
and a pornography collection
so prodigious it even scared me,
- Did Buffy get back yet?
- No. Uh, no.
Perhaps you should, uh,
circulate nearer the field
and see what you can find.
So what's the score?
- I don't see her. Do you?
- No.
Please, what's going on?
Just take off the blindfold.
I promise I won't scream. I promise.
- She's beautiful.
- No!
It's bad luck for the groom
to see the bride before the wedding.
Please, just take off the blindfold.
I promise I won't scream. I promise.
Cordelia...
Scream all you want.
We're in an abandoned building.
Help!
OK, that's enough.
You were always good to me,
always noticed me, but I ignored you.
I'm sorry. I'm glad I have
a second chance to tell you that.
D-Daryl?
I was thoughtless. I see that now.
But I've changed.
I've learned to appreciate
how much it meant...
that you wanted to be with me.
- We're ready.
- Ready? Ready for what?
You're gonna feel a little pinch,
maybe some discomfort around the neck area.
But don't worry. When you wake up
you'll have the body of a 17-year-old.
In fact, you'll have the body of several.
He was here, Chris. Where did he take her?
- To the rest of the body. To the lab.
- Where is that?
- I promised him...
- He'll kill Cordelia!
You can't just
give and take lives like that.
It's not your job.
He's in the old science lab.
Everything's set up there.
Thank you.
Now find Xander and Willow,
and tell them what's going on.
Daryl, please. You don't have to do this.
We have to, so we can be together.
We'll be together anyway.
I'll be with you, I promise.
- Is that right?
- Uh-huh.
You see anything you like?
And when you're finished,
you won't go out, you won't run away,
but we can hide together.
- Please. Please!
- Sterile enough for government work.
No!
No! Please!
Buffy, help me!
Daryl, listen.
I know what you're doing, OK?
- Your brother sent me to stop you.
- He wouldn't do that.
- My brother loves me.
- Buffy, they're crazy.
It's OK, Cordelia.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
No, I'm not done with her yet.
I'm not finished!
I won't live alone!
- I'm gettin' outta here!
- You have to help me.
Let go!
- Buffy!
- Get Cordelia!
Xander!
Get me out of here!
Come on, Xander, come on!
Come on! Get it off!
Get it off! Get me out of here! Come on!
Hurry up!
Daryl!
Don't!
- Sh-she's mine!
- Daryl!
Daryl!
No. We'll be together always. No.
Mine.
The first time he woke up, after...
He said I shouldn't've brought him back.
I was just trying to look out for him.
Like... he would have done for me.
I saw the fire. I figured you'd be here.
- Is everyone OK?
- Yeah.
We're OK.
- Sorry about all this.
- It's OK.
Although a good rule of thumb
for a first date is:
don't do anything so exciting
it'll be hard to top on a second date.
Believe it or not, since I've moved here
to live on top of the Hellmouth,
the events of this evening
actually qualify as a slow night.
Did you just say "second date"?
You noticed that, huh?
Well, I guess that makes it official.
Everybody's paired off.
Vampires get dates. Hell, even the
school librarian sees more action than me.
You ever think that the world is
a giant game of musical chairs,
and the music's stopped and we're
the only ones who don't have a chair?
- All the time.
- Xander.
I just wanted to...
thank you for saving my life.
What you did in there
was really brave and heroic.
and I just wanted to tell you
if there was anything
- I could ever do to...
- Do you mind? We're talkin' here.
- So, where were we?
- Wondering why we never get dates.
Yeah. So, why do you think that is?
God, the whole thing was so creepy.
But, at the same time, I mean,
he did do it all for his brother.
Sounds like he took it
a little over the edge.
- Love makes you do the wacky.
- What?
- Crazy stuff.
- Oh.
Crazy like a 241-year-old
being jealous of a high-school junior?
Are you 'fessing up?
I thought about it.
Maybe it bothers me a little.
- I don't love Xander.
- Yeah, but he's in your life.
He gets to be there when I can't.
Take your classes, eat your meals,
hear your jokes and complaints.
He gets to see you in the sunlight.
I don't look that good in direct light.
It'll be morning soon.
I should probably go.
I could walk you home.
Subtitles extended & timed by: UAR
...
www.tvsubtitles.net