- Previously:
- We screwed it up.
She's just disoriented from being
tormented in some hell dimension.
That the kinda demon you are?
I don't know why you can hit me,
but I'm not a demon.
So, you three have, what?
Banded together to be pains in my ass?
We're your arch Nemesises.
- Dawn, you need to eat.
- Thanks for your concern.
Why is she taking it out on you?
- This isn't gonna work.
- Are you gonna leave me?
- Willow has a problem.
- No more spells. I'm finished.
- I'm in love with you.
- You're in love with pain.
Afraid I'm gonna...?
- Things have changed.
- I'm disgusted with myself.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
We missed the bed again.
Lucky for the bed.
Is this a new rug?
No. Just looks different
when you're under it.
You know, this place is OK
for a hole in the ground. You fixed it up.
Well, I ate a decorator once.
Maybe something stuck.
- I've been thinking of changing my room.
- Yeah?
Yeah. I think the New Kids on the Block
posters are starting to date me.
Well, if you want, I can...
Are we having a conversation?
What? No.
No.
Maybe.
What?
Isn't this usually the part where you
kick me in the head and run out,...
virtue fluttering?
That's the plan.
Soon as my legs start working.
You were amazing.
You got the job done yourself.
I was just trying to keep up.
The things you do.
The way you make it hurt in all the wrong
places. I've never been with such an animal.
I'm not an animal.
You wanna see the bite marks?
You know, it's late. I should
get home before Dawn goes to sleep.
- And she's off.
- Have you seen my underwear?
What is this to you, this thing we have?
What? We don't have a thing.
We have this.
That's all.
Do you even like me?
Sometimes.
But you like what I do to you.
Do you trust me?
Never.
How can I trust you not to touch my stuff?
Actually living with supervillains
was not in the deal.
We're on the lam.
It's not like we have a choice.
This sucks. Couldn't we have
at least gotten a lair with a view?
Stop whining.
Get your sissy crap out of the way.
Quit it. Don't you curse me.
Give me my bone.
When you girls are done,
the cerebral dampener's ready to be charged.
Cool.
Got the thing?
Musk gland of a Hombja'moleev demon.
Fresh.
All right. Stand back.
Gentlemen,
the cerebral dampener is on line.
Now, with this baby, we can make
any woman we desire our willing sex slave.
I know just where to start.
- Doublemeat is double sweet. Enjoy.
- Thank you.
- Just something I'm tryin'.
- Hey. Sorry I'm late.
Time has no meaning here.
Gina, I'm takin' a break.
I have this sudden urge
to dedicate my productive cooperation.
If you close your eyes and smash yourself
in the head with frozen meat, it'll go away.
Eventually.
I'm hoping.
Thanks for coming by.
Is it bad?
I was sort of hoping you could tell me.
I knew this was gonna happen. What did
Willow do now? Did she hurt anyone?
What? No, no. Tara, this isn't about Willow.
I thought that's why
you didn't want to meet at the house.
Sorry. It's...
Willow's fine. She's been doing really well.
You'd be proud of her.
Good. That's good.
So what do you want to talk about?
It's Spike.
He can hurt me...
without his head exploding.
Oh, my God. His chip stopped working?
No. It still works.
Just not on me.
I need to know about the spell,
the one that brought me back.
I'd ask Willow, but...
You think it's you.
I don't know.
I feel different.
There are things that...
I think maybe I came back wrong.
No, Buffy. That's not...
No. You didn't.
Can you check out the spell?
Just see if there's something that...
Could you just check? Please?
Right there. That's got it.
Mad Dog Two to Mad Dog One.
I thought I was Mad Dog Two.
Mad Dog Three to Mad Dog One.
- Signal's strong and clear. Over.
- Roger that. Beginning preliminary sweep.
Keep your potatoes peeled for the Slayer.
I don't want any surprises.
We can really have anyone we want.
- It's like candy.
- Juicy, pulsating candy.
- The one with the neck. Put it on her.
- No. I want the redhead.
The redhead's too tall.
- Get off of me. Jerk.
- Take it back.
- Target acquired.
- What?
Initiating contact.
- The brunette?
- She's kinda cute.
- No, go for the leather skirt.
- Bazoombas.
- Yeah. Go for the one with the bazoombas.
Bazoombas.
So how did you get so beautiful?
OK. Does that line usually wor...?
- What the hell are you doing here?
- It's nice to see you, too, Katrina.
It's the seeing you that's throwing me.
I thought I was pretty clear
I never wanted that to happen again.
- Never's a long time, baby.
- Apparently, not long enough.
You're not still sore
about that thing, are you?
What thing would that be, exactly?
The wind-up slut you tinkered together?
Or when Little Miss Nuts and Bolts
tried to choke me to death?
OK. So I've made a few mistakes.
No. No, I did.
For ever lowering myself
to be with a jerk like you.
- No. Don't say that.
- Well, what did you expect?
To just waltz in here and sweep me off my
feet with your cheesy lines and fancy suit?
No. I just thought we could talk.
I thought maybe we could work things out.
There is nothing to work out.
What you did was sick.
Just looking at you makes me want to vomit.
- Are you sure about that?
- Yes. God! Yes, I'm sure.
I love you, Master.
I love you, too, baby.
I'm home. Who wants to help
scrape the grease off my...
- Is there singing? Are we singing again?
- No. Just the dancin'.
We're teaching Dawn synchronised
dance steps for the wedding reception.
Wanna go for a spin?
I'm heading more towards
an ungainly collapse.
- Rough day?
- Kinda.
You've been goin' at it too hard.
We hardly ever see you.
What with slingin' the Doublemeat
and poundin' the big evil.
You are looking a little pounded.
Just around the eyes.
We're thinking of heading to the Bronze
later. Wanna come? Get all unwindy?
Tall glasses of frosty relaxation on me.
Nectar of the working man.
No. I'll stay here with Dawn.
Curl up on the couch with a big bowl of
popcorn and... listen to the cars honk?
- Where are you going?
- I'm sleeping over at Janice's.
I'm falling for that again
because of the surprise lobotomy?
It's OK. I checked it out.
Janice's mom is picking her up.
I didn't think you'd care.
You're never home, so...
I know. I'm sorry.
But I'm here now,
all visible and everything.
- Can't you stay at Janice's another night?
- Her mom's cooking Mexican.
She's gonna teach me
how to make real tortillas.
Not like I knew you'd be around.
Frosty nectar. Now, please?
- Thank you, baby.
- My pleasure, Master.
That is so cool.
I could've used one of these in high school.
Gentlemen. To crime.
Crime.
- Crime tastes funny.
- Wow.
I still think I would have gone
with the bazoombas, but...
Wow.
Yeah, she's really cute.
Cute?
Look at her, men.
The shape of her lips.
The smooth, silky skin.
The way her nose crinkles when she laughs.
She's perfect.
- Yeah.
- She's totally hot.
So are you, Master.
- You think so?
- Yes, Master.
OK. So, how do we...?
- You know?
- Who gets to...?
- I do.
- That's not fair.
- Dude, you didn't call it.
- I don't have to call it. She's mine.
But don't worry.
You can play with her all you want.
After I'm done with her.
I missed you so much.
You never should have left me.
- Say it.
- I never should have left you, Master.
- Now tell me you love me.
- I love you, Master.
- Again.
I love you, too, baby. Get on your knees.
Yes, Warren.
Wait. What'd you just say?
I said "Yes, Warr... "
What the...? What did you do to me?
- Get the dampener.
- Who the hell are you?
- Your masters.
- My what?
- Where'd you put it?
- Are you kidding me?
- Get the dampener.
- You were sharing me with these dorks?
We're supervillains. Call us "master".
Wait.
- Crap.
- It's out of juice.
Is that what you used on me? Oh, my God.
First the skankbot and now this?
- What is wrong with you?
- I wanted us to be together.
There is no us. Get that through your meaty
head. I am not your girlfriend any more.
- She's your ex?
- Dude, that is messed up.
You think? You bunch
of little boys playing at being men?
Well, this is not some fantasy.
It's not a game, you freaks.
It's rape.
- What?
- No, we didn't...
You're all sick. And I'm gonna
make sure you get locked up for this.
- Then we'll see how you like getting raped.
- Stop her.
Get off me.
Charge the cerebral dampener.
- Warren...
- Charge the dampener. Andrew, get her up.
We'll give her another dose. A stronger one.
Everything's all right.
Everything's gonna be all right.
I don't think so.
She's dead.
Oh, God. Oh, God. Oh, God.
Her neck, it just...
No, that's not...
- This isn't happening.
- I just... I gotta...
I gotta... Let me think.
What'd you do?
What the hell did you do?
We did this, me and Andrew and you.
It's on all of us.
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
- Shut up.
We have to get... We have to get rid of it.
How?
Maybe a spell.
Can you teleport it outta here?
No. She's...
It's too big.
Andrew?
- Andrew?
- What?
Is there anything that you can summon,
something that can devour that much?
Maybe a Jaarvlen Flesh Eater,
but they're hard to control.
It'd go for us, too.
Well, that's it, man. We're screwed.
- Stay calm.
- Tell that to your girlfriend.
- Ex-girlfriend.
- It doesn't matter. There's a link.
You knew her, so there's a link.
You don't think Buffy'll be able
to put that together? She'll figure it out.
It was an accident.
Maybe we could turn ourselves in.
- No.
- If we go to the police now...
- No. I'm not going to jail.
- We can't hide this.
Sooner or later,
the Slayer's gonna find out she's dead.
Well, then maybe it should be sooner.
- Are you insane?
- Listen.
- No.
We have two problems:
the body and the Slayer.
Well, what if there was a way that we could
take care of them both, with one big stone?
What are they doing?
We're not gonna have to
do that at the wedding?
Cos there's this last thread of dignity
I've been desperately clinging to.
You're still doing OK, right?
Yeah. You know, some days
are harder than the really hard days.
It's easier like this, though,
when I'm not alone.
- I'm sorry I haven't been around that much.
- No, that's not...
It's OK. We know you've been all tied up.
- What?
- With your job and the slaying.
I see sitting where
there should be dancing.
- Come share in the joy of our groove thing.
- And despite that, I succumb to the beat.
- I think I'll catch the next soul train out.
- You sure?
Oh, yeah. You know, glass all the way empty.
More nectar required.
Cool. Well, shimmy on out
when you're done lubricatin'.
You see?
You try to be with them.
But you'll always end up in the dark.
With me.
What would they think of you if they
found out all the things you've done?
If they knew who you really were?
Don't.
Stop me.
No, don't close your eyes.
Look at them.
That's not your world.
You belong in the shadows.
With me.
Look at your friends, and tell me
you don't love getting away with this...
right under their noses.
I pulled a jive muscle last night.
The funky monkey claims another victim.
Tara. What are you doing here?
I mean, it's OK for you to be here if you
have things that you have to be here for.
Yeah. I'm gonna go bring Anya
up to speed on that monkey situation.
- There's a monkey problem?
- Only if you don't stretch first.
The Brekenkrieg Grimoire? Light reading?
Yeah. I was just...
No, it's OK. I didn't expect you
to stop doing magic just because...
You don't have to hide it. I'm not...
I'm doing better. No spells for 32 days.
I can even go to the magic shop now,
as long as someone's with me at all times.
But it's better now. It really is.
You know, if you were checking on me?
No, I wouldn't...
I was just looking for Buffy.
Well, I haven't seen her since last night.
She's not around much these days.
We kinda miss her.
I'm sure she feels the same way.
If you see her, can you tell her
that I need to talk to her? It's important.
- Yeah. Of course I will.
- Thanks.
Will?
I'm glad you're doing better.
Don't think about the evil, bloodsucking
fiend. Focus on anything but the evil fiend.
Thank you.
It's OK. I'm gonna get you out of here.
Can you walk? Are you hurt?
What did you do, Buffy?
Bloody hell. What'd you do that for?
Spike?
Buffy.
Spike. What's happening?
So you thought you
could just slip away, then?
Vampire, remember?
I could feel you.
Bloody hell. What'd you do that for?
Buffy.
Do you mind?
Buffy?
She's dead.
I killed her.
We have to go.
What happened?
There's nothing you can do.
We have to go before someone sees you.
What did I do?
We have to go, now.
All right. Listen to me. Buffy. Buffy.
- She's dead.
- It was an accident.
But I killed her.
- I'm gonna get you home.
- No.
I'm gonna get you home, and you're gonna
crawl in your warm bed and stay there.
I'm gonna sort this out. Trust me.
Two problems, one stone.
Nice job. She totally bought it.
Yeah.
Some of my best work.
What happens now?
The night's young.
Gotta be some more girls we could kill.
We stick to the plan.
Buffy thinks she killed Katrina.
It's her problem now.
What did you do, Buffy?
It's all right, love.
All right. It'll be our little secret.
Do you trust me?
Hey.
What time is it?
It's late.
I just wanna...
I love you.
You know that, right?
What's wrong?
I know I haven't been
everything I should be.
Everything Mom was.
But I love you. I always will.
Why are you talking like this?
Buffy?
There was an accident, in the woods.
A girl, she was hurt.
I hurt someone.
Oh, my God.
Is she all right?
No.
I'm sorry.
There's something I have to do.
I have to tell what I did.
I have to go to the police.
The police?
Dawnie, I have to.
But...
What's going to happen?
I don't know.
They'll take you away, won't they?
I'm sorry.
No, you're not.
You're never here.
You can't even stand to be around me.
- That's not true.
- You don't wanna be here with me.
You didn't wanna come back. I know that.
You were happier where you were.
You wanna go away again.
Dawn...
Then go. You're not really here anyway.
- What do you think you're doing?
- The right thing. For once.
Sorry, love. Can't let you do that.
- I have to tell them what happened.
- Nothing happened.
I killed that girl.
Demons in the woods?
Time going wonky? They won't believe you.
- I'll show them.
- Show them what?
- What did you do?
- I took care of it.
- What I had to.
I went back and I took care of it. It
doesn't matter now. No one'll ever find her.
- Where'd they find her?
- The river, half a mile from the cemetery.
Balls.
- There is nothing to connect this to you.
- It doesn't matter.
- It wasn't your fault.
- I killed her.
- It was an accident. It just happened.
- Nothing just happens.
You are not going in there.
I have to do this. Just let me go.
I can't. I love you.
No, you don't.
You think I haven't tried not to?
Try harder.
You are not throwing your life away
over this.
- It's not your choice.
- Why are you doing this to yourself?
A girl is dead because of me.
How many people are alive because of you?
How many have you saved?
One dead girl doesn't tip the scale.
That's all it is to you, isn't it?
Just another body.
Buffy.
You can't understand why this is killing me.
Why don't you explain it?
That's it, put it on me.
Put it all on me.
- That's my girl.
- I am not your girl.
You don't have a soul.
There is nothing good or clean in you.
You are dead inside.
You can't feel anything real.
I could never be your girl.
You always hurt the one you love, pet.
Buffy?
Buffy.
No, no statements.
Not until I get confirmation.
- Excuse me. I need to...
- I'll be with you in a sec.
Sunnydale PD?
Yeah. Phone's ringing off the hook here.
Listen, you got an ID on that body yet?
Yeah? OK, shoot.
Katrina Silber.
S- i-I-b-e-r.
- Warren, tell her to go away.
- I can't.
You're keeping secrets from me -
other girls and...
Trina, shut up.
- Warren.
- Thanks. Now, what's the problem, miss?
- Is this what you saw?
- Yeah, that's it.
Rwasundi. Very rare.
Its presence in our dimension
causes a sort of...
localised temporal disturbance.
- So that's why time went all "David Lynch"?
- Right.
Human perception
is based on a linear chronology.
Being exposed to the Rwasundi for a few
seconds can cause vivid hallucinations.
And a slight tingly scalp.
So that's it. These things
just made you think you killed her.
She was probably dead
long before you stumbled across her.
It wasn't the demon.
It was Warren. He knew Katrina.
He had something to do with it, I know it.
How can you be sure?
You always hurt the one you love.
Does this mean you're not going away?
Yeah. I'm not going anywhere.
We need to find Warren and the others.
Whatever they've done,
they won't get away with it.
We'll get away with it.
"Injuries consistent with a fall.
" The coroner's ruling it a suicide.
What about Buffy?
It wasn't that hard messing her
game up. If she figures it out,
we'll take care of her.
We really got away with murder.
That's kinda cool.
Yeah.
Cool.
- Are you sure?
- I've double-checked everything.
There's nothing wrong with you.
Then why can Spike hurt me?
Well, I said that there was nothing
wrong with you, but you are different.
Shifting you out of... from where you were,
funnelling your essence
back into your body,
it altered you on a basic molecular level.
Probably just enough to confuse
the sensors, or whatever, in Spike's chip.
But it's all surfacey physical stuff.
It wouldn't have any more
effect than bad sunburn.
I didn't come back wrong?
No, you're the same Buffy.
With a deep tropical cellular tan.
You must have missed something.
Will you check again?
I promise, there's nothing wrong with you.
There has to be.
This just can't be me. It isn't me.
Why do I feel like this?
Why do I let Spike do those things to me?
You mean, hit you?
Really?
He's everything I hate.
He's everything that
I'm supposed to be against.
But the only time that
I ever feel anything is when...
- Don't tell anyone. Please?
- I won't.
The way they would look at me.
I just couldn't...
I won't tell anyone. I wouldn't do that.
Why can't I stop?
Why do I keep letting him in?
Do you love him?
It's OK if you do. He's done a lot of good,
and he does love you.
And, Buffy, it's OK if you don't.
You're going through
a really hard time, and you're...
What? Using him?
What's OK about that?
- It's not that simple.
- It is. It's wrong.
I'm wrong.
Tell me that I'm wrong, please.
Please don't forgive me. Please.
God! Please don't...
Please don't forgive me.
Please don't...
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org