Almost time to wake up
and take your first look at the world.
I know you're gonna make me proud.
Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
Adam?
Spike, I want you to come with me.
You're going to help me with my problem.
- The Slayer's got pals.
- Take them away from her.
- This all goes down, the chip comes out.
- Scout's honour.
Riley had a career. He had a future till he
met you, and yeah, I got a problem with that.
Thank you.
Adam was at that cave so maybe he was there
for a reason. I'll go back, scope it out...
- You never train with me. He'll kick your arse.
- Giles!
Stupid? You finally had the guts
to say it to my face.
- What do you mean by "witch stuff"?
- You guys, what is happening?
Buffy, things have been wrong for a while.
I'm starting to understand why there's
no ancient prophecy about a Chosen One...
and her friends.
If I need help,
I'll go to someone I can count on.
- I've been waiting for you.
- And now I'm here.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Riley?
Your thoughts are troubled. In turmoil.
I understand, brother.
We have a lot to discuss.
- Speak.
- What have you done to me?
Nothing. It was Mother.
Your... Professor Walsh.
She implanted the behaviour modifier.
- A chip in my head. She really did it.
- Actually, the chip is here.
Tied directly into your central nervous
system through the thoracic nerve.
This is phase one of your preparation.
It lay dormant until now.
I simply activated it, brother.
Stop calling me that. I'm not your brother.
You're a botched science experiment
and I'm a human being,
- who'll do everything in his power...
- Sit.
You have no power.
Not yet.
Once you forget your old life
and embrace your destiny, as I have,
you will know power
you have never dreamed of.
I think you're going to like it.
Demons cling to old ways and ancient feuds.
And they're hopeless with technology.
- Unworthy.
- Not really wanting a lecture right now.
Disappointed by demonkind,
we turn to humans.
Smart, adaptive, but emotional and weak.
Blind. There's imperfection everywhere.
Something must be done.
Who will deliver us?
Mother. She saw our future.
Yours and mine.
She saw that you are necessary.
She saw the role
that you will play by my side.
Stand up.
You see, we are brothers after all.
It warms the cockles of my non-beating heart,
seeing you lads together.
I didn't send for you, Spike.
Yeah, well, I'm not much
the "being sent for" type.
I'm much more the "I did my part, now
get this chip out of my head" kinda guy.
Slightly stiffer than usual.
Subtle, but I like it.
- What's with him?
- I activated his chip.
Oh. So it's chips all around, is it?
Someone must've bought the party pack.
You get yours removed
when the Slayer is where I want her.
She's separated from her friends.
They want nothing to do with her.
She's all alone.
That's how I want her.
Where I want her is down in the Initiative.
She will ensure
that as many demons die as humans.
She will achieve maximum carnage
before she's too weak to go on.
- No. You can't...
- Stop talking.
Right. The Initiative. But getting her there -
that's what the disks are for, innit?
The witch gives her the info and
Alice heads back down the rabbit hole.
- The witch?
- Willow. About so high, perky,
good with maths. A natural choice.
- Her friend.
- Right.
One of those from whom
you so efficiently separated her.
Damn right I did. They won't be talking
to each other for a long, long...
Hang on. I think
I might've detected a small flaw.
So you failed.
Well, hey, you're supposed to be so smart.
You let me plan this thing.
Let's not quibble. The important thing is
making sure the Slayer is where we want...
- Go.
- Gone.
So we'll do this chip thing when I get back.
- Hey.
- Hello.
Oh. Pardon the robe.
It's a bit of a late start.
Right.
- I hope you're feeling all right, Mr Giles.
- Oh, quite well, thank you.
Yes, I'll probably have a briskjog later on.
- Did you want something?
- I forgot my laptop and the disks.
Yes. Please, please, come in.
Will you be working here?
You know, typing, talking?
Because that will be fine.
No. That's OK.
Got 'em.
So... see ya.
Right. Yes, well, good luck with that.
OK.
- Bye.
Xander?
You wanted to check the board
at the unemployment office this morning.
You can't go like that. They won't
even interview you if you're naked.
I'm not goin'. There's never anything good.
- Maybe I shouldjoin the army.
- Don't they make you get up really early?
Oh, yeah. Never mind.
Are you still upset about that fight you had
with your friends? It was hours ago!
- Get over it.
- Anya, you...
Forget it.
So they all think you're a lost, directionless
loser with no plans for his future. Pfft!
- Anya, you can't pfft that stuff away.
- Why not?
I don't know.
Cos I think maybe they're right.
So what if they are? You're a good person
and a good boyfriend and...
and I'm in love with you.
Whatever they think of you,
it shouldn't matter.
Yeah.
Yeah, it doesn't matter.
Adam.
Where are you?
This is where it will all happen.
Where the new race begins.
- Where are we?
- In the Initiative.
There are areas no one knew about
beyond those that needed to.
Mother kept her secrets well.
Didn't you?
- Professor Walsh?
- This is all how she planned it,
except she thought she would be alive.
Are you...
- Is that what you're gonna do to me?
- They're just workers.
You know your destiny is much greater.
Forrest.
Oh, God.
God has nothing to do with it.
Easy, sheriff.
Watch where you point that thing.
What are you doing here?
Looking for a little weekend
getaway place. Shove off.
Adam's been using these caves.
- What?
- I found his lair.
Oh, cripes. That's all I need -
running into that goon.
Adam's cleared out of here.
Something is about to go down.
Look at little Nancy Drew.
What about those disks I nabbed?
They ought to tell you something.
- Willow has the disks.
- Well, I'd get on that.
Can't ignore valuable information
just cos you two birds fell out, can you?
- Right.
- Well, you do what you want.
No worry of mine now, is it?
- Maybe you should rest. Clear your head?
- Can't. Not now. I think I'm on to something.
I've been assuming that the cipher text
was encrypted with an asymmetric algorithm.
- Then it hit me. A hexagonic key pattern.
- Hey, look, you did it!
I didn't. I haven't even finished
typing in the new code.
Something's doing it.
Must be programmed to self-decrypt
at a certain point. That is so annoying!
It's like somebody blurting out
the answer to a riddle just when you've...
I mean, yippee! We have the information.
I don't know if "yippee" is
the right response either. Read that.
Hello?
Yeah, she's right...
I mean, let me check.
It's Buffy.
Professor Walsh.
Professor Walsh, it's Riley Finn.
- Can you hear me?
- She's dead.
Artificially reanimated
with basic to moderate brain activity.
Mommy can hear you,
but she's still a walking corpse.
- So are you.
- Mm-mm. Got that wrong.
I'm surging with life, and strength.
Adam made me to be nearly as bad as he is.
Really lookin' forward
to tryin' out your girl again.
- I'm sorry, Forrest.
- Don't be.
This is the best thing
that ever happened to me.
I'm free of all my weaknesses,
and my doubts.
He's gonna fix you up, too.
Soon as we got some choice parts.
Then you and me will be back on the
same side, moving toward a new future.
- I'll never let that happen.
- You don't have a choice, brother.
- Your will belongs to us now.
- No. That's not true.
Then why don't you
get out of that chair and walk out?
- You can't control my...
- Riley, be a good boy.
Where's Anya?
Oddly, Anya decided not to join us,
despite all the fun we had at our last meeting.
And I don't think Tara felt welcome.
Why? Because of the things that we said?
Who told you we were talking
behind your back, specifically?
Well, I... Spike, specifically, but...
And who told you
we thought you should join the army?
That's not exactly what he said.
Well, Spike can be very convincing when...
- I'm very stupid.
- He played us.
He wanted us to fight to split us up.
That's where it came from -
the stuff we said the other night.
Of course. Well, piffle. Let's move on.
- I'm movin'.
- Me, too.
Good.
Great.
So, why do you think
Spike made with the head games?
He's all dressed up with no one to bite.
Gotta get his ya-yas somehow.
I think it was more than that.
I think it was Adam.
Spike's working for Adam?
After all we've done for...
Nah. I can't even act surprised.
I just went to Adam's lair and he was gone.
But Spike just happened to be there.
He made a big noise about
getting information off the disks.
Oh. I decrypted 'em.
Well, they decrypted themselves,
but I almost had it.
- What did they say?
- A bunch of stuff we already knew about 314.
But it also said there's some final phase
where Adam manufactures a bunch
of creepy cyberdemonoids like him.
There's a special lab in the Initiative,
but it didn't say where.
Adam fed Spike those disks. It has to be.
He wanted me to know
about his evil-guy assembly line.
- This lab, it's in the Initiative?
- Hidden somewhere.
I'll give the demon his due.
He thought this one out.
What do you mean?
Think how overcrowded the
containment cells are in the Initiative.
Those demons were just too easy to catch.
It's like they wanted in that place.
The Trojan Horse.
Adam's making sure the demons
attack the Initiative from the inside.
Demons versus soldiers.
Massacre, massacre.
And Adam has a neat pile of body parts
to start assembling his army.
Diabolical, yet... gross.
Does anybody else miss the mayor -
"I just wanna be a big snake"?
I've gotta shut him down.
His final phase is about to start.
- We need to warn the Initiative.
- They're not gonna listen to me.
- Riley?
- He's a deserter.
He got some bad news anyway
and kinda took off.
OK, I'm confused again.
Adam has this evil plan. Why is he
so anxious for you to know about it?
He wants me there.
Probably figures I'll even the kill ratio.
He's not worried you might kill,
oh say... him?
No. He's really not.
She's coming. I can feel it.
Good on you. Got a chunk
of prognosticating demon in there, eh?
Now, if you'll just get this chip
out of my cranium, I'll be out of your way.
Mind the hairline. I don't fancy fussing with
a comb-over once I resume my killing ways.
- Come on. We had a deal.
- When she's here.
There's certainly no lack of supplies. I only
wish I knew which ones would kill Adam.
Riley said his power source
is a uranium core embedded inside his chest.
Probably near the spine.
Great. So we just ask him to lie down quietly
while we do some exploratory surgery.
What about magic? Some kinda...
I don't know... uranium-extracting spell?
- I know. I'm reaching.
- Perhaps a paralysing spell.
- Only I can't perform the incantation of this.
- Right.
Don't you have to speak it
in Sumerian or something?
I do speak Sumerian. But it's not that.
Only an experienced witch can incant it
within striking distance of the subject.
See what you get for taking French
and not Sumerian?
- What was I thinking?
- So no problem. All we need is Combo Buffy.
Her with slayer strength, Giles's multilingual
know-how and Willow's witchy power.
Yeah. Don't tell me.
I'm just full of helpful suggestions.
As a matter of fact, you are.
- Nervous?
- No way.
I'm full of that good old kamikaze spirit.
Just because this will never work,
don't be negative.
The spell isn't powerful enough
to defeat Adam?
It's very powerful.
It's also extraordinarily dangerous.
Game faces, guys. We're going in.
- How you doin'?
- Super.
What was I thinking,
using stairs all this time?
OK.
- Will...
- No, really. It's not as scary as I thought.
No. That's not what I was gonna say.
I just...
I'm sorry.
I hate that things have been
so strained between all of us.
It's not your fault. Spike stirred up trouble.
Yeah, but I think trouble was stir-upable.
I think we've all sort of
drifted apart this year, don't you?
Maybe a little.
But, you know, first year of college, it's hard
to keep the old high-school gang together.
But I want it together. Will, I miss you.
And Giles and Xander. And it is my fault.
I've been so wrapped up in my own stuff,
I've been a bad friend.
You're the Slayer.
Your stuff is pretty crucial.
I mean Riley, and...
Riley, mostly.
Well, I haven't been Miss Available either.
I kept secrets. I hid things from everyone.
That's not your fault. Will,
you were going through something huge.
I wanted to tell you, but I was so scared.
You can tell me anything. I love you.
- You're my best friend.
- Me, too.
- I love you, too.
- Oh!
Falling now.
- Let's promise to never not talk again.
- I promise, I promise.
- Xander.
- Oh, wonderful Xander!
- You know we love you, right?
- We totally do.
- Oh, God. We're gonna die, aren't we?
- No. We just missed you.
Giles, hurry up!
You definitely wanna get down here for this!
OK. We stick together and everything
should be fine. Everybody ready? Let's...
do this.
It's Must See TV.
Bait's been taken. Trap's all set.
The Slayer has landed.
So.
One chiperectomy, please.
- Hello? Paging Dr Owe-me-one.
- She's not alone.
You've failed me again.
- Well, that's one way of looking at it.
- What's the other way?
Oh, come on!
It's not like I wasn't trying.
That's worth something, isn't it?
I suppose. Yes.
I will honour our agreement
and remove your chip.
Take his head off.
Let him go.
There's nowhere left to run.
- Colonel.
- Shut up.
- You got some nerve, lady.
- You have to listen.
You think you and your friends
can waltz into a government installation
brandishing weapons like...
- like...
- It's a gourd.
It's a magic gourd.
What kind of freaks are you people?
- Adam is here, Colonel. In the Initiative.
- Nice try.
Those overcrowded cells? Courtesy of Adam.
He's pulling a Trojan Horse on you.
Every inch of this installation
is under constant 24-hour surveillance.
- Including the secret lab?
- Including everything.
- What secret lab?
- The one Adam's been using.
The one built for the final stage
of the 314 project.
- You have no idea what I'm talking about.
- I know everything that goes on around here.
A tick on a mouse
couldn't get in without my knowing.
- If Adam wants to try, we're ready for him.
- Oh, jolly good.
How exactly do you plan to get close enough
to Adam to remove his power source?
Hit him simultaneously
with multiple Taser blasters.
Incapacitate him
with as much voltage as we can muster.
Great plan. That's right up there
with "duck and cover".
I've seen Adam hit with Taser blasts.
He feeds on it. And you're giving him
an all-you-can-eat buffet?
- You telling me my business?
- This is not your business. It's mine.
You, the Initiative, the boys at the Pentagon -
you're all in way over your heads.
Messing with primeval forces
you have no comprehension of.
- And you do?
- I'm the Slayer.
You're playing on my turf.
Up there, maybe. But down here,
I'm the one who's in control.
Sir, the power grid's down.
Backup's not responding.
We're locked in.
This will be interesting.
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
Go!
Containment area has been breached.
Hostiles are loose.
How many?
- All of them, sir.
- It's Adam.
I'm the only one that can stop him. Let me
handle this. Get your people out of here.
You men follow me.
We gotta take the armoury now.
- Sir.
- Colonel.
- These people are under arrest. Understand?
- Yes, sir.
- We've gotta find Adam.
- On it.
The enjoining spell is extremely volatile.
We can't risk it being interrupted.
We need a place that's close to you and quiet.
Uh... quiet?
- How are we doing, Will?
- Done.
Hold on.
According to this, there's air ducts
and electrical conduits all running into there.
- So?
- So there's no "there" there. Look.
- It's Adam.
- Are you sure?
Right behind 314.
- Can you unlock it?
- I don't have to.
All the locks in the Initiative
have been disengaged, except for the exits.
Demon open house.
Great. So we know we're going to 314.
Now all we have to do is get there.
Willow, down!
Come on!
OK, it should be over here.
Once I'm in, barricade the door behind me.
- Is this place OK to be Magic Central?
- It should do.
- As long as we don't get blowed up.
- What are the odds of that?
- How long before the ritual kicks in?
- Five minutes, give or take.
- I'll move fast, then.
- Buffy, I still don't like you going in alone.
I won't be.
Riley.
Are you hurt?
Say something.
What is this?
- Why won't you talk to me?
- He can't. He's not programmed to.
He's part of the final phase now.
As you were supposed to be.
Sorry. I don'tjump through hoops
on command.
I've never really been one to toe the line.
Oh.
Kill her.
I thought you'd never ask.
The power of the Slayer
and all who wield it.
Last to ancient first, we invoke thee.
Grant us thy domain and primal strength.
Accept us and the powers we possess.
Make us, mind and heart and spirit, join.
Let the hand encompass us. Do thy will.
Buffy!
Shut up. Watch me kill your girlfriend, Finn.
That's an order.
Spiritus: spirit.
Animus: heart.
Sophus: mind.
And manus: the hand.
We enjoin that we may inhabit
the vessel, the hand,
daughter of Sineya, first of the Ones.
Is that it? Is that all you got?
No. She's got me.
Look who's come off the bench.
I need to get to Adam - now. Are you able?
Go.
Fall back! Fall back!
Protect the flank! Close down that pit!
Fun, isn't it?
I do appreciate violence.
Good.
- Broke your arm.
- Got another.
I've been upgrading.
We implore thee, admit us.
Bring us to the vessel. Take us now.
- You can't last much longer.
- We can.
We are for ever.
Interesting.
Very interesting.
What are you making me do this for?
Not that I'm not enjoying myself.
But Adam's not gonna like it if I...
How can you...
You can never hope to grasp
the source of our power.
But yours is right here.
Buffy.
Wow. That was...
Nasty sort of fellow.
- Lucky for you blighters I was here, eh?
- Yes. Thank you.
But your heroism is slightly muted by your
helping Adam start a war that would kill us.
You probably just saved us
so we wouldn't stake you right here.
Well, yeah. Did it work?
Then everything's all right. We all get to be
not staked through the heart. Good work!
- Buffy!
- Wasn't it amazing?
- You were great.
- We were great.
- We still got men out there.
- Well, let's go save 'em, by gum.
You guys open the exits. You, organise
the soldiers, pull 'em back. I'll take point.
- Are you up to this?
- I am.
It was an experiment. The Initiative
represented the government's interests
in not only controlling
the otherworldly menace,
but in harnessing its power
for our own military purposes.
The considered opinion of this council
is that the experiment has failed.
Once the prototype
took control of the complex,
our soldiers suff.ered
a 40 per cent casualty rate.
It was only through the actions of a deserter
and a group of civilian insurrectionists
that our losses were not total.
I trust the irony of that
is not lost on any of us.
Maggie Walsh's vision was brilliant,
but ultimately insupportable.
The demons cannot be harnessed.
Cannot be controlled.
We therefore recommend
that this project be terminated
and all records concerning it expunged.
Our soldiers'll be debriefed.
Standard confidentiality clause.
We will monitor the civilians
and the usual measures prepared,
should they try to go public.
I don't think they will.
The Initiative itself
will be filled in with concrete.
Burn it down, gentlemen.
Burn it down and salt the earth.
Visiontext Subtitles: Claire Bates
ENGLISH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org