Previously on "Buffy The Vampire Slayer":
We had to hide the Key.
- Made it human and sent it to you.
- Dawn.
- What kind of demon am I fighting?
- Glory isn't a demon. She's a god.
Your sister took my Key and she won't
give it back. I bet you know where she put it.
"They had to be certain the Slayer
would protect it with her life,
so they sent the Key to
her in the form of a sister."
You're the Key. Go.
Before she finds you. She's here.
I love you.
The only chance you had with me
was when I was unconscious.
Let's see what you are. Or who you are.
One soldier in a vast army.
The Key is the link. The link must be severed.
- Where is the Key?
- I'd die a thousand deaths before I'd tell you.
No. No.
Tara.
No.
Tara, I'm so sorry.
- What are you gonna need?
- They gave me a lot of stuff to keep her calm.
- I told you this wasn't over.
- Oh, look at that.
Such pure green energy.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Vozdukh, priyevratis v kulak.
- Buffy.
- Keep moving.
I can't.
I really hate it when people touch my things.
- Last words, slay-runt?
- Just one.
Truck.
- No. Not now, you idiot.
- Let go of my body.
Oh, God.
And then, whoosh! All of a sudden
Glory's standing in front of us,
skanky and blonde and thinkin' she's all that
cos some bumpy heads kiss her stinky feet...
She does have nice feet. She's coming at us
and Buffy's standing there, not even blinking,
like "Bring it on" and... wham!
- Hell-bitch in orbit.
- Go, Buff.
I knew you'd best Glory.
Our years of training...
A truck hit her.
You threw it at her?
Well, no. She more kind of
waited for it to hit Glory.
But then Buffy ran
really fast and we got away.
I don't know how. That truck couldn't have
slowed her down for more than a second.
Well, how isn't important. All that matters
is that the two of you are safe.
Safe?
We've barely managed not getting seriously
dead every time we've crossed paths.
Now that she knows that Dawn is the Key...?
There must be something in the Book
of Tarnis that we can use against Glory.
Piano.
Because that's what we used
to kill that big demon that one time.
No, that was a rocket launcher.
What are you talkin' about?
We should drop a piano on her.
It works for that cartoon rabbit running from
that nice man with the speech impediment.
Or we could paint a convincing tunnel on the
side of a mountain. Let's just keep thinking.
- We'll reassemble at the magic shop, see if...
- Can't fight her.
- Well, not yet, no...
- No, not ever. She's too strong, Giles.
We won't win this with stakes, or spells,
or pulling out some uranium power core.
She's a god and she's coming for us.
So let's not be here when she knocks.
Run away?
Finally, a sensible plan.
That's not what she meant.
Is it?
We can't stay here. She'll just kill us one by
one till there's no one between her and Dawn.
We understand the severity of this,
but there must be another...
No. We stay, we die.
Show of hands for that option?
All right. Nobody goes home,
nobody tells anybody we're leaving.
Just pack whatever supplies we need
and we're gone.
Cool. Don't have to study
for that geometry test.
What about wheels? I don't think
everybody'll fit in the Xandermobile.
Just get your stuff together.
I'll handle the rest.
This is terrible. I'll never be able to mend this.
- Not really my colour, anyway.
- Oh, yes. Inappropriate humour.
Most amusing. Don't suppose you know
what led to this sartorial tragedy.
- That's not how it works.
- Yes. Of course.
I just thought maybe after
Her Magnificent Incandescence
was returned to this manly and
painfully handsome assemblage,
you might have noticed
something interesting.
A Key in human form, perhaps?
Lounging about unattended?
- If I did, do you really think I would tell you?
- Why do you fight the inevitable?
No one can stand against
Her Blindingly Scrumptious Luminescence.
Glory. Her name is Glory,
and she's your god, you little scab, not mine.
With all due respect
and fear of sharp objects,
you exist, sir,
only because of Her Divine Greatness.
You mean Her Divine Failure, don't you?
I didn't ask for any of this.
I just wanna be normal.
We play the hand we're dealt.
Nothing's mine, is it?
This life, this body, it's all infected.
The only thing I've ever cared about,
she's taken away from me.
- You know why I wanted to be a doctor?
- Flattering drawstring pants?
To be close to people. To witness their lives
and their deaths, to be there alongside them,
a part of everyday humanity.
- Maybe it's the drugs.
- Drugs, sir?
Find the right combination, keep her buried.
Impossible. Her Magnificence
can never be fully contained.
She is a perfect, all-encompassing light, one
you should feel honoured to be bathed in.
I'm thrilled. Especially with the part where
she gets her Key back and I cease to exist.
True, this oh-so-appealing form
will of necessity be shrugged off.
- Not if I get the Key first.
- And if you did, what then?
Could you do it?
Take a human life with your own hands?
Oblivion is such a small inconvenience
in the service of a deity. Accept your fate.
I mean, you said it yourself. This life
was never really yours anyway, was it?
It doesn't matter how I came by it.
It's mine. And I plan on keeping it.
- Anybody else feel that?
- What?
- Cold draught of paralysing fear.
- We just need to stay calm.
- Calm. Right.
- We gotta be like Sergeant Rock.
Cool and collected
in the face of overwhelming odds.
Overwhelming? How much more
than whelming would that be exactly?
Everything will be all right, we just need to
stay here calmly. As soon as Buffy arrives...
we'll feel oddly worse.
- What's he doing here?
- Just out for ajaunt.
- Thought I'd swing by and say howdy.
- Out.
- He's here because we need him.
- The hell we do.
He's the only one besides me
with any chance of protecting Dawn.
- Buffy, come on...
- Look, this isn't a discussion. He stays.
Get over it.
Buckle up, kids.
Daddy's puttin' the hammer down.
Sign here.
OK, that should do it.
See? Did I not tell you
how easy it would be for us to...
My pen.
The trees are singing water.
- You have him.
- Yes, General.
- Our brother has returned to the fold.
- Welcome home, Orlando.
I swear by my sword
your sacrifice will not go unavenged.
Shiny.
Yes, I suppose it is.
Pretty little girl, she's shiny too.
Watch him, make sure he's comfortable.
So shiny.
Pretty little shiny Key.
The Key? You've seen it?
Pretty little shiny girl.
The monks, they've made it human.
We know the Slayer's protecting the Key.
If what Orlando says is true...
- Prepare to advance.
- Yes, sir.
We end this now.
Shouldn't somebody be asking
"Are we there yet"?
Isn't that what
small irritating children do?
That kinda only works
if you know where you're going.
Do we know where we're going yet?
We'd be somewhere if Captain Slowpoke
would give up the wheel.
Gramps, bloody step on it.
Step on what?
I've driven tricycles with more power.
- Is anybody else queasy?
- He doesn't travel well. He's like fine shrimp.
I should've nicked that Porsche. There's
just enough room for me, you, and big sis.
- What?
- Would you give it a rest, or...
- Or you'll toss your cookies on my shoes?
- Or you can be undead man walking.
See how fast you can hitch a ride
with a flaming thumb.
Fine. Shrimp.
That guy is bloodsuckin'
the last nerve outta me.
Well, Buffy has a point.
In a confrontation, Spike may prove...
useful.
I don't know if Buffy's thinkin' too clear
on that one, or anything else right now.
- I've never seen her so...
- She's been through more than her fair share.
She just needs a chance
to catch her breath, regroup.
- She'll be all right.
- Yeah. She'II...
Yeah.
Any luck?
If you define luck
as the absence of success, plenty.
There's a couple of barrier spells,
but they only work on fixed locus.
I haven't found anything
that'll work while we're moving.
So pretty. Can I have one?
Come on.
- Anyone hungry?
- Snacks.
The secret to any successful migration.
Who's up for some tasty fried meat products?
Tara, no. What did I tell you?
I'm sorry. She didn't mean to.
She doesn't know what she's doing.
- We know.
- No biggie.
The skin's already stopped smokin'.
You go ahead and play peekaboo
with Mr Sunshine all you like.
Keeps the ride from getting boring.
All the light's gone.
No, baby. The light's still outside, OK?
All dark. All dark.
- Dark.
- All dark.
Soon.
Soon. Soon.
It's coming. The signs are in alignment.
Soon victory will be in our grasp.
All we need do is seize the moment
and squeeze until it bleeds.
Hey.
I think Anya's gonna try to cook.
Wanna come watch
the tears and recriminations?
Maybe later.
Thanks.
For what?
You know. Pretty much everything.
Yeah. I'm doin' a greatjob.
You are.
I'm the Slayer. The Chosen One.
All mythic and defender-y.
Evil nasties are supposed to flee from me.
Not the other way around.
You're not fleeing.
You're moving at a brisk pace.
Quaintly referred to in some cultures
as the big scaredy runaway.
It's the most amazing thing
anyone's ever done for me.
Itjust keeps coming.
Glory,
Riley,
Tara,
Mom.
I know.
But there's a bright side.
- There is?
- At least things can't get any crazier. Right?
You know this is your fault for saying that.
Armando.
Bring up the ranks. Advance.
- Giles.
- I see them.
See who?
Arrows. They're throwing arrows.
Dawn, get down under the table.
Horsies.
Tara.
- Weapons?
- Hello. You're driving one.
- Don't hit the horsies.
- We won't.
Aim for the horsies.
Did we shake 'em?
Stay low.
Watch out for...
Now might be a good time
for something heroic.
Xander. Hatch.
Up.
- Keep the pressure on.
- I always do, sweet bit.
Not a piano, but hey.
Everyone all right?
- We gotta find shelter.
- Yeah, bloody quick. I'm burnin' up out here.
Careful.
Spike.
Careful. Up.
- OK. Will?
- I'm on it.
Careful.
- Are you sure you're OK?
- Yeah. But Spike's hurt.
- Easy with the delicates.
- They'll heal.
Florence bloody Nightingale to the rescue.
You have a plan, right? One that doesn't
involve pointy knives and a Winnebago?
We'll rest here for a minute,
then we have to move.
- Where?
- I don't know.
We can't stay here. It's too close to the wreck.
We're too easy to find.
- Buffy.
- Will, how is he?
- Will?
- I think I've slowed the bleeding, but...
OK, just give me a minute.
Dawn, get down.
We got company.
And they brought a crusade.
- Willow.
- I'm working on it.
Go. Come on, let's move.
Come on, move it.
Buffy.
The Key.
Enemies, fly and fall.
Circling arms, raise a wall.
They have the General. Clerics.
- Energy barrier. A most powerful one.
- Can it be breached?
The witch's magic pales
to the might of our god.
The infidel's wall shall tumble before us.
Will? How long will it hold?
Half a day, maybe.
Or until Heckle and Jeckle
punch a hole through it.
So, what's the story
with these role-playing rejects?
Let's find out.
You sure Scarface can habla the English?
He understands me.
Don't you?
- You were warned we would return, Slayer.
- Took you long enough.
What are you supposed to be,
some kind of chief?
General.
In charge of what, getting captured?
You do not frighten me, child.
The instrument of chaos must be destroyed.
Look at her that way again,
and she will be the last thing you ever see.
As I've been told,
you protect the Key of the Beast.
- It's not that simple.
- Yes.
The Key has been transformed,
given breath, life.
Yet this makes no difference.
The Key is the link.
The link must be severed.
Such is the will of God.
She doesn't remember anything
about being this Key you're all looking for.
The only thing she remembers is growing up
with a mother and a sister that love her.
What kind of god would demand her life
for something that she has no control over?
We are not your enemy.
Tell your men to stand down.
No.
It is not her fault. She's human now.
The Key is too dangerous
to be allowed to exist,
no matter what form it has been pressed into.
I will not let anyone tell me...
- What happened?
- I don't know. She just went nuts.
Time. Time. Time.
Tara?
Tara.
We have to do something.
She can'tjust stay this way.
- Buffy.
- Time. Time. Time.
Time. Time.
No, it's not time for your med.
Just lie back and...
- Doctor. Doctor McCarthy.
- Time.
- It's time.
- No.
There's nothing to fear, my brother.
The Beast may have taken your mind,
but I swear to you,
she will never know the taste of your heart.
Clerics.
I want the witch's barrier down.
Now.
- I'm sorry.
- What for?
We should've stayed.
If we had, none of this would have happened.
Don't.
What you did was necessary.
What I've always admired.
Running away?
Being able to place your heart above all else.
I'm so proud of you.
You've come so far.
You're everything a watcher...
everything I could have hoped for.
Willow.
Open a door.
Speak.
- My friend was hurt when you attacked us.
- Ten of my men are dead. Honourable men.
Shall we balance the scale?
Will you let someone
come and help him or not?
Give quarter to an agent of the Beast?
What madness
would move me to such action?
- I'm done asking.
- Whoa.
This is war, isn't it?
And if there's one thing I've learned from
Sergeant Rock, it is in war, there are rules.
Or at least there should be, if you're
as honourable as you think you are.
Plus, we do have
your General Forehead Guy.
Discharge and bring life.
Handier than a Swiss knife.
Look, the door to my crypt's got
this nasty squeak, maybe you could...
Hey. It's Buffy.
I need to ask you a really big favour.
You forgot to mention
the costume party outside.
Sorry. I didn't know who else to call.
No, it's OK. I mean, yeah,
not how I pictured seeing you again,
but I'll take what I can get.
Thank you for coming.
My pleasure.
I think I got him stabilised, but there's a lot
of damage. We need to get him outta here.
I think the guys with the pointy swords
kinda have other ideas.
Don't they always.
I know this must seem
extra Outer Limits to you.
I've seen things you wouldn't believe.
You know, emergency room,
full moon on a Saturday night.
Look, if this gets too weird,
just tell me. I'll understand.
Don't worry about me. I won't leave
until I've worn out my welcome.
Thanks.
You know, those things'll kill you.
Oh. Right.
I mention today how much I don't like you?
Might've let it slip in once or twice.
How're your feelers?
It's nothing compared to the little bits we'll
get chopped into when they kick the door in.
- And here we bloody sit.
- It's not like we got much of a choice.
We could make a break for it. Use General
Armour-All as a shield, get to the doc's car...
Great plan. While all the hacking and
slashing's goin' on, what are you gonna do?
- Throw migraines at 'em?
- Look, we stay here, we all die.
- At least this way, some of us might get...
- No. We're all gonna make it.
I'm not losing anyone.
Check the supplies. See if anyone's hungry.
Dissension in the ranks.
Seldom a harbinger of glad tidings.
Shut up.
Poor frightened girl.
You've no idea what
you've gotten yourself into.
- Why don't you tell me?
- Would it make a difference?
What do you know of the Beast?
Strong. Fast. Hell god.
- From a dimension of unspeakable torment.
- A demon dimension. I know.
She ruled with two other Hell gods.
They were a triumvirate of suffering
and despair. Ruling with equal vengeance.
But the Beast's power grew beyond
even what they could conceive.
As did her lust for pain and misery.
They looked upon her,
what she had become, and trembled.
- A god afraid?
- Such was her power.
They feared she would attempt to seize
their dimension for herself,
and decided to strike first.
A great battle erupted.
In the end,
they stood victorious over the Beast.
Barely. She was cast out.
Banished to this lower plane of existence,
forced to live and eventually die
trapped within the body of a mortal.
A newborn male, created as her prison.
That is the Beast's only weakness.
Kill the man and the god dies.
Unfortunately, the identity of
the human vessel has never been discovered.
I don't understand. I've seen Glory. Not
a lot goin' on in the hairy-chest department.
You have seen a glimpse of the true Beast.
Her power was too great to be contained.
She's found a way to escape
her mortal prison for brief periods
before her energies are exhausted and she's
forced back into her cell of meat and bone.
What about me?
- What about the Key?
- Dawn.
- I want to know.
- The Key is almost as old as the Beast itself.
Where it came from, how it was created:
the deepest of mysteries.
All that is certain is that its power is absolute.
Countless generations of my people
have sacrificed their lives in search of it,
to destroy it
before its wrath could be unleashed.
- But the monks found it first.
- Yes, and hid it with their magics.
Why didn't they just destroy it?
If it's so dangerous...
They were fools. They thought they could
harness its power for the forces of light.
They failed, and paid with their blood.
What do I do?
What was I created for?
You were created to open
the gates that separate dimensions.
The Beast will use your power to return home
and seize control of the Hell
she was banished from.
That's it?
That's Glory's master plan? To go home?
You misunderstand.
Once the Key is activated, it won'tjust
open the gates to the Beast's dimension.
It's going to open all the gates.
The walls separating realities will crumble.
Dimensions will bleed into each other.
Order will be overthrown
and the universe will tumble into chaos.
All dark. For ever.
That is what you were created for.
Dawn.
You think it's true?
What he said?
I don't know.
Destroyer of the universe.
Guess cutting school
doesn't seem so bad now.
It's not you. You know that.
But it's in me, isn't it?
It's inside me.
What are we gonna do?
I won't let anything happen to you.
I promise.
Wriggling.
Come on, Tara, you have to eat something.
- Want me to try?
- I don't know.
I'm gettin' used to pickin' food out of my hair.
You.
You are not a part of this, are you?
- Just a friend of the family.
- Would you die for them?
That is what will happen if you align yourself
with the Slayer and her misguided people.
It's my life, and I'll do what I please with it.
It's notjust your life.
Unimaginable legions will perish,
including everyone here.
You can stop this.
You can save all their lives by ending one.
The little girl.
The Key. Destroy it, and the will of the Beast
will be broken, she will fade.
A distant memory.
And all of this madness will end.
- Sorry.
- Is...
- Is he gonna be OK?
- He was hurt pretty bad, Dawn.
It's because of me.
- It's all my fault.
- No, it isn't.
You don't know what's happening.
I don't have to.
I just know that sometimes
terrible things happen to good people.
It shouldn't, but it does.
It's nobody's fault.
It's just the way life is.
Is that gonna help?
Ben?
- You have to let me out.
- Ben?
- I gotta get out. Open a door now.
- What happened?
- I don't know, he just freaked out.
- Let me out.
- OK. Will, open a door.
- No.
What do you know?
Little Ben finally did something right.
The Beast.
Hey, it's Gregor.
Now it's not.
Buffy.
- The Beast. Prepare to attack.
- Great.
Attack.
Dawn.
Willow. Get it down, now.
Hear my plea.
Circling arms protecting me.
We have to...
The Beast.
The car. Get the keys.
Buffy, we have to find Dawn.
We can't let Glory...
Buffy. Buffy.
Buffy, you have to get up. We need you.
Buffy, please.
Buffy...
Visiontext Subtitles: Kerrie Slavin
ENGLISH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org