- I'm a werewolf in love.
- Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
Oz, don't you love me?
The wolf is inside me all the time.
Until I figure out what that means,
I shouldn't be around you, or anybody.
The Initiative made it.
They can't stop it, but we will.
The implant works.
Hostile 17 can't harm any living creature.
I get this chip out,
we're gonna have a confrontation.
I just like having something that's mine.
I am, you know - yours.
- Do you like cats?
- I'm more of a dog person myself.
But I'm not, like, "Death to all cats." Why?
- Cos I was thinking of getting one.
- Can you have one in dorms?
No, but this would be a sneaky cat.
That would be cool.
You mean it'd be, sort of like a familiar?
Actually, I was thinking
it'd be sort of like a pet.
You know, we could name her Trixie
or Miss Kitty Fantastico or something.
And we could make Kitty
go bonkers with string and catnip?
- Absolutely.
- Fun. I'm in.
- So you're not allergic or anything?
- Nope.
Good, cos I want my room
to be Willow-friendly.
Me, too.
So, I'm excited about the
Scooby meeting. I think.
- What's it about?
- I'm not sure.
Probably just your garden-variety disaster.
Zippo. Patrol's been totally uneventful.
My kill count's way down.
She means there's been less bad-guy activity.
- We know what that often indicates.
- Buffy doesn't make her quota? Bad slayer.
I wish it were that innocuous, but with
Adam around I feel he's involved somehow.
When things get slow it's usually
because there's extra evil brewing.
But the weird thing is,
we've been busy at the Initiative.
Our squads have got demons
coming out our ears.
- That's a metaphor.
- I got it, thanks.
I'm overhelping, aren't I?
So the activity's shifted, not stopped.
- It's fascinating.
- To an extremely bored person maybe.
Well, that was a thrilling hour.
I don't appreciate your snide remarks, Anya.
I have a lot of experience.
If I say a matter of import is brewing, I...
Hey.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Oz.
When... when did you get back?
Pretty much now.
Oz. Man... Hate to sound grandma,
but you don't call, you don't write.
Yeah. Sorry.
So are you here here,
orjust passing through?
Let's not bombard the poor chap
with questions right off.
Can I get you something? Tea perhaps?
I'll pass. Thanks.
Look, I'm going to Devon's to see
if he's got a place I can crash, but
I was hoping that we could talk.
Later.
Tonight?
I guess so.
I'll come by your place?
OK.
It's great to see you guys again.
Really.
Everyone's uncomfortable now.
- You OK?
- I...
I just... I realised I'm late for study group.
- Tara, wait.
- No, no, it's OK.
You should be with your friends,
and... and I should go.
But...
So, I was missing something
this afternoon, wasn't I?
Break-ups are tough, but when Oz walked in
it seemed emotions were running extra high.
Oz and Willow had a rough break-up.
Hold that thought.
Man. That was record time.
- It's no fun when they're that easy.
- Speak for yourself.
Base, this is Agent Finn. We've an HST down.
Please send a retrieval team to sector 72.
We're swamped here.
We'll get to it as soon as we can.
So, I was about to say something fascinating.
- Oz and Willow.
- Right.
They had a rough break-up.
Some stuff came up
and Oz pretty much bailed overnight.
It left Will really devastated.
I remember.
Before that they were doing great.
She was dealing with Oz being a werewolf...
Whoa. Back up there.
Oz is a werewolf
and Willow was dating him?
- Yes. Hence the high emotions.
- You're kidding me.
Gotta say, I'm surprised.
I didn't think Willow was that kind of girl.
- What kind of girl?
- Into dangerous guys.
- She seems smarter than that.
- Oz is not dangerous.
Something happened to him
that wasn't his fault.
God, I never knew you were such a bigot.
Whoa. Hey. How did we get to bigot?
It's just weird to date
someone who tries to eat you.
Yeah, well, love isn't logical, Riley.
It's not like you can be Mr Joe Sensible
about it all the time.
God knows, I haven't been.
I'm not talking about you.
How about we don't talk about this at all?
OK? Let's just patrol.
Hey.
So,
you wanna come inside?
Actually, I want you to come outside.
I wanna show you something.
Oz.
This is all so weird.
I feel like
this isn't really happening.
Like it's a dream or something.
It's real.
Look up.
- What?
- Look at the sky.
I guess you stopped keeping track after I left.
Full moon.
Full moon, but how?
I mean, you did it.
How did you do it? Where did you go?
It's a long story.
My God, Oz.
This is...
I mean, that's wonderful for you.
I talked to Xander, and he said
you didn't have a new guy.
No.
No new guy.
I know what I put you through,
and I'm not gonna push.
But I am a different person than when I left.
And I can be what you need now.
That's what I want.
That's why I'm here.
This is sector 27. We're all clear.
Sir.
I love this.
A woman in Tibet traded it to me
for the Radiohead record.
Got a lot of mileage out of the barter system.
So, Tibet was your favourite?
Well, it's where I stayed the longest.
A warlock in Romania sent me to the monks
there to learn some meditation techniques.
Very intense.
All about keeping your inner cool.
Good, cos you were such a spaz before.
So that's it?
You keep your cool and no more wolfie?
No, there's more. I take some herbs and stuff.
Some chanting. A couple of charms.
It's incredible.
You've been all around the world.
You've had this complete
mind/body transformation.
I've just been here. Same old Sunnydale.
- Doesn't mean you've not gone through a lot.
- It's true.
Some of it, you know, was me telling myself
I hated you and cursing your name.
- Not literally.
- Thanks for that.
And, I don't know, I...
I think I'm getting better
at my spells and stuff.
- It's so light out.
- Yeah, we talked all night.
I believe a manly-sized breakfast
is in order, don't you?
Or we could just sleep a little while.
Whatever you want.
I'll have the less confusing waffles right now.
Breakfast it is.
Let me just freshen up.
- Oh... Sorry, I'll come back.
- Are you looking for Willow?
- She's just in the bathroom down the hall.
- No, no. No, it's OK.
- I saw you at Giles' yesterday.
- Yeah.
Sometimes Willow
takes me with her to the Scoobies.
Are you sure you don't wanna come in?
- What?
- Your friend came by. The blonde girl.
But she wouldn't stay.
So what do you think?
Where do you wanna go?
- Morning.
Are those, like, regulation?
Do you have to do those every morning?
No. It's just a good way to start the day.
Then you can have your perfectly balanced
breakfast, and then you can call your mother.
OK, I've been up less than a minute
and somehow I've managed to piss you off.
- I should go home.
- No.
Come on.
Is it that whole thing about Willow last night?
Look, I only said what I said because
I'm concerned. I don't wanna see her get hurt.
You sounded like Mr Initiative:
"Demons bad, people good."
Something wrong with that theorem?
There's different degrees of...
Evil?
It's just different with different demons.
There are creatures - vampires, for example -
that aren't evil at all.
Name one.
Rye, we need you downstairs.
- The Beta team got hit.
- Bad?
We lost Willis.
- Graham?
- He's walking.
We're going on a hunt.
What kind of demon was it?
Does it matter?
- Hey.
You OK?
Yeah, I just...
I don't wanna talk about it.
I wanna hear about you and Oz.
You saw him, right?
- I was with him all night.
- All night? Oh, my God.
Wait.
- Last night was a wolf moon, right?
- Yep.
- Either you're gonna say something kinky...
- No kink.
He didn't change, Buffy.
He said he was gonna find a cure
and he did. In Tibet.
Oh, my God. I can't believe it.
OK, I'm all with the whoo-hoo here
and you're not.
No, there's "whoo" and "hoo".
But there's "uh-oh" and "why now?"
And it's complicated.
Why complicated?
It's complicated because of Tara.
You mean Tara has a crush on Oz?
No, you...
Um,...
Well...
That's great. You know, I mean,
I think Tara's a really great girl, Will.
She is.
And there's something between us.
It wasn't something I was looking for.
It's just powerful.
And it's totally different
from what Oz and I have.
Well, there you go. I mean,
you have to... you have to follow your heart,
Will. And that's what's important, Will.
Why do you keep saying my name like that?
Like what, Will?
Are you freaked?
What? No, Will...
No.
No. Absolutely no to that question.
I'm glad you told me.
- What did you say to Oz?
- I was gonna tell him,
but then we started hanging out and
I could just feel everything coming back.
He's Oz, you know?
Yeah. I know.
I don't wanna hurt anyone, Buffy.
No matter what, somebody's gonna get hurt.
And the important thing is you just have
to be honest, or it's gonna be a lot worse.
From the sound of those massive
mud flaps, I'd peg you as a demon,
which means you're in for a world of
pain.
Spike, I want you to come with me.
Do you? Well, let's go then.
Come.
- You're going to help me with my problem.
- Why's that exactly?
I am going to help you with yours.
Hi.
I can only stay for a minute. I have class.
Me, too. I have class, too.
I just want you to know that
what you saw this morning, it wasn't...
No, it's OK. I always knew
that if he came back...
We were just talking. Nothing happened.
Really?
But, you know, it was intense, just talking.
We have a lot to talk about.
I kinda feel like my head's gonna explode.
Whatever, you know, happens,
I'll still be here. I'll still be your friend.
Of course we'll be friends.
That's not even a question.
But I'm saying, I know what Oz means to you.
How can you, when I'm not even sure?
I mean, I know what he meant to me.
But he left and everything changed.
I changed, and then we...
What?
I don't know. I just... Life was starting
to get so good again, and
you're a big part of that.
And here comes the thing
I wanted most of all, and
I don't know what to do.
I wanna know, but I don't.
Do what makes you happy.
Willow.
Hey.
I thought I sme... heard Willow.
You're... you're coming
back to school here, huh?
Pretty much feeling oddly motivated.
That's...
That's great.
I mean, that's great for you and Willow, right?
- I hope so.
- Good. That's... Because...
Is that her sweater?
I just hope that you guys'll be very happy.
You smell like her.
She's all over you, d'you know that?
I can't. I... I can't talk about this.
But there's something to talk about?
- Are you two involved?
- I have to... I have to go.
Because she never said anything to me.
We talked all night, and she never...
No, stop.
Is she in love with you?
Tell me. Is she?
Run.
- Are you OK?
- What's going on?
Looks like one of the demons
that took out Graham's guys.
We'll take it back and make an ID.
- If it is, we'll put him down.
- You don't understand...
Listen, we know what we're doing.
You're in shock.
- But...
- We'll handle it.
No.
Well, that sounds like a lot of fun.
You see my problem, though. Total
annihilation of the humans doesn't help me.
- I'll need heavy casualties on both sides.
- I get that.
- I'm still not sure how the Slayer fits in.
- The humans need a leader. A champion.
The Slayer can do that.
Yeah...
The thing about the Slayer is, she is whiny,
but when it comes to the fighting
she does have a tendency to win.
Then I guess you should be on her side.
This all goes down,
the chip comes out, yeah? No tricks?
Scout's honour.
- You were a Boy Scout?
- Parts of me.
What's up? You OK?
Oz. We were talking
and he changed right in front of me.
- What? It's daylight.
- I know, but it happened.
- Oh, my God. Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
Riley and the commando guys
stopped him, but they don't know it's Oz.
- I tried to tell them, but they took him away.
- When? Just now?
- I think they might hurt him.
- I have to go find Buffy.
I know.
Tara said they took him,
right before she found me.
So that's good, right? I mean, they probably
haven't had time to eviscerate him yet.
An, you can help by making this a quiet time.
Again we're faced with the prospect
of having to infiltrate the Initiative.
It'd be great if we knew someone dating
a man on the inside, with connections. Wait.
He's still not answering his pages.
I left him another message.
- So what do we do?
- We need to move fast.
So we make a plan without Riley
and hope he calls.
What's the word?
Is this the animal that took apart our men?
- We don't know yet.
- Why the delay? Graham gave a description.
He described characteristics present
in over 40 known varieties of demon.
- So we're crosschecking DNA evidence...
- And how long's that gonna take?
I have no idea.
I don't need a bunch of tests
to know that this thing's a killer.
- Hey, he's coming to. Oz.
- We gave him Haldol to keep him quiet.
- Why? He's not a threat now.
- You only stay if you let us do our work.
Only Colonel McNamara can place a cease
order on medical testing. He said proceed.
I always suspected werewolf transformations
being based on a lunar cycle was just talk.
That's enough. He's a student. I know him.
- Take him out.
- Yes, sir.
Let's go.
See that? Transformation
related to negative stimulation.
Something's wrong.
Riley usually returns my calls by now.
- We can't wait much longer.
- I know.
OK. Xander, you and I are gonna go in.
We've done it before.
- I'm going with you.
- No. It's too dangerous, Will.
You need to help Giles hack into the
electrical grid and power down the Initiative.
Giles can do it without me. I can give him all
the instructions, I can show him what to do.
- Of course.
- I can'tjust sit here.
OK.
OK, you can back us up.
You get into the Initiative via the elevator in
the Lowell House, but my clearance is gone.
- So we grab a guy, make him take us.
- Or you could just use the back way.
- Hell of a lot less bother.
- How did you get in?
The door was unlocked.
You might wanna watch that.
Someone dangerous could get in.
Or someone formerly dangerous
and currently annoying.
Now, now. None of that.
Or I won't help you get Red's mongrel back.
Bad news travels fast with us demons.
We all like a good laugh.
Short of cash, Spike?
I happen to be seeking
monetary gratification, yeah.
But I also get a kick out of
jacking up those army ginks myself.
I know how to find the big guy
who can take you to Oz.
Uh-huh. So what's the going rate
on a wild-goose chase, Spike?
Fine, if you're not interested.
But I was stuck in that hole, and I've
heard things from guys who've gotten out.
I can get you in. No alarms,
no cameras, no waiting.
Oz.
Put these on, man.
Come on.
End of the line.
At ease.
- Permission to speak, Colonel.
- Denied.
Being new around here, Finn, I had a look
at your record and Professor Walsh's notes.
Until recently you were
an exemplary soldier headed for the top.
Then you meet this girl, this slayer, and
suddenly begin to exhibit signs of disloyalty.
You abuse your command.
But tonight?
To release a lethal HST
back into the population...
- Sir, the prisoner...
- You will speak when I tell you to.
Tomorrow I'll institute a court martial
to investigate your involvement
with the Slayer and her band of freaks.
They're anarchists, Finn.
Too backwards for the real world.
You help us take them down
and you just might save your military career.
Otherwise, you'll go to your grave
labelled a traitor.
No woman's worth that.
I mentioned I'd kill you
if this is a scam, right?
- Look, would I wear this if it was?
- You do sort of look like an evil olive.
Guys? Check it out.
For a nasty town like Sunnydale,
nobody seems to mind their locks.
You first.
Try tapping in "XH4J7" for
the emergency shutdown command.
That covers the entire electrical grid
for the university and outlying area.
Slap my hand now.
- Beg your pardon?
- In celebration.
Yes.
You know who I am?
- Yeah.
- Then you know I'm pretty good with this.
Take us to him.
Finn stays in the brig.
Helping an HST escape is a court-martial
offence. You'll make matters worse.
Riley tried to help Oz escape?
That's who you came for.
- The wolf.
- Guess we're two for one.
Get dressed.
Hey, you dropped...
- How'd you get in?
- Talk later. Stealthy escape now.
Buffy.
I leave now, I can't ever come back.
I just wanted to hear that out loud.
Hold it.
Stay back, or I'll pull a "William Burroughs"
on your leader here.
You'll bore him to death with free prose?
Was I the only one awake
in English that day?
I'll kill him.
Get him out.
- Oz.
- Willow, get back.
Let's go.
You're a dead man, Finn.
No, sir.
I'm an anarchist.
I hope everybody else is OK.
It was better to split up, right?
I mean, we're just too findable in a big clump.
It was better. Besides, I think
it's mostly me the Initiative wants now.
Probably.
So what shall we do?
We'll be safe for tonight at least.
The camps are still blacked out,
so that oughta slow the Initiative down.
I'll figure out my next move tomorrow.
Quite a day, huh?
You woke up to a big bowl of Wheaties.
Now you're a fugitive.
I don't know.
I'm sorry it ended that way,
but I am glad it's done.
I'm glad I know where I stand, finally.
I was wrong about Oz. I was being a bigot.
No, you weren't.
You were thrown.
You found out that Willow was in kind of
an unconventional relationship, and
it gave you momentary wiggins.
It happens.
Still, I was in a totally black-and-white space -
people versus monsters. And it ain't like that.
Especially when it comes to love.
I have to tell you some stuff, about my past.
And it's not all stuff that you're gonna like.
You can tell me anything.
I think so.
I think I can.
This thing looks pretty good,
considering you drove it overseas.
Well, it broke down outside of Mexico.
I traded my bass
to have it fixed and garaged.
I shouldn't have come back now.
I just thought I'd changed.
You have changed.
You stopped the wolf
from coming out. I saw it.
But I couldn't look at you.
I mean, it turns out the one thing
that brings it out of me is you.
Which falls under the heading
of "Ironic" in my book.
It was my fault.
I upset you.
Well, so we're safe then,
cos you'll never do that again.
But you're happy?
I am.
- I can't explain it.
- It may be safer for both of us if you don't.
I missed you, Oz.
I wrote you so many letters.
But I didn't have any place
to send them, you know?
I couldn't live like that.
It was stupid to think
that you'd just be waiting.
I was waiting.
I feel like some part of me
will always be waiting for you.
Like, if I'm old and blue-haired and I turn
the corner in Istanbul and there you are,
I won't be surprised.
Because you're with me, you know?
I know.
But now is not that time, I guess.
No.
What are you gonna do?
I think I'd better take off.
When?
Pretty much now.
No candles?
Well, I brought one.
It's extra flamy.
- Tara, I have to tell you...
- No, I understand.
You have to be with the person you love.
I am.
You mean...?
I mean.
OK?
Oh, yes.
I feel horrible about everything I put you
through, and I'm gonna make it up to you.
Starting right now.
Right now?
Visiontext Subtitles: Natasha Cohn
ENGLISH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org