Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
You demons can't resist
a run-and-stumble, can you?
One down... one gone.
So scabby demon
got away?
Scabby demon number 2
got away.
Scabby demon number one...
Big check
in the "slay" column.
I don't like this
little "no mouth" thing.
It's disquieting.
Well, no mouth
means no teeth.
Unless they have them
somewhere else.
Giles:
Good morning, girls.
We've been researching
the mayor's forthcoming ascension.
It's pretty riveting stuff.
What do we know?
What don't we know?
Tell her, Giles.
Well, based
on the supposed date...
Graduation day... and the mayor
being impervious to harm...
I've cross-referenced...
He's a cross-referencing fool.
And I've eliminated
several possibilities.
It's not the ritual flaying
of the demon Azorath...
nor the, um...
I don't know
what's going to happen.
That was kind of
an anticlimax.
Buffy: We don't know anything?
The whole Faith-Angel thing
was for nothing?
No, no, no. Um...
if nothing else,
Angel's charade
has brought Faith's treachery
into the open...
and this information about
the ascension will prove...
useful.
Eventually, I just need
to put it together.
Terribly sorry.
I was detained.
Official Council business.
Mr. Giles, you were speaking?
I was just filling Buffy in
on my progress
regarding the research
of the ascension.
Oh. And what took up
the rest of the minute?
Touché.
Of course, my work
is unofficial.
I'm sure, however...
with the resources of the Council
at your disposal...
you will have something to add.
Well...
I am pleased to state
with certainty
that the demon Azorath
will not in any way be...
involved in...
I'm sure we'll
find out more soon.
The demon Azorath?
So, have you talked
to Angel lately?
Not really.
Seeing him bad,
even pretend-bad...
and with Faith...
he only kissed her
for the greater good.
I don't know.
To the naked eye,
it looked like fun.
Or maybe it wasn't.
Maybe... he
wasn't even tempted.
I just wish
I could be sure.
As always,
I advise you to ask.
Like he'd tell me?
Student: Hogan!
Great game, man!
Thanks.
Hogan Martin thinks
he's soooo hot!
Like we should
all be awed by him
'cause he can put
a ball in the net.
Hey, Xander.
He said my name!
He knows my name!
Hey, Willow.
- Hi.
- Um...
Look, I can't make the study session
after school today.
Um... can we do it
fifth period?
OK.
Did you finish
the reading?
Most of it.
Percy...
I'll finish it at lunch.
That's my little trooper.
I don't know
what you're doing to him.
I actually heard him
complete a sentence.
Had a clause
and everything.
Going to watch
the game, right?
Wouldn't miss it.
See you, Hogan!
Ladies.
You're going
to the game?
I didn't know
you liked basketball.
I didn't, either...
but I've really started
getting into it.
Especially now that
we're in the championships...
it's so exciting.
Too bad you're patrolling...
'cause we're all going.
Oz, Xander, everybody.
Right.
Everybody who isn't
currently Buffy.
You touched
one of the demons.
A good touch.
Not a bad touch.
Anyway, it's been
itching like crazy.
No big.
Just another problem
for the good people
at Lubriderm, right?
This the demon
in question?
In the disgusting flesh.
Hmm...
What?
It says they
can infect a host.
Infect?
Giles!
- Hmm?
- Infect?!
Oh. Uh...
"infect the host
with an aspect
of the demon."
That's all it says.
An aspect
of the demon?
That's rather terse, isn't it?
You mean
like a part of it?
There could be
any number of explanations
for your hand. I mean,
a new fabric softener
can cause irritation.
In any case,
I... I would advise
not to attempt to track
the one that got away.
Let's minimize
your exposure.
A part of the demon.
I hope it's not
the outside part.
H-O-G-A-N. It's Hogan!
Go Hogan!
Is it me, or is this
really lame?
I don't know. I usually
enjoy lameness...
and this is leaving me
kinda cold.
Well, according to
Freddy's latest editorial...
"The pep rally is a place for
"pseudo-prostitutes
to provoke men
"into a sexual frenzy...
which, when thwarted, results
in pointless athletic competition."
And the downside being?
The school paper is edging
on depressing lately.
Have you guys noticed that?
I don't know. I always
go straight to the obits.
What are you doing, Buffy?
Nothing.
Checking for horns.
Ah, you know, Buffy,
I don't even think Giles is right
about you becoming
like a demon.
I mean, he's totally burnt,
you know...
dealing with Faith
and this ascension thing.
Between you and me,
he's not doing his best work.
But what if he is right?
I'm suddenly gonna grow
this demon part...
and we don't even know
what it is.
It could be claws
or scales...
What?
Was it a boy demon?
T-O-M.
It's Tom!
Go Tom!
They really are very good.
Their spelling's improved.
You know, Oz, I look
at all this beauty...
all these healthy
young women...
and I wonder why I ever
wasted my time on Cordelia.
I mean, look at her.
She's no better-looking
than the rest of'em.
None of'em
are really my...
Oh, my God,
he's looking at her!
He's got his filthy...
adult Pierce Brosnan-y
eyes all over my Cordy.
You're a very complex man,
aren't you?
It's just I'm scared, Wil.
There's this thing in me,
and I can't find it. I can't stop it.
What if it changes me?
I mean not just
the way I look.
All of a sudden, I... I could be
something that's not me anymore.
Yeah, whoo-hoo!
Oh, sorry.
They spelled Percy...
and... and I have
to show support. He's needy.
But... But I heard what you
were saying, really...
and... and I would be
frightened, too...
but I'm sure
you're gonna be OK.
Still got a mouth.
Sorry.
It's OK.
I didn't see you...
so I should've known
you were there.
What are you doing here?
It's a dangerous time,
you know, with Faith.
Yeah, Faith.
She, well...
Faith, what can
you say about her?
I just want to make sure that you're,
you know, OK, that you're safe.
Well, the fact that
you're right here...
Does that mean
Faith's around?
Are you keeping me safe
by tracking me,
or are you tracking her?
I'm tracking you.
Something's bothering you.
A lot of things...
the most recent
being this demon... actually, 2.
I touched one of them...
and now I'm gonna get
a big case of the bumpies
or a tail or something.
Aspect of the demon.
You know the drill.
By rumor. But that
doesn't mean anything.
I mean, sometimes demons...
they just exaggerate their power.
Demon hype...
or maybe not.
I spend all my time
in the dark here anyway.
It's not like I'd be at a game,
you know, with my friends
where someone could see me
in my new monster part.
Hey.
I won't let anything happen
to you if I can help it.
And no matter what,
I'll always be with you.
Hey, I'll love you even
if you're covered with slime.
I liked everything
until that part.
Could you believe it?
Right at the buzzer,
3 points for the win.
It was intense.
Yeah, for a minute there...
I thought you were gonna
make an expression.
I felt one coming on.
I won't lie.
Man, I've never seen anyone
jump like Hogan Martin.
They should call him
"TheJumper."
Or a name that isn't an article
of women's clothing. Hey, remember...
Shh.
Hmm. Quietness.
We either lost...
or we won, and you don't
want me to feel bad.
Ooh, yeah, it wasn't
really a good game.
Yeah, tall hoops,
but then tall guys.
What's the point?
Pretty dull.
Are you guys crazy?
It was an incredible game.
I've never cheered so hard
in my life.
I still have knee marks
on my back.
From the pyramid.
Yeah, well, I still bet
patrolling was way better...
'cause, wow, important.
Well, I thought I saw
a 4-legged demon...
but it was just a dog.
Weredog?
Regular.
Tough luck.
Yeah.
Thinking: I wonder if she and
Wesley have kissed.
It really bugs you, huh?
What?
Cordelia and Wesley
smooching.
Man, you read my mind.
Ooh!
Whoa there. You watch
where you're going now.
I'm sorry, Mr. Beach. I will.
Thinking: Students. If we could just
get rid of all the students.
Boy: When I'm a software jillionaire...
and you're all
flippin'burgers...
who's the loser then?
Girl: Maybe I'll take French,
I said. How hard can it be?
French babies learn it, idiot.
Boy: I swear,
someday my pants
are gonna fall right off.
Boy: God, Buffy
is so beautiful.
I mean,
look at that body.
God...
I'd love to shove her against
that locker right now and just... Ooh!
Is this the thing,
the aspect thing?
Because I gotta say, if it is,
it is way better than a tail.
I mean, I have a hard
enough time as it is
finding jeans
that fit right.
Buffy, slow down.
I'm... I'm not even convinced
that this is genuine mind reading.
Y-Y-You're most likely
projecting your...
When I walked in
a few minutes ago...
you thought,
"Look at her shoes.
"If a fashion magazine
told her to...
she'd wear cats strapped
to her feet."
I, um...
the demons are telepathic.
I should have known.
That's why they don't need mouths.
Of course. The demons
are telepathic.
I know. You just told me.
That's why they don't
need mouths.
And you should have known.
I... This is astounding.
It was happening out
in the hallway.
Principal Snyder has Walk Like
an Egyptian stuck in his head.
And the boys of the school
are seriously disturbed.
It's weird, but, Giles,
think about it.
I mean, think
about what I could do.
It could be very useful.
You could anticipate
your opponent's every move...
turn his plans
against him.
Oh, way better than that.
Jealousy.
Buffy! Right. Very good.
Ms. Murray: Jealousy...
I knew that.
...Clearly is the tool that
Iago uses to undo Othello.
But what's his motivation?
What reason does Iago give for
destroying his superior officer?
"Cassio has my place.
'Twixt my sheets,
he's done my office. "
Well, he was passed over
for promotion.
Cassio was picked instead...
and people were saying
that Othello slept with his wife.
Buffy did the reading?
Buffy understood
the reading?
Xander: When did she study?
Was I supposed to study?
Ms. Murray's kinda hot.
I was gonna say Cassio.
Ugh! I hate her.
Any other reason?
Race!
Um, good, Nancy.
Can't overlook that.
Boy: Look at them, scrambling
for the teacher's praise
like pigeons
for old bread crusts.
Wil, who's that guy?
That's Freddy Iverson.
He writes those editorials
for the school paper. He's sardonic.
Freddy: Bread crusts.
That's deep.
I should write that down.
Ms. Murray: Cites race
as a motive.
Is there something else
at work here?
Well, he, um...
he sort of admits himself
that his motives are... spurious.
He... He does things
because he enjoys them.
It's like he's not...
he's not really a person.
He's a... the dark half
of Othello himself.
[Students React]
Wow! Whoa!
Buffy. Really. Very astute.
I said something quite
like that in my dissertation.
I know. I mean,
I agree... with that.
Yes, and doesn't that also explain
Othello's readiness to believe Iago?
Within seconds,
he turns on Desdemona.
He believes that
she's been unfaithful...
and we're all like that.
We all have
our little internal Iagos
that tell us our husbands
or our girlfriends or whatever
don't really love us.
We can never really see
what's in someone's heart.
Oh!
Oh, sorry!
Sorry about the daytime.
I just ducked out of school,
and that's when they have it.
Um... you look good.
I mean, I... I know
I saw you last night...
but sometimes things
can change real quick.
I mean, really quickly.
Listen to me.
I'm talking like Faith.
Not that she was so bad to have around,
you know, before the evil.
You know, I think
she was hurting a lot.
And some people...
protective-type people...
Might be drawn
to that, I guess.
Well, the thing about Faith...
You can't get
into my mind.
How did you...
Why not?
It's like the mirror.
The thoughts are there...
but they create
no reflection in you.
You got your aspect
of the demon.
Yeah.
Giles doesn't know how long
it's gonna last, but it's OK.
A little headachy, but...
You don't have to play games
with me, Buffy... ever.
Well, you're not exactly
"Joe, here's what I'm thinking."
So ask me.
Oh, but that would've
made sense.
What do you wanna
know about? Faith?
How I felt kissing her?
Pretending to have no soul?
Watching you suffer?
Well, since you bring it up.
I hated hurting you...
more than I could stand.
Look, the thing
about Faith... I'd understand.
You know, she has that whole
"bad girl" thing working for her.
Kissing her meant nothing.
I don't want a bad girl.
I've done that before.
I've lived a long time, Buffy,
and I'm past that.
I've been with dozens
of girls like her. More.
Oh, this honesty stuff is fun.
I mean,
there's no comparison.
In 243 years, I've loved
exactly one person.
Who?
It is me, right?
Next time just ask.
OK.
And, Buffy, be careful
with this gift.
A lot of things that seem strong
and good and powerful...
they can be painful.
Like, say, immortality?
Exactly. I'm dying
to get rid of that.
Funny.
I'm a funny guy.
She can read our minds?
Our every impulse
and fantasy?
Every one.
Oh, God.
I don't see what
this has to do with me.
I don't see what this
has to do with me.
Willow: Well, I think
it's great, right?
I mean, you enjoy your
other slayer powers.
Yeah, it'll be fun.
And did you see Nancy Doyle's face
in English class today?
Yeah.
She's hardly even
human anymore.
How can I be
her friend now?
She doesn't need me.
No, I do need you.
Cordelia: OK, what are
you talking about?
Because you are
so creepy right now.
Giles: I think
there must be
some precedence
for occurrences such as this.
I'll... I'll
research it.
Wesley, can you
give me a hand?
Of course. Where do you think
we should start?
Oz: I am my thoughts.
If they exist in her...
Buffy contains everything that is me,
and she becomes me.
I cease to exist.
Hmm.
Xander: What am I gonna do?
I think about sex
all the time. Sex. Help!
4 X 5 is 30. 5 X 6 is 32.
Naked girls. Naked women.
Naked Buffy! Oh, stop me!
God, Xander! Is that
all you think about?
Actually? Bye!
Xander has just
illustrated something.
The chances are you're
all going to be thinking
whatever you least
want Buffy to hear.
It's a question, of course,
of mental discipline.
He's right.
Look at Cordelia.
No, don't look
at Cordelia.
She's a student.
Oh, I am bad.
I'm a bad, bad man.
Excuse me.
What's it like, Buffy?
I don't know.
It's a little weird, but, look,
please don't for a second think
that don't need you,
because I do...
and I wanna share this
with you.
It's like all
these doors are opening
to all these little worlds...
and I can just walk
right inside.
Oz: No one else exists, either.
Buffy is all of us.
We think, therefore she is.
She knows so much.
She knows what Oz is thinking.
Before long, she'll know him
better than I do.
No, don't think that.
I can't help it, Buffy.
I'm sorry.
I... I just can't.
If you don't need me,
I'm gonna follow the redhead.
I guess I won't be
writing that book
winning friends
through telepathy.
Whatever. I wonder
when I can go.
Whatever. Can I go?
Excuse me. Can you hear me
thinking in here?
I could go out
into the hall.
You know what? You stay.
I'm getting a headache.
I'll go.
She is so hot.
I hate my body.
I swear, I will scream
from boredom.
No one's ever
gonna love me.
What if I never
get breasts?
I can't believe
the test is today.
Get rid of the students.
It's that easy.
What if I'm the last virgin
in the world?
He has the cutest butt.
I hate her.
Here. It's happened before.
A man in Ecuador,
quite recently.
Can we contact him?
I'd say not. He can't
communicate with anyone.
Dead?
No. He's in complete
isolation.
The power...
he can't shut it off.
It's gotta get better.
Tell me it gets better.
I hate school.
Am I normal?
When am I ever gonna
to need to know algebra?
Are you through with
the mashed potatoes?
She doesn't even
know I'm here.
I want a car so bad.
Come on. Come on.
Didn't she wear
that skirt yesterday?
She's OK.
She has the sweetest face
I ever saw.
If I stand in just
the right place...
I can sorta see
into the arm hole of her top.
The test is today.
[Buffy Hearing A Pandemonium
OfThoughts]
[Sinister Voice]
This time tomorrow...
I'll kill you all.
She's going nuts!
[Buffy Hearing Pandemonium
OfThoughts]
She touched me!
I think she's waking up.
She's OK.
Oh, thank goodness.
Xander: Her eyes are opening.
Cordelia: I'm cold.
Are you all right?
I told them not
to move you.
They probably severed
your spinal cord.
I'm OK.
Buffy?
No, really, I'm OK.
Listen, there's a killer
in the cafeteria.
See? I've been saying for years
that the lunch lady's gonna do
us all in with that mulligan stew.
I mean, what the hell's
a mulligan?
Someone was thinking it.
They thought, "This time tomorrow,
I'll kill you all."
I have to find them.
Did you recognize
a voice?
No.
Willow:
Boy or girl?
I don't know.
It was hardly human.
It was so full of anger
and pain.
[Pandemonium]
Buffy, you can't.
No, I have to find them.
Are you sure
they meant it?
Xander: Yeah, who hasn't
just idly thought
about taking out the whole place
with a semiautomatic?
I said idly.
I know the difference.
He... She... Whoever...
They meant it...
and they're gonna do it.
She looks so tired.
How horrible.
Xander: I'll bet it was Hogan.
I'm not getting
any warmer.
Shut up!
I'm sorry. Just... Could
you guys not think so loud?
Or so much?
Buffy, you should go home.
I'll take you home.
Yeah. OK. No.
I need you guys to go back
to the cafeteria.
Make a list of everyone
who's there.
We have to find the killer
before lunch tomorrow.
We'll do it, Buffy.
A list of all the students.
Yeah, Nancy was there.
She's scary.
And, oh, teachers, too.
Mr. Beach... he thought
something
about getting rid
of all the students.
I can't shut it out, Giles.
It's like this invasion
of my head.
It's like there are these strangers
walking around in there.
Look at this. I can't even be
around people anymore...
not that they're really clamoring
to be near me anyway, even you.
Well, I'm sorry, Buffy.
It's hard for all of us.
But Wesley and I are looking
for a way to help.
I'll be OK, right?
I mean, even if you
can't get rid of it?
You'll be fine.
I promise.
If it doesn't go away,
she'll go insane.
I think we have everyone
that was in the cafeteria.
I'll do some computer work;
match it against the FBI
mass murderer profiles...
see if maybe we can rule
some people out.
I'm still having trouble
with the fact
that one of us
is just gonna
gun everybody down
for no reason.
Yeah, because that never happens
in American high schools.
It's bordering on trendy
at this point.
Besides which,
Sunnydale High...
center of evil
and all that.
Let's get to work.
We have till
lunchtime tomorrow...
we hope.
There. You look better already.
Thanks, Mom.
I'm, uh, I'm just gonna
get you another pillow.
I really don't need one.
But you need
another blanket.
Mom, I'm fine.
How, uh...
about some soup?
Chicken and stars?
Mom, please,
just come sit with me.
Um... I've, uh...
I've got laundry.
Why are you...
You had sex with Giles?
It was the candy.
We were teenagers.
On the hood
of a police car?
I'll be downstairs.
You feel better.
Twice?!
OK, I've taken our list
and narrowed it down
to a dozen strong suspects.
Here are your
personalized assignments.
Ooh! I was hoping
there'd be assignments.
I think I should
work with Wesley.
You have no shame.
Oh, please. Like shame
is something to be proud of?
Be quiet!
Sorry,
but this is important.
Talk to everyone
on your list
and... and use
the sample questions.
Today, people!
Oh! Write neatly and
label your work sheets.
Fantasies are fun,
aren't they, Jonathan?
I guess.
We all have fantasies
where we're powerful and respected...
where people
pay attention to us.
Maybe.
But sometimes the fantasy
isn't enough...
is it, Jonathan?
Sometimes we have to make it
so people don't ignore us...
make them pay attention.
You know what
I'm talking about, don't you?
You w-w-want me
to pay attention?
This is
for the yearbook?
Yeah.
Personality profiles.
Can you ask it again?
Sure. Do you ever feel that you've
created a false persona for yourself
of the guy who does
everything right...
and how much of a strain does it
put on you to maintain it?
Huh. Wow. I guess...
moderate strain?
Is that a good answer?
I wanna get this right.
Yeah, that's good.
Hi, Mr. Beach.
I was just wondering...
were you planning on killing
a bunch of people tomorrow?
Oh, it's for the yearbook.
OK, so turnoffs include
smoking, insensitive men...
and Birkenstocks.
Now, your idea of the perfect
romantic evening.
Kay, let's start with you.
Freddy?
I should've just quit.
Look at him smiling...
like he thinks
I don't know about her.
She doesn't know a thing.
I can't believe
I'm getting away with this.
One more drink.
That'll do it.
20 years with that company.
You think I can't
smell her perfume?
It's just a little drink.
He shouldn't even
be the boss.
The bottle's almost empty
anyway.
I should've had a promotion
a long time ago.
Wait till next time
he comes home smelling like that.
[Thoughts Continue]
Well, seems to be
coming along all right.
Yes. Buffy's being driven mad...
we have no proof
that this is gonna work...
and it still requires the heart
of the second demon...
which we have no idea
how to get without the slayer.
Negative thinking
doesn't solve problems.
Who is going to get
the demon heart?
Berk.
Do I often imagine
classmates are spying on me
or otherwise
acting suspiciously?
Right.
Not till just now.
What?
Talk louder, dude.
I'm just saying it's
gotta be frustrating...
having this secret.
You gotta be kind of filling up
with resentment...
unexpressed rage
just waiting to burst out...
today at lunch.
What secret? Being gay?
Man, I'm out.
I'm so out I've got my grandma
fixing me up with guys.
That's, uh... nice.
But it sounds like, uh...
you're having
a rough time with it?
No.
Look...
just do it.
That weird Freddy Iverson guy
that does the school paper?
He's gay?
No, dude, but I bet
he'd put in like a...
coming-out announcement
for you.
Something tasteful.
[Knock Knock]
Freddy?
He's the only one
we couldn't find?
Yeah. Freddy Iverson.
The newspaper guy?
But we can't figure out it's him
without the work sheet, right?
We do have this, people.
Today's editorial titled "Big Game
Draws Mindless Brain-dead Mob."
Does he mention
the cheerleaders?
Because we were on.
Joyce: I can't stand this.
I keep wondering if I'm
hurting her with my thoughts.
You're not.
Not anymore.
She can't pick one thought
out of the...
out of the din.
[Banging On Door]
I got it.
No. [Groans]
I'm gonna help you.
Who?
All right.
Shh.
Giles!
Angel.
Thank God.
Are you all right?
Do you hear thoughts?
No.
Did you find the killer?
OK, Oz, you got me.
What are your friends
gonna do, hold me down?
You better believe it,
buster.
You can't threaten
a big murder
without getting us
pretty darn ticked.
Murder? What murder?
You're not here
about the review?
The review?
Yeah. Last Thursday?
"Dingoes Ate My Baby
played their instruments
as if they had plump Polish sausages
taped to their fingers."
Sorry, man.
No. It's fair.
I just get
a lot of hate mail...
and I thought you were gonna come
and deliver some personally.
Hey, if you find any tasteful
announcement about me from Larry...
Xander, we have
to figure this out.
We have no shot.
The killer could be anyone.
We lose.
Buffy: We still have
a few minutes.
- Buffy!
- You're OK!
Can you hear thoughts?
Just when I wasn't
thinking about sex.
OK. Here's the new plan.
We're gonna get Snyder
to evacuate the school...
and just hope the killer's
not waiting outside.
"By this time tomorrow
you'll all know what I've done.
"I'm sure you understand
that I had to do it...
"and that although
death is never easy...
it's the only way."
God! Doesn't anyone write in
to praise the cheerleaders?
We are so unsung.
Jonathan. Ohh!
I had him in my grasp!
Slippery weasel!
Split up. Find him.
Jonathan!
Are you in here?
Ooh.
Jell-O.
Huh. I could've done that.
Get away from me.
OK, Jonathan, you wanna
point that somewhere else?
Don't you
try and stop me.
No. No, no stopping.
Just here for the view.
Hey, look. City Hall.
Go away.
Never gonna happen.
You think
I won't use this?
I don't know, Jonathan.
I just...
Stop... doing that!
Doing what?
Stop saying my name
like we're friends.
We're not friends.
You all think
I'm an idiot.
A short idiot.
I don't.
I don't think about you
much at all.
Nobody here really does.
Bugs you, doesn't it?
You have all this pain,
all these feelings...
and nobody's really
paying attention.
You think
I just want attention?
No. I think you're up in the clock
tower with a high-powered rifle
because
you wanna blend in.
Believe it or not,
Jonathan...
I understand
about the pain.
Oh, right...
'cause the burden
of being beautiful and athletic...
that's a crippler.
You know what?
I was wrong.
You are an idiot.
My life happens to,
on occasion...
suck beyond
the telling of it...
sometimes more
than I can handle.
And it's not just mine.
Every single person down there
is ignoring your pain
because they're too busy
with their own.
The beautiful ones...
the popular ones...
the guys that pick on you.
Everyone.
If you could hear
what they were feeling...
the loneliness,
the confusion...
It looks quiet down there.
It's not.
It's deafening.
You know, I could've
taken that by now.
I know.
I'd rather do it this way.
I just wanted it to stop.
Yeah, well, mass murder?
Not really doctor recommended
for that kind of pain.
Besides, prison,
it's a lot like high school...
only instead of noogies...
What are you
talking about?
Actions having consequences.
You know, stuff like that.
Well, I...
I wouldn't ever
hurt anybody.
I came up here
to kill myself.
Rat poison!
Drop your spoons!
Step away from the spoons!
OK, let's calm down.
Vermin.
You're all vermin.
You come in here,
and you eat filth!
I don't see this being
settled with logic.
So you're feeling better
about Angel?
Well, we talked...
then he ripped out the heart
of a demon and fed it to me...
and then we
talked some more.
See? That's how
it should work.
Morning.
Hi, Giles.
Oh, I should get
to the yearbook office.
I'm gonna give 'em
the murderer profiles.
They're really
a good read.
- Bye.
- See ya.
How are you?
Nothing but quiet.
Nobody in here but me.
Jonathan. How's he?
Pretty crappy.
His parents are freaking.
He got suspended.
And toting
a piece to school...
not exactly winning him
a place with the in-crowd.
But I think he's dealing.
Well, it's good of you
to check on him.
It's nice to be able
to help someone
in a nonslaying capacity...
except he's starting
to get that look.
You know, like he's
gonna ask me to prom.
It'd probably be good
for his self-esteem if you...
Oh, come on!
What am I, Saint Buffy?
He's like 3 feet tall.
I'm glad to see you've recovered
from your psychic encounter
more or less intact.
Feel up to some
training?
Sure. We can work out
after school.
You know, if you're not too busy
having sex with my mother.
Aargh!
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org