- Previously:
- Why won't you sleep with me again?
- Because I don't love you.
- Like hell.
- Thought you were gonna go see Tara.
- She was seeing someone else.
We should have some coffee sometime.
I'm free tomorrow.
- Whoa.
- Shut it all down!
- Is that the cam in the Magic Box?
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, God. What is she...?
- That's enough.
You left me, Xander. At the altar.
I don't owe you anything!
So you go out and bang
the first body you can find?
- It's good enough for Buffy.
- Shut up and leave her out of...
Tara?
You can't just... have coffee and expect...
- I know.
- There's just so much to work through.
Trust has to be built again, on both sides.
Can we just skip it?
Can you just be kissing me now?
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
When did morning happen?
After the moon went down.
I forgot how good this could feel.
Us, together.
- Without the magic.
- There was plenty of magic.
It's getting late.
- Wanna get up?
- No.
Oh, God, no.
I was just thinking about Buffy.
Oh.
- She still isn't back?
- I didn't hear her.
She wouldn't talk about what happened at the
magic shop when she got home last night.
She just asked how close I was
to tracing the camera signal
back to the empire of the nerds.
Then she left again.
I'm sure she'll be OK.
Yeah, I'm not really worried about her
going up against Warren and the others.
I know this is gonna sound crazy, but...
I think something might be going on.
With Spike and Buffy.
I mean, she looked so hurt when
she saw him with Anya. I think maybe...
They've been sleeping together.
No. I wouldn't go that far.
No, I mean she told me
they've been sleeping together.
Sleeping together? You mean,
like, the naked kind of together?
I'm sorry I didn't say anything
but I promised her I wouldn't.
Does everybody know? Am I the only one...
God, no. She didn't even
mean to tell me. It just came out.
How could she hide
something like this from me?
I think she was afraid
of the look you'd get on your face.
- Kind of like the one you're wearing now.
- Oh, no, I'm not...
I'm just... trying to understand.
So is she.
Wow, she probably
really needs someone to talk to.
Probably.
We've been kind of busy.
Maybe we didn't hear her come home.
Buffy?
Is she back yet?
Not yet. I'm sure she'll be home soon.
- Everything's fine. Just go back to bed.
- It's ten o'clock.
Oh. Uh...
You don't think
she's gonna hurt Spike, do you?
- She told you about Spike?
- It was kinda obvious after last night.
Yeah, I totally knew.
It must have hurt so much.
To see him and Anya like that.
And poor Xander.
Everything is so screwed up.
It's gonna be all right.
It's just complicated. When people have such
strong feelings for each other, sometimes...
Is she back yet?
Oh. Hey.
You and...?
- That's my cue to go put some clothes on.
- No! I'm totally not here.
You guys, you do whatever you want.
I'll go watch TV, downstairs, really loud,
in the basement where I can't hear anything.
Oh, my God!
I love you guys!
All right! Let's make this quick.
Fine. But I'm not leaving
till we have a little chat.
Very little, considering
the pummelling that needs to occur.
I mean, guys, hello?
Slayer here. Did you honestly
think I wouldn't find you?
Well, that can't be good.
OK. That's gonna cost you.
OK, we're here, ready for action.
Bad-guy-fighting action.
Guys, you didn't have to...
You know, if you still wanna be alone.
- No. No, we're good.
- We're better than good.
- Great.
- Super.
Mm-hm.
- OK. All right, we'll stop.
- Oh, you better not.
So, nerds - how are them... they?
I found their lair but they knew
we were tracing their signal.
They left in a hurry. Van was gone,
but everything else was still there.
We should go back.
Tara and I can sherlock around.
Nothing left now. Giant buzz saw.
There was a thing.
This is all that I could save.
We need to go through it,
see if we can find anything that might tell us
what they're doing, where they're going.
This might take a while.
Anything we can do to fast-forward? We need
to find Warren before anyone else gets hurt.
Should we call Xander?
I don't think he's really in the Scooby space.
We need to give him some time.
Maybe they've heard something
in the demon bars about those guys.
- Spike...
Spike's not part of the team.
So he's not going to be around any more?
I don't know, Dawn. Not for a while.
What about Anya? She might be
able to help with the demon texts.
I'm guessing she's not feeling
real researchy right now.
I know how you feel. Maybe I can help.
How could Carl do that to me? That bastard!
He's a man. Look no further.
But with my sister? She's not even pretty.
Well, it isn't always about looks.
Or a beating heart.
Sometimes intimate sweaty relations with the
wrong person seems a good idea at the time.
She's fat. He cheated on me
with my fat, ugly sister.
Likes'em fleshy, huh?
Bet you wish he'd bloat up a few thousand
pounds and pop like a big old meat zeppelin.
He said he loved me.
Then he must've meant it, cos guys never say
anything they don't really mean, do they?
They say "l love you" and you think it's true.
They say "Oh, Anya, I wanna be with you
for the rest of my life," and you believe them.
You believe they feel the same about you
because that's the way love's supposed to be.
Who's Anya?
You get all excited, with the tingly
anticipation, but wait. Not so fast.
There's the apocalypse, the back
from the grave, the blah, blah, blah!
By the time you're standing there
in that expensive white dress
you've dreamed of since you became human,
he gets all heebie-jeebie and decides
"I'd rather just go steady."
Men suck. I wish Carl's flesh would...
He said it isn't me, but how can I believe him?
I mean, he knew he didn't wanna get married.
Deep down, he knew.
But he lied to me every day for months.
- I wish...
- He lied and lied and lied some more.
Who's gonna notice with all the other lies
flying around like monkeys?
Then he thinks he can sweep
the carnage under the rug by saying...
I'm sorry. Sorry.
I'm sorry. Sorry. Please! I'll never
try to desecrate your chamber again.
Don't hurt me. Please!
Hit him again. Hit him again!
Wow. They're tougher than I thought. One jolt
from this should have dropped an elephant.
You want a piece of this, huh?
Not so tough, are you, now, Pufnstuf?
Hey, hey, hey! We need him fresh,
all right? Not smokehouse.
I'm done being the bait. Next time
one of you can wiggle on the hook.
If this works, the next time
we'll be the thing that everyone's afraid of.
OK. So... what now?
Well, now it's your turn, Sparky.
Does it help?
Doesn't hurt.
Not planning a campout, are we?
No. I'm sleeping over at Janice's.
Figured Willow and Tara
might want some time to, uh...
So the birds are flying again, eh?
Ain't love grand?
I wanted to stop by
on my way and... you know.
Everybody's pretty mad at you.
Yeah. Kind of picked up on that.
You're not gonna be
coming around any more, are you?
It's complicated, Niblet.
Everybody's been saying that.
It must be true, then.
Was it worth it? What you did with Anya?
Buffy told you?
Kind of caught the show.
There was a camera
somewhere in the Magic Box.
Warren and Jonathan and that other guy
had been watching Buffy.
Wankers.
Do you love her?
Oh, no. No.
It was just a...
It was a bad day. For both of us.
We just had a few drinks, and things just...
No. Not Anya.
Buffy.
Do you really love her?
Then how could you do that to her?
Oh, right, cos big sis was treating me
so well up until that point.
Must still be a bit of the evil
left in me after all.
I don't know what happened
between you two.
But what you did last night...
If you wanted to hurt Buffy, congratulations.
It worked.
This is it. We found it.
- You sure it's in there?
- Be careful.
Only Nezzla demons
can pass through the barrier.
- Everything else gets curly-fried.
- This sucks.
- Just make sure all your skin's covered.
- Why can't I just use a glamour?
You can't Siegfried-and-Roy the barrier.
It's gotta be the real deal.
- It's still wet.
- Good. Then it should still be fresh enough.
"Should be"? Wait a minute, what do you
mean? What do you mean, "should be"?
Wasn't sure that would work.
Jackass.
- You think he knows?
- Well, if he did, why would he be here?
Why is he? Our mojo's tight, bro.
We could've pulled this ourselves.
Well, somebody had to guinea-pig
the meat suit. Were you gonna volunteer?
- I don't trust that leprechaun.
- Stay frosty.
This works the way we planned it, by the end
of the evening Jonathan won't be a problem.
- You got it?
- Yeah, I got it.
- That's it?
- Better be.
No way I'm going back through there.
That thing stings like a mother.
- Dude, unholy hair gel.
- Get off.
- Make me, skin job.
- Shut up.
Gentlemen, the Orbs of Nezzla'khan.
Strength. Invulnerability. The deluxe package.
They're everything I've ever dreamed of.
Those things have been there for a zillion
years. How do we know they'll still work?
Oh, they work.
You don't look any different. I thought they
were supposed to make us all huge and veiny.
- Are you sure they're working right?
- Let's find out.
- Mahatma!
- Welcome to the show, boys.
- That was so hot.
- Let me try'em!
- Watch the paws, little man.
- Ow!
- We're supposed to share.
- Oh, relax.
You'll each get a whirl.
Soon as I'm done playing with'em.
Hey.
I think there's a cold one in the fridge.
Thanks, but I think
it's still a little early for me.
She loves you. You know that.
Anya was just...
She was hurting.
She was hurting and she did
this really stupid thing.
With your boyfriend.
He's not my boyfriend.
I know why Anya...
I understand, I do.
But you...
All those times I told Spike to get lost.
That he didn't have a chance
with a girl like you.
- You don't know how hard it's been.
- What, lying to me?
Being here.
After I was brought back...
You have no idea
how hard it is just being here.
- You could have told me.
- You didn't wanna know.
So you went to him instead?
Xander, what I do with my personal life
is none of your business.
It used to be.
It just happened, OK?
Oh, like, "Say, you're evil."
"Get on me."
You fought side by side
with him when I was gone.
- You let him take care of Dawn.
- But I never forgot what he really is.
God, what were you thinking?
You're asking me that? Cos your decision-
making skills have really sparkled lately.
I'm not saying I didn't make any mistakes. But
slaughtering half of Europe wasn't one of'em.
He doesn't have a soul, Buffy.
Just some leash they jammed in his head.
You think he'd still be all snuggles
if that chip ever stopped working?
Would you still trust him with Dawn then?
It doesn't matter.
I'm not seeing him any more. It's over.
Yeah. There's a lot of that going around.
It's all a mess.
These things take time. We'll figure it out.
Sure. We'll decipher codes,
foil evil schemes...
- Finally get out of bed.
- I was with you up until there.
Whoa.
What is it?
One of their data CDs. It's filled with
encrypted blueprints, schematics.
- To what?
- I'm not sure.
Their designations have been stripped.
Maybe we can cross-reference them
with the county clerk's office.
Would that involve getting up?
- Eventually.
- Then I'm coming out firmly against it.
What about the trio's evil scheme?
Well, I'm kinda busy working on my own.
You're all wet.
- It's a good thing I'm part fish.
- Which part?
The part with the hook in it.
Careful. Someone might reel you in.
Yeah, but then there'd be
the flopping and the... gasping.
Maybe it'd work out, but chances are
I'd leave you in your white dress,
find you spawning with another fish
who's spawning my good friend
night and day behind my back.
Then comes the fighting, and again
with the flopping and the gasping.
Chicken of the Sea here's not doing
too good with the women these days.
Huh?
Sorry, I'm just looking to curl up
with the quiet alone tonight.
We don't have time for this.
Ease up, twitchy.
All right.
Let's make some noise.
Not bad. How hard you gonna hit
when you're blowing in the wind?
That was rhetorical.
Ow.
Are you hurt? You're not moving so well.
- Get out.
- We have to talk.
- I really don't.
- Well, this isn't just about you.
As much you'd like it to be.
You spoke. I listened. Now leave.
I'm sorry.
Not that it matters any more,
but I needed you to know that.
- Why?
- Because I care about you.
Then you might wanna try
not sleeping with my friends.
I didn't go to Anya for that.
I was looking for a spell.
You were gonna use a spell on me?
It wasn't for you.
I wanted something.
Anything to make these feelings stop.
I just wanted it to stop.
You should have let him kill me.
- I couldn't do that.
- Why?
- You know why.
- Because you love me.
- No, I don't.
- Why do you keep lying to yourself?
How many times do...
I have feelings for you. I do.
But it's not love. I could never
trust you enough for it to be love.
Trust is for old marrieds, Buffy.
Great love is wild,
and passionate and dangerous.
It burns and consumes.
Until there's nothing left.
Love like that doesn't last.
I know you feel like I do.
You don't have to hide it any more.
- Spike, please stop this.
- Let yourself feel it.
- No.
- You love me.
- No, stop it.
Spike, stop! Ow! What are you doing?
Ow!
Let it go. Let yourself love me.
- Buffy... Buffy...
- Spike, no. Ow! I'm hurt!
Stop! Ow! Stop it, please!
I know you felt it... when I was inside you.
No! No! No! No! No!
Ow! Ow!
Please! Please!
- Spike...
- You'll feel it again.
- Please don't do this!
- I'm gonna make you feel it!
Stop!
Ask me again why I could never love you.
- Buffy, my God, I didn't...
- Because I stopped you!
Something I should have done
a long time ago.
What are we doing here?
Somebody might recognise us.
This is great. We're risking everything
so that Charles Atlas can get a date.
He's gonna end up getting us
thrown into jail. Or worse.
- Maybe you and I should think about...
- Warren's the boss.
He's Picard, you're Deanna Troi.
Get used to the feeling, betazoid.
The clothes, and the cars, and the money,
it's all just window-dressing.
Baby, this is what's really important.
- Two souls, coming together...
- Hey!
She only comes together with me.
So get lost, shrimp.
Frankie? Oh, my God, is that you?
How long has it been?
It's Warren. Remember? Warren.
Gym class, fifth period?
You and your jock buddies
gave me such a hard time.
That thing with the underwear?
God, I thought I'd never stop crying.
- That was you?
- That was me. But, hey, no hard feelings.
I know you were just fooling around.
Like I'm gonna be with your girl
in about five minutes.
- What'd you say?
- You heard me, meathead. Go walk.
You're dead, you little...
This ain't high school.
Frankie!
Let's party.
Oh, don't worry about the tab,
now, ladies. It's on Daddy tonight.
Don't worry. Daddy gonna give you some too.
I think it's the "Daddy" thing
that's throwing her.
- Cos incest's not that sexy.
- Oh, crap.
Let's leave the ladies to their impending
nausea and move the freak show outside.
OK. But let me ask you something first.
You think you could
put in a word for me with Anya?
If she's taking it from a vamp,
I think I might have a chance.
No wonder she's screwing a dead guy.
You hit like a girl.
Well, at least I know how to get one.
- Let's see how popular you are with no face.
- We have to go.
We go when I'm ready.
Hey, it's your call, but...
we're gonna miss that thing you wanted
to do tonight if we don't leave right now.
It's your lucky night, Shemp.
We just leave him?
What if he sics the Slayer on us?
Bring her on.
Buffy? I found Warren.
Actually, my face kinda found him...
This what you call
not seeing Spike any more?
What did he do? Did he hurt you?
He tried. He didn't...
- Son of a bitch.
- Don't.
Please, just... don't.
Hey, I think we finally have something.
- What happened?
- Nothing.
What'd you find out?
We deciphered pretty much
everything except these.
It isn't written in any ancient language
we could identify.
It's Klingon. They're love poems.
Nothing to do with the insidious scheme
you're about to describe.
What have you got for me
that doesn't rhyme?
This.
It was filled with blueprints and schematics.
To what?
Banks, armoured car routes,
corporate vaults. This is big.
They're looking to score some serious dinero.
We don't think they're planning just one job.
Spree, anyone?
- I can't cover all these at once.
- You don't have to.
- We think there's one they may hit tonight.
- It's time-sensitive.
Be careful. Warren's gone all Mighty Mouse.
Emphasis on the "might".
Good. Then I won't have to hold back.
Please, stop it! Please stop!
Please don't do this! Please!
- Please!
- Buffy...
- I'm gonna make you feel it.
- Stop!
Knock, knock.
I was just in the neighbourhood
so I thought, you know...
There's a Knight Rider marathon
on the TV, so... I got hot wings!
What have I done?
Why didn't I do it?
What has she done to me?
She done... who?
Oh.
Slayer, huh? Gosh.
She break up with you again?
We were never together.
Not really.
She'd never lower herself that far.
She's a sweet girl, Spike, but hey.
Issues.
And no wonder, with the whole
coming back from the grave and whatnot.
I had this cousin who got resurrected
by some kooky shaman.
Whoo, boy! Was that a mess.
- Why do I feel this way?
- Love's a funny thing.
Is that what this is?
I can feel it.
Squirming in my head.
- Love?
- The chip.
Gnawing bits and chunks.
Maybe a wet cloth...?
You know, everything
always used to be so clear.
Slayer. Vampire. Vampire kills slayer,
sucks her dry, picks his teeth with her bones.
It's always been that way.
I've tasted the life of two slayers.
But with Buffy...
It isn't supposed to be this way.
It's the chip!
Steel and wires and silicon.
It won't let me be a monster.
And I can't be a man.
- I'm nothing.
- Hey.
Come on, now, Mr Negative. You never know
what's just around the corner. Things change.
Yeah, they do.
If you make them.
All right, that's the last one.
- Quite a haul, huh?
- Always the biggest gate of the year.
- Don't lose any.
- Yeah.
Wanna grab a bite after?
I think Rupert's is still open.
What the hell?
- There's something back there!
- I can't wait to get my hands on his orbs.
Yeah, I'm sure he'll be
giving'em up any second now.
Hey. Is this your bank?
Cos if not, there's gonna be a fee for that.
I was wondering when
Superbitch would show up.
- You got a problem with strong women?
- Nothing I can't handle.
You seem a little off. Is this a bad day?
It's gettin' better.
That all you got?
No!
There's two ways this can end. And right
now I'm thinking they're both gonna hurt.
I think you're right.
What's the matter, baby?
You never fight a real man before?
Wow. That almost hurt, kitten.
Kill her. Kill her!
- You know who I am? Huh, Slayer?
- You're a murderer.
Well, that too, but more to the point...
I'm the guy that beat you.
And it's not the muscles, baby. It's the brains.
I'll remember that
when I knock'em clean out of your...
Whoa! Sparky, I didn't think you had it in you.
Orbs! Smash his orbs!
Say good night, bitch.
Good night, bitch.
You're nothing but a sad little boy, Warren.
But it's time you grow up,
and pay for what you've done.
Get away from me. I swear to God
I'm gonna take you down, you piece of...
Oh, come on.
Well played, Slayer.
Why didn't I get one of those?
This round to you.
But the game is far from over.
Jet packs. You jerks
were setting me up to take the fall.
He left me. He flew away and left me.
Oh, God.
The big house.
How could he do this to me?
He promised we'd be together,
but... he was just using me.
He never really loved... hanging out with us.
You think he'll come back for us?
I mean... he wouldn't just take off, would he?
Get nice and comfy, Slayer. I'll be back.
And when I do, things are gonna change.
Hey. Clothes.
- Better not get used to'em.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Xander.
- OK, not quite the response I was fishing for.
No, he's here.
Think they're making up?
I hope so. That's the best part.
Time for the spring poking already?
Just making sure there are
no more evil-trio cameras.
Or evil uno.
The sinister yet addictive card game?
Warren. Jonathan and Andrew got clinked,
but... Warren pulled a Rocket Man.
You'll find him. He won't be
much good without his friends.
No, he won't.
How did we get here?
Scenic route. Long drive.
- The past few weeks...
- I know.
I thought I hit bottom, but... it hurt.
That you didn't trust me enough
to tell me about Spike.
It hurt.
I'm sorry.
I should have told you.
You would have, if I hadn't given you so
many reasons to think I'd be an ass about it.
Guess we've all done
a lot of things lately we're not proud of.
I think I've got you beat.
- Wanna compare?
- Not so much.
I don't know what I'd do...
without you and Will.
Let's not find out.
I love you. You know that, right?
Buffy!
You think you can just do that to me?
You think I'd let you get away with that?
Think again.
Your shirt...
Tara?
Sweet fancy Moses! Where the hell did he...
Oh, God.
Tara? Baby?
Baby, come on! Get up!
Oh, God. Buffy? Buffy?
Buffy?
No! No!
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org