Do not ask again.
Your powers were a gift
of the lower beings.
You have proved
unworthy of them.
I was robbed of them.
By your carelessness.
For 1,000 years
I wielded the powers
of the wish.
I brought ruin
to the heads of
unfaithful men.
I brought forth
destruction and chaos
for the pleasure
of the lower beings.
I was feared
and worshipped
across the mortal globe.
And now I'm stuck
at Sunnydale High.
Mortal.
Child.
And I'm flunking math.
This is no concern of ours.
You will live out
your mortal life and die.
Give me another chance.
You can fold
the fabric of time.
Send me back
to that place
and I'll change it.
I won't fail again.
Your time is passed.
Do you have any idea
how boring 12th graders are?
I'm getting
my power center back.
And if you
won't help me,
then by
the pestilent gods,
I will find someone
who will.
The Watcher Council shrink
is heavy into tests.
He's got tests
for everything.
T.A.T. s, Rorschach,
associative logic.
He even has that test
to see if you're crazy
that asks if you
ever hear voices
or you ever wanted
to be a florist.
Ooh, I used to want...
Wait.
Florist means crazy, right?
I never wanted to do that.
Neat.
Thanks. It's all about
emotional control.
Plus, obviously, magic.
Hey, you want to go
to the espresso pump
and get sugared up on mochas?
I'm gonna pass.
Hit the pool and do some laps.
How come the sudden
calisthenics?
Aren't you sort of
naturally buff, Buff?
[Chuckles]
Buff Buff.
Well, they've got us running around
on the physical side, too.
A lot of reflex
evaluation
and precision training,
you know.
I just... Well,
I want to do...
Better than Faith?
So very shallow.
Competition is
natural and healthy.
Plus, you'll definitely ace her
on the psych tests.
Just don't mark
the box that says
"I sometimes like to kill people."
I know Faith's not
gonna be on the cover
of Sanity Fair,
but she had it rough.
Different circumstances,
that could be me.
No way.
Some people just don't
have that in them.
Look, I'm sorry.
I know how you hate
talking about Faith.
No, it's OK.
No, really,
we should just...
No. It doesn't bother me.
I mean it.
Uh, Will?
Oh.
Emotional control?
I'm working on it.
[Howling]
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
As far as I'm concerned,
this is a marriage
made in heaven.
Willow Rosenberg,
despite her unsavory
associations,
represents the pinnacle
of academic achievement
at Sunnydale High.
Percy West represents
a devastating fast break
and 50% from behind
the 3-point line.
I'm not sure I understand
the marriage part.
You've got the brains,
he's got the fast break.
It's a perfect match.
Match?
You want us to breed?
I want you to tutor him.
Percy is flunking
history.
Nothing seems to be able
to motivate him.
Hey, I'm challenged.
You're lazy, self-involved,
and spoiled.
That's quite
the challenge.
But we need
a winning year,
especially after last year's debacle
with the swim team.
Can't have our
point guard benched.
So, you're gonna take on
a little teaching job.
I know how you
enjoy teaching.
Well, I have a lot
of work of my own.
You've got a letter
of acceptance
from every university
with a stamp.
Yes, but I still have
classes and I don't...
Rosenberg...
it's time to give
something back
to the community.
I know you want to help
your school out here.
Ask me how I know.
How do you...
I just know.
So he threatened you?
With what?
Well, it wasn't exactly
anything he said.
It was all in his eyes.
I mean, there was some
nostril work as well,
but mostly eyes.
Snyder needs me
to kick his ass.
Oh, no, Buffy,
don't get in trouble.
I'll be OK.
I just hate the way
he bullies people.
He just assumes
everyone's time is his.
Willow, get on
the computer.
I want you to
take another pass
at accessing
the mayor's files.
OK.
Well, that
was a blast.
How did it go?
Princess Margaret here
had a little trouble
keeping up.
How did it go?
[Breathing Heavily]
Faith, uh...
did quite well on
the obstacle field.
Still a little
sloppy, though.
Do you feel up to taking
Buffy out, or shall I?
Oh, no, no, no,
I'll be fine.
Just give me
a minute.
And some
defibrillators,
if it's not
too much trouble.
You're gonna
love it, B.
It's just like fun,
only boring.
Faith, this evaluation
is a necessary part
of the Council.
I know.
I'm on board here.
Just shooting
my mouth off.
I better change.
Good luck.
What you doing?
I'm trying to access
the mayor's personal files.
Can you do that?
Well, he's got some
tricky barriers set up.
Can you get past 'em?
Eventually,
I'll get through.
That's very interesting.
Yeah, I thought so, too.
Are you serious
about this place?
Of course I am.
No slayer of mine
is gonna live in
a fleabag hotel.
That place has a very
unsavory reputation.
There are immoral liaisons
going on there.
Yeah, plus
all the screwing.
This place is the kick.
We'll keep your old place,
in case you need to see
your friends there,
but from now on...
Oh, hey.
Hey, hey, shoes. Shoes.
Thanks, sugar daddy.
Now, Faith, I don't find
that sort of thing amusing.
I'm a family man.
Now, let's kill
your little friend.
Don't worry. I wouldn't
ask you to do it.
Not this early in
the relationship.
Besides, I think
a vampire attack
would be less suspicious
anyway.
In the meantime,
let's take a look
at the rest of
the apartment, huh?
If I'm not mistaken,
some lucky girl
has herself
a Play Station.
No way.
Yes way.
Hey.
Oz. Hi.
There's something
about you
that's causing me
to hug you.
It's like I have
no will of my own.
Where were you yesterday?
We got back late,
sort of very.
We? Who? Where?
The band. We had a gig
in Monterey Sunday night.
Oh, you did?
How come I didn't know?
I thought you did.
Maybe I would
have liked to go.
Didn't figure you
for missing school.
You think I'm boring.
I'd call that a radical
interpretation of the text.
We're playing tonight
at The Bronze.
I can't. I have
too much homework.
If you get done early...
Percy. Hey.
Listen, I thought we could
get together today at lunch
and go over
your Roosevelt paper.
You know, what books
you'll need and stuff.
What are you
talking about?
Me tutoring you.
Your history paper?
Oh, yeah. Snyder said
you were gonna do it.
He never said that.
What meeting
were you at?
Look, I'll get
the books you need.
Just meet me at lunch
and we'll...
No, no, no. I don't
have any time at lunch.
I gotta hang out.
Well...
What, you got something
better to do?
Just type it up
and put my name on it.
Oh, and don't type too good.
Dead giveaway.
I'm eating this now.
It's not lunchtime,
I don't even care.
- Hey.
- Willow,
did you remember
to tape
Biography last Friday?
Uh-huh.
See, I told you.
Old Reliable.
Oh, thanks.
What?
Old Reliable?
Yeah, great.
There's a sexy
nickname.
Well, I didn't
mean it as...
No, it's fine.
I'm Old Reliable.
She just means,
you know,
the geyser. You're
like a geyser of fun
that goes off at
regular intervals.
That's Old Faithful.
Isn't that the dog
that the guy had to shoot...
That's Old Yeller.
Xander, I beg you
not to help me.
Will, I didn't mean it
as a bad thing.
I think it's good
to be reliable.
Well, maybe
I don't want to be
reliable all the time.
Maybe I'm not just
some doormat person.
Homework gal.
I'm thinking
nerve strike.
Maybe I'll
change my look.
Or cut class.
You don't know.
And I'm eating
this banana.
Lunchtime be damned.
Will, wait.
I'm really sorry.
Buff, I'm storming off.
It doesn't really work
if you come with me.
Oh.
Uh, Willow?
Uh, hi.
Anya. I'm sort of
new here.
Um, I know Cordelia.
Oh, fun.
Yeah. Um, listen,
I have this little
project I'm working on,
and I heard you were
the person to ask...
Yeah, that's me.
Reliable dog geyser person.
What do you need?
Oh, it's nothing big.
Just a little spell
I'm working on.
A spell?
Oh. I like the black arts.
I just need a secondary
to create a temporal fold.
I heard you were
a pretty powerful wicca, so...
You heard right, mister.
I'm always ready to work
some dark mojo.
So, tell me,
is it dangerous?
Oh, no.
Well, could we
pretend it is?
The necklace was
a family heirloom
passed down for generations.
Then it was stolen
from my mom's apartment.
How does the spell work?
Uh, well...
we both call on Eryishon,
the endless one...
offer up the standard
supplication,
then there's a teensy
temporal fold... we hope.
Um, then I pour
the sacred sand
on the representation
of the necklace,
and Eryishon brings it forth
from the time and place
it was lost.
Cool.
Are we ready?
I think so.
Eryishon. K'shala.
Meh-uhn.
Diprecht. Doh-tehenlo
nu-Eryishon.
The child to the mother.
The river to the sea.
Eryishon, hear my prayer.
That was... What was that?
Oh, it's not here.
It's not here.
OK, that's
a little blacker
than I like my arts.
Oh, don't be such a wimp.
That wasn't just
some temporal fold,
that was some weird
hell place.
I don't think you're
telling me everything.
I swear, I am just trying
to find my necklace.
Well, did you try looking
inside the sofa in hell?
Look, we'll just
try it again, and...
No. I think
emphatically not.
I can't do it by myself.
That's a relief.
I'm out of here.
Fine. Go.
Idiot child.
I believe these
chicken feet are mine.
Look...
magic is dangerous,
Anya.
It's not to be
toyed with.
Now, if you'll
excuse me,
I have someone else's
homework to do.
Nothing!
This is weird.
Excuse me, young lady...
Shh!
Oh... oh...
* There's a chair in my head *
* In which I used to sit *
* Took a pencil and I wrote *
* The following on it *
* Now there's a key *
* Where my wonderful mouth
used to be *
* Dig it up
and throw it at me *
* Where can I run to
Where can I hide *
* Who will I turn to *
* Now I'm in
a virgin state of mind *
* Got a knife to disengage *
* The voids that I can't bear *
* Cut out words
I've got written *
* On my chair *
* Like
Do you think I'm sexy *
Hey.
Rosenberg?
What are you doing,
trick-or-treating?
You're supposed to be at home
doing my history report.
I flunk that class, you're
in big trouble with Snyder.
Till we graduate,
I own your ass.
Bored now.
I'm having
a terrible night.
Want to make it better?
What's going on?
Is there a funny thing?
Back off.
You stay the hell
away from her.
OK. Sure.
Xander...
Will. Changing the look
not an idle threat
with you.
You're alive.
Uh...
Will, this is verging on
naughty touching here.
Don't want to fall
back on bad habits.
Hands. Hands
in new places.
You're alive.
You mentioned that
before.
Will, are you OK?
No. Everything's different.
There you are.
Hey, Buff.
Aren't you gonna
introduce me to your...
Holy God, you're Willow.
You.
You know what?
I like the look.
It's, um, it's extreme,
but it looks good,
you know.
It's a leather thing.
And, uh... I said extreme
already, right?
I don't like you.
Will, I'm sorry
about today.
You know how my foot
likes to live in my mouth,
but you know,
you really didn't have
to prove anything.
Leaving now.
Will, gotta say,
not loving the new you.
Will, wait...
Get off me.
Willow Rosenberg.
I'm not supposed to
talk to strangers.
Then we won't talk.
You made me cranky.
There's been a mistake here.
We were sent after a human.
Really?
Who do you work for?
I'm not telling you
a thing.
Aah!
Who do you work for?
Wilkins. The mayor.
Aah!
Who do you work for?
You.
Get your friends.
Bring them here.
The world's no fun anymore.
We're gonna make it
the way it was.
Starting with The Bronze.
Oh, Buffy. I thought you
were going out tonight.
I didn't expect...
What is it?
This isn't real.
I can't feel
anything.
Arms, legs,
She was truly the finest
of all of us.
Way better than me.
Much, much better.
It's all my fault.
No, it's me.
It's me.
I'm the one that
called her reliable.
She must have gone out
and gotten attacked,
which she never
would have done
if I hadn't have
called her reliable.
And now my best
friend is...
What's going on?
Geez, who died?
Oh, God. Who died?
Back!
Get back, demon.
Willow,
you're alive.
Aren't I usually?
Oh!
I love you guys, too.
OK. Oxygen becoming
an issue.
Giles, what's going on
with these...
Oh.
Oh. Sorry.
It's really nice that
you guys missed me.
Say, you all didn't
happen to do
a bunch of drugs,
did you?
Will, we saw you
at The Bronze.
A vampire.
I'm not a vampire.
You are. I mean,
you were.
Giles, planning on
jumping in
with an explanation
any time soon?
Well, uh... something...
something very strange
is happening.
Can you believe the Watcher's Council
let this guy go?
What a day.
Give me a beer.
I.D.
I'm 1,120 years old.
Just give me a friggin' beer.
I.D.
[Sighs] Give me a Coke.
Man, we need
a roadie.
Other bands
have roadies.
Well, other bands
know more than 3 chords.
Your professional bands
can play up to 6,
sometimes 7 completely
different chords.
That's just, like,
fruity jazz bands.
Oz.
Hey, man.
You looking
for Buffy?
As always.
Well, no sightings
as of yet,
but I think she
said she'd show.
That doesn't look good.
Everybody, shut up.
All right.
Nobody cause any trouble
or try to leave...
and nobody gets hurt.
Why don't
I believe him?
Well, he lacks
credibility.
Can you get
out of here?
Skylight in the roof.
I can make it.
I think we need
some backup.
I think
I'm needed here.
10-1. Could get
pointless.
Look. Everyone's
all afraid.
It's just like
old times.
Get Buffy.
Do it now.
Dude, check out
your girlfriend.
What's your name?
Sandy.
You don't have
to be afraid...
just to please me.
If you're all good
boys and girls,
we'll make you young
and strong forever
and ever.
We'll have fun.
If you're not...
Questions? Comments?
Willow.
You don't want
to do this.
I don't?
But I'm so good at it.
Who did this to you?
I know you.
You're a white hat.
How come you're talking
to me like we're friends?
'Cause he thinks
you're someone else.
He thinks you're the Willow
that belongs in this reality.
Another me?
You know this isn't
your world, right?
I mean, you know you
don't belong here.
No. This is
a dumb world.
In my world there are
people in chains,
and we can ride them
like ponies.
You want to get
back there.
Yeah.
So do I.
This is creepy.
I don't like the thought
that there's a vampire
out there that
looks like me.
Not looks like... is.
It was exactly you,
Will, every detail.
Except for your not
being a dominatrix...
as far as we know.
Oh, right.
Me and Oz
play Mistress of Pain
every night.
Did anyone else
just go to a scary
visual place?
Oh, yeah.
Buffy, I...
Something's happened
that...
Willow's dead.
Hey, Willow.
Wait a second.
We're right there
with you, buddy.
We saw her, too.
At The Bronze.
OK. She's there now
with a cadre of vampires
looking to party.
We can figure out
who she is
after we stop
the feeding frenzy.
- How many of them were there?
- 8 or 10.
Should we
call Faith?
No, I don't want her
in combat yet.
- Not around civilians.
- Here, here.
Guys?
What are we gonna do with me?
The other me?
I don't know, Will.
I mean, we just have
to stop them.
I get that.
I just kind of
wanted to know...
Oh. Hey. Go.
I'll catch up.
Alone at last.
Well, look at me.
I'm all fuzzy.
What do I want with you?
Uh...
Your little school friend
Anya said
that you're the one
that brought me here.
She said that you could
get me back to my world.
Oh.
Oh. Oops.
But I don't know...
I kind of like the idea
of the two of us.
We could be
quite a team
if you came around
to my way of thinking.
Would that mean
we have to snuggle?
What do you say?
Want to be bad?
This just can't get
more disturbing.
[Growls]
Ack! No more.
You're really starting
to freak me out.
You don't want to play,
I guess I can't
force you.
Oh, wait.
I can.
Bitch.
It's extraordinary.
It's horrible.
That's me as a vampire?
I'm so evil,
and skanky.
And I think
I'm kind of gay.
Willow,
just remember,
a vampire's
personality
has nothing to do
with the person it was.
Well, actually...
That's a good point.
So, uh,
what do we do now?
We still have to
get to The Bronze.
Even if they're supposed
to wait for her
they may start feeding.
Vampires are not
notoriously reliable.
So we charge in,
much in the style
of John Wayne?
High casualty risk.
I haven't any other
plan, though.
Uh, I have a
really bad idea.
They're still in
a holding pattern.
That's good.
It means they must really
be afraid of you.
Who wouldn't be?
Are you OK
in that?
It's a little binding.
I guess vampires really
don't have to breathe.
Gosh, look at those.
Um, Willow,
you go in
and defuse the situation
as best you can.
At least try and get
some of them to come out
and even up the odds
a bit.
First sign of trouble,
you give us a signal.
We come in hard and fast.
What is the signal?
Me screaming.
Giles, you and Xander
wait by the back entrance.
Good.
Now, you're sure
you're up to this?
Don't worry.
I won't do anything
that could be interpreted
as brave.
We'll be right outside.
Hi. I'm back.
Alphonse:
Did you find the girl?
Yep. I did.
Where is she?
I killed her.
And sucked her blood,
as we vampires do.
You know, I think maybe
I heard something out there.
Why don't you
go check?
How could you kill her?
She was our best shot
at getting your world back.
I don't like that
you dare question me.
Maybe I'll have my minions take you
out back and kill you horribly.
Vampires. Always thinking
with your teeth.
She bothered me.
She's so weak
and accommodating.
She's always letting people
walk all over her,
and then she gets cranky
with her friends for no reason.
I just couldn't
let her live.
You know, he's been gone
for a while.
Why don't you
go check on him?
Well, boss, since
that plan is out,
why don't we get
with the killing?
Oh, this is
like a nightmare.
Hello? Giles?
Wesley?
I just happened
to stop by...
for books.
Hey, you.
Hey me?
Hey me what?
I have a name, you know.
Uh, Cordelia.
What did you do?
Lock yourself
in the book cage?
Yeah.
Let me out...
'cause I'm so
helpless.
OK.
I think Giles keeps a spare.
How'd you manage to lock
yourself in, anyway?
Uh, I was looking
at books.
I like books...
'cause I'm shy.
Yeah, right.
The famous shy girl act
all the boys fall for.
Open the cage.
Wait.
It occurs to me that we've never
really had the opportunity to talk.
You know, woman to woman...
with you locked up.
Don't want to talk.
Hungry.
What could we talk about?
Oh!
Hey! How about the ethics
of boyfriend stealing?
I don't know if I feel
like killing anymore.
I'm so bored.
It would be like
shooting fish in a barrel.
Where's the fun?
With all due respect, boss,
the fun would be the eating.
Maybe we should let
everyone go,
give them a 30-second
head start.
Wait a minute.
No! I like my plan.
Oh, nice try.
OK, let's get
to the killing.
Why don't we start with her?
Why don't we start
with you?
If she's a vampire, then I'm
the Creature from the Black Lagoon.
And, OK...
it isn't even like I was
that attracted to Xander.
It was more just that we kept being
put in these life or death situations,
and that's always
all sexy and stuff.
I mean, I more or less
knew he was a loser,
but that doesn't make it OK
for you to come around and... What?
Do I have something
on my neck?
Not yet.
Am I getting a zit?
Cordelia,
I'm very sorry.
I realize I was wrong.
I'll never steal
your boyfriend again.
Like you could.
I should just leave you
in there,
but I'm a great humanitarian,
and you will just have to think
of a way to pay me back sometime.
OK.
How about dinner?
Aah! Aah! Aah!
I didn't mean all that
stuff I said before.
I want you to have Xander.
My blessings on you both.
I'm so over him.
I need fresh blood.
Aah!
No more hiding.
Back!
Creature of the night.
Leave this place!
Don't wanna.
[Sighs] Whatever.
Yaahh!
I'm sorry.
No, no.
A little on edge.
You know,
men in combat.
Grr.
Are you all right?
You saved my life.
Thank you.
Oh, yes. Uh... yes.
Was that?
Willow.
They got Willow.
So, you doing anything
tonight?
I'm just so tired of being around
human beings and all their baggage.
I don't care if I
ever get my powers back.
I think he should eat you.
This girl has a history of mental
problems dating back to early childhood.
I'm a blood-sucking fiend.
Look at my outfit.
A human. I should have
smelled it right away.
A human? Oh, yeah?
Could a human do this?
Aaaah!
- Sure. Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Humans do that. Yeah.
- I think, yeah.
Uhh!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Happy, but ow!
Devon, come on!
No more snuggles?
Buffy, no!
Nice reflexes.
Well, I work out.
This world's no fun.
You noticed that, too?
So, um, in your reality,
I'm like this bad ass vampire, huh?
People afraid of me?
Oh, yeah.
I'm bad.
I'm not sure about releasing
this thing into the wild, Will.
It is a demon.
I just can't kill her.
No.
Me, neither.
I mean,
I know she's not me.
We have a big nothing
in common, but still.
There but for the grace
of getting bit.
We send her back to her world,
then she stands a chance.
It's the way
it should be anyway.
Uh, we're
about ready here.
Don't you try any
tricks now, dear.
I don't need tricks.
When I get my powers back,
you will all grovel before me.
Pfff!
If you, uh, Willows
would like to, uh,
complete the circle.
Good luck.
Try not to kill people.
Hands! Hands!
You wanna go out
tonight?
Strangely, I feel
like staying at home...
and doing my homework...
and flossing...
and dying a virgin.
You know,
you can O.D. on virtue.
Between me and my evil self,
I've double guilt coupons.
I see now where the path
of vice leads.
I mean, she messed up
everything she touched.
I don't ever
want to be like that.
Hey. Oh, hi.
Oh, hi, listen,
I didn't have a chance...
OK, so I did the outline
for the paper on Roosevelt.
It turns out there were
2 President Roosevelts,
so I didn't know exactly
which one to do, so I did both.
I know they're kind of short,
but I can flesh them out.
Oh, and here's
the bibliography.
Um, and I can retype
that if you want.
You just let me know what I did wrong,
and I'll get on it.
You wanna go out
tonight?
9:00 sound good?
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org