IN EVERY GENERATION
THERE IS A CHOSEN ONE.
SHE ALONE WILL STAND
AGAINST THE VAMPIRES,
THE DEMONS.
AND THE FORCES OF DARKNESS.
SHE IS THE SLAYER.
[ Cordelia ]
I JUST LOVE SPRINGTIME,
ME IN BRIGHT, SPRING FASHIONS.
SPRING TRAINING.
ME AT THE END-OF-SCHOOL DANCE.
THE END OF SCHOOL.
DEFINITELY MY FAVORITE
TIME OF YEAR.
I AM, OF COURSE, HAVING
MY DRESS SPECIALLY MADE.
OFF-THE-RACK
GIVES ME HIVES.
LET ME GUESS.
BLUE LIKE YOUR EYES.
MY EYES ARE HAZEL,
HELEN KELLER.
YOU TWO WILL LOOK
SO FINE TOGETHER
IN THE MAY QUEEN
PHOTO.
WELL, I HAVEN'T
BEEN ELECTED MAY QUEEN YET.
OOH! OH! OH!
[ Chuckles ]
BEHOLD THE WEIRDNESS.
YOU'RE PROBABLY WONDERING WHAT
I'M DOING WITH THIS STUFF, HUH?
- WOW! I'M NOT.
- UH, FOR HISTORY CLASS.
MR. GILES HAS THIS, LIKE,
HOBBY OF COLLECTING STUFF,
WHICH HE LENT ME
FOR SHOW-AND-TELL.
DID I MENTION
IT'S FOR HISTORY CLASS?
SHE IS ALWAYS HANGING WITH
THAT CREEPY LIBRARIAN...
IN THAT CREEPY
LIBRARY.
HEY, DID I EVER TELL YOU ABOUT THE
TIME SHE ATTACKED ME AT THE BRONZE?
I DON'T KNOW WHY THIS SCHOOL
ADMITS MENTALS LIKE HER.
"IF YOU PRICK US,
DO WE NOT BLEED?
"IF YOU TICKLE US,
DO WE NOT LAUGH?
"IF YOU POISON US,
DO WE NOT DIE?
AND IF YOU WRONG US,
SHALL WE NOT REVENGE?"
OKAY.
SO TALK TO ME, PEOPLE.
HOW DOES WHAT SHYLOCK
SAYS HERE ABOUT BEING A JEW...
RELATE TO OUR DISCUSSION ABOUT THE
ANGER OF THE OUTCAST IN SOCIETY?
CORDELIA. WELL, HOW ABOUT "COLOR
ME TOTALLY SELF-INVOLVED"?
CARE TO ELABORATE?
YEAH.
WITH SHYLOCK, IT'S
WHINE, WHINE, WHINE,
LIKE THE WHOLE WORLD
IS ABOUT HIM.
HE ACTS LIKE IT'S JUSTICE, HIM
GETTING A POUND OF ANTONIO'S FLESH.
IT'S NOT JUSTICE.
IT'S YICKY.
BUT HAS SHYLOCK SUFFERED? WHAT'S
HIS PLACE IN VENICE SOCIETY?
WELL, EVERYONE LOOKED DOWN ON HIM.
THAT IS SUCH A TWINKIE DEFENSE.
SHYLOCK SHOULD
GET OVER HIMSELF.
PEOPLE WHO THINK THEIR
PROBLEMS ARE SO HUGE CRAZE ME,
LIKE THIS TIME I SORT OF RAN
OVER THIS GIRL ON HER BIKE.
IT WAS THE MOST
TRAUMATIZING TIME MY LIFE,
AND SHE WAS TRYING TO
MAKE IT ABOUT HER LEG,
LIKE MY PAIN MEANT NOTHING.
WELL, CORDELIA'S RAISED AN INTERESTING
POINT HERE... [ Bell Rings ]
WHICH WE'LL PURSUE
AT A LATER TIME.
UM...
MS. MILLER?
GOOD OBSERVATIONS
TODAY, CORDELIA.
IT'S ALWAYS EXCITING TO KNOW
SOMEONE'S ACTUALLY DONE THE READING.
THANKS. UM, I WANT TO TALK
TO YOU ABOUT MY FINAL PAPER.
I'M REAL UNFOCUSED.
I HAVE ALL THESE THOUGHTS,
AND I'M PRETTY SURE THEY
ALL CONTRADICT EACH OTHER.
WELL, I HAVE YOUR OUTLINE HERE, BUT WHY
DON'T YOU STOP BY TOMORROW AFTER SCHOOL?
WE'LL GO OVER IT THEN. THAT'D BE GREAT.
THANKS A LOT.
YOU'RE WELCOME. I'LL SEE YOU THEN.
OKAY, BYE.
HARMONY, THE DRESS IS READY. IT'S SO GREAT!
MITCH IS GONNA DIE!
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
HEY, MITCH,
YOU GOING TO THE BRONZE?
LATER. I'M PICKING
OUT MY TUX FIRST.
GOT TO LOOK SHARP FOR THE BIG DIG.
OH, THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU GOT TO LOOK GOOD
TO BE ON CORDELIA'S ARM.
OH, IT'S NOT HER ARM
I'M LOOKING TO BE ON.
[ Girl Giggles ]
WHO'S THERE?
[ Giggling ]
OKAY, FUN TIME'S OVER.
COME OUT.
[ Groaning ]
[ Animal Howling ]
NOW, REMEMBER WHO TO
VOTE FOR FOR MAY QUEEN,
AS IN ME. [ Chuckles ] THANKS.
HI! ISN'T THIS
THE BOMB?
I'M SUCH THE CAMPAIGN
STRATEGIST.
"C."
FOR CORDELIA?
NO, "C" FOR WILMA,
LITTLE BRAIN.
OF COURSE "C" FOR CORDELIA. THIS WAY, PEOPLE
WILL ASSOCIATE ME WITH SOMETHING SWEET.
HERE'S A CHOCOLATE... OH, I DON'T
THINK I NEED THE LOONY FRINGE VOTE.
WELL... I DON'T EVEN
LIKE CHOCOLATES.
OKAY, THAT WAS THE LAMEST
COMEBACK OF OUR TIMES.
SO WHAT'S CORDELIA UP TO?
BRIBERY. SHE'S DESPERATE TO BE MAY QUEEN.
SHE DOES LOVE TITLES.
OH, GOD! REMEMBER IN SIXTH
GRADE WITH THE FIELD TRIP?
RIGHT! RIGHT! THE GUY WITH
THE ANTLERS ON HIS BELT.
"BE MY DEPUTY." AND
REMEMBER, THE HAT?
- GEE, IT'S FUN THAT WE'RE SPEAKING IN TONGUES.
- [ Laughing ]
I'M SORRY.
IT WAS JUST, WE HAD THIS,
UH... YOU HAD TO BE THERE.
IT'S NOT EVEN FUNNY.
REALLY.
CORDELIA JUST HAS A HISTORY
OF TRYING TOO HARD.
YEAH. WHAT KIND OF MORON WOULD
WANT TO BE MAY QUEEN ANYWAY?
- I WAS.
- YOU WHAT?
AT MY OLD SCHOOL.
SO THE GOOD KIND OF MORON WOULD
DO THAT,
THE, UH, NON-MORON, I MEAN.
WELL, WE DIDN'T
CALL IT MAY QUEEN,
BUT WE HAD THE CORONATION AND
THE DANCE AND ALL THAT STUFF.
- IT WAS NICE.
- YOU DON'T NEED THAT ANYMORE. YOU'VE GOT US.
[ Giggling ]
"BE MY DEPUTY."
[ Laughing ]
GUYS! COME ON! MITCH GOT
WAILED ON. I THINK HE'S...
HE'S DEAD?
OF COURSE NOT.
DEAD. WHAT ARE YOU,
GHOULS?
THERE ARE NO DEAD
STUDENTS HERE...
THIS WEEK.
CLEAR BACK. MAKE
ROOM, ALL OF YOU!
- MITCH, WHAT HAPPENED?
- I DON'T KNOW.
I-I HEARD SOMETHING.
I TRIED TO
GRAB A-A BAT...
[ Laughs ] THAT HIT ME.
- WHAT HIT YOU?
- THE BAT, BY ITSELF.
THE THING WAS FLOATING,
AND IT KNOCKED ME OUT.
I BETTER
CHECK OUT THE SCENE.
WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING?
UM, MITCH WANTED ME TO GET
HIS COMB. HE-HE LIKES HIS COMB.
I DON'T THINK MITCH
NEEDS HIS COMB RIGHT NOW.
I THINK MITCH NEEDS
MEDICAL ATTENTION,
AND YOU NEED TO STAY AWAY
FROM THE CRIME SCENE.
ALWAYS STICKING YOUR NOSE IN.
SUE?
WHAT DID YOU SAY? MITCH
WAS GONNA SUE THE SCHOOL?
SUE?
WHO?
WELL, HIS DAD IS THE MOST
POWERFUL LAWYER IN SUNNYDALE.
HOLD ON. WHAT HAVE
YOU TWO HEARD?
HIS DAD, THE LAWYER,
YOU HAVEN'T HEARD OF HIM?
OTHER LAWYERS
CALL HIM "THE BEAST."
"LOOK"?
THAT'S ALL IT SAID?
LOOK AT WHAT? LOOK AT MITCH?
MAYBE.
ALL I KNOW IS
IT'S A MESSAGE.
AND? OH, HERE YOU ARE.
AND MONSTERS DON'T
USUALLY SEND MESSAGES.
IT'S PRETTY MUCH CRUSH,
KILL, DESTROY.
THIS WAS DIFFERENT. I'D
HAVE TO SAY YOU'RE RIGHT.
I LOVE IT WHEN HE SAYS THAT.
ANY THEORIES?
IT'S A BIT
OF A PUZZLE, REALLY.
I'VE NEVER ACTUALLY
HEARD OF ANYONE
ATTACKED BY A LONE
BASEBALL BAT BEFORE.
MAYBE IT'S A VAMPIRE BAT.
I'M ALONE
WITH THAT ONE, HUH?
WELL, ASSUMING THE BAT
ITSELF IS NOT POSSESSED,
THERE ARE A FEW POSSIBILITIES
THAT BEAR INVESTIGATING:
SOMEONE
WITH TELEKINESIS...
THE POWER TO MOVE
OBJECTS AT WILL...
AN INVISIBLE CREATURE,
AND, POSSIBLY, A POLTERGEIST.
A GHOST?
YES, AND A VERY ANGRY ONE.
YEAH, I'D SAY.
THE LOCKER ROOM
WAS A REAL SCENE.
IF IT'S A GHOST, THEN WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT A DEAD KID.
I GUESS SO.
YOU KNOW,
WHY DON'T YOU COMPILE A LIST
OF DEAD OR MISSING KIDS?
IT'S PROBABLY
A GOOD PLACE TO START.
AND I'LL RESEARCH ALL THE
POSSIBILITIES, GHOSTS INCLUDED.
XANDER, IF YOU'RE NOT DOING ANYTHING,
WOULD YOU LIKE TO HELP ME?
WHAT? SO THERE'S
HOMEWORK NOW?
WHEN DID THAT HAPPEN?
IT'S ALL PART OF THE GLAMOROUS
WORLD OF VAMPIRE-SLAYAGE.
WHAT PART DO YOU HAVE? I'M GONNA
FIND OUT WHAT I CAN ABOUT MITCH.
- THIS ATTACK WASN'T RANDOM.
- WELL, I WANT THAT PART.
FINE. YOU CAN DO IT. ASK AROUND.
TALK TO HIS FRIENDS.
- TALK TO CORDELIA.
- TALK TO CORDELIA?
SO, RESEARCH, HUH?
HI.
UH, HI.
CORDELIA, YOU WEREN'T IN FIFTH PERIOD.
I WENT TO THE HOSPITAL.
OH, MITCH. HOW IS HE?
WILL HE BE OKAY?
WELL, THE DOCTOR
SAYS HE'LL BE FINE.
THEY'RE GONNA
SEND HIM HOME TOMORROW,
BUT YOU SHOULD HAVE SEEN HIM
LYING THERE, ALL BLACK AND BLUE.
HOW'S HE GONNA LOOK
IN OUR PROM PICTURES?
HOW AM I EVER GOING TO BE
ABLE TO SHOW THEM TO ANYONE?
WELL, THEY CAN DO WONDERFUL THINGS
WITH AIRBRUSHES THESE DAYS.
YOU THINK?
HI. HI. DID YOU SEE MITCH?
HE JUST BROKE UP WITH
WENDY EIGHT SECONDS AGO,
AND HE'S ALREADY NOSING AROUND.
IT'S SHAMELESS.
IN THE SPRINGIF HE
MAKES VARSITY BASEBALL,
MAYBE I'LL TAKE HIM ON A TEST DRIVE.
[ Laughs ]
HI, GUYS!
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I JUST HOPE THEY CAN PROP HIM UP
LONG ENOUGH TO TAKE THE PICTURE.
- CORDELIA, CAN I TALK TO YOU?
- OH, GREAT.
WHY IS SHE ALWAYS
TRYING... [ Grunting ]
[ Grunts ] HARMONY!
- [ Girl Gasps ]
- OH, FOR HEAVEN'S SAKES.
CLEAR BACK, EVERYONE.
GIVE HER SOME AIR.
YOU, SCHOOL NURSE, NOW.
[ Moans ] OH, MY ANKLE.
I THINK IT'S BROKEN.
- WHAT HAPPENED?
- HEY, WHO'S THE PRINCIPAL HERE?
- SHE FELL!
WE WERE STANDING
AT THE TOP OF THE STAIRS,
AND SHE JUST FELL
ALL BY HERSELF.
- NO! I WAS PUSHED!
- [ Girl Giggling ]
- OW!
- DON'T SUE.
[ GIGGLING ]
IS ANYBODY HERE?
[ THUD ] [ Footsteps ]
HEY, WHO'S HERE?
OKAY,
I KNOW SOMEONE'S HERE.
LOOK, I'M NOT GOING TO HURT YOU.
I JUST WANT TO TALK TO YOU.
[ Footsteps ]
[ Bell Ringing ]
[ Boy ] SAY, GUYS?
[ Buffy ] GILES, HAVE YOU
EVER TOUCHED A GHOST?
NO, BUT FROM WHAT I'VE HEARD, HAVING A GHOST
PASS THROUGH YOU IS A SINGULAR EXPERIENCE.
IT'S A RATHER COLD,
AMORPHOUS FEELING
THAT MAKES YOUR HAIR STAND ON END.
YOU SEE, THAT'S MY PROBLEM.
I TOUCHED THE THING, BUT
IT DIDN'T GO THROUGH ME.
IT BUMPED INTO ME,
AND IT WASN'T COLD.
- SO WE'RE TALKING ABOUT WHAT, AN INVISIBLE PERSON?
- A GIRL. SHE LAUGHED.
A GIRL ON CAMPUS WITH THE
ABILITY TO BECOME INVISIBLE.
- THAT IS SO COOL!
- COOL?
WELL, YEAH, I WOULD GIVE ANYTHING
TO BE ABLE TO TURN INVISIBLE.
I WOULDN'T USE MY POWERS
TO BEAT PEOPLE UP.
I'D USE MY POWERS TO PROTECT
THE GIRLS' LOCKER ROOM.
IT MUST BE A FAIRLY
HEADY EXPERIENCE,
HAVING THAT ABILITY.
HOW'D SHE GET IT?
IS SHE A WITCH?
'CAUSE WE CAN
FIGHT A WITCH.
GREEK MYTH SPEAKS OF
CLOAKS OF INVISIBILITY,
BUT THEY'RE USUALLY
FOR THE GODS.
RESEARCH BOY COMES THROUGH
WITH THE KNOWLEDGE.
THIS GIRL'S SORT
OF PETTY FOR A GOD.
SHE'S GOT A GRUDGE,
BUT WHY HARMONY?
HARMONY AND MITCH:
THEIR COMMON DENOMINATOR IS...
- CORDELIA.
- SO WHAT NOW?
FIRST THING TOMORROW, WHY DON'T YOU
PULL UP THAT MISSING KIDS LIST.
GOT IT.
I'LL SEE YOU THEN.
SEE YA.
BYE.
OH, HEY, DO YOU WANT TO COME TO
OUR PLACE TONIGHT FOR DINNER?
MOM'S MAKING HER FAMOUS PHONE
CALL TO THE CHINESE PLACE.
XANDER, DO YOU GUYS
EVEN HAVE A STOVE?
SO, I'LL LOOK INTO WAYS THAT YOU
CAN DE-CLOAK AN INVISIBLE SOMEONE.
WHAT ABOUT YOU? I THINK CORDELIA'S GOING
TO BE WORKING ON HER MAY QUEEN DRESS.
MAYBE THERE'LL BE SOME ACTION. I
GUESS I'M GONNA START THE HUNT.
HOW EXACTLY DO YOU PROPOSE TO
HUNT SOMEONE YOU CAN'T SEE?
[ Giles ] YOU MAY HAVE TO
WORK ON LISTENING TO PEOPLE.
[ Buffy ] VERY FUNNY.
I THOUGHT SO.
SHOULD I WEAR MY HAIR UP?
DO YOU THINK
I SHOULD WEAR IT UP?
[ GIRLS LAUGHING ]
HOW DOES
THE, UM, HEM GO?
IS IT... IS IT
LONG ENOUGH OR...
ISN'T IT BEAUTIFUL?
OHH!
?[ FLUTE PLAYS ]
?[ CONTINUES ]
[ CREAKING ]
WHO'S THERE?
[ Gasps ]
AHH...
A VAMPIRE
CASTS NO REFLECTION.
DON'T WORRY.
I'M NOT HERE TO EAT.
BUFFY TOLD ME YOU DON'T
FEED FROM HUMANS ANYMORE.
- NOT FOR A LONG WHILE.
- IS THAT WHY YOU'RE HERE, TO SEE HER?
I CAN'T.
IT'S, UH...
IT'S TOO HARD FOR ME
TO BE AROUND HER.
A VAMPIRE IN LOVE
WITH A SLAYER.
IT'S RATHER POETIC...
IN A MAUDLIN SORT OF WAY.
WHAT CAN I, UH...
WHAT CAN I DO
FOR YOU?
I KNOW YOU'VE BEEN
RESEARCHING THE MASTER.
YES. THE VAMPIRE KING.
I'M TRYING TO LEARN AS MUCH
AS I CAN ABOUT HIM
FOR THE DAY THAT
BUFFY MUST FACE HIM.
SOMETHING'S ALREADY IN
MOTION, SOMETHING BIG,
BUT I DON'T KNOW WHAT.
YOU'VE READ ALL THE SLAYER
LORE THERE IS, RIGHT?
I'VE STUDIED ALL THE EXTANT
VOLUMES, OF COURSE.
BUT THE MOST SALIENT BOOKS OF
SLAYER PROPHECY HAVE BEEN LOST:
THE TIBERIUS MANIFESTO,
THE PERGAMUM CODEX.
THE CODEX?
IT'S REPUTED TO HAVE CONTAINED
THE MOST COMPLETE PROPHECIES
ABOUT THE SLAYER'S ROLE
IN THE END YEARS.
UNFORTUNATELY, THE BOOK WAS
LOST IN THE 15th CENTURY.
NOT LOST...
MISPLACED.
- I CAN GET IT.
- [ Gasps ]
THAT WOULD BE MOST HELPFUL.
UH, MY... MY OWN VOLUMES
HAVE, UH...
HAVE BEEN RATHER USELESS
OF LATE.
- LEGENDS OF VISHNU?
- [ Chuckles ]
THERE'S AN INVISIBLE GIRL
TERRORIZING THE SCHOOL.
THAT'S NOT REALLY
MY AREA OF EXPERTISE.
NOR MINE, I'M AFRAID.
IT'S FASCINATING, THOUGH.
BY ALL ACCOUNTS, IT'S A
WONDERFUL POWER TO POSSESS.
OH, I DON'T KNOW.
LOOKING IN THE MIRROR EVERY DAY
AND SEEING NOTHING THERE...
IT'S AN OVERRATED
PLEASURE.
[ Cordelia ] GOD! I AM NEVER SITTING THROUGH
ONE OF THOSE ALUMNI LECTURES AGAIN!
TWO HOURS OF
"MY TREK THROUGH NEPAL."
HELLO. THERE
IS NOBODY CARING.
DID YOU GUYS SEE HIS TOUPEE?
IT LOOKED LIKE A CABBAGE.
AND THOSE SLIDES?
"THAT'S A MOUNTAIN.
"THAT'S
A MOUNTAIN, TOO.
NOW LOOK
AT SOME MOUNTAINS."
I SWEAR HE HAD 3 SLIDES AND
JUST USED THEM OVER AND OVER.
I KNOW, BUT DID YOU SEE HIS TOUPEE?
IT WAS, LIKE, THE WORST.
WE'RE TALKING, OKAY?
OH! AND DID YOU GUYS CHECK
OUT THAT EXTREME TOUPEE?
YEAH. THAT'S REALISTIC.
IT LOOKED LIKE A CABBAGE.
[ All Laughing ]
THAT'S SO FUNNY.
[ Giggling, Laughing ]
[ Mr. Snyder ]
THE WINNER IS CORDELIA CHASE.
LET'S BRING UP
OUR NEW MAY QUEEN.
THANK YOU FOR MAKING
THE RIGHT CHOICE...
AND FOR SHOWING ME
HOW MUCH YOU ALL LOVE ME.
BEING THIS POPULAR IS NOT JUST
MY RIGHT, BUT MY RESPONSIBILITY.
AND I WANT YOU TO KNOW I
TAKE IT VERY SERIOUSLY.
SO GILES SAID
YOU'D BE HERE.
WHY ARE YOU BEING HERE?
LAST NIGHT WAS A BUST,
BUT I STILL THINK
CORDY'S THE KEY HERE.
THE MISSING GIRLS LIST.
THEY'VE STAYED MISSING.
I PULLED UP THEIR CLASSES, ACTIVITIES,
MEDICAL RECORDS. GOOD WORK.
HAS CORDELIA HIRED
A BODYGUARD OR SOMETHING?
HEY, YOU GUYS, CHECK OUT THIS ONE.
IT'S THE MOST RECENT ONE.
MARCIE ROSS DISAPPEARED,
LIKE, SIX MONTHS AGO.
I DON'T KNOW HER.
ME, NEITHER.
HER ONLY ACTIVITY WAS BAND.
SHE PLAYED THE FLUTE.
SO? WELL, LAST NIGHT WHEN I WAS
HUNTING I HEARD THIS FLUTE,
BUT I COULDN'T FIGURE OUT
WHERE IT WAS COMING FROM.
AND IT WAS IN THE BAND ROOM THAT
I LOST MISS INVISIBLE YESTERDAY.
YOU KNOW, THIS ALL TRACKS.
I'M GOING TO CHECK IT OUT.
SEE YOU GUYS LATER? OKAY.
WE'LL SEE YOU AFTER GEOMETRY.
[ Cordelia ] ASK, "HEY, WHAT AM I
WEARING TO THAT SPRING FLING?"
"MARCIE ROSS."
SO IT IS YOU.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
CORDELIA, COULD YOU POSSIBLY
BE ON TI... [ Footsteps ]
[ GIRL GIGGLING ]
WHO'S THERE?
[ Cordelia ]
MS. MILLER?
OH, MY GOD!
MS. MILLER!
ARE YOU OKAY?
[ WHEEZES, COUGHS ] MS. MILLER... AHH!
WHAT HAPPENED?
[ Miller ]
ATTACKED... DIDN'T SEE.
[ Chalk Clattering On
Blackboard ] OH, MY GOD.
A NEST?
LOOKED LIKE SHE'D
BEEN THERE FOR MONTHS.
IT'S WHERE I FOUND THIS.
CHECK IT OUT.
OH, MY GOD.
"HAVE A NICE SUMMER."
THIS GIRL HAD
NO FRIENDS AT ALL.
UH, ONCE AGAIN, I TEETER AT THE
PRECIPICE OF THE GENERATION GAP.
"HAVE A NICE SUMMER" IS WHAT YOU
WRITE WHEN YOU HAVE NOTHING TO SAY.
IT'S THE KISS OF DEATH.
YOU GUYS DIDN'T
KNOW MARCIE ROSS?
NEVER MET HER. WHY?
'CAUSE YOU BOTH
WROTE IT, TOO.
"HAVE A NICE... " YEESH.
WHERE AM I?
OH.
"HAVE GREAT SUMMER."
SEE? I CARED.
BUT YOU DON'T
REMEMBER HER?
NO. I PROBABLY DIDN'T SEE
HER, EXCEPT TO SIGN THE BOOK.
I MEAN, THIS IS
A BIG SCHOOL.
XANDER, WE EACH HAD
FOUR CLASSES WITH HER LAST YEAR.
SO NO ONE NOTICED HER,
AND NOW SHE'S INVISIBLE.
WHAT? SHE TURNED INVISIBLE
BECAUSE NO ONE NOTICED HER?
OF COURSE.
I'VE BEEN INVESTIGATING THE
MYSTICAL CAUSES OF INVISIBILITY,
WHEN I SHOULD HAVE LOOKED
AT THE QUANTUM MECHANICAL.
PHYSICS.
I THINK I SPEAK
FOR EVERYONE HERE
WHEN I SAY, HUH?
IT'S A RUDIMENTARY CONCEPT
THAT REALITY IS SHAPED,
EVEN-EVEN CREATED...
BY OUR PERCEPTION.
AND WITH THE HELLMOUTH BELOW US
SENDING OUT MYSTICAL ENERGIES...
PEOPLE PERCEIVED MARCIE
AS INVISIBLE,
AND-AND SHE BECAME SO.
SO, WHO KNOWS
THE ANSWER TO THIS ONE?
THINK ABOUT IT.
CORDELIA. WELL, JUST BECAUSE
THE STORY'S ABOUT HIM...
DOESN'T NECESSARILY MEAN
HE'S THE HERO, RIGHT?
EXACTLY,
SO WHAT DO WE CALL HIM?
WILLOW. WELL, THE PROTAGONIST.
- XANDER.
- WHY CAN'T HE BE BOTH?
I MEAN, HE DID DO SOME THINGS
THAT WERE PRETTY HEROIC.
ABSOLUTELY. WHO DOESN'T
AGREE WITH THAT?
OKAY.
AND HOW ABOUT YOU?
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Not Audible ]
IT ISN'T THIS GREAT POWER
THAT SHE CAN CONTROL.
IT WAS SOMETHING
THAT WAS DONE TO HER...
THAT WE DID TO HER.
NO WONDER
SHE'S MIFFED.
WHAT DOES SHE WANT?
JUST WHAT
WE THOUGHT.
CORDELIA.
WHAT?
I KNEW YOU'D BE HERE.
BUFFY...
I, UH, I KNOW WE'VE HAD
OUR DIFFERENCES,
WITH YOU BEING
SO WEIRD AND ALL...
AND HANGING OUT
WITH THESE TOTAL LOSERS.
OOH.
WELL, ANYWAY,
DESPITE ALL OF THAT,
I KNOW THAT YOU SHARE
THIS FEELING...
THAT WE HAVE
FOR EACH OTHER, DEEP DOWN.
NAUSEA?
SOMEBODY IS AFTER ME!
THEY JUST TRIED TO KILL
MRS. MILLER...
SHE WAS HELPING ME
WITH MY HOMEWORK...
AND MITCH AND HARMONY.
THIS IS ALL ABOUT ME...
ME, ME, ME!
WOW. FOR ONCE
SHE'S RIGHT.
SO YOU'VE COMING
TO ME FOR HELP.
BECAUSE... YOU'RE ALWAYS AROUND WHEN
ALL THIS WEIRD STUFF IS HAPPENING.
AND I KNOW
YOU'RE VERY STRONG,
AND YOU'VE GOT
ALL THOSE WEAPONS.
I WAS KIND OF HOPING
YOU WERE IN A GANG.
PLEASE. I DON'T HAVE
ANYONE ELSE TO TURN TO.
PLEASE...
SIT DOWN.
OKAY, THANKS.
YOU KNOW, I...
I DON'T RECALL EVER
SEEING YOU HERE BEFORE.
OH, NO. I HAVE A LIFE.
OKAY.
CORDELIA, YOUR ATTACKER
IS AN INVISIBLE GIRL.
WHO IS REALLY,
REALLY ANGRY AT YOU,
WHICH I CAN'T
IMAGINE PERSONALLY,
BUT IT TAKES
ALL KINDS, YOU KNOW?
WELL, I DON'T CARE WHAT IT IS.
JUST GET RID OF IT.
WELL, IT'S NOT
THAT SIMPLE.
IT'S A PERSON. IT'S...
IT'S THIS PERSON.
NOW, DO YOU HAVE ANY
IDEA WHY SHE'D BE SO...
OH, GOD, IS SHE REALLY
WEARING LAURA ASHLEY?
SO HOMICIDAL?
I HAVE NO IDEA.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THIS GIRL
BEFORE IN MY LIFE.
[ Marcie Ranting ]
YOU DIDN'T SEE ME COMING.
[ Mumbling ] CORDELIA, YOU DON'T REMEMBER ME.
I REMEMBER YOU.
ALL YOUR SLUT FRIENDS... I HATE THEM! THEY
TAKE YOUR LIFE AND THEY SUCK IT OUT OF YOU.
THAT BASTARD...
[ Indistinct ]
THEY GOTTA LEARN.
ACCORDING TO WHAT YOU TOLD US
ABOUT THE ATTACK ON MS. MILLER,
WE NOW HAVE
TWO MESSAGES FROM MARCIE.
LOOK AND LISTEN.
MESSAGES WE DON'T
UNDERSTAND.
I DON'T THINK WE'RE
SUPPOSED TO... YET.
MARCIE'S NOT QUITE READY,
BUT FROM WHAT SHE DID
TO CORDELIA'S PICTURE,
I WOULD SAY THAT SHE'S WIGGED
ON THE WHOLE MAY QUEEN THING.
MAYBE SHE'S GONNA DO
SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
STOP THE CORONATION
TONIGHT, MAYBE.
KEEP YOU GUYS
AWAY FROM THE BRONZE.
NOTHING IS KEEPING ME
FROM THE BRONZE TONIGHT.
CAN WE JUST REVEL IN YOUR
FABULOUS LACK OF PRIORITIES?
IF I'M NOT CROWNED TONIGHT,
THEN... THEN MARCIE'S WON,
AND THAT WOULD BE BAD!
SHE'S EVIL, OKAY?
WAY EVILER THAN ME.
CORDELIA HAS A POINT.
BUFFY'S WITH ME ON THIS.
ANYWAY, CONTINUING THE
NORMAL MAY QUEEN ACTIVITIES
MAY BE THE BEST WAY
TO DRAW MARCIE OUT.
WE CAN USE CORDELIA
AS BAIT.
GREAT! BAIT?
WILLOW, XANDER, YOU'LL HELP
ME BEGIN OUR RESEARCH ANEW.
UNLESS WE FIND A WAY TO
CURE MARCIE'S INVISIBILITY,
THEN BUFFY WILL BE...
A SITTING DUCK.
- COME ON.
- WELL, I HAVE TO TRY ON MY DRESS.
AND AM I
REALLY BAIT?
SO, HOW MUCH
THE CREEPY IS IT...
THAT THIS MARCIE'S
BEEN AT THIS FOR MONTHS?
SPYING ON US.
LEARNING OUR MOST
GUARDED SECRETS.
SO ARE YOU SAYING
SHE'S INVISIBLE...
BECAUSE SHE'S
SO UNPOPULAR?
THAT ABOUT SUMS IT UP.
BUMMER FOR HER.
IT'S AWFUL
TO FEEL THAT LONELY.
SO YOU'VE READ SOMETHING
ABOUT THE FEELING?
HEY, YOU THINK
I'M NEVER LONELY
BECAUSE I'M SO CUTE
AND POPULAR?
I CAN BE SURROUNDED BY PEOPLE
AND BE COMPLETELY ALONE.
IT'S NOT LIKE ANY OF
THEM REALLY KNOW ME.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW IF THEY
LIKE ME HALF THE TIME.
PEOPLE JUST WANT TO BE
IN THE POPULAR ZONE.
SOMETIMES WHEN I TALK,
EVERYONE'S SO BUSY
AGREEING WITH ME,
THEY DON'T HEAR
A WORD I SAY.
WELL, IF YOU FEEL
SO ALONE,
THEN WHY DO YOU WORK SO
HARD AT BEING POPULAR?
WELL, IT BEATS BEING
ALONE ALL BY YOURSELF.
?[ Flute ] SHH.
LISTEN.
COME ON.
WE COULD TALK TO HER,
PERHAPS REASON WITH HER.
OR POSSIBLY GRAB HER.
THERE ARE THREE OF US.
LET'S GO.
IF YOU EVER TELL ANYONE THAT
I CHANGED IN A MOP CLOSET...
YOUR SECRET
DIES WITH ME.
LOOKS OKAY
BUT HURRY.
OKAY.
?[ Continues ]
OVER HERE.
MARCIE.
WE KNOW WHAT
HAPPENED TO YOU.
PLEASE, CAN WE
TALK TO YOU?
WE'RE SORRY
WE IGNORED YOU.
CAN YOU SAY...
GULP?
[ Footsteps ] [ Door Slams ]
[ POUNDING ON DOOR ]
WHAT'S THAT SOUND?
[ HISSING ]
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU
WERE SAYING BEFORE?
I UNDERSTAND.
SOMEHOW IT DOESN'T SEEM TO MATTER
HOW POPULAR YOU ARE WHEN...
[ Cordelia ] YOU WERE POPULAR?
IN WHAT ALTERNATE UNIVERSE?
IN I.A.
THE POINT IS, I DID SORT OF FEEL
LIKE SOMETHING WAS MISSING.
IS THAT WHEN YOU BECAME
WEIRD AND GOT KICKED OUT?
OKAY, CAN WE HAVE
THE HEARTFELT TALK...
WITH A LITTLE LESS
TALK FROM YOU?
CORDELIA?
[ CRASHING ]
[ Muffled Cries ] CORDELIA!
CORDELIA!
[ Yells ]
BUFFY!
IT'S GAS.
SHE'S SNUFFED OUT
THE PILOT LIGHT.
THE GAS IS UP FULL.
I CAN'T FIND
THE SHUTOFF VALVE.
IS THIS IT?
OK, THAT'S BAD.
HOW ABOUT THE DOOR?
NO!
ONE SPARK, AND YOU'LL TAKE
THE WHOLE BUILDING WITH US.
CORDELIA!
OH, MY GOD.
[ Blow Lands ] [ Grunts ]
[ Footsteps ]
[ Gasps, Moans ]
BUFFY.
YOU'RE AWAKE?
YEAH.
I CAN'T FEEL MY FACE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
MY FACE.
MY FACE IS NUMB.
WHAT IS SHE DOING?
I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
[ Grunts, Groans ]
THAT SHOULD GIVE US
A FEW MINUTES, BUT WE'VE...
IF WE DON'T GET OUT
OF THIS ROOM SOON...
WHY IS MARCIE
DOING THIS?
THE LONELINESS,
THE CONSTANT EXILE.
SHE'S...
SHE HAS GONE MAD.
YOU THINK?
[ Marcie ] I'M DISAPPOINTED.
I REALLY HOPED YOU GUYS
HAD FIGURED IT OUT BY NOW.
WELL, WHY DON'T
YOU EXPLAIN IT?
COME ON, MARCIE, WHAT ARE
WE SUPPOSED TO LEARN?
YEAH. WHAT DO YOU WANT
TO TEACH US?
[ Marcie ] YOU DON'T GET IT.
YOU'RE NOT THE STUDENT.
YOU'RE THE LESSON.
WHAT DID YOU DO
TO MY FACE?
YOUR FACE.
THAT'S WHAT THIS IS
ALL ABOUT, ISN'T IT?
YOUR BEAUTIFUL FACE.
IT'S WHAT MAKES YOU SHINE...
JUST A LITTLE BIT BRIGHTER
THAN THE REST OF US.
WE ALL WANT WHAT YOU HAVE,
TO BE NOTICED, REMEMBERED,
TO BE SEEN.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
[ Marcie ] I'M FULFILLING
YOUR FONDEST WISH.
I'M GONNA GIVE YOU A FACE
NO ONE WILL EVER FORGET.
[ GAS HISSING ] [ Coughing ]
ONE, TWO, THREE!
AGAIN.
MARCIE,
YOU CAN'T DO THIS.
[ Marcie ] WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA DO, SLAY ME?
MARCIE, YOU KNOW THIS IS WRONG.
[ Punch Lands ]
YOU SHOULD HAVE
STAYED OUT OF MY WAY.
YOU KNOW, I-I THOUGHT YOU
WOULD UNDERSTAND MY VISION,
BUT YOU'RE JUST LIKE THEM.
PLEASE DON'T DO THIS.
NO...
NO!
YOU SHOULD BE GRATEFUL.
PEOPLE WHO PASS YOU
ON THE STREET...
ARE GONNA REMEMBER YOU
FOR THE REST OF THEIR LIVES.
CHILDREN ARE GONNA
DREAM ABOUT YOU.
AND EVERY ONE OF YOUR FRIENDS WHO
COMES TO THE CORONATION TONIGHT
WILL TAKE THE SIGHT
OF THE MAY QUEEN...
TO THEIR GRAVES.
[ Cordelia ] WAIT!
NO. WE REALLY HAVE
TO GET STARTED.
THE LOCAL ANESTHETIC
WILL WEAR OFF SOON.
I DON'T WANT YOU TO FAINT.
IT'S LESS FUN
IF YOU'RE NOT AWAKE.
YOU GUYS ARE, UH...
YOU'RE BLACKING OUT ON ME.
LET ME SEE.
I THINK WE SHOULD START
WITH YOUR SMILE.
I THINK IT SHOULD BE WIDER.
MARCIE, I KNOW YOU THINK
I DON'T UNDERSTAND, BUT I DO.
YEAH, I'LL BET
YOU KNOW HOW I FEEL.
I BE YOU CAN BE
WITH ALL YOUR FRIENDS
AND JUST FEEL SO ALONE 'CAUSE
THEY DON'T REALLY KNOW YOU.
YOU'RE JUST A TYPICAL
SELF-INVOLVED, SPOILED LITTLE BRAT,
AND YOU THINK YOU CAN CHARM YOUR
WAY OUT OF THIS, DON'T YOU?
ISN'T THAT WHAT YOU THINK?
[ Blade Slashes ]
[ Screams ]
I SEE RIGHT THROUGH YOU.
HYAH!
OH, MY GOD! GET ME
OUT OF HERE, PLEASE.
JUST HOLD STILL.
[ Footsteps ] [ Blow Landing ]
OHH!
AAH!
OH, MY GOD!
COME ON!
[ COUGHING ]
WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU TELL ME.
I'M UP, MOM.
HI. WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I BROUGHT YOU THE CODEX.
I CAME IN THROUGH THE BASEMENT.
I SMELLED THE GAS.
YES, WELL,
SHUT IT OFF,
OTHERWISE THE WHOLE
BUILDING WILL GO UP.
I'LL GET IT.
IT'S NOT LIKE
I NEED THE OXYGEN.
COME ON, LET'S
GET OUT OF HERE.
YOU KNOW, I REALLY
FELT SORRY FOR YOU.
YOU'VE SUFFERED.
THERE'S ONE THING I REALLY
DIDN'T FACTOR INTO ALL THIS.
YOU'RE A THUNDERING LOONY.
BUFFY,
ARE YOU OKAY?
AAH! OH, MY GOD!
OH, MY GOD!
AAH, BUFFY!
AAH!
BUFFY!
OH, MY GOD.
[ Sobbing ]
[ Marcie ]
HEY, MORON, I'M INVISIBLE.
HOW YOU GONNA
FIGHT SOMEONE YOU CAN'T SEE?
OH, MY GOD.
CORDELIA, SHUT UP.
OKAY.
[ Creaking ] AAH!
I SEE YOU.
AAH!
EVERYBODY,
STAY WHERE YOU ARE!
F.B.I., NOBODY MOVE.
OK, WE'LL TAKE IT
FROM HERE NOW, MA'AM.
TAKE WHAT FROM WHERE?
I'M AGENT DOYLE. THIS
IS AGENT MANETTI.
WE'RE HERE
FOR THE GIRL.
WELL, WHERE WERE YOU
10 MINUTES AGO
WHEN SHE WAS
PLAYING SURGEON?
I'M SORRY. WE CAME
AS FAST AS WE COULD.
WE'LL TAKE IT
FROM HERE ON.
YOU CAN CURE HER?
WE CAN...
REHABILITATE HER.
IN TIME,
SHE'LL LEARN TO BE A USEFUL
MEMBER OF SOCIETY AGAIN.
VERY USEFUL.
THIS ISN'T THE FIRST TIME
THIS HAS HAPPENED, IS IT?
IT'S HAPPENED
AT OTHER SCHOOLS.
WE'RE NOT AT LIBERTY
TO DISCUSS THAT.
IT WOULD BE BEST FOR YOU TO
FORGET THIS WHOLE INCIDENT.
DO YOU KNOW THAT
YOU GUYS ARE VERY CREEPY?
THANK YOU
FOR YOUR HELP.
OH, AND, UH...
HAVE A NICE DAY.
CAN I GET UNTIED NOW?
THANKS.
I JUST CAN'T BELIEVE
HOW TWISTED MARCIE GOT.
BY THE WAY, HOW DID YOU GUYS
GET OUT OF THE BOILER ROOM?
OH, WELL, WHEN THE GAS
WAS COMING DOWN...
JANITOR,
UM, FOUND US,
SHUT THE VALVE OFF.
WE WERE REALLY LUCKY.
I'LL SAY.
HI.
HEY.
LOOK, UM, I DIDN'T GET A CHANCE
TO SAY ANYTHING YESTERDAY,
WITH THE CORONATION
AND EVERYTHING,
BUT, UM, I GUESS I JUST
WANT TO SAY THANK YOU.
ALL OF YOU.
THAT'S FUNNY, 'CAUSE SHE
LOOKS LIKE CORDELIA.
YOU REALLY HELPED
ME OUT YESTERDAY,
AND YOU DIDN'T HAVE TO,
SO THANK YOU.
IT'S OK.
LISTEN, WE WERE GONNA GRAB LUNCH
IN A MINUTE, IF YOU WANTED TO...
WHOA. YOU'RE NOT HANGING
WITH THESE LOSERS, ARE YOU?
ARE YOU KIDDING?
I WAS JUST
BEING CHARITABLE,
HELPING THEM WITH
THEIR FASHION PROBLEMS.
YOU THINK I REALLY FELT LIKE
JOINING THAT SOCIAL LEPER COLONY?
PUH-LEASE!
BOY, WHERE'S
AN INVISIBLE GIRL
WHEN YOU REALLY
NEED ONE?
WE THINK YOU'LL
BE HAPPY HERE.
YOU SHOULD FIT
RIGHT IN.
WELCOME, MARCIE.
CLASS, THIS IS MARCIE.
PLEASE SIT DOWN.
OK, CLASS,
LET'S GET STARTED.
EVERYBODY TURN
TO PAGE 54 OF YOUR TEXTS.
GRR! ARG!
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org