In every generation there is a Chosen One,
She alone will stand against the vampires,
the demons and the forces of darkness.
She is the Slayer.
Can I help you?
Rupert Giles. I need to see him.
Mr. Giles, he's our librarian.
Next building over,
first door on your left.
You're welcome.
Oh, God.
Deidre?
Philip.
Help! Help! Somebody, please!
Must we have this noise
during your callisthenics?
It's not noise! It's music!
I know music! Music has notes!
This is noise!
I'm aerobicising! I must have the beat!
Wonderful.
You work on your muscle tone
while my brain dribbles out of my ears.
Help! Help, please!
Help me, somebody, please!
Very good. And the rest is silence.
"The Dark Age"
Time to go to sleep.
I'm on a beach.
But not one of those American beaches.
One of those island beaches
where the water's way too blue.
And I'm laying on my towel.
And it's just before sunset.
- And Gavin Rossdale's massaging my feet.
- Oh, that's good!
Uh, I'm in Florence, Italy. I've rented
this scooter that's parked outside.
And I'm in a little restaurant eating ziti.
And there are no more tables left...
so they have to seat this guy with me,
and it's John Cusack.
Very impressive.
You have such an eye for detail.
- 'Cause, with the ziti...
- What are you two up to?
Just having a quick game of
Anywhere But Here.
Oh! Amy Yip at the water-slide park.
You never come up with anything new.
I'm just not fickle like you two, OK?
I'm constant in my affections.
Amy Yip at the water-slide park.
Do you think Giles ever played
Anywhere But Here when he was in school?
Giles lived for school. He's actually
still bitter that there are only 12 grades.
He probably sat in math class thinking
"There should be more math.
This could be mathier"
Come on! You don't think
he ever got restless as a kid?
Are you kidding?
His diapers were tweed.
- Giles!
- Oh. There you are.
Hey, morning. Say, is that tweed?
What? Oh, yes. Um...
- Now, look. Tonight is very important.
- Now that's a surprise!
So, what's on tap tonight
that's so important?
Uprising? Prophesied ritual?
Preordained death-fest?
Ah, the old standards.
Medical transport is delivering
a monthly supply of blood to the hospital.
- Vampire meals-on-wheels.
- Hopefully not.
Uh, we'll meet outside the hospital
at 8:30 sharp.
- I'll bring the weaponry.
- I'll bring the party mix.
- Just don't be late.
- Have I ever let you down?
Do you want me to answer that,
or shall I just glare?
- Morning, England.
- Oh, hello, Ms, er... Jenny.
- Feel the passion.
- Willow.
Coughing, not speaking.
- Are we still on for tomorrow?
- What's tomorrow?
I'm reviewing some computer basics for the
couple of students who've fallen behind.
Willow's helping out for extra credit.
Those poor schlubs
have to attend school on Saturday!
9 a.m. OK with you, Xander?
Got a bit of schlub on your shoe there.
- Cordelia's gonna meet us.
- Ooh, gang, do you hear that?
A bonus day of class plus Cordelia!
Mix in a little rectal surgery,
and it's my best day ever!
- Walk me to class?
- Pleasure.
- Look at them.
- A twosome of cuteness.
Can't you just image them getting together?
Oh! Thank you so much
for loaning me the Forester book.
- It's wonderful.
- Glad you enjoyed it.
That was so romantic. So... evocative.
That edition was my father's.
I must have read it... 20 times.
Yeah, you know how you have to,
to dog-ear your favorite pages
- so you can go back to them?
- Uh, uh, what?
Well, I mean, I-I practically had to
fold back every single page.
So finally I just started underlining
all the pages I really wanted to discuss.
- Underlined?
- But then, of course,
I spilt coffee all over it.
I can't even read it.
- It's a first edition.
- I'm lying, Rupert.
The book's fine.
I just love to see you squirm.
Yes, well, I, uh... trust
I gave good... squirm.
Did anyone ever tell you
you're a fuddy-duddy?
Nobody ever...
seems to tell me anything else.
Did anyone ever tell you
you're kind of a sexy fuddy-duddy?
No. Actually, that-that part
usually gets left out.
I ca-can't imagine why.
This weekend.
Would you like to go out?
Mm, no, I think I'd like to stay in.
- This... Saturday.
- Saturday night.
Let's see if I can make you squirm.
- Rupert Giles?
- Yes?
Detective Winslow.
You're gonna have to come with me.
Why?
There was a homicide on campus last night.
The victim had no identification,
but he was carrying this slip of paper...
with your name and address on it.
My name?
Well, evil just compounds evil,
doesn't it?
First I'm sentenced
to a computer tutorial on Saturday,
now I have to read some computer book.
There are books on computers?
Isn't the point of computers
to replace books?
Cordelia, I'm a little busy right now.
Oh, great!
Can you help me with a ticket? It's
totally bogus. It was a one-way street.
- I was going one way.
- Cordelia!
What? Why does everyone
always yell my name?
I'm not deaf.
And... I can take a hint.
- What's the hint?
- To come back later.
Yeah, when you've visited decaf land.
Where do you want me to go?
- Have you had your breakfast?
- No.
That was probably a good idea.
- Do you know him?
- Yes.
I mean... I did.
His name's Philip Henry.
He was a friend of mine in London.
I haven't spoken to him in 20 years.
Can you think of any reason
why he might have wanted to contact you?
No.
Do you know what that is?
- The tattoo?
- No.
No, I don't.
"Don't be late." Sheesh!
- Hey, fellas.
- Hey.
All's well that ends
with cute ER doctors, I always say.
Since when do doctors take deliveries?
See ya!
Hey! No samplin' the product.
- Angel!
- Buffy. Look out!
- How did you know about this?
- It's delivery day.
Everybody knows about this.
They only ruined one bag.
Do you think you can make sure
the hospital gets the rest?
Thanks. I'm worried about Giles.
- He was supposed to meet me here.
- Maybe he's late.
Giles? Who counts tardiness as,
like, the eighth deadly sin?
You're right. Go.
Buffy. It's late. Uh, you all right?
I was gonna ask you the same thing.
Yes. No, I'm fine. Fine.
I'm, er... I'm rather busy at the moment
so... I'll see you on Monday
at-at school.
Giles, did you forget?
The hospital, vampires,
handy carry-out packets of blood?
Oh! Yes, uh...
Are you all right? Were you hurt?
No. I mean, my feelings a little.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing, nothing. Nothing's wrong.
I'm just in... the, uh,
middle of something extremely important.
And... I'm sorry,
but I'm gonna have to say good night now.
I'm sorry to disturb you.
Uh, I realize it's, uh,
five in the morning there, um...
Uh, I-I'm trying to reach Diedre Page.
My name is Rupert Giles,
uh, uh, she knows me.
It's, it's very important.
I'm terribly sorry. I didn't know.
When did she, er... pass away?
Oh. That recently.
Um... Yes. Yes, um...
We were friends when we were young.
My condolences.
So.
You're back.
This isn't right. School on a Saturday.
It throws off my internal clock.
When are we gonna need computers
for real life anyway?
Hmm, let's see. There's
home, school, work, games...
You know, computers are on the way out.
I think paper's gonna make a big comeback.
- And the abacus.
- Yeah, you know,
you don't see enough abaci.
Hi, guys. The first thing
we're gonna do is... Buffy?
- Huh? Did I fall asleep already?
- You miss your friends.
Sit here, Buff. Demilitarize the zone
between me and Cordelia.
Yeah, and de-louse him
while you're at it.
Actually, I wanted
to talk to you for a second.
- Is something wrong?
- Is there some crisis
that requires instant action?
Very far from here?
- It's Giles.
- Ooh. He's all right, isn't he?
I don't know. He didn't show up
when he was supposed to last night.
And then, when I went over to his place,
he was acting... well, very anti-Giles.
He wouldn't let me in.
And he looked really bad.
I think he might have been...
- I think he was drinking.
- He was home alone drinking?
- But... tea, right?
- It wasn't tea, Will.
Yep. Yep, I knew this would happen.
Nobody can be wound as straight and narrow
as Giles without a dark side erupting.
My Uncle Rory was the stodgiest
taxidermist you've ever met, by day.
By night, it was
booze, whores and fur flyin'.
- Were there whores?
- He was alone.
Give it time.
So, none of you guys have noticed
anything different lately?
- No.
- Not really.
- Uh, you haven't seen anything weird?
- Nope.
No. He seemed perfectly normal yesterday
when I saw him talking to the police.
And you waited till now
to tell us this because?
- I didn't think it was important.
- We understand. It wasn't about you.
What were the police
talking to him about?
Oh, don't tell me.
I know this one. Um...
Something about...
a homicide.
That's it. I'm calling him right now.
- I know you. You ran that costume shop.
- Oh, I'm pleased you remember.
You sold me that dress for Halloween
and nearly got us all killed!
But you looked great.
- So now we're even?
- I'll let you know when we're even.
- What are you doing here?
- Snooping around.
- Honesty. Nice touch.
- It's one of my virtues.
- Not really.
- I've got a great idea.
Why don't I just call the police
and have you arrested
for breaking and entering, and then
I can get back to my fun Saturday?
Yes, the police. Well,
they'll have all those questions
and they'll really need Rupert
to answer them all.
- You know Giles.
- We go back.
Way back. You don't happen
to know where he is, do you?
- Hello.
- Giles, it's me.
Buffy, unless this is an emergency,
I'll see you on Monday.
What's the Mark of Eyghon?
- Giles?
- Cat got his tongue?
I'm in your office with someone who claims
to be an old friend of yours. Ethan Rayne?
He's there with you?
Listen, Buffy, you're... You're
in grave danger while Ethan's there.
I want you to put the phone down and get
out of the library as soon as possible.
I'm not going anywhere
until you give me some answers!
Buffy!
Ethan!
Don't let him get away!
I'm not gonna get close enough
to feel his pulse, but... he looks dead.
Except for the walking
and attacking Buffy part.
He's dead.
Sorry, Philip. Really, I am.
- Is everyone all right?
- Super!
- I kicked a guy.
- We're OK.
The dead guy here
interrupted our tutorial.
Been meaning to thank you for that.
- It can't be.
- Yes, it can.
- Hello, Ripper.
- I thought I told you to leave town.
You did. I didn't. Shop's lease
is paid till the end of the month.
Why did he call him Ripper?
You should have left when I told you.
- Oh.
- Giles!
You put these people in danger.
The people I care about.
If you cared so much about them,
why didn't you leave town?
You've been having the dreams. I know.
I have. We both know what's coming.
What dreams? What is going on here?
- Tell her, Ripper.
- Giles!
Jenny!
Now, there's something
you don't see every day.
I'm gonna be in therapy till I'm 30.
Where's Ethan?
Where'd he go?
Are you all right, Jenny?
Careful. Can you stand?
I think so.
This is what happens
when you have school on Saturday.
Lean on me.
It'll be all right.
- Promise?
- I promise.
I believe you.
- How's your head?
- Throbbing.
I lost Ethan.
Giles, what's going on?
It's complicated, Buffy.
And quite frankly, it's private.
I don't care from private.
I care from dead guys attacking us.
I care from you lost weekending
in your apartment.
I wasn't...
I was just trying to find a solution.
Giles, share.
What is the Mark of Eyghon?
Hey!
This is not your battle.
And as your Watcher, I'm telling
you unequivocally to stay out of it!
- I have to get Jenny home.
- Mm. Thank you.
We have work to do.
Will, I want you to find out
anything and everything you can
- about the Mark of Eyghon.
- I'll try the Net.
But Mark of Eyghon sounds like
Giles-and-his-books sort of deal.
Then we hit the books.
Xander, how do you feel about digging
through some of Giles' personal files
- and seeing what you can find?
- I feel pretty good about it.
Does that make me a sociopath? Nah!
- What?
- What about me? I care about Giles.
Work with Xander.
- When I say "care", I-I mean...
- Cordelia!
OK, OK!
Thanks for bringing me here.
I'm not quite ready
to be home alone just yet.
Jenny, uh...
I'm so very sorry about all of this.
I, er...
I never meant for you
to be involved in-in...
any of this.
So I got involved.
It's what happens
when two people... get involved.
I really am, however,
gonna have to get you home.
It's not, uh...
Well, I'm... not a very safe person
to be around at the moment.
Nothing's safe in this world, Rupert.
Don't you know that by now?
It's not Egyptian, it's Etruscan!
Mistaken for Egyptian
by the design pattern.
But any fool can see
it predates their iconology.
Look, the Mark of Eyghon,
worn by his initiates.
"Eyghon, also called the sleepwalker,
can only exist in this reality...
by possessing an unconscious host."
"Temporary possession imbues
the host with a euphoric feeling of power."
Yeah, but what about not temporary?
"'Unless the proper rituals are observed,
the possession is permanent,
and Eyghon will be born
from within the host."
- I'm guessing eww.
- Wait. Hey, listen.
"Once called, Eyghon can also
take possession of the dead,
but its demonic energy
soon disintegrates the host
and it must jump to the nearest dead or
unconscious person to continue living."
I still don't get
what this has to do with Giles.
I don't know about Giles,
but ancient sects used to...
induce possession for
bacchanals and-and orgies.
OK. Giles and orgies in the same sentence.
- I could have lived without that one.
- Wait a minute.
The dead guy's all puddly now.
So the demon's gone.
There was no one dead to jump into.
I mean, we're all not dead, right?
No. No one dead.
But someone unconscious.
- What was that?
- What was what?
I thought I heard something.
I didn't.
Here.
Drink that and then I'll...
drive you home.
You could take me home...
or you could take advantage
of me in my weakened state.
Thank you, operator.
There's no answer at Ms Calendar's
and Giles' phone is out of order.
I'm gonna go over there.
Jenny, um...
I'm, I'm really very attracted t-to you.
- Good.
- But, um...
Now really isn't the right time.
Oh, there's never been a better time.
It's not right.
I would be taking advantage.
God, you just don't change, do you?
What?
"It's not right. It wouldn't be proper."
"People might get hurt."
You're like a woman, Ripper.
You cry at every funeral.
You never had the strength for me.
You don't deserve me.
But guess what?
You've got me...
under your skin.
Was it good for you?
Oh, you never had the stomach.
But that's OK,
'cause I'm about to rip it out!
Back off!
Three down, two to go.
Be seein' ya!
- Are you all right?
- Jenny. Oh, God.
- Giles, how do we stop this?
- Oh, God. What have I done?
Talk to me!
Giles, you're scaring me.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be sorry. Be Giles.
Come on, we fight monsters.
This is what we do.
They show up, they scare us, I beat 'em up
and they go away. This isn't any different!
It is different.
- Because you don't know how to stop it?
- Because I created it.
Did you find anything?
The most meticulous banking
and phone records you've ever seen.
And, um... this.
That's Giles?
I was 21.
Studying history at Oxford.
And, of course, the occult by night.
I hated it.
The tedious grind of study, the...
overwhelming pressure of my destiny.
I dropped out. Went to London.
Fell in with the worst crowd
that would have me.
We practiced magics.
Small stuff, for pleasure or gain.
Then Ethan and I discovered something...
bigger.
Eyghon.
Yes.
One of us would, um...
go into a deep sleep...
and the others would, uh...
summon him.
It was an extraordinary high.
God, we were fools.
- And you couldn't control it.
- One of us, Randall...
He lost control.
Eyghon took him whole. We tried
to exorcise the demon from Randall...
but it killed him.
We killed him.
We thought we were free
of the demon after that.
But now he's back.
- And, one by one, he will kill us all.
- Three down, two to go.
Then it's going after Ethan.
I better beat it there.
- We'd better.
- I'd better.
Giles, you're barely mobile
and speed is of the serious essence here.
I don't know how to stop it
without killing Jenny.
I've got the guys working on it.
I'll, um... try to contain it
until we figure something.
Buffy.
I'm sorry.
I know.
Ethan?
Ethan!
Giles told me everything.
Look, it's coming for you.
And you came to protect me.
I'm touched.
Don't worry. It's nothing personal.
To protect Giles, I have to protect you.
How does Ripper inspire such goodness?
- 'Cause he's Giles.
- And I'm not.
- Still, lucky me.
- Hm. Lucky you.
Well, we can't run. Eyghon will find us.
- This mark's like a homing beacon.
- It's OK. I'm not much into running.
- Aren't we manly?
- One of us is.
You're gonna hide till it's over.
- Excellent plan.
- Is there a way into the back?
Uh, there's a back door.
It's locked. I think it's solid.
We'll set up there. Let's go.
Oh, no. Please.
Ladies first.
Wakey wakey. You're missing all the fun.
- What fun?
- Your initiation.
You know what? I'm not real interested
in joining your club.
Too late. I already voted you in.
You know, I hope you're not
taking this personally, Buffy.
I actually kind of like you.
It's just that I like myself a lot more.
If you think of it karmically, this is,
this is really big for your soul, you know.
Taking my place with the demon,
giving... so that others may live.
I'm gonna kill you.
Will that blow the karma thing?
Sweet child.
Now this may sting a little, just at first.
But don't worry, that'll go away
once the searing pain kicks in.
You can go ahead and scream if you like.
We have to figure out how to
kill this thing and we need to do it fast.
- Uh... hot lava.
- That's for a heretic.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, OK. Uh...
Oo, oo! 'Bury a potato!'
No, that's for warts.
Who writes this stuff?
I've got the solution right here.
"To kill a demon, cut off its head."
Oh, yeah-yeah-yeah! We'll, uh, find
Ms. Calendar, then we'll decapitate her.
Hey! She'll be the first headless
computer teacher in school.
- You think anybody'll notice?
- Do you know what you need, Xander,
besides a supply of acne cream?
- A brain.
- That's it!
12 years of you and I'm snappin'!
I don't care if you're a girl.
I'm throwin' down. Come on!
I've seen you fight.
And don't think I can't take you!
Give it your best shot!
Hey!!!
We don't have time for this!
Our friends are in trouble!
Now, we have to put our heads together
and, and get them out of it!
And if you two aren't with me 110%,
then get the hell out of my library!
- We're sorry.
- We'll be good.
OK. Now, we've done the research.
We just have to figure out
how to use it.
Oh, hey! Why don't we find another
dead body for the demon to jump into?
Yes! At the cemetery!
That won't kill the demon.
It'll only give it a change of scenery.
Oh. Oh! Oh, I've got it! I've got it!
She's good.
Hmm. I think
I missed my calling as an artist.
Ethan, listen to me.
This is a bad idea.
You're dealing with
something very dangerous.
But it will get Eyghon off my scent.
Now relax. I'm finished with you.
This is for me.
Ethan? No. No!
Well, I hate to mutilate and run, but...
It's your time.
Eyghon! Take me.
Buffy, get out of here.
No! No!
I've been waiting a long time to do this.
- He's killing her.
- No, trust me. This is gonna work.
Jenny!
- Jenny?
- Rupert.
You knew that
if the demon was in trouble
it was gonna jump
into the nearest dead person.
- I put it in danger.
- And it jumped.
Well, I've had a demon inside me
for a couple hundred years...
just waitin' for a good fight.
- Winner and still champion.
- I think that Ethan guy disappeared again.
Darn. I really wanted
to hit him till he bled.
Well, at least it's over.
You know what the worst thing is?
I was saving up for some
very important shoes.
And now I have to blow my entire allowance
to get this stupid tattoo removed.
Let's just hope
my mom doesn't see it first.
Puttin' that demon into Angel
was pretty brill, Will.
I wasn't sure it was gonna work.
- But it did.
- Like a charm.
Hey! Maybe you should consider
a career as a Watcher.
Oh, no. I don't think
I could handle the stress.
And the dental plan is crap.
I don't see how Giles does it.
I don't think he has a choice.
Jenny. Jenny.
Rupert. Hi.
Uh... I tried to call you last night.
See how you were.
Yeah, I-I-I, uh...
I left my phone off the hook.
I seem to need a lot of sleep lately.
But, but you're al-alright?
Is, is, is there anything you need?
No, I'm fine.
I mean, I'm not...
running around, wind-in-my-hair,
the-hills-are-alive-with-
the-sound-of-music fine, but...
I'm coping.
- I would like to help.
- I know.
Perhaps we could, um, talk sometime, um...
Dinner, or, or a drink?
- When you're feeling stronger.
- Sure. Some time.
Yeah. Some time.
I better get to class.
Of course.
Hey.
Is... she OK?
- The hills are not alive.
- I'm sorry to hear that... I think.
I don't think
she'll ever really forgive me.
Maybe she shouldn't.
Maybe you should.
I never wanted you to see that side of me.
I'm not gonna lie to you.
It was scary.
I'm so used to you
being a grown-up and...
then I find out that you're a person.
Most grown-ups are.
Who would have thought?
Some are even...
short-sighted... foolish people.
So... after all this time...
we finally find out that we do
have something in common.
Which, apart from being a little weird...
is kind of OK?
I think we're supposed
to be training right now.
Yes, yes. Um...
We need to...
concentrate on your... flexibility.
And you know what?
I have just the perfect music.
Go on, say it. You know you want to.
It's not music, it's just, uh,
meaningless sounds.
- There. Feel better?
- Yes. Thanks.
The Bay City Rollers. Now that's music.
I didn't hear that.
Subtitles extended & timed by: UAR
www.tvsubtitles.net