Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
Buffy, I love you.
We conjure the goddess Thespia
to help us locate demonic energy.
Are you sure we're ready for that?
Or not.
Tell me where the Key is.
The Key is energy. It's a portal.
- My brethren sent it to you.
- Dawn.
- She's not my sister?
- She doesn't know that.
Tell me a story.
OK. Once upon a time, there was a kitty.
She was very little and she was all alone
and nobody wanted her.
- This is a very upsetting story.
- But it gets better.
Cos one day the kitty was running
around the street and a man came,
and swooped her up,
and took her to the pound.
At the pound there were lots of other kitties
and there were puppies and some ferrets...
Were there dolphins?
Yes. Many dolphins at the pound.
Was there a camel?
There was the front of a camel. A half-camel.
Did the kitty get chosen
by some nice people?
Well, now you ruined the ending.
I'm sleepy.
Do you mind if I keep the light on?
I was gonna look up some spells.
It's fine. I don't need to be snuggled.
Vixen!
You've been Spell Gal night and day lately.
Well, I just wanna keep up with you and...
Well, I just like to be useful.
You know, to the gang?
I just... never feel useful.
You are. You're essential.
- Think Buffy found out anything tonight?
- At the factory? I don't know.
If there was something,
I figured she'd call us.
I don't know what to say.
Tell me about it.
She has no idea?
No. She thinks she's my kid sister.
Are you going to tell her?
How can I?
She'd freak and that's the last thing we need.
We have to keep her safe.
This woman, this whatever she was.
She knows you now.
Should we be thinking
about sending Dawn away?
Away where?
I don't know.
Your father's?
Yeah. He's...
in Spain, with his secretary.
Living the cliché.
I called him when Mom got sick.
He hasn't even...
I'm sorry.
When he bailed on us,
I remember Dawn cried for a week.
Except she didn't.
She wasn't there,
but I can still feel what it was like.
They sent her to me, Giles.
I think I have to take care of her.
I want to.
- Do we tell the others?
- No. No one.
They'd act weird around her,
and it's safer for everyone if they don't know.
Yes.
We have to find out who this woman is
and what she needs Dawn for.
- If she comes after you...
- She'll come.
She'll come for us.
OK. Now I'm upset.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
- Thumb! Necessary opposable thumb!
- Sorry. Crybaby.
- You know what, guys? Just leave it here.
- Got it.
- I don't need help.
- Just be careful.
But we just helped her
move the stuff in a few days ago.
And it was fun!
People help each other out, Anya.
It's one of our strange customs.
Giles, you're doing the smallest amount
of helping that can actually be called helping.
Well, I saw myself
in more of a patriarchal sort of role.
You know. Lots of pointing and scowling.
- You two, stop that!
- He started it.
He called me a bad name.
I think it was bad. It might've been Latin.
- Stop it, or you're going to break something.
- Or I'm going to break something.
Can't believe you're giving up
this cherry corner suite.
Just a few days after we moved you in!
It's no big.
You know, with Mom not being well,
I'm hardly ever here.
Just figured I'd save a little cash
for this semester.
- I think that's smart.
- Still, it's hard to give up.
Two entrances. A lot of opportunity
for bawdy French farce.
- Everybody loves bawdy...
- Where's Dawn?
- I think she just walked out.
- Dawn!
- Some of your CDs are my CDs.
- I know. Come help me fold.
Feeling that fight?
Nothing like getting your ass kicked
to make your ass hurt.
- You'll take her next time.
- Cos you'll have backup, baby.
- She's messing with all of us.
- Yes. We'll find her weaknesses and then...
Yeah. You learn her source and
we'll introduce her to her insect reflection.
That was funny
if you studied Taglarin mythic rites.
- And are a complete dork.
- Then how come Xander didn't laugh?
I don't know that Taglarin stuff.
Hey. You wanna start
taking stuff down to the car?
- Yeah.
- OK.
Stupid.
OK. Guys, now remember,
you have to be at the Bronze by eight.
Bronze.
Tomorrow night! Tara's birthday!
Right! Right.
We have to bring presents?
Birth is a present thing?
I got something picked out, yeah.
You guys can all still come, right? I mean,
I know there's this new evil and all, but...
No, no. We'll be there. I could definitely
use a break from all this craziness.
- What's the story?
- Another crazy. Got her family out there.
- A guess. No history of mental problems?
- Yeah. That makes, like, five this month.
They told me Sunnydale
was gonna be interesting.
- Aren't you off?
- Yeah, as of now. Have fun.
I need a favour.
Thank you for coming. We value your
patronage. Come again for more purchases!
Could we be a little less effusive, Anya?
Don't want to frighten the people.
I'm just so excited. They come in, I help them.
They give us money in exchange for goods.
You give me money for working for you.
I have a place in the world now.
I'm part of the system. I'm a working gal!
Yes. Why don't you start
organising the shipping orders?
No, that's boring.
I just wanna do the money parts.
Well, sure I forgot about the party.
There's kind of a lot going on.
And it's not, you know, the most
thrilling social event of the season.
Yeah. It's a big deal for Willow, though.
I mean, you are gonna be there?
Yeah. Barring monsters.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Gimme sugar. I've come to buy sugar.
We value your patronage.
Any breakthroughs
on the identity of Miss Congeniality?
Well, I've narrowed it down some.
Your definition of narrow
is impressively wide.
Well, you didn't give me much to go on. She
looks human, so the mug shots are no use.
You can't be more specific
about what she's like?
She was kinda like Cordelia, actually.
- I'm pretty sure she dyes her hair.
- That one, of course. Our work is done.
- There must be something on her.
- The answer is somewhere here.
It's right in front of us
and we're too blind to see it!
I'm helping. I'm reading.
I'm quiet.
So, what'd you get her?
Tara. You said you got a present already.
Yeah, that was a tangled web of lies, sweetie.
I'm not really sure what kind of thing she'd...
- I mean, I don't really know her that well.
- I know.
- I mean, she's nice.
- Yeah! Yeah, nice. Nice.
- I just... I sort of...
- I don't necessarily get her, but she's nice.
- Yeah. There's just that thing.
- That thing.
- That thing of not understanding...
- Half of what she says?
- As for example. But she's super nice.
- You betcha.
Think there'll be a lot of Wiccas there?
Heavy Wiccan crowd?
That's sort of her deal. Her and Willow are all
Wiccie. Swinging with the Wiccan lifestyle.
- Which is cool.
- Oh, yeah.
I just hope we fit in, not awkward.
With Willow, it's like she's got
this whole new thing in her life.
But she's still Willow. I can figure her out.
But Tara, I know she likes Willow.
She already has one of those.
I have a present-buying headache.
Tara's birthday is
one too many things to worry about.
Relax. You should take a few minutes.
Train or stretch out.
Do something to work off the tension.
You want me, Slayer, come and get me.
Oh, I'm coming. I'm coming right now!
What are you thinking?
All about you, baby.
You're my little lamb.
- Come up with anything yet?
- Candles maybe, or bath oils of some kind.
I saw a really cute sweater at Bloomie's,
but I think I want me to have it.
- And you are talking about what on earth?
- Tara's birthday. We're at a loss.
You're in a magic shop
and you can't think what Tara would like.
I believe you're both profoundly stupid.
We don't really know
what kind of things witches like.
What, are we gonna get her
some cheesy crystal ball?
Bloody well better not.
I've got mine already wrapped.
Are all these magic books?
Private collection. Books for sale
are against the walls over there.
All these books got spells in 'em?
Turn people into frogs, things like that?
Yeah, we're building a race of frog people.
It's a good time.
So, are you all witches or...?
Hey, don't do a spell on me now.
Was there something in particular
you were looking for?
Her insect reflection. That is so good.
- That'd be funny, if her centre of power was...
- Well, what do you know?
What's the matter?
You don't have a hug for your big brother?
Brother?
Willow, this is Donny.
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
And these are my friends.
What, all of you hang out?
Wow. That's more people
than you met in high school.
How did you find...
I mean, how come you came?
Well, duh, birthday girl.
We came down in the camper,
been all over the campus.
"We"?
Look what I found!
Dad, hi.
Well, here's my girl.
- Such a surprise.
- Yes.
- Cousin Beth.
- Hey.
One of your dorm-mates
said I might find you here.
These are... these are friends.
This is Mr Giles. He runs the shop.
- How do you do?
- Pleasure.
I don't mean to interrupt your plans.
I know we've come kind of suddenly,
- but I thought we could have dinner.
- OK.
Why don't I pick you up at six,
and we'll do some catching up?
Yes, sir.
Forgive me for running out.
We're double-parked.
Nice to meet you all.
That's so weird. Your whole family.
Yeah.
- They seem nice.
- You know. They're OK.
- Families are always...
- They make you crazy.
Usually.
- Wanna get into research mode?
- Sure.
- Honey, I'm home.
- Did you have a good day at work?
It's a rat race.
I squared away your stuff.
Wouldn't even know you left.
You're a god.
You're like the God of Boyfriends.
Nah, I just like it when you owe me favours.
Well, this earns you a big favour.
There could be outfits.
Be still, my heart.
- See ya later.
- Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Where do you think you're going?
- To Melinda's for dinner.
- Since when?
- Now-ish.
- You can't. It's not safe for you to walk there.
- It's across the street.
- What's the big deal? I'm just gonna go...
- No.
It's family night.
And besides, Melinda's a bad influence.
I don't like you hanging out
with someone that... short.
I am so glad you're moving
back into the house.
This is the source of my gladness.
She makes me crazy.
That's kinda the word I was searching for.
What? She shouldn't be going over there.
A lot of young people are experimenting
with shortness. Gotta nip that in the bud.
She can't be running out whenever she'd like.
- It's more than that.
- What do you mean?
You tell me.
We all have to be careful.
This demon chick is exciting and new.
- I don't know what I'm up against.
- If we're in trouble, I can contact Graham.
- Maybe get the government boys on it.
- No! I don't want them anywhere near this.
Just a suggestion.
Look, the fewer people
that are involved, the safer I will feel.
Every time I think I'm getting closer to you...
- I gotta take off.
- Wait! What?
- I'll call you later.
- Riley.
I want you to help. I'm not...
Yeah. I know you got a lot on your mind.
If you decide you wanna let me in
on any of it, you let me know.
I'll come running.
The door wasn't locked. I was a little early.
I suppose you wanted me
to see all these... toys.
You don't even try to hide it any more.
I'd hoped maybe you'd gotten over
the whole witchcraft thing.
That if we let you go,
you'd get it out of your system.
Then they told me
to look for you in the... that store.
I didn't know that you were coming.
Of course we came.
We haven't heard from you in months.
Your birthday's getting closer.
You know what that means.
I don't think it's...
- It won't mean that...
- You're turning 20.
It's the same age
your mother was when she...
Do your friends even know?
Yes.
Are you lying to me?
You're coming home with us.
You know it's the only way.
Home?
You can't control what's going to happen.
You have evil inside of you
and it will come out.
Letting yourself work all this magic
is only going to make it worse.
Where do you think that power comes from?
It... doesn't feel evil, sir.
Evil never does.
I don't feel much like eating right now.
I'll give you some time,
but we need to be gone by morning.
Your family loves you, Tara, no matter what.
How do you think your friends are going
to feel when they see your true face?
Finally. I thought you were
gonna nap the whole day away.
Stop whining. I remember
when the Lei-Ach were a proud warrior race,
not sneaking around hospitals looking for
sickly types to suck the bone marrow from.
But... let's talk about
my problems for 30 seconds,
if that's perfectly all right with you.
Blonde. Short.
Strong for a human, and massively rude.
Broke my shoe, took my monk.
Any idea who I'm talking about?
A slayer? Oh, God, please don't tell me
I was fighting a vampire slayer!
How unbelievably common!
If I had friends and they heard about this...
And you know she's going around
telling everybody. She's probably just...
Pay attention! I am great and I am beautiful,
and when I walk into a room
all eyes turn to me,
because my name is a holy name
and you will listen!
Get your friends. Find the girl.
Kill the girl. OK, baby?
You have the cutest little suppurating sores!
Has anyone ever told you that?
- Hey.
Was dinner fun?
Well, there's Scoobyage afoot. Giles called
a meeting about our spanking new menace.
You should go. They don't need me for that.
You can fill me in.
No. No, you have to come.
This demon chick is
supposed to be really powerful
and I was thinking,
maybe we can try that spell.
- You know, the one to find demons?
- That didn't work.
Yeah, but we only tried it once
and I think I got some ingredients wrong.
Well, I'm tired. We can do it tomorrow?
- You sure you don't wanna...
- Look, my family's here, OK? I can'tjust...
Not everything is about
your friends and stuff.
Sorry.
No! No, I mean...
There's just so much going on.
I just... I'm really tired.
OK.
I'll see you in the morning. You can fill me in.
Great. We'll be demon hunters.
- Am I late? Did I miss any exposition?
- No, I've nothing earth-shattering to relate.
I've had a few thoughts and wanted to
make sure that we were on the same page.
- Can I buy one of these?
- No.
- With my own money?
- I let you come.
Now sit down and look studious.
Well, first of all,
I want to talk to you about safety.
- This creature could be...
- Will be.
Will be coming after Buffy
and possibly all of us...
Blind Cadria, desolate queen,
work my will upon them all.
Your curse upon them, my obeisance to you.
Now, I may have a lead
on this monk that Buffy spoke of.
There are a few orders that I've read up on...
- I'm sorry, where was I?
- The monk.
Yes. I'd like us all
to start looking at these orders.
It's possible the one this monk
belonged to was wiped out entirely...
You shouldn't be comin' in here.
You got a rep with these monsters.
But you come in here, night after night.
Were you lookin' to get killed?
I come for the ambience.
What can I say? The place just reeks of class.
- Yeah. Well, if Willy was here...
- Willy's not here. Hit me.
Drinking alone? It's not a good sign.
So they tell me.
I buy you a drink, neither one of us
has that problem any more. Now, do we?
- Vodka tonic.
I'm Sandy.
Riley.
- This place is such a dive.
- No, no, it's great.
You just have to close your eyes.
Plug up your nostrils. It's fine.
We could go somewhere else.
Someplace more private.
Oh, Sandy, Sandy.
It's no good.
My heart belongs to another.
Besides, I don't go out with vampires.
They're never interested in my intellect.
- Hi, baby!
- Hello, sweetbreads. Have fun?
It was so exciting. You wouldn't believe it.
I went to April Fool's
and absolutely everything was on sale.
You paid for it?
Oh, no. I just killed the clerk.
Still, a bargain's a bargain.
I ran into Carol Beets.
You know? She sired Brandon,
Brandon from the sewer gang?
And she said the Lei-Ach demon was
recruiting his brethren to kill the Slayer!
How's that?
Apparently, he got recruited by some big
nether-wig and now he's on a mission.
You think they might actually do it? Kill her?
God, that would be pleasant.
Well, if they do,
I think we should do something.
Like a gift basket or something.
- Where are you going?
- To get a decent seat.
If the Slayer's gonna die, I'm gonna watch.
- Tara.
- Beth, what are you...?
- I was looking for you.
- I'm sorry we didn't get to have dinner.
I just wanted to see if everything was OK.
See if you needed any help
with anything. Packing?
Beth, I'm not coming back with you.
- You're not?
- I don't think so.
- You selfish bitch.
- What?
You don't care a bitty bit
about your family, do you?
Your dad's been worried sick
about you every day since you left.
There's a house that needs taking care of.
Donny and your dad do for themselves,
while you're down here
living God knows what kind of lifestyle.
I can't wait till your little friends
find out the truth about you.
And they will, you know.
Doesn't matter how innocent you act.
- They'll see.
- No, they won't.
They will, unless you do
some kind of spell on them.
- You did!
- No!
You did something to them.
I'm telling your father.
No! No, it wasn't anything!
You think you can just go around
cursing people? Your dad's gonna pop.
It was just so they wouldn't see.
So they wouldn't see the demon part of me.
Please don't tell Dad. It's harmless.
I thought I heard something.
Don't you see how out of control you are?
You've lied to these people for a year and
now you've put a spell on them. Is that right?
Is that a human thing to do?
Now, I'm telling your father.
If he doesn't force you
to come home, and he should,
I know he's going
to tell your friends the truth.
If I were you, I'd tell them first,
and then I'd tell them goodbye.
- Do I get paid overtime for this?
- Certainly not.
- Dawn, would you close the door?
- I didn't open it.
Giles! There's something in here!
Where'd it go?
Under there. Go.
You'd be welcome.
Where'd it go?
It's over there!
- How many?
- I've been injured once this month!
Shut up!
Buffy, behind you!
- Tara, where is it? Can you see it?
- Oh, God.
Blind Cadria, lift your veil.
Give evil form and break my spell.
What in God's name is that?
Lei-Ach demon. Fun little buggers.
Big with the marrow-sucking.
- I don't understand.
- I'm not sure I do either.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I was trying to hide.
I didn't want you to see what I am.
- Tara, what?
- What do you mean, what you are?
Demon. The women in our family
have demon in them.
Her mother had it.
That's where the magic comes from.
We came to take her home before...
Well, before things like this
started happening.
You cast a spell on us
to keep us from seeing your demon side.
That's why we couldn't see our attackers.
Nearly got us killed.
- I'll go. I'm very sorry.
- The camper's outside.
Wait! Go?
She just did a spell that went wrong.
It was just a mistake.
It's not the point and it's not your concern.
She belongs with us.
We know how to control her problem.
Tara, look at me.
I trusted you more than anyone in my life.
- Was all thatjust a lie?
- No!
Do you wanna leave?
- It's not your decision, young lady.
- I know that!
Do you wanna leave?
You're going to do what's right, Tara.
Now, I'm taking you out of here
before somebody does get killed.
The girl belongs with her family.
I hope that's clear to the rest of you.
It is.
You want her, Mr Maclay?
You can go ahead and take her.
You just gotta go through me.
- What?
- You heard me.
You wanna take Tara
out of here against her will,
- you gotta come through me.
- And me!
Is this ajoke?
I'm not gonna be
threatened by two little girls.
- You don't wanna mess with us.
- She's a hair-puller.
And you're notjust
dealing with two little girls.
- You're dealing with all of us.
- Except me.
- Except Spike.
- I don't care what happens.
This is insane. You people have
no right to interfere with Tara's affairs.
We are her blood kin!
Who the hell are you?
We're family.
Dad?
You gonna let 'em just...?
Tara, if you don't get in that car,
I swear by God I will beat you down.
And I swear by your full and manly beard,
you're gonna break something trying.
Well. I hope you'll all be happy
hanging out with a disgusting demon.
- Excuse me. What kind?
- What?
What kind of demon is she?
There's a lot of different kinds.
Some are very, very evil, and some have been
considered to be useful members of society.
- Well, I... What does it matter?
- Evil is evil.
Well, let's just narrow it down.
Why don't I make this simple?
- He hit my nose!
- And it hurt... him, I mean!
- And that only works on humans.
- There's no demon in there.
It's just a family legend, am I right?
Just a bit of spin to keep the ladies in line?
You're a piece of work. I like you.
- I'm not a demon.
- You're not a demon.
He hurt my nose.
Yeah? You're welcome.
Mr Maclay, I would say
your business here is finished.
Tara, for 18 years your family
has taken care of you and supported you.
- If you wanna turn your back...
- Dad.
Just go.
Magic.
Are you happy now?
Sorry I'm late.
- You came.
- Of course I came.
No, see, cos your insect reflection
represents your insignificance
in terms of the karmic cycle.
But it's still not funny.
This place is so cool. Except I have
to wear this stupid stamp on my hand.
- That's to keep you from boozing it up.
- Oh, please. Only losers drink alcohol.
So what's an eagle reflection?
My dance?
- Good birthday?
- Best birthday.
I still can't believe you didn't tell me
about your family and all that.
I was just afraid
if you saw the kind of people I came from,
you wouldn't wanna be anywhere near me.
See, that's where you're a dummy.
I think about what you grew up with,
and then I look at what you are.
It makes me proud.
It makes me love you more.
Every time I...
Even when I'm at my worst,
you always make me feel special.
How do you do that?
Magic.
Visiontext Subtitles: Yasmeen Khan
ENGLISH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org