- So what do you think?
- It's nice.
But do you think Cordelia will like it?
I don't know.
Does she know what one of these is?
OK, big yucks.
When are you, guys, gonna
stop making fun of me for dating Cordelia?
I'm sorry. But never.
I just think you could find
somebody more... Better.
Uh. Parallel universe, maybe.
Here the only other person
I'm interested in is, um, unavailable.
Besides, Cordy and I
are really gettin' along.
We're not fighting as much, and yesterday
we just sat together, not even speakin'.
You know, just, uh,
enjoying comfortable silence.
Man, that was dull.
I'm glad that you guys are getting along.
Almost really.
And don't stress over the gift.
Well, this is new territory for me.
I mean, my valentines are usually
met with heartfelt restraining orders.
She'll love it.
I wish dating was like slaying, you know?
simple, direct, stake to the heart,
no muss, no fuss.
Sorry to say, Xand.
Slaying is a tad
more perilous than dating.
Well, you're obviously
not dating Cordelia.
"Bewitched, Bothered and Bewildered"
Wait up!
Hey, wait up!
Excuse me? Where's the fire sale?
Oh, sorry. Didn't see you.
Well, why didn't you
call me back last night?
We need to talk about
our outfits for the dance.
I'm gonna wear red and black,
so you need to switch.
Red and black?
Is that what Xander likes?
Xander?
What does he have to do with this?
Well, a girl wants to look good
for her geek.
Xander's just...
When are you two gonna start wearing
cute little matching outfits?
'Cause I'm planning to vomit.
Let's go.
Papers on my desk.
Anybody tries to leave without giving me
a paper is looking at a failing grade.
This time I'm ready for ya.
No F for Xander today.
No, this baby's my ticket
to a sweet D minus.
- Hey, Amy.
- Hey.
You, guys, going to the
Valentine's Day dance at the Bronze?
- I think it's gonna be a lot of fun.
- Go ahead, you know you wanna say it.
My boyfriend's in the band.
- Cool!
- I think you've now told everybody.
- Only in this hemisphere.
- What about you?
Oh, Valentine's Day is just a cheap gimmick
to sell cards and chocolate.
Bad break-up, huh?
Believe me when I say "Uh-huh".
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you, Amy.
I just hate to think of you solo
on Valentine's Day.
I'll be fine. Mom and I are gonna have
a pig-out and vid fest.
It's a time-honored tradition
among the loveless.
- Did you, guys, see that?
- See what?
In class. I think Amy just worked
some magic on Miss Beakman.
You mean like witchcraft?
- You know, her mom's a witch.
- And an amateur psycho.
Amy's the last person
that should be messing with that stuff.
- Maybe I should go talk to her.
- Buffy? Buffy?
- Might I have a word?
- Have a sentence even.
- Oh, good. Well...
- Back it up before you leave.
- Rupert.
- Ms Calendar.
I'm glad we ran into each other, actually.
I was hoping that we could, uh...
- Do you have a minute?
- Erm...
Actually, not, not just now. Um...
I, uh, have a matter
to discuss with, with Buffy.
Right. Let's go.
Are you OK?
Me? I'll... I'll be fine.
Um, I was more concerned about you,
actually.
Since Angel, erm, turned...
I've, um, been reading up on,
on his earlier activities.
Y'know, uh, feeding patterns
a-and the like.
And?
Around Valentine's Day, he, he,
he's rather prone to, uh...
well, erm, brutal displays of, uh...
He would think of it
as affection, I suppose.
- Like what?
- No... no, uh, need to go into details.
- That bad?
- Suffice it to say, I...
I, I think it would be best
if you stayed off the streets...
For a few nights.
I, I'll, erm...
I'll patrol.
You know, keep an eye on things.
Better safe than sorry.
It's a little late for both.
Fancy it, pet?
It's beautiful.
Nothing but the best for my gir...
Happy Valentine's Day, Dru.
Angel!
It's still warm.
I knew you'd like it.
I found it in a quaint little shopgirl.
Cute.
Here.
I'll get it.
Done.
I know Dru gives you pity access...
but you have to admit it's so much
easier when I do things for her!
You would do well
to worry less about Dru...
and more about that slayer
you've been tramping around with.
Dear Buffy. Hm.
I'm still trying to decide
the best way to send my regards.
Why don't you rip her lungs out?
That might make an impression.
Lacks... poetry.
It doesn't have to.
What rhymes with lungs?
Don't worry, Spike.
Angel always knows...
what speaks to a girl's heart.
# "Pain" by Dingoes Ate My Baby
(Four Star Mary)
# Feelin' I've been lost for years
# You can never understand me
# Unless you've seen those tears
# But you never get to sleep
# When I'm away
# I don't mind...
# The deeper that you lay
- Oz has his cool hair today.
- I think I'm a groupie!
# Out of time
# Pain, I can't sleep
- Oh, hey!
# Hey!
# I can't sleep
Let's get outta here.
# Running...
Here.
Mom?
- Buffy, it's me.
- Yeah. You just startled me a little.
I was just checking the back door.
Somebody, um, left these for you.
# Hey!
# I can't sleep
- Hey.
- Your clothes. You look so good.
Oh. I let Buffy dress me.
- Well, not physically.
- Perfect.
Had to make this harder, didn't you?
OK, clearly the fact
that I please you visually
- has got us off on the wrong foot here.
- Xander...
Let me finish.
I've been thinking a lot
about us lately.
The why and the wherefore.
You know, once, twice.
A kissy here, a kissy there.
And you can chalk it all up to hormones.
And maybe that's all we have here -
tawdry, teen lust.
But maybe not.
Maybe something in you sees something
special inside me, and vice versa.
I mean, I think I do. See something.
So...
Xander.
Thank you.
It's beautiful.
I wanna break up.
OK, not quite the reaction
I was lookin' for.
I know. I'm sorry. It's just...
Who are we kidding?
Even if parts of us do see specialness...
We don't fit.
Yeah.
OK.
Do you know what's a good day
to break up with somebody?
Any day besides Valentine's Day!
I mean, what?
Were you runnin' low on dramatic irony?
I know.
I didn't mean to do it this way. I...
Well, you did.
Dude! Way to get dumped!
- Buffy, my bud, you would not believe...
- Can't talk right now. Angel.
- Do you need help?
- It's all right.
Gee, Xander, maybe
you should learn a second language,
so that even more girls
can reject you.
What are you doing?
Amy. Good to see ya.
You're a witch.
No, I'm not.
That... that was my mom, remember?
Yeah. I'm thinkin'
that runs in the family.
I saw you working
that mojo on Miss Beakman.
- Maybe I should go tell somebody.
- That's not even... That is so mean!
- Blackmail is such an ugly word.
- I didn't say blackmail.
Yeah, but I'm about to blackmail you,
so I thought I'd bring it up.
What do you want?
What do I want?
I want some respect around here.
I want, for once, to come out ahead.
I want the Hellmouth
to be workin' for me.
You and me, Amy.
We're gonna cast a little spell.
- A love spell?
- Yeah.
You know, just the basic.
Can't eat, can't sleep,
can't breathe anything
but little old moi.
Well, that kind of thing
is the hardest, I mean...
to make someone...
love you for all eternity?
Whoa! Whoa! Back up.
Who said anything about eternity?
A man can only talk self-tanning lotion
for so long before his head explodes.
Well then, I don't get it.
If you don't wanna be
with her for ever, what's the point?
The point is, I want her to want me,
desperately,
so I can break up with her...
and subject her to the same hell
she's been puttin' me through.
Oh, I don't know, Xander.
- Intent has to be pure with love spells.
- Right. I intend revenge.
Pure as the driven snow.
Now, are you gonna play, or
do we need to have another chat
about invisible homework?
I'll need something of hers.
A personal object.
Right.
"Soon" what, Giles?
You never held out on me until the big,
bad thing in the dark became my ex-honey.
- Where's this from?
- He said it with flowers.
This isn't the time to start
becoming Mr. Protective Guy.
I can't just hang around and I can't
prepare when I don't know what's coming.
No. Of course. You're right.
S-sit down.
Oh, come on! Don't flatter yourself.
I'm not gonna make a big scene.
I just want the necklace back.
What? I thought it was a gift!
No, last night it was a gift.
Today it's scrap metal.
I figure I can melt it down
and sell it for fillings or something.
- You're pathetic!
- Come on.
I'm not gonna add to
the Cordelia Chase Cast-Off Collection.
It's in my locker.
I can wait.
Here. It's a good thing we broke up.
Now I don't have to pretend I like it.
Diana!
Goddess of love and the hunt...
I pray to thee.
Let my cries bind the heart
of Xander's beloved.
May she neither rest nor sleep...
until she submits to his will only.
Diana!
Bring about this love and bless it!
Blow out the candle now!
Remember? I don't remember.
- What?
- Morning, ladies.
Some kind of weather
we've been havin', huh?
What do you want?
You can't be sniffing around
for more jewellery to melt,
'cause all you ever gave me
was that Smallmart-looking thing.
Is this love? 'Cause maybe on you
it doesn't look that different.
What are you doing? Are you going,
like, stalker boy on me now?
- Sorry, my mistake.
- Yeah, I should say so.
What is his deal?
Oh, here's another. Here.
Um, 'Valentine's Day.' Yes, uh...
'Angel nails a puppy to the...
- Skip it.
- Uh, but it...
I don't wanna know.
I don't have a puppy. Skip it.
Right you are. I'll get another batch.
I have a plan.
- We use me as bait.
- You mean make Angel come after you?
No, I mean chop me into little pieces
and stick me on hooks
for fish to nibble at
'cause it would be more fun
than my life.
Yeah. I heard about you and Cordy.
- That's her loss.
- Yeah.
Not really the popular theory.
You know what I'd like?
Why don't you and I do something
together tonight? Just the two of us.
- Really?
- Yeah. We can comfort each other.
Well, would lap dancing
enter into that scenario at all?
'Cause I find that very comforting.
Play your cards right...
OK, uh... you do know
that I'm Xander, right?
I don't know, I just...
heard that you and Cordy
broke up, and...
I guess I was just surprised
how glad I was.
It's funny... how you can
see someone every day,
but... not really see them. You know?
Yeah, it's funny.
And it's just gettin' funnier.
Xander,
can I talk to you for a minute?
Yeah, OK.
Oh! This is interesting!
- Xander?
- Yeah.
- I don't think the spell worked out right.
- Oh, yeah, it bombed. No biggie.
Well, we can always try again.
I am still pretty new at this.
Oh, no, no. It's OK. You know what?
It was wrong
to meddle with the forces of darkness.
I see that now.
- I think we've all grown. I gotta go.
- Oh, we don't have to cast any spells.
We can just... hang out.
Sure.
- What?
- Well, I liked spending time with you.
You're so sweet.
You know, it's funny how you can...
you can see a person every day and...
Not really see them?
Exactly.
So, anyway, I thought it may be...
- Hi, Xander.
- What?
You're in Mr. Baird's
history class, right?
- Yeah.
- I thought, maybe
- we could study together tonight.
- Do you mind? We were talking.
I really gotta go.
Right now.
Sorry. I wanted to surprise you.
Good job! High marks.
Don't be so jumpy.
I've been in your bed before.
Yeah, but, Will,
we were both in footie pajamas.
Xand, I've been thinking.
Will, I... I think I know
what you've been thinking.
But this is all my fault.
- I cast a spell and it sort of backfired.
- How long have we been friends?
A long, long time.
Too long to do anything
that might change that now.
But friendships change all the time.
People grow apart. They grow closer.
This is good - how close we are now.
I feel comfortable
with this amount of closeness.
In fact, I can even back up
a few paces and still be happy.
See?
I want you, Xander...
- to be my first.
- Baseman?
Please, tell me we're talking baseball.
We both know it's right.
It's not that I don't find you sexy.
Is it Oz? Don't worry about him.
He's sweet, but... he's not you.
Yes, he is! And you should go to him.
'Cause he's me!
I-I-I don't wanna use force.
Force is OK.
That's it! This has gotta stop!
It's time for me to act like a man!
And hide!
Ha, very funny. What did I do now?
Wear red and purple together?
You know what you did.
Xander is wounded because of you.
Are you tripping? I thought
you wanted me to break up with him.
Only a sick pup would let Xander get away,
no matter what her friends said.
What does it take to make you people happy?
#"Got the Love"
by The Average White Band
# Yeah
# Got the love, got the love
# Mm, yeah
# Sugar baby
# Got the love, got the love
# Oh, now, babe,
you been gone such a long time
# Been thinkin' 'bout what it is we got
# Not all the time in the world
# But we got a lot
# Now, there's much more
than a ghost of a chance
# We can make it
# Right this time
# 'Cause you've got to stay mine
# Yeah, I got the love
# Got the love, got the love...
# We got to make it work
Xander.
- What is it?
- It's... it's me.
- Throwing myself at your mercy.
- What? Why?
I made a mess, Giles.
See, I found out that Amy's into
witchcraft, and... I was hurt I guess.
So I... made her put the love whammy
on Cordy, but it backfired.
And now every woman in Sunnydale
wants to make me her cuddle monkey.
Which may sound swell on paper, but...
Rupert, we need to talk. Hey, Xander.
Nice shirt.
Look, Rupert,
I know you're angry at me,
and I don't blame you,
but I am not just gonna go away.
I mean, I care far too much about you to...
Have you been working out?
I cannot believe
you were fool enough to do this.
Oh, no. I'm twice the fool it takes
to do something like this.
Has, erm...
Has Amy tried to reverse the spell?
I get around Amy and all she wants
to do is talk honeymoon plans.
Rupert, maybe I need to
talk to Xander alone.
Do you have any idea
how serious this is?
People under a love spell,
Xander, are deadly.
They lose all capacity for reason.
And if what you say is true, and the
entire female population is affected...
Don't leave the library.
I'll find Amy and see
if we can put a stop to this thing.
No.
Alone at last.
- Buff! Give me a heart attack!
- Oh...
I'm gonna give you more than that.
Buff, for the love of God,
don't open that raincoat.
Come on, it's a party.
Aren't you gonna open your present?
It's not that I don't want to.
Sometimes the remote impossible
possibility that you might like me...
was all that sustained me. But not now.
Not like this.
This isn't real to you.
You're only here because of a spell.
I mean, if I thought you had one clue
what it would mean to me...
But you don't.
So I can't.
So you're saying this is all a game?
A game? I... No!
You make me feel this way
and then you reject me?
- What am I, a toy?
- Buffy, please calm down!
I'll calm down
when you explain yourself!
Get away from him.
He's mine.
Oh, I don't think so.
- Xander, tell her.
- What? I... uh...
He doesn't have to say.
I know what his heart wants.
Funny. I know what your face wants.
What is this? You're two-timing me?!
Goddess Hecate, work thy will!
Before thee let the unclean thing crawl!
Buffy!
Oh, my God!
- Wh-what just happened?
- Buffy.
Where... where is she?
- Oh, my God!
- Why is she here?
Can you focus for a minute?
You just turned Buffy into a rat!
Buffy can take care of herself.
- Why don't we go someplace private?
- Can you...
I'm not going anywhere
until you change her back.
You heard him. So why don't you
undo your magic trick and get lost?
Who made you queen of the world?
Well, you're old enough to be.
Well, what can I say?
I guess Xander's just too much man
for the pimple squad.
Goddess Hecate, to you I pray...
- with this...
- Quit with the Hecate!
OK, what now?
You don't like my locker combination?
It's just not right.
You never loved him. You just used him.
- You make me sick.
- OK, Harmony,
if you need to borrow my Midol,
just ask.
You two, sit!
Be quiet.
We have to catch the Buffy-rat.
Ooh, there!
Good, Buffy.
Just...
- That kinda hurt.
- Kinda? What was that for?
I was on the phone all night
listening to Willow cry about you.
Now, I don't know exactly what happened,
but I was left
with the strong urge to... hit you.
- I didn't touch her, I swear.
- Xander!
Where's Buffy?
Amy turned her into a rat.
I don't see her.
If anything happens to her, I'll...
Oh, just go home. Lock yourself away.
You're only going to
cause more problems here.
Um, Amy, Jenny and I will try
and break the spell.
Oz, if you could aid us in finding, erm...
Buffy?
Sure. Absolutely.
- If...
- Just go. Get out of my sight.
Buffy?
What are you doing?
You guys are crazy!
You thought you could do better,
is that it?
We'll knock that snotty attitude
right out of you!
You must have...
botched the ritual so that
Cordelia's necklace actually
protected her from the spell.
It should be easily reversible.
Where did you learn animal transformation?
Why did you send Xander away?
He needs me.
- That's a laugh.
- He loves me.
We look into each other's souls.
No one can love two people at once.
What we have, is real.
Instead of making me ill,
why doesn't one of you try to help me?
- You have no idea what I'm going through.
- I know it's not love!
It's obsession - selfish, banal obsession.
Xander has put himself
in very grave danger.
If you cared at all about him,
you'd help save him
rather than wittering on
about your feelings.
Now, let's get on with some work.
Now, Jenny...
Great.
I think we...
- lost 'em.
- I should have known
I'd find you with her.
Will. Come on,
you don't wanna hurt me.
Oh, no?
You don't know how hard this is for me.
I love you so much.
I'd rather see you dead
than with that bitch!
- OK, now I really think we've lost 'em.
- Dammit, Xander, what's going on?
- Who died and made you Elvis?
- Buffy's house.
Let's get inside. I'll explain later.
- Come on!
- Xander? Cordelia?
Yeah. Hi.
What happened?
Why are you all scratched up?
- Where's Buffy?
- She's, um...
around.
Well, sit down and tell me about it.
Why don't you run upstairs and grab
some bandages out of the bathroom?
Let me, uh, get you something to drink.
You in the mood for cold or hot?
I-I...
I think it's more of
a hot night, don't you?
- Whatever.
- You are so tense. Mmm.
What are you doing? Make me yak!
Cordelia, go back upstairs.
This is between us.
- Gross. I think not. Let's go.
- What are you doing?
Hey, get your hands off me!
And keep your mom-aged mitts
off my boyfriend.
Former!
Why has everyone gone insane?
Insane? Is it so impossible
for you to believe
that other women find me attractive?
The only way you could get girls
to want you would be witchcraft.
That is such a...
Well, yeah, OK. Good point.
Oh, my God!
Xander, honey, let Joycie in.
Hon, let Joycie in.
- Upstairs! Buffy's room!
- Sweetheart?
Good. The mob still hasn't found us.
We should be safer up here.
Works in theory.
Xander!
- Where's Buffy?
- Cordy, get outta here!
Perfect.
I wanted to do
something special for Buffy.
Actually, to Buffy.
But this is so much better.
If it's any consolation,
I feel very close to you right now.
- Buffy, how...?
- Don't fret, kitten.
Mummy's here.
I don't know what you're up to,
Dru, but it doesn't amuse!
If you harm one hair
on this boy's head...
You've gotta be kidding. Him?
Just because
I've finally found a real man...
- I guess I really did drive you crazy.
- Your face is a poem.
I can read it.
Really? It doesn't say
"Spare me" by any chance?
How do you feel about eternal life?
We couldn't just start with a coffee?
A movie maybe?
- There he is! He's mine!
- Get off!
All you had to do was love me!
No!
Get out of the way! Get off him!
Back off!
Ah, sorry, Dru.
Guess you're not invited.
It's never gonna work for us, Xander.
We have to end it.
Here, Buffy.
Right.
Go on. You first.
- Xander!
- Gimme a nail.
If we die in here,
I'm gonna kick your ass. I mean it.
None of this would've happened
if you hadn't broken up with me.
But no, you're so desperate
to be popular!
Me? I'm not the one who embraced the black
arts just to get the girls to like me.
Well, congratulations. It worked.
It would've worked fine, except your hide's
so thick not even magic can penetrate it!
You mean the spell was for me?
Xander, let me touch you!
Goddess of creatures great and small,
I conjure thee to withdraw.
Hecate!
I hereby license thee to depart.
Buffy?
- Oh, my God!
- Stay behind me.
Xander!
I need you. Come here, please!
Erm, Diana!
Goddess of love, be gone!
Hear no more thy siren's song.
Get off!
Get off me!
What's going on? Where am I?
What's going on?
- Hi, Oz!
- Hi.
I seem to be having
a slight case of nudity here.
But you're not a rat!
So call it an upside.
You think, maybe
you could get me some clothing?
Yes, I can. Just, uh,
don't go anywhere.
Really not an issue.
What... What did we...?
Boy, that was the best scavenger hunt ever!
- "Scavenger hunt".
- Your mom seemed to buy it.
So she says.
I think she's just so wigged at hitting on
one of my friends that she's repressing.
She's getting pretty good at that.
I should probably start worrying.
Well, I'm back to
being incredibly unpopular.
It's better than everyone
trying to axe-murder you, right?
Mostly, but, uh...
Willow won't even talk to me.
- Any particular reason she should?
- How much groveling are we talking here?
Oh, a month, at least.
Xander, come on.
I mean, this is worse for her than anyone.
She loved you before you invoked
the great roofie spirit. The rest of us...
- You remember, huh?
- Oh, yeah.
I remember coming on to you.
I remember begging you to undress me.
And then a sudden need for cheese.
I also remember that you didn't.
- Need cheese?
- Undress me.
It meant a lot to me, what you said.
Come on, Buffy, I couldn't
take advantage of you like that.
OK, for a minute it was
touch and go there.
You came through.
- There might just be hope for you yet.
- Well, tell that to Cordelia.
You're on your own there.
Cody Weinberg called me
at home last night.
- Cody Weinberg? The one with the 35OSL?
- The very one.
Said he's thinking of asking me
to the pledge dance on Thursday.
- That's so huge!
- Yeah!
There's just two other girls
he's gonna ask first,
and if they refuse, then... Watch it!
Sorry.
God! You know, I'm glad
your mom stopped working at the
drive-through long enough to dress you.
Oh, that reminds me.
Did you see Jennifer's backpack?
- It is so trying to...
- Harmony, shut up!
Do you know what you are, Harmony?
You're a sheep.
- I'm not a sheep.
- You're a sheep!
All you ever do is what everyone else does,
just so you can say you did it first!
And here I am
scrambling for your approval
when I'm way cooler than you are
'cause I'm not a sheep!
I do what I wanna do
and I wear what I wanna wear.
And you know what?
I'll date whoever the hell I wanna date.
No matter how lame he is.
Oh, God! Oh, God!
- It's gonna be OK. Just keep walkin'.
- Oh, God, what have I done?
- They're never gonna speak to me again.
- I'm sure they are.
If it helps, whenever we're around them,
you and I can fight a lot.
- You promise?
- You can pretty much count on it.
Subtitles extended and timed by UAR
www.tvsubtitles.net