You know how I feel about you.
It's... pretty obvious, isn't it?
There's never been
anyone else for me... but you.
And we're... good friends
and it's time to take the next step.
Would you, uh...
date me?
Oh, that's good: "Date me."
- It's terrible, right?
- Huh?
Oh, no. Well, yes. "Date me" is silly.
What I should do is just start
with talking about the dance.
You know, Buffy,
Spring Fling just isn't any dance.
It's a time for students to choose a mate,
and then we can...
observe their... mating rituals
and tag them before they migrate.
- Just kill me!
- You're doing fine.
Why is it so hard?
I should just walk up to her and say:
"Hey, I like you.
Let's go to the dance together."
- Direct and to the point.
- I'm ready.
I wanna do it now. I gotta do it now.
Buffy's not here.
You can practise on me some more.
No, I can't wait till tomorrow.
I'll be thinking about it too much.
Why didn't Buffy show up tonight?
- What's she doing?
- You know. The usual.
- What was that?
- What was what?
Someone's out there.
That's silly. Who would be out there?
Three in one night.
Giles would be so proud.
"The Master shall rise."
Yes, this is it!
"The Master shall rise
and the Slayer..."
My God!
The stairs. Under the stairs!
Yes! Yes! Shake, Earth!
This is a sign! We are in the final days!
My time has come! Glory!
Glory!
What do you think? Five point one?
"Prophecy Girl"
Morning.
Wow. The damage looks fairly structural.
Are we safe in here?
Buffy!
What? Do I have something on my face?
No... and yes, we're safe.
Probably best not to go up there.
How're you doin', Giles?
Get much sleep last night?
I've been working.
Me too. I went hunting last night
and it is awfully sweet of you to ask.
It's getting hairy out there, Giles.
I killed three vampires last night. One
of them was practically on school grounds.
- Their numbers are increasing.
- And they're getting cockier.
Look, I'm not loving it.
Last night was a pretty close call.
Yes.
Giles, care?
I'm putting my life on the line,
battling the undead.
I broke a nail, OK? I'm wearing a press-on.
The least you could do
is exhibit some casual interest.
You could go "Hm."
Oh, sorry...
I'm very glad that you're all right.
I need to verify...
- I just can't really talk right now.
- Fine.
That's OK. I can't put it off any longer.
- I have to meet my terrible fate.
- What?
Biology.
- Wow, that was boring.
- I don't feel that "boring" covers it.
No. "Boring" falls short.
Even I was bored. And I'm a science nerd.
- Don't say that.
- I'm not ashamed.
It's the computer age. Nerds are in.
- They're still in, right?
- Willow, don't you have a thing?
A thing?
The thing... that I have...
which is... a thing...
that I have to go to!
See you later.
- What on earth is her deal?
- She's Willow.
So... Buffy, I wanted to...
There's this thing I wanted to ask you,
to talk to you about.
- OK. What's up?
- Let's go over here and sit.
- OK. Now you're making me nervous.
- Oh, no, no.
There's nothing to be nervous about.
Really. It's silly.
Hey! Leave.
Thanks.
Well?
You know, Buffy, Spring Fling is a time
for students to gather and...
Oh, God.
Buffy, I want you to go to the dance
with me. You and me, on a date.
I don't know what to say.
Well, you're not laughing,
so that's a good start.
Buffy, I like you. A lot.
And I know we're friends
and... we've had experiences.
We've fought some bloodsucking fiends,
and that's all been a good time.
But I want more.
I wanna dance with you.
Xander, you're one of my best friends.
You and... Willow.
Well, Willow's not looking to date you.
Or if she is, she's playing it
pretty close to the chest.
I don't wanna spoil
the friendship that we have.
I don't wanna spoil it either.
But that's not the point, is it?
You either feel a thing, or you don't.
I don't.
Xander, I'm sorry.
I just don't think of you that way.
Well, try. I'll wait.
- Xander...
- No.
Forget it.
I'm not him.
I guess a guy's gotta be undead
to make time with you.
That's really harsh.
Look, I'm sorry.
I don't handle rejection well.
Funny... considering
all the practice I've had, huh?
Xander, I'm sorry. I never...
You know what?
Let's just not.
Hello. This is Giles.
Rupert Giles.
I-I need to see you.
No. I realise that.
Come after sundown.
Good. I'll see you then.
You know, that outfit looks
just like the one you wore yesterday -
only wrinklier.
Were you here all night?
Sorry, I'm not really
up to socialising just now.
Something's going on, Rupert. And
I'm guessing you already know what it is.
What do you know?
Well, I have been surfing the Net
looking for unexplained incidents.
People are always sending stuff my way.
They know the occult's my turf.
Here is the latest.
"A cat last week gave birth
to a litter of snakes."
"A family was swimming in Whisper Lake
when the lake began to boil."
And "Mercy Hospital last night, a boy
was born with his eyes facing inward."
I'm not stupid. This is apocalypse stuff.
And throw in last night's earthquake,
and I'd say we've got a problem.
I would say
the end is pretty seriously nigh.
I don't know if I can trust you.
I helped cast that demon out of the
Internet. I think that merits some trust.
Look, I'm scared, OK?
Plus, I've got this crazy monk e-mailing me
from Cortona about some Anointed One.
The Anointed One? He's dead.
- Someone's dead?
- Who is this monk?
Brother Luca something. Keeps sending
out global mailings about a prophecy.
I need you to talk to him.
Find out everything he knows.
Look, Rupert, you haven't told me jack,
so what's with the order?
Just do it!
I'll explain later.
You'd better.
I'll get everything tonight after practice.
The guys'll help me.
Well, it's all in the A-V room.
The sound system, and the decorations...
And, oh, Aura needs help, uh,
moving the coolers.
Don't sweat it!
Well, bring everything to the Bronze
and I'll meet you there in the morning.
Done.
You're so sweet.
Why are you so sweet?
I don't know! 'Cause
I'm usually mean as a snake!
Willow!
I'll see you in the morning.
- I really like your outfit!
- No, you don't.
- No, I really don't. But I need a favour.
- What kind?
Well, the Bronze won't let us
use their sound system,
and I need someone who knows
how to hook one up.
If you could just show up tomorrow morning,
I'd be really, really grateful.
I mean, I'd talk to you
at the dance and everything.
- Sure.
- Great. Tomorrow at ten?
Sure.
- Hey.
- How'd it go?
- On a scale of one to ten? It sucked.
Well, I guess it could be worse.
I could have gangrene on my face.
- What did she say?
- Apart from "no", does it really matter?
She's still jonesing for Angel.
Couldn't care less about me.
- At least now you know.
- Yeah, you're right. The deal's done.
The polls are in
and it's time for my concession speech.
I know what we'll do. We can go.
Be my date. We'll have a great time.
We'll dance, we'll go wild.
What do you say?
- No.
- Good.
- What?
- There's no way.
Willow, come on.
You think I wanna
go to the dance with you and
watch you wish you were
at the dance with her?
Do you think that's my idea of high jinks?
You should know better.
- I didn't think.
- I'm sorry it didn't work out for you.
I'll see you on Monday.
That's OK.
I don't wanna go.
I'm just gonna go home, lie down,
and listen to country music.
The music of pain.
Giles, you are not gonna believe this.
It's clear. It's what's gonna happen.
It's happening now.
Angel?
It can't be. You've gotta be wrong.
I've checked it against
all my other volumes. It's very real.
Well, there's gotta be some way round it.
Listen, some prophecies are a bit dodgy.
They're mutable.
Buffy herself has thwarted them
time and time again.
But this is the Codex. There is
nothing in it that does not come to pass.
- Then you're reading it wrong.
- I wish to God I were!
But it's very plain. Tomorrow night,
Buffy will face the Master
and she will die.
Well, have you verified the text?
So that's it, huh?
I remember the drill.
One Slayer dies, the next one's called.
I wonder who she is.
Will you train her?
Or will they send someone else?
- Buffy...
- Does it say how he's gonna kill me?
Do you think it'll hurt?
Don't touch me!
Were you even gonna tell me?
I was hoping that I wouldn't have to,
that there was... some way around it.
I've got a way around it. I quit.
- It's not that simple.
- I'm making it that simple. I quit!
I resign! I'm fired!
You can find someone else
to stop the Master from taking over.
I'm not sure that anyone else can.
All... the signs indicate...
Signs?
Read me the signs!
Tell me my fortune!
You're so useful,
sitting here with all your books!
You're really a lot of help!
No, I don't suppose I am.
- I know this is hard.
- What do you know about this?
You're never gonna die.
You think I want anything to happen to you?
Do you think I could stand it?
We just gotta figure out a way...
I already did. I quit, remember?
Pay attention!
Buffy, if the Master rises...
I don't care!
I don't care.
Giles, I'm 16 years old.
I don't wanna die.
(# "I Fall to Pieces" by Patsy Cline)
# I fall to pieces
# each time I see you again.
(# "Inconsolable" by Jonatha Brooke)
# I never knew what enough was
Hi, honey.
- # Until I'd had more than my share
- You all right?
Sure.
You're probably just full
from that bite of dinner you nearly had.
Feel like telling me what's on your mind?
# I let the darkness in
And it was then I lost the dare
- Mom, let's go away!
- What?
- Anywhere. Just for a while. A weekend.
- Honey!
No, it'll be great! You and me,
a mother-daughter thing...
We can talk about all the embarrassing
things you love to bring up.
- You know the gallery's open on weekends.
- Mom, please.
Isn't the prom tomorrow night?
Or Spring Fling,
whatever they're calling it?
- I guess.
- Nobody asked you?
- Someone.
- But not the right someone.
See, sometimes I actually do know
what you're thinking.
Well, then, uh... This probably
isn't the best time for this but, uh...
I saw you eyeing it at the store.
I figured...
Mom, we can't afford this.
The way you've been eating,
we can afford it.
It's beautiful.
I think you should wear it...
To the dance.
No. I-I can't go to the dance.
Says who? Is it written somewhere?
You should do what you want.
Homecoming, my freshman year of college.
I didn't have a date,
so I got dressed up and I went anyway.
- Was it awful?
- It was awful. For about an hour.
- Then what happened?
- I met your father.
He didn't have a date either?
He did. And...
That's a... much funnier story
that you will not get to hear.
Oh, but it was a beautiful night.
- And you had your whole life ahead of you.
- Yeah.
Must be nice.
Kevin said he'd bring everything
to the Bronze last night. He promised!
We'll never get everything ready in time!
He probably forgot.
It's not that big a deal.
You don't understand! I'm not mad.
He totally flaked on me. On me!
And I don't even care.
God help me, I think it's cute.
There they are!
They're watching cartoons.
That's so cu... That's not cute.
That's annoying. I'm annoyed.
Right. I'm furious.
Men! I don't know why
we put up with them.
I hear ya.
Obviously, Kevin has underestimated
the power of my icy stare.
Oh, my God! Kevin!
Kevin!
Buffy!
There's something on the news.
Willow!
I've seen so much.
I thought I could take anything.
But, Buffy...
This... This was different.
It'll be all right.
I'm trying to think how to say it,
to explain it so you understand.
It doesn't matter as long as you're OK.
I'm not OK.
I knew those guys.
I go to that room every day.
And when I walked in there,
it wasn't our world any more.
They made it theirs.
And they had fun.
- What are we gonna do?
- What we have to.
Promise me you'll stay in tonight, OK?
Buffy.
I like your dress.
Take care.
Soon!
OK. So this Master guy tried to open
the Hellmouth, but he got stuck in it.
And now all the signs are reading
that he's gonna get out,
which opens the Hellmouth, which
brings the demons, which ends the world.
Yes. That about sums it up, yes.
You know, the part that gets me, though,
is where Buffy is the Vampire Slayer.
She's so little.
Did you manage to get in touch
with this Brother Luca chap?
As far as I can tell, no one can.
He's disappeared.
Did send out one last global, though.
- A short one.
- What did it say?
Isaiah 11:6. Which I dutifully looked up.
"The wolf shall live with the lamb.
The leopard shall lie down with the kid."
"The calf, the lion
and the fatling together,"
"and the little child to lead them."
It's kind of warm and fuzzy
for a message of doom.
Well, it all depends
where he's leading them to.
Aurelius wrote of the Anointed One,
"The Slayer will not know him,
and he will lead her into Hell."
So Luca thinks the Anointed is a kid.
If the vampire that Buffy killed
was in fact not the Anointed, then
it may well be.
- Well, then we need to warn her.
- I don't intend involving her at all.
What do you mean?
Buffy's not going to face the Master. I am.
No, you're not.
So I'm looking for a kid, huh?
And he'll lead me to the Master?
Buffy, I'm not gonna
send you out there to die.
Now, you were right. I-I've waded around
in these old books for so long,
I've forgotten what the real world is like.
It's time I found out.
You're still not going up
against the Master.
- I've made up my mind.
- So have I.
I made up mine first.
I'm older and wiser than you and...
Just do what you're told for once!
All right?
That's not how it goes.
I'm the Slayer.
I don't care what the books say.
I defy prophecy and I'm going.
There's nothing you can say
will change my mind.
I know.
When he wakes up, tell him...
I don't know.
Think of something cool.
Tell him I said it.
You fight the Master and you'll die.
Maybe.
Maybe I'll take him with me.
Help me.
It's OK. I know who you are.
She what?!
I told you there was something
going on with her.
And she knew
about this prophecy of yours?
- Oh, man. What do we do?
- We stay calm. First thing.
- Calm?
- I think he's right.
I'm sorry, calm may work
for Locutus of the Borg here,
but I'm freaked out,
and I intend to stay that way.
- Xander...
- How could you let her go?
As the soon-to-be-purple area of my jaw
will attest, I did not "let" her go!
Well, how can we help her?
Uh, I'm sorry to bring this up, but we
also have an apocalypse to worry about?
- Do you mind?
- How come she's in the club?
Hey! Once the Master gets free,
the Hellmouth opens,
the demons come to party,
and everybody dies.
I don't care. I'm sorry. I don't.
- Right now, I gotta help Buffy.
- We don't even know where she's gone.
No. But I can find out.
Well, look who's here.
Mind if I come in?
- Make yourself at home.
- She's gone.
- What do you mean?
- Buffy! She's gone to fight the Master.
- He'll kill her.
- Rumour has it.
Only we're not gonna let it happen.
What do you propose we do about it?
Look, I know
you can find this Master guy.
He's underground, right?
Take me to him.
You're way out of your league, kid.
The Master'll kill you before you can
even breathe, if you're lucky.
How can I say this clearly?
I don't like you.
At the end of the day,
I pretty much think you're a vampire.
But Buffy's got
this big old yen for you.
She thinks you're a real person.
And right now,
I need you to prove her right.
You're in love with her.
Aren't you?
The Master is as old
as any vampire on record.
There's no telling how powerful he'll be
if he reaches the surface.
OK. Here's my question.
The Hellmouth opens.
Yes.
Where?
If he's underground and it's right
where he is, where's it gonna open?
Good point. Look, you have a look
through the "Black Chronicles".
Willow.
- Willow!
- Huh?
Could you look through
the local histories, please?
Check for any common denominators,
locations of incidents and such.
Right. OK.
Welcome.
Thanks for having me.
You know you really ought to
talk to your contractor.
- Looks like you got some water damage.
- Oh, good.
The "feeble banter" portion of the fight.
Why don't we just cut to the...
Nice shot.
This way. What?
- You're looking at my neck.
- What?
- You checked out my neck.
- No.
Keep your distance.
- I wasn't looking at your neck!
- I told you to eat before we left.
You're not going to kill me
with that thing.
Don't be so sure.
You still don't understand
your part in all this, do you?
You are not the hunter.
You are the lamb.
Now let's think about this.
Vampires have been gathering.
They know he's coming.
They will be his army.
Do you think they'll
gather at the Hellmouth?
Well, the last time
the Master tried to rise was the Harvest.
He sent a bunch of vampires
to get him fresh blood.
- Where did that go down?
- The Bronze.
- The prom!
- We have to warn them.
No, we'll go. You have to
concentrate on demon killing.
- My car's in the lot.
- Stay close together.
- And for goodness sake, be careful!
- We will.
You know, for someone who's all-powerful,
you sure do like to hide.
I'm waiting for you.
I want this moment to last.
Well, I don't.
I understand.
What if they get to the Bronze
before we do?
- Don't need to worry about that.
- Why not?
'Cause they're not going to the Bronze.
You tried.
It was noble of you.
You heard the prophecy that I was about
to break free and you came to stop me.
But prophecies are tricky creatures.
They don't tell you everything.
You're the one that sets me free.
If you hadn't come, I couldn't go.
Think about that.
Oh, God! The power!
By the way,
I like your dress.
- What was that?
- It's too late. He's gone up.
She's dead.
- No. She's not dead.
- She's not breathing.
But if she drowned, there's a shot. CPR.
You have to do it. I have no breath.
Come on.
Come on!
- Why are they coming here?
- Not caring.
Get in!
Come on.
Breathe.
Breathe!
Come on.
Buffy?
Xander?
Welcome back.
I was sitting where
Kevin and I used to park,
and all of a sudden
these things are coming at me!
- What do we do now?
- We've gotta get to the library.
Great.
Of course, we generally walk there.
What the...?
- What's happening?
- Guess!
Why are they coming here?
My world.
My beautiful world!
Easy. Easy.
- The Master?
- He's gone up.
No. You're still weak.
No.
No, I feel strong.
I feel different.
Let's go.
They're coming in through the stacks.
The bookshelves!
My office.
Somebody help!
So, how do you know
where the Master's going?
I know.
Oh, look. A bad guy.
You two wait here.
Keep the other vampires off me.
- Angel, better put on your game face.
- I'm ready.
One way or another, this won't take long.
See how you like it!
This won't keep 'em out for long!
Giles!
The Hellmouth.
Yes!
Come forth, my child.
Come into my world.
I don't think it's yours just yet.
You're dead!
I may be dead,
but I'm still pretty.
Which is more than I can say for you.
You were destined to die!
It was written!
What can I say? I flunked the written.
Come here.
Giles!
Did you really think you could best me
here when you couldn't below?
- You have fruit-punch mouth.
- What?
Save the hypnosis crap for the tourists.
Where are your jibes now?
- Will you laugh when my Hell is on Earth?
- You're that amped about Hell?
Go there!
- The vampires?
- Gone.
- The Master?
- Dead. The Hellmouth is closed.
Buffy?
Oh, I'm sorry.
- It's just been a really weird day.
- Yeah. Buffy died and everything.
Wow! Harsh.
I should have known
that wouldn't stop you.
Well, what do we do now?
I don't know about the rest of you,
but I'd like to get out of this place.
I don't like the library
very much any more.
Hey, I hear there's a dance
at the Bronze tonight.
- Could be fun.
-Yeah!
- Buffy?
- Sure.
We saved the world. I say we party.
I mean... I got all pretty.
What about him?
He's not going anywhere.
Loser.
- I'm not dancing, though.
- We'll see.
So what's the story with the car?
I'm really, really hungry.
- By the way, I really like your dress.
- Yeah, yeah. A big hit with everyone.
Subtitles by Visiontext
Additions & timing by UAR
...
www.tvsubtitles.net