Previously:
It looks like I'm not as
toothless as you thought.
- How?
- You came back wrong.
Willow, you're using too much magic.
You want me to just keep my mouth shut?
That'd be a good start.
- Forget.
- I know you used that spell on me.
What is wrong with you?
- I don't think this is gonna work.
- Are you saying you're gonna leave me?
- Amy? How've you been?
- Rat. You?
- Dead.
- Oh.
It's nice having another
magically inclined friend around.
There's gotta be some place,
like, bigger than this.
It's way too early to go home yet.
- It's beautiful.
- Congratulations. Phase one is complete.
- I'm in love with you.
- You're in love with pain.
Are you afraid I'm gonna...
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
What time is it?
Almost seven.
God, I just closed my eyes for a minute.
And now there's cartoons.
Plus a mother of all night-wedgies.
It's not tragic.
I'm sure as soon as I stand up...
No, Dawn. Why didn't anybody wake us up?
Where is everyone?
Willow didn't come home either.
They were out all night.
- Where are they?
- I'm sure they're fine, Dawnie.
I'm sure they just... lost track of time.
When...
When did the building fall down?
I don't know.
Must have been sometime
between the first time and the...
Oh, my God.
- Shoe. Need my shoe.
- What's the hurry, love?
The hurry is I left Dawn all night.
And don't call me "love".
You didn't seem to take issue
with that last night.
- Or with any of the nasties we whispered.
- Can we not... talk?
I don't see why you have
to run off so quick.
- Thought we could...
- Not gonna happen.
Last night was the end of this freak show.
- Don't say that.
- What did you think was gonna happen?
What, we're gonna read the newspaper
together? Play footsie under the rubble?
Not exactly what I had in mind.
- Stop!
- Make me.
- No, no, I have to...
- Stay.
I'm stuck here. Sun's up.
I knew the only thing better
than killing a slayer would be...
What?! Is that what this is about?
Doing a slayer?
I wouldn't throw stones. You seem
to be quite the groupie yourself.
Shut up.
I'm just saying... vampires get you hot.
A vampire got me hot. One.
But he's gone. You're just...
You're just convenient.
So, what now?
You go back to treating me like dirt...
till the next time you get
an itch you can't scratch?
Well, forget it.
Last night changed things.
I'm done being your whipping boy.
- Nothing's changed. It was a mistake.
- Bollocks! It was a bloody revelation.
You can act as high and mighty
as you like...
but I know where you live now, Slayer.
I've tasted it.
- Get a grip. Like you're God's gift.
- Hardly.
Wouldn't be nearly as interesting, would it?
Let me go!
I may be dirt... but you're the one
who likes to roll in it, Slayer.
You never had it so good as me. Never.
- You're bent.
- Yeah, and it made you scream, didn't it?
I swear to God,
if you tell anyone about last night,
I will kill you.
Right.
You're gonna want these, too.
Pancakes?
Sure.
Should we call Xander? What if
they're all in a ditch somewhere?
Ditches are bad.
Mom always used to talk about the ditches.
Nobody's in a ditch. We'll call, but...
we'll give them some time
before we wake them up.
Funny shapes, or...?
It'll wear off in a day or...
- Hey.
- Hey. I just...
Buffy didn't come home
last night either, so...
Hey... this is Amy. Amy, Tara. Tara, Amy.
- How you doing?
- Fine. I...
- I'd better get going.
- Amy! Amy the rat?
- Sorry.
- No, that's fair. I was a rat.
When...?
Last night. It's nuts.
Everything's different.
I mean... the Bronze, for one thing.
Willow's a freaking amazing witch now.
I couldn't keep up with her last night.
- Amy.
- No, it's true!
I can do some transmogrify, but she is
messing with dimensions. It was awesome!
This blowhard dude? First she made
his mouth disappear. And then...
I'm talking too much. Sorry.
It's just been, you know, me and a bag
of pellets for the last few years, so...
No, it's fine.
It's just, um... I really need to go.
- Tara, you left some stuff upstairs...
- I'll get them later.
Tara!
Buffy! Where were you? Are you OK?
- I'm fine.
- You're not. You're all sore and limpy.
I'm not sore, I just...
I had a fight, you know, the...
all-nighter kind.
Figured. I knew that's why you didn't call.
So, what's the big bad?
Should we be worried?
No. I mean, I think you guys are safe.
- Tara was here?
- I guess she stayed over with Dawn.
You guess? Where were you?
We went out. We kinda lost track of time.
I never would have
if I knew you weren't coming home.
No, of course. I mean, you know...
It wasn't intentional.
And, you know, everyone's safe.
- You are, right? You're OK?
- Oh, yeah. I mean, um...
I think my pancakes are burning, but...
Tara was making them.
I've... I've gotta get some sleep.
Me too.
Yeah. I should go home.
Dad's expecting me.
- OK. I'll call you later.
- Yeah. Good.
Are you sure you're all right?
I'm sorry about everything.
It's OK. You should rest.
You're beat from monster-wrestling
all night.
Yeah. Right. Thanks.
I'm gonna crash, too. Night, Dawnie.
No problem. I'll just go
find some awake people.
All these demons are starting to look alike.
You got reptiles, reptiles with horns,
reptiles with gills.
And I'm still finding nothing of
the Steal a Diamond, Freeze a Guy variety.
An, would you hand me that one next to you?
Great. We're not even married yet
and already you've stopped listening to me.
- Anya!
- I'm sorry, but this is pointless!
We've been researching for ever and
we still don't know who robbed the museum.
What's up?
Anya has a theory.
She thinks Martha Stewart froze that guy.
Don't be ridiculous.
Martha Stewart isn't a demon.
- She's a witch.
- Please, she... Really?
Yes. Nobody could do that much decoupage
without calling on the powers of darkness.
Fascinating, but we have work to do.
I know I do. I can't decide whether
to put my bridesmaids in cocktail dresses,
or the traditional burlap with blood larva.
The traditional what?
I was a demon for a thousand years. I can't
turn my back on all the ways of my people.
Can I weigh in on this me wearing larva...
No.
At least I'm not asking you to perform
the rite of self-flagellation.
Guys, there's something out there.
There is. And as much as I hate to admit
that my bizarre bride-to-be has a point,
we're getting nowhere here, Buff.
Maybe it's time to hit the streets.
Get Spike on it.
No! No Spike. And no hit the streets.
We stay put, you know? Away from
distractions. We'll figure this out.
What about Willow? Can't she do something?
Maybe. But she's home sleeping.
Sleeping? She sick?
No, she was out late. With Amy.
And I'm bizarre. At least I didn't dump you
to hang out with an ex-rat.
No, it's not like that. She's just
helping Amy through a transition.
And making herself
a playmate to do magic with.
- Someone who won't monitor her like Tara.
- Willow's a grown-up.
Maybe she doesn't need to be monitored.
She's going through something,
but we're not her.
Maybe she has reasons for acting this way.
And so what if she crossed a line?
We all do stuff. Stupid stuff.
But then we learn, and we don't do it again.
So, you know,
who are we to be all judgy?
Not judgy, Buff. Just observy.
All we're saying is she's acting
different. She's not herself.
What do you wanna do?
It's gonna be hard to top last night.
I don't know if I can.
I felt awful today and I couldn't do magic.
Took me all day to get my powers back.
I think we should just take it easy.
- I have a better idea.
- What?
I know this guy,
and he knows spells that last for days.
And the burnout factor is, like, nothing.
- Really? He's a warlock?
- I guess.
I am not kidding you.
This guy will blow your mind.
He will take you to places
that you can't even imagine.
Is it dangerous?
Would that stop you?
- This is it.
- Where? You said the guy lived around here.
He does. You can't feel it?
What do you...?
- Here.
- It's hot.
Come on.
It's cool, isn't it? The place is cloaked.
Yeah.
Moves around a lot too.
Keeps Rack out of trouble.
Rack? Who's...?
Rack! Rack, it's my turn.
- No, you said I was up.
- I've been here for hours!
I believe these two are next.
Thanks, Rack, for taking us.
It's been a while. You'll never believe...
- You were a rat.
- How did you know?
I hope that taught you
not to mess with spells you can't handle.
You should leave that
in the hands of a professional.
This one's giving off vibes.
I don't mean to vibe at you,
if it's in a negative way.
No, no, I mean you have power, girl.
It's just coming off you in waves.
Not so much. I mean, I can do stuff but...
I get tapped out quick, and I've used
practically every spell I know.
What do you want me to do about that?
I don't know. I thought...
- Amy said...
- "Amy said. "
Amy said I could help you.
But did Amy say how you could help me?
- No. I have some money, a bit...
- Not money.
Well, I could help you
with your computer. I'm really handy.
Just relax. I'm not gonna hurt you.
You gotta give a little to get a little,
right?
It's OK. It's over fast.
That's right.
I'm just gonna take a little tour.
You taste like strawberries.
- Or you could do it the hard way.
- Spatulas are for wimps.
I'm making peanut-butter
and banana quesadillas. You want?
No, thanks. I'm more in water mode.
You sure? It's my own brand-new invention.
I'm sure.
No, my tummy's feeling kinda rumbly.
Your loss. Very delicious.
Buffy called. She's going straight
from the Magic Box to do some patrolling.
- Oh. Did she need help?
- No, she was just calling to check in.
For the tenth time today.
I think she's feeling all Joan
Crawford cos of the other night.
Yeah. About that, I'm really sorry.
I shouldn't have assumed
Buffy would be here.
Right. Assume and make you
an ass out of me. Or something.
Anyway, please, it's cool. It's not like
I even needed Tara to stay over.
I'm so totally fine on my own.
But you are gonna be around tonight, right?
Right, totally!
We can do something if you want.
A movie, maybe?
Really? But I thought
you weren't feeling so good.
Well... nothing a little Dawnie time
won't fix.
If you bag the peanut butter,
I'll even buy you dinner.
Thank God!
Remind me never to invent that again.
Great, this'll be great. I'll grab
the paper and see what's playing.
I'll leave a note for Buffy
on the refrigerator.
It's the first place she goes
after patrolling.
Hello?
Willow?
Dawn?
- What's going on?
- Busted.
Where's Willow?
She said... She said I could... wait!
- What is this?
- It's not what you think it is! It's sage!
That is what I think it is.
What's going on? Where's Willow and Dawn?
I saw her, but that was...
I like your coat.
When does the Slayer find time to shop?
So they didn't let you in?
Not that they know of.
- What else did you take?
- Nothing.
What else?!
Please! I need this stuff.
Willow wants me to have it. She understands.
Understands what? Breaking into
someone's house for kitchen spices?
No, I don't think so.
You should.
She's as bad as I am. Worse.
I bet she's at Rack's right now.
- Rack's?
- A place. He does spells. Heavy stuff.
- Willow's his new favourite.
- She's there? With Dawn?
Oh, don't shake me again, I'm gonna boot.
Then tell me where this place is
and I won't.
- It's downtown, but it moves.
- What do you mean, "it moves"?
It's downtown. I'm not sure
where it would be tonight exactly...
- Tell me how to find it.
- You just kinda have to feel it out...
Oh, God, I think I'm gonna...
So the burger was good? You liked it?
Are you kidding?
It was like a meat party in my mouth.
OK. Now I'm just a kid,
and even I know that came out wrong.
It was good.
But you should have had something.
I will. I'll eat.
I'm... saving myself for popcorn.
The other day, you had fun?
Mm... what other day? Give me
a Mon or a Fri here, something to work with.
- The other day with Tara.
- Yeah.
I mean, it was nice.
But it wasn't a laugh riot.
She's sad and everything.
- Did she say something?
- Not exactly.
I can just tell, by the way she was acting.
Are you sure you're OK? You look a little...
I'm fine.
And Tara's in her new place
and everything? She's all settled in?
We really didn't get into...
Is this right?
Is this the way to the movies?
Oh, yeah, I'm...
I just took you the long way around.
But we're almost there.
I just have to make one quick stop first.
What is this place? Why is it hidden?
I don't know. It's cool, isn't it?
You just hang here for a minute
and I'll be back.
You want me to conjure you
a magazine or something?
What about the movie? It starts at nine.
We'll make it. I'll just be a minute. And
it doesn't matter if we miss the trailers.
I like the trailers.
What do you think, strawberry?
Can you handle some more?
God, do you sleep through anything?
I was like yelling, and nothing.
I'm a bit knackered. Had a long night.
Someone should teach you
how to use candles in foreplay, love.
- Get dressed. Dawn's missing.
- Again?
Ever think about a LoJack for the girl?
- What's the story?
- She went out with Willow.
Willow? That's a sorry excuse to come by.
If you want the touch all you need to do...
Spike. Willow's into something.
Her and Dawn have been missing for hours.
- There's some guy named Rack.
- Rack?
- Yeah, he's some sort of...
- He deals in magic. Black stuff. Dangerous.
I've been all over
and I can't find his place.
He cloaks it. You can only feel it
if you're into the big bad. A vampire...
So let's go!
Oh, that's right. Hide your blushing eyes.
Hey, wait your turn.
Hey, Dawnie. It's movie time.
Do you know how long I've been here?
It's too late for the movie.
And that guy smells...
- Are you OK?
- Fine. Let's get outta here.
So, what do you wanna do, cutie?
It's late. I just wanna go home.
No way! I said we were gonna have fun,
and we're gonna have fun.
I'm serious.
I think we should just get out of here.
"We should just get out of here. "
Come on, Dawnie, it's grown-up time. Do
you wanna play with the grown-ups or not?
Why are you acting this way?
Don't get all weird on me. We're fine.
Everything's fine.
- Anything?
- Not yet.
I might pick up on it if you stop
asking me every two seconds.
Spike, if you're dragging this out...
What, so I can linger near
your precious self? Get a grip.
Like you've never drawn things out before.
Maybe, but we've been through this,
haven't we? Things have changed.
Will you quit that? The only thing that's
different is that I'm disgusted with myself.
That's the power of your charms.
Last night... was the most perverse,
degrading experience of my life.
Yeah. Me too.
That might be how you get off,
but it's not my style.
No, it's your calling.
Gave me a run for my money, Slayer.
Now, I admit it.
You've had me by the short hairs.
I love you. You know it.
But I got my rocks back.
You felt something last night.
Not love.
Not yet. But I'm in your system now.
You're gonna crave me, like I crave blood.
The next time you come calling, if you don't
stop being a bitch, maybe I will bite you.
That's it! I want you out of my life.
Out of my work, out of my home...
Too late for that.
You invited me in already.
And as for your work, you need me.
- Like tonight.
- I'll find Dawn myself.
You really gonna put your little sis
in danger just to spite me?
Willow, I'm serious. I'm going home.
Then go! God, I thought we were gonna hang.
You're not coming with me?
I don't know.
Maybe I could just pop you back.
With magic?
- What's that?
- What? I didn't...
- I'm getting out of here.
- Aw, Dawnie, don't.
It was probably a cat
or something like that.
- It's OK. He's not real.
- Seems real. Very real.
- You summoned me, witch.
- I didn't.
Did. You raised hell with your magics.
Fresh!
- She has nothing to do with it. It was me.
- Yes.
He's coming! He's too fast.
Open. Get in.
Close.
Drive.
What are you doing?
Take that, scuzz.
Oh, God.
Dawn!
Nowyou're scared? Better late than never.
- Oh, no.
- Dawn...
What happened? Are you OK?
He was after Willow.
She made the car drive. Don't!
I need to see it. Let me see your arm.
Oh, God, there's blood.
- We need to get her to a doctor.
- Is she OK? Is she OK?
Back off, Will. I got her.
- No, Dawnie.
- I mean it. Stay away from her.
Dawnie, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry. It was an accident!
I didn't see. I'm so, so sorry.
Dawnie! Dawnie, don't.
Dawnie, I'm sorry. I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Get up.
I screwed it up. Everything. Tara...
You know what? You did screw up.
You could have killed her! You almost did!
I know, I know.
I can't stop, Buffy! I tried and I can't.
- You can.
- I can't. I can't.
I ju... God, I need help.
Please! Please help me! Please.
Please.
- Is she OK?
- She's sleeping.
The ER doc gave her something for the pain.
It knocked her out.
But she's gonna be all right?
It's a fracture. It's gonna take some time.
God, I'm... sorry. I'm so...
I just don't understand. I don't understand
why you'd go to see somebody like Rack.
And I don't understand
why you'd drag Dawn into it.
I don't know.
The magic, I thought
I had it under control, and then...
I didn't.
Because of Tara?
No. It started before she left.
It's why she left.
It seemed like things were going so well.
It was.
But, I mean, if you could be...
the plain old Willow or super Willow,
who would you be?
I guess you don't actually have
an option on the whole super thing.
Will, there's nothing wrong with you.
You don't need magic to be special.
Don't I? I mean, Buffy, who was I?
Just... some girl.
- Tara didn't even know that girl.
- You are more than some girl.
And Tara wants you to stop. She loves you.
- We don't know that.
- I know that. I promise you.
I just...
It took me away from myself. I was...
free.
I get that. More than you...
But it's wrong.
People get hurt.
If something had happened to Dawn tonight...
Something worse...
- I know.
- No, I don't think you do.
I... I was out of my mind.
I did things I can't even...
It won't happen again, I promise.
No more spells. I'm finished.
Good. I think it's right, to give it up.
No matter how good it feels.
It's not worth it.
Not if it messes with the people I love.
The magic wasn't all great.
I won't miss the nosebleeds
and the headaches and stuff.
There you go.
Or keeping stinky yak cheese in my bra.
- Don't ask.
- Now I don't have to.
Cos it's over.
Exactly. It's over.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org