Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
[Growling]
Nnnfrr!
Oh, God! Demon! Demon!
What kills a demon?!
Nrrrf!
Nnffrr!
Oh, Nerf!
Not Nerf! Knife!
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
OK. That was too close
for comfort.
Not that slaying
is ever comfy, but...
you know what I mean?
If you guys hadn't
been here to help...
Willow: But we were.
And we did,
and we're all fine.
Isn't he gonna go poof?
Uh, I guess these guys don't.
We'll have to bury him
or something.
Ooh...
makes you appreciate vamps,
though.
No fuss, no muss.
So how come Faith
was a no-show?
I thought mucusy demons
were her favorites.
Couldn't reach her... again.
She hasn't been
hanging out much.
I detect worry.
A little bit.
Slaying's a rough gig.
Too much alone time isn't healthy.
Stuff gets pent up.
We should try to do more
socializing with her.
Well, burial detail aside...
does this cap us off
for the day?
You got plans?
I cannot stress enough
how much I don't have plans.
No luck reaching Cordelia?
I've left a few messages.
60... 70.
But you know
what really bugs me?
OK, we kissed.
It was a mistake.
But I know that was positively the last
time we were ever gonna kiss.
Darn tootin'.
And they burst in
rescuing us...
without even knocking?
I mean, this is really
all their fault.
Your logic does not
resemble our Earth logic.
Mine is much
more advanced.
At least tomorrow's Monday...
another school day.
Well, that's good.
You know, focus on school.
That's the strong
Willow way to heal.
Actually, I was more
thinking Oz will be there...
and I can beg
for forgiveness.
That works, too.
I want to be strong, Willow.
But then I think...
I may never get to be
close to Oz again...
and it's like all the air
just goes out of the room.
I know the feeling.
Right. I mean, you went through it
with Angel, and you're still standing.
So tell us, wise one,
how do you deal?
I have you guys.
[Answering Machine Beeps]
Hey, it's Xander.
If you get this, call me.
[Beep]
Hi. Xander.
I, uh... Well, I'm in
if you feel like calling.
Bye.
[Beep]
Hi, Cordelia. Um...
if you get the chance,
if we can talk, I'm here.
[Beep]
Hey, again. It's me.
I'm here. Again.
How's it goin'?
Oz hasn't been
to his locker.
There may be books
in there that he needs...
but still, he doesn't come.
Has Xander seen Cordelia?
I don't think so.
But she is coming in today.
Amy saw her last night
at the mall.
How was she?
I don't know.
Amy said she looked
pretty... scary.
Cordelia!
You look amazing.
Oh. You have to meet Anya.
She just moved here...
and her dad just bought...
What was it?
Oh. A utility.
Or something.
Nice bag. Prada?
Good call.
Most people around here
can't tell Prada from Payless.
God, Cordy!
When I heard about...
Well, I mean,
I couldn't believe it.
But it was smart,
you know, the injury thing?
You take a week off...
let everybody forget
about the temporary insanity...
that was Xander Harris.
Xander who?
Oh!
You know what
you have to do.
Start dating.
Get back on the horse.
Oh, absolutely!
I am ready to ride!
Then I have just the stallion.
He's so you.
[Slurping]
[Harmony Giggles]
I'm pretty sure
he won't cheat on you.
At least not for a while.
Plus, he's got a kill moped.
Oz. Wow.
Look at us,
running into each other...
as two people who go
to the same school...
are so likely to do
now and then.
Hey.
Oz, wait. Please?
What I did...
When I think that
I hurt you...
Yeah. You said all
this stuff already.
Right, but... I want
to make it up to you.
I mean, if you let me,
I want to try.
Just...
You can leave me alone.
I need to figure things out.
But maybe if we talk
about it, we could...
Look...
I'm sorry this is hard for you.
But I told you what I need.
So I can't help feeling
like the reason you want to talk...
is so you can feel
better about yourself.
That's not my problem.
Hey, John Lee.
Do I have something
caught in my teeth?
So... what's new?
God, it's been, like,
a gazillion years.
Look, the guys are kinda
down on me lately.
Coach just cut me back
to second string.
If anyone saw me hanging...
with Xander Harris's
castoff on top of that...
death, you know, but...
maybe... if you want to
go someplace private...
What?
Think about it.
Hey.
Go ahead, dazzle me with
your oh-so-brilliant insults.
Just join the club.
Hardly. Actually,
I've been looking for you.
Ever since we met this morning,
I was, like...
thank God there's one other
person in this town
who actually reads W.
But Harmony...
Oh, she follows me around.
If that girl had an original thought,
her head would explode.
Is that Gucci?
Um... no.
It's an actual old thing,
sort of a, um...
good-luck charm
my dad gave me.
Too bad I didn't have
one of those pre-Xander.
Can I just say... men.
Second it.
Apart from being
without class...
the guy's obviously blind.
Deserves whatever he gets.
I'm not even
thinking about him.
I am past it.
I am living my life.
Still, I mean...
Don't you kinda wish...
I don't wish. I act.
Starting now,
Xander Harris is gonna get...
a bellyful of just
how over him I am.
[Rock Music]
[Forced Laughter]
Excuse me.
I need to be both giving
and receiving of mirth.
Is it too much to ask
for a little backup?
I'm here for you, Xand.
I'm support-o-gal.
I just...
feel a little weird...
about this
us-against-Cordelia thing.
She's had a rough time.
It's true. Cordelia belongs
to the justified camp.
She should make us pay.
And pay and pay and pay...
In fact, there's just not
enough pay for what we...
Look, you want to do
guilt-a-palooza, fine...
but I'm done with that.
Starting this minute...
I'm gonna grab ahold of
that crazy little thing called life...
and let it do
its magical little healie thing.
What's done is done.
Let's be in the moment.
Behold the beauty
that is now.
Who's with me?
He's actually making sense.
We're young and free
in America.
How dare we be spun by love
or the lack of same?
Absolutely.
I-It's self-indulgent.
I-I'm in.
I'm on the joy train.
That didn't work.
Who wants chocolate?
I'm up.
Look at her.
Tears of a clown, baby.
Or is it...
grins of a sad person?
Or maybe it's...
Xander, your hand.
Oops! Sorry.
But why oops?
I mean, we always touch digits.
It's a friend thing.
Comfort, like chocolate.
Maybe it used to be,
but since we...
It's different.
I-I'm sorry.
But if I want to make things
right with Oz...
my hands,
my... all my stuff...
has to be for him only.
Hey, Cordelia, wait a second.
Did Xander send you
to beg for him?
Because if he did...
No. I'm a free agent,
I promise.
I just wanted
to see how you are.
Never been better.
Cordelia, I know what it's like
to be hurt by someone.
Hurt so much that you don't think
you're gonna make it.
But I told my friends how I felt,
and you know what?
I got a little better.
[Gasp]
Cordelia, look...
out.
You know what I've been
asking myself a lot this last week?
Why me?
Why do I get impaled?
Why do I get bitten
by snakes?
Why do I fall
for incredible losers?
And you know,
I think I finally figured it out...
what my problem is.
It's...
Buffy Summers. That's when
all my troubles started.
When she moved here.
Are you OK?
Oh, I just pulled
some stitches last night.
Know why?
Surprise.
It was Buffy's fault.
Oh, hey, it's garbage girl.
Loved the look last night, Cor.
Dumpster chic
for the dumped.
Here.
I think you need this
more than I do right now.
Yeah, I can use some luck.
And a stick with pointy,
sharp bits.
If that Buffy wasn't...
I swear...
She's a pain.
But Xander,
he's an utter loser.
Don't you wish...
I never would have
looked twice at Xander...
if Buffy hadn't made him
marginally cooler...
by hanging with him.
Really?
Yeah, I swear.
I wish Buffy Summers
had never come to Sunnydale.
[Gasp]
Done.
Anya?
I wish Buffy Summers
had never come to Sunnydale.
She was, like...
a good fairy.
A scary, veiny...
good fairy.
Ha ha!
Where have you been?!
Ted Chervin just totally
went for third with Ginger...
in front of everybody.
Love the dress.
It's so daring.
John Lee: Cordelia.
Yeah?
Look, every guy on campus
has probably asked...
but if you're not going
to the winter brunch with anyone...
I'd be honored,
and we'd have fun.
I'll get back to you.
Really?
Yeah.
Great.
Cordy, you reign.
I do?
I mean, I do.
So what's with
the winter brunch thing?
[Bell Ringing]
All right. Now, don't forget...
tomorrow we have our, uh,
monthly memorial...
so, uh, there's no class.
Cordelia: What's the rush?
Oh, you know, my mom
hates it when I'm late.
Since when?
Aren't we going out tonight?
Girl: Curfew starts
in an hour.
Curfew?
Come on, I'm in
a really good mood.
Let's go to The Bronze.
Is that a joke?
Oh! The Bronze isn't cool
in this reality.
I've got to make these
little adjustments.
Cordy... what's with you?
I mean, you wear this
come-bite-me outfit...
you make jokes
about The Bronze...
and you're acting
a little schizo.
You're right.
I just... Well, I bumped
my head yesterday...
and I keep forgetting stuff.
Not that I care, but Xander Harris,
he's miserable, right?
And that Willow freak
he hangs with...
not even a blip on
the radar screen, right?
Well... yeah.
They're dead.
OK.
Not funny.
You. Where did you
put my car?
Pardon?
My auto!
El convertablo?
You students aren't allowed
to drive, and you know it.
- What?!
- Go on now, miss.
You better get in
before the sun sets.
[Gate Squeals]
[Gasp]
Well, what do ya know?
Cordelia Chase.
What is this,
some kind of sick joke?
Harmony told me
you were dead.
Now, why would she
say something like that?
Let's think.
Listen to me.
We have to find Buffy.
She'll figure out
a way to save us.
She was supposed
to be here...
and as much as it
kills me to admit it...
things were better
when she was around.
Buffy?
The slayer?
No! Buffy
the dog-faced girl!
Duh! Who do you think
I'm talking about?
Willow: Bored now.
This is the part
that's less fun.
When there isn't
any screaming.
What's up with you two
and the leather?
Play now?
It's not that I don't appreciate
your appetite, Wil...
but I thought we agreed
it was my turn.
No. No!
No way!
I wish us into Bizarro Land...
and you guys
are still together?!
I cannot win!
Probably not.
But I'll give you
a head start.
[Gasp] No!
I love this part.
You love all the parts.
No fun.
She didn't even
hardly fight.
[Tires Squealing]
Aw, swell.
It's the white hats.
I've got them!
Get the girl!
Oz: How's she doing?
Her pulse is strong.
What was she doing
wearing that?
Everyone knows that vampires
are attracted to bright colors.
That's Cordelia. It's better
to look good than to feel alive.
Uh, go and watch
the perimeters...
in case they follow.
[Techno Music Playing]
[Woman Screaming]
Man: Oh, my God!
Slap my hand,
dead soul man.
Ahh.
Xander. Willow.
Hungry?
I've lost my appetite
for this one.
She keeps looking at me.
I'm trying to eat,
and she looks at me.
Go on!
I remember that lust
for the kill.
Now... what news
on the Rialto?
Had a prime kill.
Old crush, actually...
till that wanna-slay
librarian showed up.
He'll be dealt with
soon enough.
Weird thing.
Girl kept talking
about Buffy.
"Gotta get Buffy here."
Isn't that what
they called the slayer?
Hmm.
Buffy. Ooh. Scary.
Someone has to talk
to her people.
That name is striking fear
in nobody's hearts.
She talked of summoning
a slayer here...
now, at this time...
and you didn't kill her?
Well, they had crosses.
The plant begins operation
in less than 24 hours.
You will find this girl.
You will kill her before
she contacts the slayer...
or I'll see you two
kissing daylight.
[Groans]
Hey! Hey...
Giles!
It's all my fault!
I wasn't... I made
this stupid wish...
Come on.
Please lie...
No! You have to get Buffy.
Buffy changes it.
It wasn't like this.
It was better.
I mean,
the clothes alone...
But people were happy.
Mostly.
And...
Wait.
Why are you here
and she's not?
I mean, you... you
were her watcher.
H-How do you know
I was a watcher?
- I've never...
- [Footsteps]
What?
I thought I heard
something.
Now, I want you
to start again...
and explain everything
very carefully.
You're in a big cage.
Not too bright,
book guy.
[Snarls]
So you're a watcher, huh?
Watch this.
They hit us right outside.
Nancy?
She's dead.
Um... would you mind...
Could you take her
to the incinerator?
I have some business to...
Wait a moment.
The deed is done.
You killed the girl
who sought the slayer?
It was too easy.
I felt cheap.
Excellent.
The opening will commence
as scheduled.
So... you're pleased?
Ecstatic.
Then... can I play
with the puppy?
Be my guest.
Yes, I understand, but it's
imperative that I see her.
Here.
Well... when will you?
Yeah, well,
you are her watcher.
I'd expect her to at least
check in to...
Yes, I'm aware that
there's a great deal
of demonic activity
in Cleveland.
It... Well, it happens,
you know...
that... that Sunnydale
is on a hellmouth.
It... It is so.
Well... Just...
Just give her the message...
if you ever see her again.
Willow: Bored now.
Daytime is the worst.
Cooped up for hours.
Can't hunt.
But the Master said
I could play.
Isn't that fun, puppy?
Aw...
Puppy's being all quiet.
Come on.
Don't be a spoilsport.
[Groans]
Guess what today is.
Today the plant opens.
It's a big party.
[Groans]
You remember I told you
about the plant.
All those people
you tried to save?
It's gonna
be quick for them.
Not for you, though.
It's gonna be slow for you.
That's right, puppy...
Willow's gonna make you bark.
Aah!
Oh...
Maybe I went too hard
on you last time.
Aah!
Ohh!
Too hard?
No such thing.
Watch it with those things.
You almost got my hair.
Sorry.
Got carried away.
Don't you want to?
No, thanks, baby.
I just want
to watch you go.
[Angel Screams]
Here it is!
I found it.
Look.
It's what, um,
Cordelia was wearing.
It's the... the, uh...
symbol of... of Anyanka.
I don't think I know her.
Well, no. Um, um,
Anyanka...
is sort of a patron saint
of scorned women.
What does she do?
Uh, she grants wishes.
So Cordelia wished
for something?
Well, if it was
a long, healthy life...
she should get
her money back.
She said something about
everything being different...
that the... world wasn't
supposed to be like this.
It was, um, better.
Before.
OK. The entire world sucks because
some dead ditz made a wish?
I just want it clear.
She said the, uh...
the slayer was supposed
to be here...
was meant
to have been here already.
Certainly would
have helped.
Yes. I tried calling her,
but, um...
Look, I'm gonna have to...
research this Anyanka
thing further.
Um, I have some more...
volumes at home.
You two get some sleep.
Watch your back.
Woman: No!
[Screaming]
- Get up there!
- [Screaming]
Hey!
Run!
Buffy Summers?
That's right.
Wanna tell me
what I'm doing here?
Ah! Ah! Ah!
Yes!
Here. "In order
to defeat Anyanka...
"one must destroy
her power center.
"This should reverse
all the wishes she's granted...
rendering her mortal
and powerless again."
You see? Without
her power center...
she'd just be
an ordinary woman again.
And all this would be, um...
well, different.
Well, I'd say that
my watcher muscles...
haven't completely
atrophied after all.
Great.
What's her power center?
Um, well, um... um...
It doesn't say.
Why don't I just put
a stake through her heart?
She's not a vampire.
Well, you'd be surprised
how many things that'll kill.
I don't want to kill her,
Miss Summers.
I want to reverse
whatever effect...
she's had on this... this world.
[Sighs]
You're taking an awful lot
on faith here, Jeeves.
Giles.
Kill the bad fairy...
destroy the bad fairy's
power center, whatever...
and all the troubles
go away?
Well, I'm sure
it's not that simple, but...
World is what it is.
We fight. We die.
Wishing doesn't change that.
I have to believe
in a better world.
Go ahead.
I have to live in this one.
Cordelia said she knew that
I was meant to be your watcher.
She said she knew you.
She's probably
just a big fan.
The Master sent his most
vicious disciples to kill her.
Now, she must have posed
some threat to him.
The Master?
Um, supreme vampire
around these parts.
He lives on the outskirts
of town in an old club.
You know where he lives...
and no one's ever tried
to take him out?
People have tried.
Well, point the way.
I might as well do some good
while I'm in this town.
You can't just walk
in there and...
Look, you wanna stay here
and play make-believe, fine.
I'm not gonna be any help
to you anyway.
There's only one thing
I'm good at.
At least let's muster
some kind of force.
I don't play well
with others.
Now, I'm gonna
ask you this once...
and then I'm gonna get testy.
[Drops Book]
Where is this club?
Angel: Buffy.
Buffy Summers.
It's you.
I mean...
you don't remember.
How could you?
How did you
know my name?
I waited.
I waited here for you.
But you never...
I was supposed to help you.
[Scoffs]
You were gonna help me.
The Master rose.
He let me live...
to punish me.
I kept hoping
maybe you'd come.
My destiny.
Is this a get-in-my-pants thing?
You guys in Sunnydale talk
like I'm the Second Coming.
I'm sorry.
I just meant...
Look, I don't have time
for stories.
Where's the Master?
They're at his factory.
It starts tonight.
Factory?
I... [Grunts]
I can take you there.
[Gasp]
Oh, you gotta
be kidding me!
Wait! I won't hurt you.
No. You'll leave that
to your Master.
You don't believe
I want to help you?
Believe I want him dead.
The Master: And now behold
the technical wonder...
which is about to alter
the very fabric of our society.
Some have argued that such an
advancement goes against our nature.
They claim that death is our art.
I say to them...
Well, I don't say anything
to them because I kill them.
Undeniably, we are
the world's superior race.
Yet we have always been
too parochial...
too bound by the mindless
routine of the predator.
Hunt and kill, hunt and kill.
Titillating?
Yes.
Practical? Hardly.
Meanwhile, the humans,
with their plebeian minds...
have brought us
a truly demonic concept...
mass production!
Vampires: Yeah!
Yeah!
We really are living
in a golden age.
O... Anyanka...
I beseech thee.
Um...
In the name
of all women scorned...
come before me.
Oh!
Do you have any idea
what I do to a man...
who uses that spell
to summon me?
Bring on the first!
Get back!
You!
Girl: Nooo!
No! Please! No!
Help me!
No!
Noooo!
- No... Oh!
- [Electric Shocks]
She's still alive, you see...
for the freshness.
What's the plan?
Don't fall on this.
Welcome to the future.
To the future!
The future!
Uh-oh. Puppy got out.
Cordelia Chase...
what did she wish for?
I had no idea her wish
would be so exciting.
Brave new world.
I hope she likes it.
You're gonna
change it back.
I'm not afraid of you.
Your only power
lies in the wishing.
Wrong!
Angel: Buffy, look out!
Buffy...
Anyanka: This is
the real world now.
This is the world
we made.
Isn't it wonderful?
Anyanka:
You trusting fool!
How do you know the other world
is any better than this?
Because it has to be.
No!
I wish Buffy Summers
had never come to Sunnydale.
Done.
That would be cool.
No. Wait.
I wish Buffy Summers
had never been born.
Done!
And I wish
that Xander Harris...
never again knows
the touch of a woman.
And that Willow wakes up tomorrow
covered in monkey hair.
Done!
In fact, I wish all men, except maybe the
dumb and the really agreeable kind...
disappear off the face of the Earth.
That would be so cool!
Or maybe...
Grr! Arrgh!
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org