I was thinking of asking out Buffy.
I've never courted anyone like Buffy before.
I don't think I've ever met
anyone like Buffy before.
Um, Buffy...
Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
Big Bad is back. And this time...
The Slayer set me up too.
- Situation?
- Gentlemen, suit up. We have a code red.
Hostile 17 has escaped.
Fail to recapture it, and everything
we've worked for - the Initiative - could end.
Nobody's failin' on my watch.
- My implant?
- The implant works.
Hostile 17 can't harm any living creature
without intense neurological pain.
- You're a little peculiar.
- I can live with that.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
- Looking for me?
- Holy... What do you want?
- Look who's home.
- Slayer...
Go back where you came from.
Things were great before you came.
And they say one person
can't make a difference.
Of all the duties of a dean,
one of the most pleasant
is to see a colleague realise a dream.
Ladies, gentlemen, students,
I present to you Professor Gerhardt
of the Anthropology Department.
When I first realised we were outgrowing
our cultural centre, I was concerned.
Then I realised it was like seeing one's child
grow up and move on to better things.
In this case, a spacious new facility
to be built on this site.
Look at him. Have you ever seen
anything so masculine?
- Dean Guerrero, or his wife?
- I think she means...
Oh. Very manly. Not at all Village People.
So much sexier than
the outfit from his lastjob.
I miss the free hot dogs on sticks.
I'm imagining having sex with him, right now.
That's why it's appropriate
that the groundbreaking
for the UC Sunnydale
Cultural Partnership Center
is taking place so near Thanksgiving.
Because that's what the melting pot is about:
contributions from all cultures,
making our culture stronger.
- What a load of horse hooey!
- We have a counter point?
Yeah. Thanksgiving isn't about
blending of two cultures.
It's about one culture wiping out another.
And then they make animated specials
with the maize and the big, big belt buckles.
They don't show you the scene
where all the bison die,
and then Squanto
takes a musket ball in the stomach.
For some of that
you were channelling your mother?
Well, yeah, sort of. That's why she doesn't
celebrate Thanksgiving or Columbus Day,
the destruction of the indigenous peoples.
I know it sounds a little overwrought,
but really she's right.
Yeah. I guess I never really
thought about it that way.
With Mom at Aunt Arlene's
I'm not getting a Thanksgiving.
Maybe it's just as well.
Well, I think that's a shame.
I love a ritual sacrifice.
Not really a one-of-those.
To commemorate a past event,
you kill and eat an animal.
It's a ritual sacrifice - with pie.
..and thus, a symbolic beginning.
What's she doing?
Xander said he was gonna dig.
I want to see Xander dig.
- That part's just ceremonial.
- Well, it bites.
She's not rippling at all.
Oh, look. There he goes.
Look at him.
Very... diggy.
Soon he'll be sweating.
I'm imagining having sex with him again.
Imaginary Xander is quite the machine.
What happened?
Hey, buddy, are you all right?
OK, don't move.
I'm OK! I'm...
- I'm OK.
- All right. We'll get you some help.
Where am I OK?
While they were pulling Xander out,
I heard the anthro professors talking about it.
Man, were they excited.
It's the old Sunnydale Mission,
which everyone thought was lost.
Huh?
Is there something out there?
Oh. No.
I'm sorry. A lost mission.
A hairbrush I can understand. By the way,
I will find that and get it back to you.
- But how do you lose a mission?
- Huge earthquake in 1812.
Everyone just assumed the mission was
levelled. Instead, they built right over it.
It's like what happened in the '30s
with that church the Master was in.
Doesn't it make you wonder what else
is there? Right under our feet.
- Mostly, I've found sewers full of demons.
- Oh, right.
- Man, it's crazy out there.
- Post-midterm frenzy.
And the holiday. Everyone's goin' home.
It looks like a lotta lucky moms are gonna be
getting brimming baskets of dirty laundry.
It's so not fair.
I mean, they all get a family holiday just
because they can go home to their families.
It's a turvy-topsy world.
You know what? I should have
my own Thanksgiving.
I can cook the meal,
have all you guys over. It'll be great.
Buffy, earlier you agreed with me about
Thanksgiving. It's a sham. It's all about death.
It is a sham.
But it's a sham with yams.
It's a yam sham.
- You won'tjokey-rhyme your way out of this.
- I know. But I want it.
It's like Professor Walsh
was saying about sense memory.
I smell a roasting turkey
and I'm eight years old.
I liked having that to look forward to.
Everything's different now.
Well, I suppose there could be slight yams.
I mean, we could definitely use
a little comfort food.
I bet Giles doesn't have any plans.
And Xander always avoids
his family gatherings.
We could not invite Anya.
I don't know. She and Xander
seem pretty tight lately.
Grumble, grumble.
Look, Pilgrims aside, isn't that the point of
Thanksgiving? Everybody has a place to go?
Man, I'm beat.
- We'll do one more sweep, then cash it in.
- I gotta pack tonight.
- You got a flight?
- Wednesday night.
Professor Walsh
wants me here for the debriefing.
That's a short Thanksgiving.
With the hostile loose,
we're lucky to be goin' home at all.
It's neutered. The implant works great.
He can't hurt any living thing.
As long as he knows about the Initiative,
he's a threat. We do this the professor's way.
Mama's boy.
That's a nasty cough. You might need
to spend the weekend in quarantine.
Oh, no. I'm done coughing.
I just don't want anyone gettin' sick.
Xander, what are you doing?
You're supposed to be digging.
I went to watch you digging,
and you weren't there doing it.
I'm going now.
Just kinda tough gettin' going today.
Your head is moist. Oh! You're sick.
Well, you can't go to work.
- Oh. Anya...
- You're pasty and wet and disgusting.
They can dig without you.
I don't really feel that bad.
I inflicted a lot of putrefying diseases
on men when I was an avenging demon.
You look like you're getting all of them.
OK. I'll stay.
But you should go. You could catch it.
Then we'll die together. It's romantic.
Let me get your trousers off.
You're a strange girlfriend.
I'm a girlfriend?
There's a chance I'm delirious.
Ah, yes.
Well, whatever it is
that's making you sick, so far I like it.
It's a very exciting opportunity.
I can't wait to go down there myself.
It's just...
It means we're gonna have to
start looking for a new location.
No, it's really up to the dean.
I just hope this doesn't
cost us another year.
OK. Talk to you later.
I'll never get used to this.
One day she's at the Friendship Ceremony,
and the next day, she's on the news.
The coroner's office said
she was missing an ear.
So I'm thinking
maybe we're looking for a witch.
There are some great spells that work
much better with an ear in the mix.
That's one fun little hobby
you've got there, Will.
Or maybe an ear-harvesting demon that...
It's, like, building another demon
completely out of ears.
Or... Oh. Thought.
We're just assuming
someone else cut off the ear.
What if it was self-inflicted, like Van Gogh?
So she brutally stabbed herself, dumped
the body and then cut off her own ear?
No. She cut off her ear, then killed herself,
then dumped the body...
I'm really off my game, aren't I?
Yeah.
Wait. Something's missing from this case.
- Early 1800 Chumash knife. There's a picture.
- What's it look like?
Pretty darn scary.
It was more like a riot than a Ralphs.
I nearly used slayer moves on a woman
who was hoarding the pumpkin pie filling.
And at some point you are going
to tell me about the murder?
Oh. Right. The knife was
some sort of Indian artefact.
- Chumash, I think. That's all we got.
- Oh, the Chumash Indians.
They were indigenous to this whole area.
That's interesting.
Then, of course, the murder weapon
might have just been a convenient choice.
Uh-uh. There was a big scissors right there.
That knife was picked for a reason.
Do you even own a turkey pan?
Tell me again why
we're not doing this at your house.
Giles, if you would like to get by in American
society, you have to follow our traditions.
You're the patriarch.
You have to host the festivities.
And this is in no way an elaborate scheme
to stick me with the cleanup?
How about that ceremonial knife, huh?
Juicy piece of clueage, don't you think?
All right, I'll look into
the Chumash connection.
See if there's any ritual significance
to the ear removal.
Thank you.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
I still need to pick up a few things,
so I'll check in.
And keep your hands off the food.
Oh, I'll try and restrain myself from eating
uncooked potatoes and cranberries.
So, what do you think?
She sounds good.
Kind of intense
about this Thanksgiving thing.
I think perhaps she's a little Ionely.
But I meant about the murder.
Whatever killed the woman in the museum
is probably the danger.
This danger... Your friend has
some ominous vision about Buffy?
It's all terribly vague.
There are other things happening.
Maybe I'm wrong,
but I can'tjust keep watching.
I'm glad you're watching out for her,
but she's not helpless,
- and it's not yourjob to keep her safe.
- It's not yours any more either.
Are you gonna walk away?
All right.
But I feel we should tell her.
I don't like keeping this secret.
If she knew I was here,
it would distract her. It could get her hurt.
I don't want to get in the way.
I assume there is a connection
to the old mission.
Something is angry about being disturbed.
Or it was trapped there
and now it's released.
Something with a fondness
for ancient weapons?
- You know Father Gabriel?
- No.
He knows the history of this place
back to mission times.
- He might be able to fill in some blanks.
- OK. I'll see about contacting him.
- Where are you going?
- To watch her.
It's not fair.
You know that's what she'd say.
You can see her, but she can't see you?
Believe me, I'm not gettin'
the good half of this deal.
To be on the outside
looking in at what I can't...
No. I'd forgotten how bad it feels.
But you have whipped cream.
I saw it in Giles's fridge.
But that's whipped cream in a canister.
It's only right if you whip it yourself.
Hey, and then later we can churn our own
butter and make sweaters out of sheep.
OK. It's the last thing. I promise.
Besides, I have to see that priest
Giles called about.
- Thinks he might have some information.
- Buffy? Hey, Buffy.
Riley. Where did you come from?
I didn't see you at all.
Oh, just across the street.
And a couple of blocks down.
- Hey, Willow.
- Hi.
Well, I'm just gonna let you two...
Look! They're selling coffee
in the coffee shop. Yum.
Angel! Evil - you're all evil again.
I'm not evil. I'm here to help Buffy.
- What's goin' on?
- My friend had a vision. Buffy's in danger.
- So tell her. Help her.
- If she sees me, it'll be worse.
See, I don't get all this "leaving for her
own good" garbage. Because that's what it is.
You can'tjust give up
because there's obstacles.
- Willow.
- Sorry. My stuff.
You know how I feel about her.
If there was any way...
Yeah, I know.
It's just everything's different now.
Hey, is Cordelia really working for you?
Of all the people you could've hired...
Willow, I'm here to protect Buffy.
I don't have a lot of time for personal stuff.
Right. Well, how can I help?
Well, if you can just tell me...
Who's that guy?
It'll be just like when I was a kid. Only without
me building a fort out of mashed potatoes.
- Sounds like fun.
- It will be.
You know, if you don't already have plans,
you should come.
I'm a great cook - in theory. I've eaten a lot.
That sounds so great.
But I'm outta here tonight.
I got a last-minute flight to Iowa.
Iowa.
That's one of the ones in the middle, right?
My folks and I always do Thanksgiving at my
grandparents' house. A farm outside Huxley.
- Sounds nice.
- It is.
After dinner, we all go for a walk
down by the river with the dogs.
There's trees and... And you're thinking
it's like I grew up in a Grant Wood painting.
Exactly - if I knew who that was.
Just a guy who painted stuff
that looked like where I grew up.
Well, have fun at the homestead.
Always do. What's the line? "Home's the
place that, when you have to go there..."
"..they have to take you in."
Get out!
- But, babe, this is where I belong.
- Out! I mean it.
I've been doing a lot of reading,
and I'm in control of my own power now,
so we're through.
You don't mean that.
Yes, I do.
I do.
I mean it a lot.
See?
I knew you'd end up
welcoming me back with open...
arms.
No.
I'm powerful and I'm beautiful
and I don't need you to complete me.
And you're mean.
You had that in our bed?
- Do you know how dangerous that is?
- Let's find out.
- You wouldn't.
- You did it to me, remember?
All right. All right. I'll go. Just...
What?
Can I have someone to eat?
Father Gabriel?
Father?
Are you out here?
God...
- You can't stop me.
- You're very wrong about that.
I am vengeance. I am my people's cry.
They call for Hus,
for the avenging spirit to carve outjustice.
They tell you to start an ear collection?
You slaughtered my people.
Now you kill their spirit.
This is a great day for you.
It's clear we're dealing
with a spirit of some kind.
It's very common for Indian spirits
to change to animal form.
Well, it's plenty uncommon
for me to freeze up during a fight.
I had the guy. I was ready
for the takedown and I stopped.
- And "Native American".
- Sorry?
We don't say "Indian".
Oh, right. Yes, yes.
Always behind on the terms.
Still trying not to refer
to you lot as "bloody colonials".
And the thing is, I like my evil
like I like my men: evil. You know?
Straight up, black hat, tied to the train tracks,
"my electro-ray will destroy Metropolis" bad.
Not mixed up with guilt and
the destruction of an indigenous culture.
This spirit warrior - Hus, you called him -
has killed innocent people.
OK, we need to boil those
and put them through the ricer.
I don't think I have a ricer.
You don't have a ricer? What do you mean?
- How could someone not have a ricer?
- Well, do you have one at home?
I don't know. What's a ricer?
We'll mash them with forks,
as the Pilgrims did.
- Did you get the part about innocent people?
- Yes. OK? And I do wanna stop him.
I'd just like to find
a non-slayey way to do it.
- Hey.
- Peas?
- Peas.
- These are frozen.
- What's all that?
Atrocities. I got the full poop on the Chumash
Indians and our fabulous buried mission.
- You said you'd get fresh ones.
- Atrocities?
Peas. They come in pods. You shell them.
I didn't have time. I was reading
about the Chumash war.
The Chumash were peaceful.
Oh, they were fluffy indigenous kittens,
till we came along.
- They'll be mushy.
- They won't be.
I like mushy peas.
You're the reason we had Pilgrims
in the first place.
So what happened to the Chumash?
How about imprisonment, forced labour,
herded like animals into a mission
full of bad European diseases.
Boy. The Cultural Partnership Center
didn't stress any of that stuff.
Not even a diorama. And it gets better.
The few Chumash
who tried to rebel were hanged.
And when a group was accused
of stealing cattle, they were killed.
Men, women and children.
And for proof
to bring back to their accusers...
They cut off their ears?
So Hus wasn't kidding about vengeance. He's
re-creating all the wrongs done to his people.
- Then it's up to us to stop him.
- Yes, but after dinner, right?
Are you sure we shouldn't be helping him?
No, I think perhaps we won't help the angry
spirit with his rape and pillage and murder.
Well, OK, no. But we should be
helping him redress his wrongs.
Bring the atrocities to light.
If the history books are full of them,
they already are.
- Giving his land back.
- It's not exactly ours to give.
I don't think you wanna help. I think you just
wanna slay the demon, then go "La, la, la".
And I think your sympathy for his plight
has blinded you to certain urgent facts.
We have to stop this thing.
- OK, Unfeeling Guy.
- Willow, that's not fair.
I have to baste.
Willow,
I have reason to believe that Buffy may be
in particular danger from this menace.
You mean... Angel?
- I saw him too.
- That's not terribly stealthy of him.
I think he's lost his edge.
- But Buffy doesn't know?
- No, no. Not a peep.
That's good. But this is why I think
we should all keep a level head in this.
I think mine is the level head
and yours is the one things would roll off of.
- Happy Thanksgiving.
- Xander!
- You look like death.
- Are you OK?
You didn't bring rolls?
The doctor couldn't figure it out. He said
I had a lot of symptoms that didn't connect.
I think they do connect.
What, to this Chumash spirit vengeance guy?
Didn't you say the Chumash
got all diseased in the mission?
Yeah. This has a better account.
It lists the various...
Various? As in?
Well, the important thing is not to panic.
You just recited the mystical panic-causing
incantation, so little hope there.
Let's talk about the various.
Well, they did suffer from malaria,
some smallpox...
- I was gonna say smallpox.
- You know, syphilis...
- But basically standard...
- Syphilis?
Well... But this is probably mystical,
and it'll all go away as soon as...
As soon as what?
- We still don't know what we're gonna do.
- Maybe I can find something.
Let's give him some land.
That'll clear everything up.
- Sarcasm accomplishes nothing, Giles.
- It's sort of an end in itself.
Can we come rocketing back to the part
about me and my new syphilis?
It'll make you blind and insane.
But it won't kill you.
The smallpox will.
Maybe there's a Wiccan spell that can cure it.
Something regular medicine
doesn't know about.
Ooh, there was a potion!
Sage, salt... onion?
- That's the stuffing.
- Oh, God.
Oh. You're gonna get vesicles and pustules.
They have pictures.
- I hate this guy.
- He's just doing what was done to him.
- I didn't give him syphilis.
- You freed his spirit.
And after a century of unrest,
he saw you as one of his oppressors.
What, so he rises up and
infects the first guy he sees?
- That's no fair.
- Like you've never woken up cranky?
Why the others? Why them particularly?
So we take this guy out.
Buffy, it is for to be slaying
sometime soon, yeah?
That's sort of the question before the court.
Question?
- There are two sides to it.
- To slaying him?
- Well, the member from Syphilis votes yea.
- It's not that simple.
He's a vengeance demon. You don't talk
to vengeance demons. You kill them.
- I didn't know you felt that way.
- What?
Anyway, he's a spirit, not a demon.
And we've never faced this sort of spirit
before. We don't know what will kill it.
- Again with the killing.
- Figuratively speaking. Or bind it. Whatever.
Willow, we all appreciate your perspective.
- Sometimes vengeance is justified.
- You know I didn't mean you.
No one appreciates the truth of the situation.
I think we do.
This is no good!
It needs more condensed milk.
Buffy, Xander is in danger.
Are you sure the solution is pie?
- Over bickering, I'll take pie.
- We will find a solution.
And we will have a nice dinner, OK?
Both. End of story.
I'm going to have Thanksgiving,
and it'll be perfect.
Hus won't stop.
Vengeance is never sated, Buffy.
Hatred is a cycle. All he will do is kill.
Help me.
What part of "help me"
do you not understand?
The part where I help you.
Come on. I'm parboiling out here.
- Want me to help make it quicker?
- Invite me in.
- No.
- Very unlikely.
Damn it!
Look, I'm safe. I can't bite anyone.
Willow, tell 'em what I did.
You said you were gonna kill me, then Buffy.
Yes, bad, but let's skip to the part
where I couldn't bite you.
It's true.
- He had trouble performing.
- Yeah. It looks like they've done me for good.
What are you saying?
Spike had a little trip to the vet, and now
he doesn't chase the other puppies any more.
I can't bite anything. I can't even hit people.
So you haven't murdered anybody lately?
Let's be best pals.
I've got information - about the soldier boys
you were fighting. I've got the inside scoop.
Come on. What have you got to be afraid of?
First People, who dwell in Mishupashup,
hear me and descend.
Walk with me upon Itiashup again.
Hear me also, Nunashush,
spirits from below,
creatures of the night.
Take human form and join the battle.
Bring me my revenge.
Bloody hell, woman!
You're cuttin' off my circulation.
- You don't have any circulation.
- Well, it pinches.
- Get over it. I have more important worries.
- I came to you in friendship.
Well, all right, seething hatred. But I've got
useful information and I'm being mistreated.
So tell me everything you know.
- I'm too hungry to remember everything.
- Then sit.
- How much butter goes in with these?
- Half a stick, and a quarter cup of brandy.
You do have brandy, don't you?
What?
Oh. Yes. On the bookcase.
- I wouldn't say no to a brandy.
- What's wrong?
The victims.
Apart from Xander,
Hus has targeted authority figures.
Father Gabriel,
the curator of the cultural centre...
- Who else fits?
- Just a small brandy.
Dean Guerrero. He's the king of us,
and he was at the ceremony.
A likely candidate. We should warn him.
Will, anything in those books about
how to stop a Native American spirit guy?
Some nice, nonjudgmental way to,
you know, kill him?
I'm not gonna help you kill him.
I'm not on board.
Will, what choice do we have?
Buffy, this isn't a Western. We're not at Fort
Giles with the cavalry coming to save us.
It's one Ionely guy. Oppressed
warrior guy, who's just trying to...
- Kill a lot of people?
- Well, I didn't say he was right.
Will, you know how bad I feel
about this. It's eating me up.
A quarter cup and simmer.
But even though it's hard,
we have to end this.
Yes, he's been wronged,
and I personally would apologise...
Oh, someone put a stake in me.
You got a lot of volunteers in here.
I just can't take all this mamby-pamby
boohooing about the bloody Indians.
- The preferred term...
- You won. All right?
You came in, killed them and took their land.
That's what conquering nations do.
Caesar did, and he didn't say "I came,
I conquered, I felt really bad about it."
History is not people making friends.
You had better weapons
and you massacred them. End of story.
Well, I think the Spaniards actually did
a lot of... Not that I don't like Spaniards.
Listen to you. How are you gonna
fight anyone with that attitude?
- We don't wanna fight anyone.
- I just wanna have Thanksgiving.
Yeah. Good luck.
- If we could talk to him...
- You exterminated his race.
What could you possibly say
that would make him feel better?
It's kill or be killed here.
Take your bloody pick.
Maybe it's the syphilis talkin',
but some of that made sense.
I made these points earlier,
but it's fine. No one listens to me.
Fine, OK. But someone
still has to go warn the dean.
- I'll go. I need the air.
- Not alone.
- I'll go.
- Me too.
- You sure you're up to it?
- Oh, leave that one.
He looks like he's ready to drop, and I think
I can eat someone if he's already dead.
- I'm up to it.
- I'll keep on looking for a solution.
Yeah. Guys, the dean's house
is up past the gym. And hurry!
Dinner's in an hour.
- Hey. When do I get fed?
- Later. I hope the others are OK.
Do you know what happens to vampires
who don't get to feed?
- I wondered that.
- Giles, plates.
Living skeletons, mate. Like famine pictures
from those dusty countries.
Only not half as funny.
- You can have gravy. That has blood in it.
- Do you know what else has blood in it?
Blood.
Do I have to gag you? Because I won't
listen to you whine all through my dinner.
It'll be a nice, quiet, civilised...
You!
Listen, maybe I wasn't clear about
how terrible we all feel. We're trying to help.
- What's goin' on?
- It isn't working.
You can have casinos now.
Get down!
What about me? You gonna
leave me here like this?
Hey! Watch the heart.
- That was a waste of time.
- I think he thought we were crazy.
If Anya hadn't opened the conversation
with "Everybody got both ears?"
I liked his wife. She gave me pie.
- So what do we do now?
- We could stay here and stand watch, or...
Willow.
Angel?
So this is Angel.
He's large and glowery, isn't he?
- He's evil again.
- I'm not. Why does everyone think that?
- Angel's here to protect Buffy.
- I haven't been evil for a long time.
She's not supposed to know he's here.
Angel, any news?
The Chumash weapons are missing
from the centre. Where's Buffy?
At Giles'. She sent us
to check on Dean Guerrero.
- Why the Dean?
- He may go after someone in charge.
- A leader?
- He's a warrior.
To a warrior, the leader means
the strongest fighter.
- Buffy.
- He's formed a raiding party.
- We gotta get over there.
- I'll call her. Get back fast.
Here. You guys can ride.
Hello?
Yes.
Yes, we're well aware of that. We're...
under siege now, actually. Thank you.
- Who was that?
- A... Someone. We need a plan.
Yes. Let's talk about it some more.
- Where's your weapons chest?
- Over there.
Buffy!
Remember that conquering nation thing?
Apologise.
- Shut up, Spike.
- Fine. I'll do it myself.
Hey, sorry. Sorry about that, chief.
How many?
The leader, upstairs.
Two by the living-room windows.
One through the window by the door.
- There's too many.
- We need help.
OK. One,
two,
three.
Stop them!
Enough!
Ow! Bloody hell!
- Giles, these guys, they don't die.
- Bit busy over here.
Why... won't... you die?
What's he like when he is evil?
Help the others.
Your knife can kill you.
A bear! You made a bear.
- I didn't mean to.
- Undo it! Undo it!
Hey, Gentle Ben! Over here!
That's for giving me syphilis.
What happened? Did we win?
I feel lousy.
- Well, the turkey came out rather splendidly.
- Oh, it was yummy.
It's just... Did you see me?
Two seconds of conflict with an indigenous
person and I turn into General Custer.
Violence does that.
You know, instinct takes over.
Yeah. That's the fun.
Nobody asked you.
Oh, lay off. You all had a fine meal.
But me?
An entire siege. You'd think
one of you would bleed a little.
Good work, Buffy. On both counts.
- Thanks.
- Well, you know, you should be very pleased.
It wasn't exactly a perfect Thanksgiving.
I don't know. Seemed kinda right to me.
A bunch of anticipation,
a big fight, and now we're all sleepy.
And we did all survive.
I guess that much is true.
First Thanksgiving on my own
and we all got through it.
And you know what?
I think my syphilis is clearin' right up.
And they say romance is dead.
Or maybe they just wish it.
Well, maybe we started
a new tradition this year.
Maybe not.
But at least we all worked together.
It was like old times.
Especially with Angel
bein' here and everything.
Oops.
Subtitles by Visiontext
ENGLISH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org