Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
Tara?
Willow, what did you do?
We have to get you out of here
or you'll both be killed.
- What about Warren?
- She killed him.
We've gotta get out of this town. Mexico. We
should go to Mexico.
- How did you do it?
- What is she talking about?
- Nothing. Let's go.
- I can see you.
You got your soul back.
Cassie?
Cassie? Cassie!
This... is just the beginning, love.
Horror and bloodshed.
From beneath you, it devours.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
# Night falls
# I fall
# And where were you?
# Warm skin
# Wolf grin
# And where were you?
# I fell into the moon
# And it covered you in blue
# Can I make it right?
# Can I spend the night?
# High tide
# Inside
# The air is dew
# And where were you?
# Wild eyed
# I died
# And where were you?
# I crawled out of the world
# And you said I shouldn't stay
# Can I make it right?
# Can I spend the night
# Alone?
Here we go.
You keep circling around.
Just drive straight in.
Will you shut up? We gotta keep it low pro.
- You're scared.
- Of course I'm scared.
Last time we were here,
33.3 per cent of us were flayed alive.
Calm down. No one's getting flayed alive.
We've got a plan. We're gonna fix all that.
We should have stayed in Mexico.
I didn't like it there.
Everybody spoke Mexicoan.
You could've learned it. You learned
the Klingon dictionary in two weeks.
That had much clearer
transitive and intransitive rules, OK?
Besides,
I can't keep having those nightmares.
Me neither.
Desde abajo, te debora.
"It eats you, starting with your bottom."
(whispers) We've gotta make it right.
We're outlaws with hearts of gold.
# Anchovies, anchovies, you're so delicious
# I love you more than all the other fishes
Oh!
Ah, she'll think it's blood.
Taste my blade, spawn of evil!
(Spanish music on radio)
(turns volume up)
Cool!
- (loud thump)
- (microwave beeps)
So...
this is the UC library, huh?
It's so big.
Hey!
I know you. I mean...
- I saw your picture.
- Yeah!
I know, it's kinda weird
because we never really met.
- Or kinda weird cos you're really dead.
- Yeah, well...
- Did I fall asleep?
- No, no, I'm here.
I mean, not here here.
It's kinda complicated.
Kind of ironic, too, you know? I...
write all that intense poetry about the end,
and here I am again.
- Chatting you up.
- Yeah, ironic.
I knew this would
completely freak you out. It's just...
She asked that I come talk to you.
It's important.
- She?
- Don't worry, I'm not gonna hurt you...
Who asked you? What are you talking about?
She says she still sings.
What?
Remember that time on the bridge
when you sang to each other?
Well, she says even though you can't hear it
she still sings to you.
Tara?
Oh, come on, she is so dead!
Well, he's clearly a psychopath.
Is so! What?!
No, that is not Tom Hanks.
Well, what channel are you on?
(loud thump)
OK, there it is again.
I keep hearing this, like, thumping.
- (turns volume down)
- (thumping)
No... I can't tell if it's...
Kit? Are you there?
Is there a storm?
(volume is turned back up)
Buffy?
- Buffy Summers?
- Have we...?
Webs. Holden Webster.
We went to school together.
European History.
I let you crib off
my Vaclav Havel essay that time.
You really don't remember me?
Sure! Sure.
(TV/radio/CD player blaring)
(music on radio continues)
Oh, God.
Oh, God!
(radio frequency changes)
(woman) Dawn?
Mom?
OK, um...
Junior year, spring production of Pippin.
I did the lighting design.
- I didn't see it.
- You helped me move the lighting board.
I dropped it on your foot.
Right, foot. Yes, of course.
History class.
It's all coming back. Sorry.
Well, you know, it's not like I was
a big part of your life or anything.
No, I just... I didn't recognise
your face - all demon and...
- I think you've filled out a lot.
- Oh, yeah.
I got into tae kwon do in a big way
at Dartmouth, so...
- That's great.
- Yeah.
- So what have you been up to?
- Well, apparently dying.
No, but other stuff.
You know, majoring in Psych.
Really liking that.
Took a year off to do an internship
at the Sunnydale Mental Hospital.
Wow. That's gotta be a... popularjoint.
I keep telling them we ought to get
a velvet rope and a bouncer.
- You remember Jason Wheeler? Crazy Jay?
- Oh, yeah.
He always had that shtick of
"I'm crazy! I'm crazy!"
- How is he?
- Crazy.
He's been in the chronic ward
since graduation.
- Not really that funny, I guess.
- Ironic, sorta.
Yeah.
- Whoa. Did my face just change?
- Yeah.
You look human now.
You can do that - go back and forth.
Oh, so I'm a vampire. How weird is that?
- Sorry.
- No, no.
Feels great. Strong.
Like I'm connected to a powerful evil that's
gonna suck the world into a fiery oblivion.
- How about you?
- Not so much connected.
No, no. I mean...
you know, with the stake and the cross.
You do this kind of thing a lot?
I'm the Slayer. It's sort of a thing.
So, what?
You, like, fight vampires professionally?
I don't get paid. It's more like a calling.
Since... Even in school.
I heard rumours about you back then.
You were mysterious.
- I was?
- Well, you were never around.
A lot of kids thought you were dating some
old guy, or that you were heavy religious.
- Scott Hope said you were gay.
- What?! I dated that ringworm.
He says that about every girl he breaks up
with. And then, big surprise, he comes out.
Men. Do I know how to pick 'em.
- So, all that time you were a slayer?
- The.
- "The", like as in "the only one"?
- Pretty much.
Oh.
So... when you said "not connected",
that was kind of a telling statement.
- Ah, Psych 101 alert.
- Well, I'm just saying.
I need emotional therapy
from the evil dead.
- It was your phrase.
- I'm connected.
- I'm connected to a lot of people, OK?
- No, no. No, I hear ya.
- (ringing)
- (Buffy) I really am!
Buffy! Come on, pick up.
I don't know what to do.
Do it again! I heard you.
(thump)
- (loud thump)
- Why are you doing this?!
(loud thump)
Why are you...? I don't understand.
- (thumping continues)
- Stop. Stop it! Stop it!
- (screams)
- (thumping stops)
- Hello?
- (loud thump)
Once for yes.
Twice for no.
Mom?
(thump)
It's you?
Are you OK?
(two thumps)
You're not. Mom?
Mommy?
Are you alone?
(two thumps)
(rumbling)
Aargh!
Why are you doing this?!
Get up, you wuss.
I have shin splints. Ow.
- We should turn on a light.
- No, they'll see it from outside.
- Right.
- (breaking glass)
- Maybe we should go get Buffy.
- No way.
Tell her what we know
about the Seal of Danzalthar.
Think, McFly. Why would
she believe us without any proof?
We go to her empty-handed,
we'll be in the clink in a microsecond.
I ain't going back to the big house.
That place changes a man.
That's why we need proof.
Think of it as trial by fire. A quest.
Una questa.
We find it. We alert the Slayer.
We help her destroy it. We save Sunnydale.
Then we join her gang
and possibly hang out at her house.
Right. OK, what do we do?
We should find the principal's office
and work our way down from there.
OK, um...
You go check down the hallway
and I'll go over there.
Check communications?
- Check. Check.
- Check.
- Echo 2 to Echo 1.
- This is Echo 1. Go ahead.
Do you think
they'll really let us join their gang?
Nice job!
- I'm scared out of my freaking gourd here.
- Take it easy. Take it easy.
Do you have any idea
how hard it is to act this cool?
Calm down, you're doing great.
All specs are within parameters.
You keep leaving me.
I hate it when you leave me.
One time you died and I ended up a Mexican.
We've been over this. Now, that death thing
was all part of the master plan.
Come on.
"If you strike me down..."
"I shall become more powerful than
you could possibly imagine." Of course.
- You think maybe Willow could kill me, too?
- Hey, don't worry.
If Short Round pulls off his end
of the bargain, we'll both become gods.
"That boy is our last hope."
"No... there is another."
- Really? Who's our last hope?
- No, I was just going with it.
It was a thing. No, he's our last hope.
Tara? Is it you?
She's sorry she couldn't come herself.
Why didn't she? I don't understand.
I mean, if you can manifest yourself...
- She just can't.
- Why not? I don't understand.
Because of what you did.
- What?
- You killed people. You can't see her.
It's just how it is. I'm sorry.
But... but she's talking to you?
And... and she can hear me?
Tara?
Tara, I miss you.
I miss you so much.
Can she hear me?
What's happening? Did she say anything?
What? Did she go away?
- She's crying.
- No. No, don't cry.
Don't cry, sweetie. Talk to me.
She misses you, too.
She wishes she could touch you.
Me too. Oh, me too.
Oh, God, Tara. It hurts so much.
Every day it's like this giant hole.
And it's not getting better.
It will. It can.
How? You're gone.
But you're not.
You're strong, like an Amazon, remember?
I do. I remember.
(Webster) So, you meet someone,
you form a bond...
But it never lasts.
Do you mean all relationships, or just yours?
My parents weren't exactly the paragon of
stay-togetheryness. Maybe that's part of it.
I think there are people out there
who'd make it. I just...
target the impossible ones,
with deadly accuracy.
You think you do that on purpose?
Maybe you're trying to protect yourself?
Protecting myself?
From heartbreak, misery,
sexual violence and possible death?
- Not so much.
- From committing.
I commit! I'm committed. I'm a committee.
So it's them. You're reaching out,
they're just not coming through.
It's different. I think you're confusing me
because you're evil.
I just think you're in some pain here.
Which I do kind of enjoy, cos I'm evil now.
But you should ease up on yourself.
It's not exactly like you have
the patent on bad relationships.
Wouldn't it be cool if I did?
And what, are you supposed to be
settling down already? At 21?
You know, my girlfriend at college,
she's so sweet.
But that doesn't mean I'm gonna go vampify
her just so we can be together forever.
- "Sire."
- What?
The word. When you turn a human
into a vampire, it's you "sire" them.
- Cool.
- It's a noun, too.
Oh, I have so much to learn.
Come on, isn't this insane?
I mean, I was afraid to talk to you in high
school. And now we're, like, mortal enemies.
Wouldn't it be cool if we became nemeses?
Is that how you say the word?
We're gonna have to fight to the death,
aren't we?
- It's the time-honoured custom.
- Wow.
Reality just shows up sometimes,
doesn't it?
But I've got the bloodlust pumping,
and I kinda get it.
I'm looking for a fight.
Nothing personal.
- Oh, no. I mean, you've been great.
- And fun catching up.
I haven't kept in contact with
many friends from high school.
Guess I'll be looking them up pretty soon.
Yeah.
Hey, I don't mean to be Count Buttinsky here,
but you just don't seem as thrilled.
- Is it because we're gonna fight?
- It's cos I'm gonna win.
(laughs)
Hello?! Two years of tae kwon do
and vampire strength.
Somebody's counting their chickens.
You're not leaving this graveyard.
Can't let ya.
Do the words "superiority complex"
mean anything?
You think I'm gonna let you kill people?
I get the battle against evil.
It's not the issue.
- There is no issue. Don't issue me!
- Just answer me this.
Whose fault was your parents' divorce?
OK, this is beyond evil.
This is insane troll logic.
- What do my parents have to do with...?
- I'm just curious. Your opinion.
- They both had a lot of...
- Off the top of your head.
- My dad.
- Uh-huh?
He cheated.
I... I think he cheated.
So... of all of these relationships of yours,
that you knew subconsciously
were totally doomed,
whose fault is that?
It's incredibly different.
I was just wondering.
Is it possible, even a little bit,
that the reason you have trouble
connecting to guys
is because you think
maybe they're not worth it?
Maybe you think you're better than them.
- Say, there's that bloodlust I was looking for.
- Struck a nerve.
I'll strike a nerve cluster, you don't get off
this! I don't remember you being so annoying.
- You don't remember me!
- I do.
Yeah, like, after 30 minutes of reminding.
I don't take it personally - you were
in your own little world in school.
All "chosen". All "destiny".
Who could live with that for seven years
and not feel superior?
I'm not. My God, if anything...
- What?
- I just...
If you knew what I've done,
what I've let myself become.
My best friends don't even...
You'd laugh, you heard
some of the things I've done to them.
Buffy... I'm here to kill you, not to judge you.
The last guy I was with, it got really...
I behaved like a monster.
Treated him like...
And at the same time, I...
I let him completely take me over.
Do things to me that...
(sniffs) I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to get
all true-confessions on you there.
I don't know what's wrong with me.
There's nothing wrong with you.
Everyone's got issues.
- You son of a bitch.
- What?!
I'm gonna kill you
just a little bit more than usual.
Aw, come on!
I mean, we had a moment.
You opened up.
It was really sweet.
It made me want to bite you.
I'm sorry if I overstepped my bounds.
I'm new to this mortal-enemy stuff.
Pretty fast learner, though, right?
- (Dawn) I hear you.
- (beastly growl)
- I hear you breathing.
- Are you hurting my mother?
- (beastly growl)
Are you keeping her
from coming back to me?
Mom?
I... I see you.
I'm coming towards you, OK?
She's trying to talk to me.
Get off her and let her talk to me!
The axe!
Aargh!
(demonic voice) Get out!
- No!
- (beastly growl)
She's my mother. I'm staying.
Seeing the high school again...
part of me wishes I could go back.
Everything's shifting around.
I feel like we're in Hellraiser.
- I hate Pinhead.
- Let me see that.
Did we circle all the way around?
- We should start over.
- There it is.
What?
Are you sure?
Yeah.
You know, I think you may be right.
If this lines up, what we're looking for
should be right under there.
See? You're dead.
That enough of a moment for ya?
OK. But are you killing me cos I'm evil
or because you opened up?
Agh!
What is wrong with you?
Nothing. I got no worries, I'm dead.
The biggest thing on my mind is whether
Tricia Waldman came to my funeral.
Do you remember her? Ohh - biteable.
See, this is what I hate about you vampires.
Sex and death and love and pain -
it's all the same damn thing to you.
It's kind of a guy thing.
We talk about nailing a girl, there's all this...
No, it is not the same.
With vampires, it is completely...
Believe me, I know.
Oh my God!
Oh your God, what?
Well, not my God, because I defy him
and all of his works. Does he exist?
- Is there word on that, by the way?
- Nothing solid.
I keep getting off topic
cos my mind is racing here.
All right. I'll make a deal with you.
We fight, to the death - great.
That last fight was exhilarating.
I had a move coming up to block that stake.
But you have to answer one question.
If I'm right, I get to ask anything -
no secrets, no defensiveness.
Anything I wanna know.
What's your question?
Your last relationship.
Was it with a vampire?
I don't know where to start.
After Warren shot you...
You know all about that, what happened?
It was horrible. I was horrible.
I lost myself, the regular me.
Well, you were grieving.
A lot of people grieve.
They don't make with the flaying.
- I hurt so many people.
- It was the power.
But I am the power. It's in me.
Did I mention
the random destruction of property?
- The Magic Box is not so much a box now.
- The power is bigger than you are.
- I know, but...
- Things are more clear where Tara is.
Where we are.
We can see your path, and you have to stop.
You can't use magic again, not ever.
Black magic, of course.
But Giles says it isn't as simple
as quitting it all, cold turkey.
It's too dangerous. You can't
take the chance that you'll lose control.
I don't want to. I can't.
- I never wanna cause that kind of pain.
- Of course you don't.
So, I won't.
I'm gonna be OK.
She says...
What?
You're not gonna be OK.
You're gonna kill everybody.
- We almost got this thing uncovered.
- Yep.
I hope Buffy'll know how to destroy it.
36-19-27. That's it!
That was my locker combination.
It's been bugging me all night.
I spent years
trying to forget about high school.
- Why are you trying so hard to remember it?
- I guess I miss it. Don't you?
- Yeah, I really miss it(!)
- I'm serious. I really miss it.
Time goes by and everything drops away.
All the cruelty, all the pain,
all the humiliation.
It all washes away.
I miss my friends. I miss my enemies.
I miss the people I talked to every day.
I miss the people who never knew I existed.
I miss 'em all.
I wanna talk to them, you know?
I wanna find out how they're doing.
I wanna know what's going on in their lives.
You know what? They don't wanna talk to
you - all those people you just mentioned.
Not one of them is sitting around going
"I wonder what Jonathan's up to right now."
Not one of them cares about you.
Well, I still care about them.
That's why I'm here.
- (growling)
- (Dawn) I know you're there.
I will cast you out.
My mother needs to talk to me.
(growling continues)
I cast you from this place.
It is your poison and your bane.
(beastly growling)
- It is the skin that is cut from your flesh!
- (growling continues)
Aargh!
And the joke is, he loved me.
I mean, in his own sick, soulless way
he really did care for me.
But I didn't wanna be loved.
Didn't you?
I have all this power.
I didn't ask for it.
I don't deserve it.
It's like... I wanted to be punished.
I wanted to hurt like I thought I deserved.
I sorta think...
You know, this is complicated.
If you'd rather just fight...
Tell me.
I feel like I'm worse than anyone.
Honestly, I'm beneath them.
My friends, my boyfriends -
I... feel like I'm not worthy of their love.
Cos even though they love me,
it doesn't mean anything
because their opinions don't matter.
They don't know.
They haven't been through
what I've been through.
They're not the Slayer.
I am.
Sometimes I feel...
This is awful.
I feel like I'm better than them.
Superior.
Until you can't win.
And I thought I was diabolical.
Or at least I plan to be.
You do have a superiority complex. And
you've got an inferiority complex about it.
Kudos.
It doesn't make any sense.
Oh... it makes every kind of sense.
And it all adds up to you feeling alone.
But, Buffy, everybody feels alone.
Everybody is. Until you die.
Speaking of...
you ready for our little death match?
I suppose.
Uh... thanks for listening.
Oh, you know, there's some things
you can only tell a stranger.
You're not a stranger.
- That stuff with Spike is pretty...
- Hold it.
- What?
- Did you say Spike?
I cast you out with every prayer
from every god that walks the Earth
or crawls beneath.
I cast you out
with the strength of those who love me.
with the strength I have inside me!
I cast you out into the void!
- (beastly groans)
- Die, you bastard!
(noise and wind stop)
Mom?
- I'm gonna what?
- That's why I came. We needed to warn you.
You saw my path?
What do you know?
What did you see?
- You don't wanna know what we saw.
- Oh, God!
But if you stop - completely, no more magic...
Right. Right, stop.
What about Giles?
He made it seem like it was just as dangerous
for me to quit completely.
You can't. If you do
so much as another spell...
I tried to stop. I tried.
- What if I can't do this?
- Don't think that way.
How can I not?! You're telling me
I'm gonna murder all my friends.
I'm not strong.
I'm not an Amazon. I'm just me.
There is one thing.
- One thing you could do to stop it.
- What? Anything.
Then you could see her.
You wouldn't have to talk through me.
- Tara?
- That's what you want, isn't it?
- Of course.
- So go. Be with her.
Everybody will be safe,
and you'll be together again.
It's not that bad.
Really.
It's just like going to sleep.
Who are you?
What do you mean?
How do you know Spike?
What do you mean, how?
He was the guy that...
- Oh, what's the word?
- Sired.
Yeah, he was the guy that sired me.
Things are coming, Dawn.
Listen, things are on their way.
I love you and I love Buffy.
But she won't be there for you.
What?
- Why are you...
- When it's bad, Buffy won't choose you.
She'll be against you.
No!
No, don't go!
Please, don't go!
The suicide thing was too far, huh?
- Hm. You seemed so ripe.
- Tell me who you are.
I stand by my opinion. The world'd be a better
place if you took a razor blade to your wrist.
Stop.
I can see it now.
Candlelight, the Indigo Girls playing, picture
of your dead girlfriend on your bloody lap.
- Stop it.
- "Oh, baby, you left such a big hole!"
"It hurts so bad!"
This last year will seem like cake after
what I put you and your friends through,
and I am not a fan of easy death.
The whole good-versus-evil,
balancing-the-scales thing? I'm over it.
I'm done with the mortal coil.
But believe me, I'm going for a big finish.
From beneath you, it devours.
Oh, not it.
Me.
(# "Blue" by Angie Hart)
# I fell into the moon
# And it covered you in blue
# Can I make it right?
# Can I spend the night
# Alone?
Visiontext Subtitles: Claire Bates
Urgh! Argh!
ENGLISH SDH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org