Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
That's right. Big boy.
Come and get it.
I got him! Go!
Any time now...
He's getting away!
And... ow.
That really never works.
Are you guys all right?
First of all. What was
with the acrobatics?
How did that happen?
Wasn't Andy Hoelich
on the gymnastics team?
That's right. He was.
Cheater!
OK. And the second problem
I'm having...
"Come and get it. Big boy"?
Well...
Well. The slayer
always says a pun
or a witty play on words.
And I think it throws
the vampires off
and it makes them frightened
because I'm wisecracking.
OK. I didn't really have
a chance to work on that one.
but you try it every time.
Uh. If I may suggest...
"This time it's personal."
I mean. There's a reason
why it's a classic.
I've always been amazed
with how Buffy fought. But...
in a way. I feel like
we took her punning for granted.
Xander. Past tense rule.
Oh. Sorry. I just meant we
in the past took it for granted
and. Uh. We won't
when she gets back.
Do you think Buffy knows
school's starting tomorrow?
Tomorrow.
Right.
Big day.
Oh. I'm gonna be busy a lot.
but. But only till 3:00.
and that's when
you usually get up.
I can't wait to see Cordelia.
I can't believe
I wonder what our first
homework assignment's gonna be.
Hey. You're excited
over Cordelia. OK?
We've all got issues.
I guess we should pack it in.
Yeah.
Wouldn't it be great if Buffy
just showed up tomorrow?
Like nothing happened?
She just can't show up.
she got kicked out.
Well. Yeah. I know.
I just wish...
I wish we knew where she was.
How did you find me here?
If I was blind.
I would see you.
Stay with me.
Forever.
That's the whole point.
I'll never leave.
Not even if you kill me.
Anything else?
That'll do us. Peaches.
Pay at the counter.
Sure you don't want me
to work it off for you?
Ha ha ha ha.
You guys ready?
Yeah. I think we're good.
Um..."Anne."
What'll you have?
Well. OK... what can
we get with this?
Um...
Can we get cake?
Don't be stupid.
We gotta eat healthy.
We can't have cake.
Can we get pie?
We've got a peach pie.
I can't guarantee
there's a peach in it.
We shouldn't have
blown all our money.
Come on. It was worth it.
Hey. Check this out.
It's nice.
It's nice and. Uh. Permanent.
Yeah. Forever.
I mean. That's
the whole point.
Hey. Do I know you?
I don't think so.
Really? Where are you from?
I'll get your pie.
I'm not feeling great.
Do you think you
can cover for me?
Sure. Okay.
So. No joy at the cemetery?
No. He got away.
We still have some
glitches in the system.
like...
vampires getting away.
But I think we're improving.
For God's sake be careful.
I mean. Uh.
I appreciate your efforts
to keep the vampire population down
until Buffy returns.
but. Uh. Well. If anything
should happen to you...
you should be killed.
I should take it somewhat amiss.
You'd be cranky?
Entirely.
Well. We try not to get killed.
That's part of our whole
mission statement.
"Don't get killed."
Good.
I think you're going
to love that one.
- Hi.
- Hey. Willow.
How was your summer?
Oh. I can't believe
you brought that up.
Las Palmas was
the nightmare resort.
They order you around and
make you have organized "fun."
and I use sarcastic quote marks.
Plus the fact there are
cockroaches in Mexico
big enough to own property.
It was all about dread.
How was your summer?
Oh. It was OK.
Is Xander around?
Well. Uh. Yeah. Somewhere.
Good. Great.
I haven't seen him yet.
Do I look OK?
- Oh. Yeah.
- How's my hair?
Uh. It's good.
He didn't meet anybody
over the summer. Did he?
No. Who's he gonna meet
in Sunnydale.
but monsters and stuff?
But then again he's always
been attracted to monsters.
How's my hair?
Still good.
Hi.
Maybe he's forgotten me.
Well. I'll just
have to make him remember.
See ya.
You came to visit me.
You came with books?
Are they books for me?
Actually. They're kind of for me.
I don't get it.
Well. It's sort of a funny story.
You remember when I didn't graduate?
Well. I know you had
a lot of incompletes.
but that's what
summer school was for.
Yeah. Remember when I didn't go?
Whoa. Slow down. People.
Summer is over.
Be somber.
But you never said anything.
How am I supposed to react
to this rather alarming news?
Well. Actually. I was pretty much
banking on you finding it cute.
Traditionally. You know. Repeating
a grade isn't exactly a turn-on.
And-And you're
practically a genius.
You're Mr. Test Scores.
It's all a little weird.
So the cute thing is out?
Have you guys seen Cordelia?
Yeah. She's around here somewhere.
I don't want to
come on too geeky.
But. Uh. OK. I'm psyched.
There's gonna be some heat.
if you know what I mean.
So you guys might want
to duck and cover.
And I'm starting to be geeky.
OK. Bye.
- How's my...
- Your hair is fine.
Cool.
This is our year.
I'm telling you.
Best football season ever.
I'm so in shape. I'm a rock.
It's all about egg whites.
If we can focus.
keep discipline.
and not have quite
as many mysterious deaths.
Sunnydale is gonna rule!
I'm trying to get
to cute. Really.
But I'm still sorta
stuck on "strange."
Well. I'd be willing
to bargain down to "eccentric"
with an option on "cool."
- Hey.
Good summer?
It was all right.
Cool.
Yeah.
Well. I'll see ya.
Yeah. Whatever.
I'm no one.
Yes? Thank you. Thank you.
I have a lead.
A friend in Oakland
has a sketchy report
of a young girl
fending off a group
of vampires about a week ago.
There's a plane out
in about an hour.
And what makes this different
from the last 9 leads?
Well. I believe there's
a meal on this flight.
Look. I don't mean
to poop the party here.
it's just. You get
your hopes all up.
and then it's just a big fat
raspberry. And I feel bad.
But it's good that
you're looking. Though.
You shouldn't give up.
Oh. Yeah. Definitely.
Yes. One must try.
Well. I should go.
You don't think
maybe he'll find her?
I think he'll find her
when she wants to be found.
Anne?
Buffy?
Don't be mad.
I won't turn you in or nothing.
I guess you don't recognize me.
Lily?
I mean from before.
I was calling myself
Chantarelle then.
I used to...
Well. I was in this cult
that worshipped vampires.
So lame. I know.
Yeah...
I. Uh. I remember.
But you kinda saved us.
I never thanked you or anything.
Did you tell anyone who I was?
Oh. No.
Not even Rickie.
I mean. I was so surprised
to see you here.
waiting tables...
But I wouldn't tell.
I know how it is
when you gotta get lost.
Do you. Uh...
Do you live nearby?
Well. There's
a couple of places.
Uh. They're abandoned. And
a lot of people stay there.
So how come you
came up with Anne?
It's my middle name.
Lily's from a song.
Rickie picked it.
I'm always changing anyway.
Chantarelle was part
of my exotic phase.
It's nice.
It's a mushroom.
It is?
That's really embarrassing.
Um. Well. It's
an exotic mushroom.
if that's any comfort.
Well. Before that. I was
following this loser preacher
and calling myself
Sister Sunshine.
What do they
call you at home?
I like Lily.
It's cool for now.
Hey. Do you have any money?
I didn't mean that like...
Well. I just mean.
I know this guy.
he's gonna have this kinda
rave thing in his basement.
We could go.
I mean. I could show you
if you had...
'Cause I'm broke.
I don't think so.
I just kind of...
I want to be alone.
I didn't mean to bug you.
No. I didn't mean
that. It's just...
A lot of people like that...
It's too much.
I do have the money.
though. So.
why don't you and Rickie go.
and then maybe
I could meet you...
No. It's OK.
Forget about it.
That's not very polite.
Are you OK?
I'm no one.
Geez. I didn't see you.
Maybe you shouldn't move.
Maybe you should lie down.
Somebody call an ambulance!
No! I'm OK. I just...
I need to go.
Whoa.
Oh.
where are you running to?
Sorry.
Maybe I should ask.
where are you running from?
You're pretty new around here.
You've got the look. Though.
The look?
Like you had to grow up
way too fast.
What's your name?
Hey. Um. I'm Ken.
Here. Go ahead.
take one of these.
Don't be shy
about stopping by.
I guess you're not
starving. But...
we're not just interested
in feeding the body.
You might find something
you're missing.
I'm all right.
Then why are you here?
This is not a good place
for a kid to be.
You get old fast here.
The thing that drains
the life out of them is despair.
I mean. Kids come here. And
they got nothing to go home to.
This ends up being
the last stop for a lot of them.
Shouldn't have to be that way.
Ooh-ooh-ooh
On my way to freedom
I ask myself
Why did I come here?
To find my
Own way to freedom
And a change is gonna come
- I'm gonna find my way
- Find my way
Find my way back to freedom
- Gonna find my way
- Find my way
Find my way
Find my way back to freedom
Boy. I'm glad we showed up
for "Depressing Night."
I wonder what she's
doing right now.
Oh. I know what she's doing.
Gabbing to all of her friends
about her passionate affair
with Pedro the cabana boy
laughing about me thinking
how she still might have
feelings about me.
Oh. It's possible you were
talking about Buffy.
It's possible.
The Bronze just never
seems the same without her.
And the slaying isn't
getting any easier. Either.
I don't know. I think we're
kinda getting a rhythm down.
We're losing half the vamps.
Yeah. But. Rhythmically.
We just need to work
on our timing. I think.
No. I know what we need.
A vampire slayer?
Next best thing.
Bait.
[Knock On Door]
Uh. Hello.
Hello. Um. May I...
Oh. Uh. Of course.
Come on in.
I've just come back from Oakland.
A friend of mine
called with a lead.
Stories about someone
fighting vampires.
It didn't pan out.
I'm afraid.
No Buffy.
No vampires.
Bunch of schoolkids
in heavy mascara
listening to extremely
silly music.
Well. Thank you for going.
I can hardly...
I can hardly leave the house.
I'm just afraid she'll call
and she'll need my help.
Buffy is the most capable
child I've ever known.
I mean. She may be
confused. Unhappy.
but I honestly believe
she's in no danger.
I just wish
I could talk to her.
The last thing
we did was fight.
Joyce. You mustn't blame
yourself for her leaving.
I don't.
I blame you.
You've been this huge
influence on her. Guiding her.
You had this whole relationship
with her behind my back.
I feel like you've
taken her away from me.
I didn't make Buffy
who she is.
And who exactly is she?
Buff... Uh. Anne?
Can I talk to you?
Look. This really isn't
a good time. Can it wait?
Rickie's gone.
I haven't seen him
for more than a day.
I... He's never left
for that long.
I think something's...
happened.
Maybe something's happened.
Well. Did you call the police?
[Sighs]
Rickie skipped out on his parole.
They would just cause
more trouble.
I don't know.
did you ask around?
Can you help me?
Uh. I can't.
But that's who you are
and stuff. Right?
I mean. You help people.
and. You know...
I can't get into this.
I'm sorry. Lily.
You know how to do stuff.
I don't. Not anymore.
But... I don't know
what to do.
We gave blood lots of times
'cause you get a few bucks
and they have cookies.
You're a fan of the sugar rush?
It's nice.
Hi. Are you here to donate blood?
Uh. We're looking for a friend.
Rickie T.?
We come in sometimes.
Rickie. Sure.
Uh. He's not here.
Well. Do you know if he's
been in the last day or so?
Let me check the sheet.
This'll probably go
faster if we split up.
Can I come with you?
OK. Where did I lose you
on the whole splitting up thing?
Oh. Sorry.
I was thinking we could check out
some of your hangouts
and then. I guess.
meet later at my place.
OK.
Sorry. Guys.
He hasn't been here.
Thanks.
I'll tell him you were looking.
Great.
Rickie?
Did you find Rickie?
I thought of...
Well. He likes to go
to this movie house.
you can get in
around the back...
Lily...
I think he's dead.
But...
he takes care of me.
I'm sorry.
We're gonna get a place.
His cousin can get him
a job at the car wash.
Lily. There's...
there's something else.
The person that I found...
was old.
He looked about 80.
Well. That's not Rickie.
I'm sure it was.
I don't know how. But...
it was like something
drained the life out of him.
Do you mean like a vampire?
No.
A vampire couldn't accelerate
the aging process.
Maybe it was something
in his blood.
When was the last time
you guys gave blood together?
I don't understand.
Maybe it's not Rickie. OK?
Lily. This is something you're
just gonna have to deal with.
But he didn't do anything wrong.
why would this happen to him?
That's not the point.
These things happen all the time.
You can't just...
close your eyes
and hope that they're
gonna go away.
Is it 'cause of you?
What?
You know about monsters
and stuff.
You could have brought
this with you.
I didn't bring
anything with me.
And I didn't ask for you
to come to me with your problems.
I just wanted to be left alone.
If you can't deal.
then don't lay it off on me.
Are you OK?
Hey. It's OK.
Maybe I can help.
You can't.
Look. I know you all think
I'm a big square
handing out leaflets
about hope.
But hope is a real thing.
just like despair.
Hope can fill up the part
of you that's missing.
But Rickie...
Rickie?
Say. Are you Lily?
Right. He was
talking about you.
You've seen Rickie?
Oh. Sure.
Rickie's with us now.
She said he was dead.
Well. Someone's sure
handed you a tall tale.
Rickie's no more dead
than I am.
Why don't you come
to Family Home?
We'll get you taken care of.
Candidate for what?
What are you doing?
Breaking into your office and
going through your private files.
Candidate for what?
I'm calling the police.
Now. You've got a whole bunch
of candidates here.
I wonder if any of them
are missing like Rickie.
Gosh. I bet they are.
You're getting yourself
in a lot of trouble.
I don't want any trouble.
I just want to be alone
and quiet in a room
with a chair and a fireplace
and a tea cozy.
I don't even know what
a tea cozy is. But I want one.
Instead. I keep
getting trouble.
which I am more than
willing to share.
What are you doing
with these kids?
Nothing.
I just...
I give him the names
of the healthy ones.
Give them to who?
Well...
don't you look nice?
I guess.
Well. You don't want to wear
your own outfit to the cleansing.
It'll get soaked.
A cleansing is
like a baptism? Right?
Not quite the same.
Will I see Rickie after?
Oh. Of course.
He's waiting for you.
He's very excited.
Cordelia:
Why do I have to be bait?
I'm always bait.
Why can't Willow be bait?
He's already seen Willow.
And could you complain louder
so all the vampires leave?
I think this is a good spot.
Is everybody packin'?
Let's do it.
I'm doing this
for Buffy's sake.
This has nothing to do with you.
Yeah. Like I needed
that cleared up.
Go away.
This is my hiding spot.
Where do I hide?
You don't hide.
You're bait.
Go act baity.
What's the plan?
The vampire attacks you.
And then what?
The vampire kills you.
We watch. We rejoice.
Cordelia:
Everything's a joke with you.
Xander:
No. Just our relationship.
What relationship?
Right. I forgot.
We actually want
to bury that piece
of the past. Don't we?
We come to this station
to wash away the past.
Go ahead. Kneel.
We let the water
run over the sin
and the pain
and the uncertainty.
It looks kinda... dirty.
Yeah.
Buffy:
You know. I just...
I woke up.
and I looked in the mirror.
and I thought.
hey. What's with all the sin?
I need to change.
I'm...
I'm dirty.
I'm bad with the...
sex and the envy
and that loud music
us kids listen to nowadays.
Uh...
Oh. I just suck at undercover.
Where's Ken?
This is a private moment.
If you could just...
How do you make 'em old. Ken?
Do you feed on youth?
What's the deal?
Do you really wanna know?
What's going on?
Aaaaah!
Unh! Ohh...
Oh! Unh!
Ohh...
Ken: Oh. My face.
Ow! My face!
Do you have any idea
how hard it is
to glue that thing on?!
Guards!
[Heavy Blows.
Metal Striking Metal]
[People Groaning]
Welcome to my world.
I hope you like it.
You're never leaving.
Let me ask... How long did it
take you to forget me?
Were you still taxiing
down the runway.
or was it actually
in the cab?
Oh. Yeah! Mr. Faithful?!
You probably met up with some
hot little Inca mummy girl.
Yeah. I heard about her.
[Willow Struggling]
Aah! Help!
Aah!
Xander!
Oh. Unh...
Lily...
Always knew
I would come here...
sooner or later.
I knew I belonged here.
Where?
Hell.
This isn't hell.
Isn't it?
Unh...
What is hell
but the total
absence of hope?
The substance.
the tactile proof of despair.
You're right. Lily.
This is where you've
been heading all your life.
Just like Rickie.
Rickie...
He forgot you.
Well. It took him a long time.
He remembered your name
years after he'd
forgotten his own.
But in the end...
Years?
But...
Oh. Interesting thing...
Time moves more quickly here
than in your reality.
A hundred long years
will pass here.
On Earth...
it's just a day.
So you just work us till we're
too old and spit us back out.
That's the plan.
See. Lily.
you'll die of old age
before anyone wonders where
you went. Not that anyone will.
That's why we chose you.
You didn't choose me.
No.
But...
I know you...
Anne. Heh.
So afraid.
So pathetically
determined to run away
from whatever it is
you used to be.
to disappear.
Congratulations.
You got your wish.
Guard: You work...
and you live.
That is all.
You do not complain or laugh
or do anything besides work.
Whatever you thought.
whatever you were
does not matter.
You are no one now.
You mean nothing.
Who are you?
Aaron.
No one.
Who are you?
I'm Buffy.
The vampire slayer.
And you are...?
Raaagghh!
Anyone who's not
having fun here.
follow me.
Buffy: There's no way we can get back
up there without meeting new people.
OK. Lily.
when those guards leave.
and they will leave.
I want you to take these people
and get them up there. OK?
Fast and quiet.
You're leaving me? But...
Lily...
you can handle this.
'Cause I say so.
We've gone public.
Quick. Get them up. Go! Quiet!
I'm sorry I said
this was your fault before.
Lily. This can wait.
Well. In case we die...
Go! Go!
Come on. Come on!
Everybody go! Run!
Humans don't fight back.
[Enraged]
Humans don't fight back!
That's how this works!
Get down there!
[Gasps]
[Whimpering]
Ken: One of you fights...
and you all die!
That...
was not...
permitted.
Yeah. But it was fun.
You've got guts.
I think I'd like to slice you open
and play with them.
Let everyone know!
This is the price
of rebellio...
Aaagh!
They'll be coming.
Unh! Unh!
OK...
this works...
the abs...
and the glutes. Unh!
Ohh. I'm gonna feel this
for a week.
Raaagghh!
Aah-aah-aaaah!
Yaaaaggghhh!
You've ruined...
You've...
Hey. Ken.
wanna see my impression
of Gandhi?
Gandhi?
Well. You know.
if he was really pissed off.
Ooh!
What do we do about...?
Let me give you the tour.
This concludes our tour.
It's really nice.
All the rent's paid up
for the next 3 weeks.
I spoke to Mitch at the diner.
He said you can start
on Thursday.
He's. Uh...
He's kind of... repulsive.
but. Uh. He won't give you
a hard time.
Um...
I'll call and
check up on you.
I'm not...
great at taking
care of myself.
Gets easier.
Takes practice.
Hey...
Can I be "Anne"?
[Knock At Door]
Grrr! Arrggh!
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org