Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
(Xander) You killed your best friend.
lt didn't work cos there wasn't enough blood.
Maybe that's what the First needed Spike for.
- We don't have time to baby-sit a hostage.
- l'll be good.
Somebody left this in the courtyard.
l was just returning it.
- That's some full-service principalling.
- l try.
Agh!
There must be a reason
why the chip is going wonky.
His chip. We can either repair it...
or remove it.
Robson!
Robson blacked out, but the last thing he
remembers is Giles's head about to be axed.
lt's started....
l understand. l'll take care...
lt was extraordinary good luck, of course.
And training - years of training.
Chao-Ahn, keep up.
You're new here, Chao-Ahn.
Take note. Remember about training.
But l honestly feel the largest part of it
was instinct. lnstinct and reflexes.
There's a sort of wary watchfulness
l developed over the years.
lt's like another sense.
Spike!
- Hey! You're not in pain.
- Hey! You're not the First.
- What?
- Anya said you were the First. You were evil.
You're supposed to be all go-throughable.
Then what did you tackle me for, you berk?
What's that supposed to do?
l didn't think of that.
More importantly, you just hit me.
Why didn't your chip go off?
Yeah, well...
Well, when we were at the lnitiative...
- There was a choice.
- Right. Either repair the chip, or remove it.
You had it remov... You removed the chip?
Yeah.
- (Spike) Had to make a choice.
- lt really is OK.
- What's a chip?
- They removed the chip?
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
- You know this is very dangerous.
- You just heard the horror stories.
Wear hoops, they'll catch, rip your lobe off.
Lobes flying everywhere.
That's not what l'm talking about.
You mean Spike not having a chip.
Free-range Spike.
l have to ask. Why on earth
did you make that decision?
l guess it was instinct,
like you were talking about.
l made that up!
l knew the Bringer was there
because his shoes squeaked.
Buffy, it's crucial
that we keep these girls safe.
l can't count the dangers.
The First, the Bringers,
random demons, and now Spike.
- And the principal.
- What?
Oh, nothing much. He was in
the school basement, holding a shovel,
acting evasive.
Plus, he's got that whole
"too charming to be real" thing going on.
- l'm looking into it.
- Well, that sounds very responsible of you.
Balances out
the "vampire on the loose" issue.
Nothing's changed, Giles.
Spike had a chip before, remember?
When the First had him kill
and sire all those people.
We have no idea if his chip was working then.
A new chip might restrain him should
the First attempt to activate him again.
Spike has a soul now. That's what's
gonna stop him from hurting people.
- Buffy...
- He can be a good man, Giles. l feel it.
But he's never gonna get there
if we don't give him the chance.
Buffy, l want more for you.
Your feelings for him are colouring
yourjudgment. l can hear it in your voice.
That way lies a future filled with pain.
l don't want that for you.
We haven't...
Things are different since he came back.
lt doesn't matter if you're not physical with
each other any more. There's a connection.
You rely on him, he relies on you.
That's what's affecting yourjudgment.
You think l'm losing sight
of the big picture, but l'm not.
When Spike had that chip, it was like
having him in a muzzle. lt was wrong.
You can't beat evil by doing evil. l know that.
Well, l hope you're right.
You're gambling with a lot of lives.
Hi, can l help? You seem kinda confused.
- You aren't wearing a green apron.
- Confused, but sort of randomly observant.
Sorry, l just mean...
you don't work here, right?
No. Right. Just helpful.
- l'm Xander.
- Lissa.
And l guess l could use some advice.
- l can't tell if l've got the right rope.
- That depends what it's for.
Something functional around the house,
or, you know, recreational.
By which l mean, for example,
boating or mountain climbing.
Not for tying someone up for sexy, funky fun.
ln conclusion, rope can be
useful in various ways.
- l have a kayak.
- Again with the random. l like it.
Sorry. l need to store my kayak.
So l was thinking maybe l could suspend it
from the ceiling in the garage
- with ropes and a pulley, or a winch thing.
- Not a bad plan.
You'll need stronger rope.
Wanna have coffee with me later?
What?
Oh, you're the only one
that gets to be random?
Now, if l were a sign of being evil,
where would l... be?
- Buffy?
- Oh, Principal Wood. lt's you.
- You looking for something?
- File folders. And mechanical pencils.
l wanna write on a file folder
with a mechanical pencil.
The supply cabinet
in the outer office has those things.
Oh, this isn't a supply cabinet? My bad.
OK. Thanks.
- Hey, Buffy...
- Yeah?
Um... What are you doing tonight?
Preparing for tomorrow's
counselling sessions.
No, really.
Watching a reality show about a millionaire.
Well, then... l'd like to take you out to dinner,
if that's all right with you.
l mean, you don't have to. l'm not saying
come to dinner if you enjoy having a job.
l may have to make up a document saying
l didn'tjust say that and have you sign it.
Sure. l'd be happy to have dinner with you.
Great. l'll draw up the paperwork.
- So he asked you out to dinner?
- Yeah.
lsn't that weird? He's a principal.
He's a young, hot principal with earrings,
but he's a principal.
Why do you think he asked me out?
He could be interested, right?
Yeah, sure. You're a frisky vixen.
Or it could be work-related.
Maybe l'm getting promoted
for doing such a good job.
Oh, right. That makes sense too.
Or maybe he knows that l suspect he's
up to something and he's going to kill me.
Well, you'll have to dress for the ambiguity.
He's not even acting that suspicious.
lt's just - there he is.
On the Hellmouth. All day, every day.
That's gotta be like being showered
with evil. Only from underneath.
- Not really a shower.
- A bidet. Like a bidet of evil.
Buff, if he's really interested,
are you interested back?
l don't know.
He's good-looking, and he's solid.
He's smart. He's normal.
So, not the wicked energy, which is nice.
l don't want to only be
attracted to wicked energy.
Or what if he is wicked?
ls that why l'm attracted to him?
l'm gonna wait for that sentence
to come around again before l jump on.
You know what? Yeah, l think l like him.
- And he'd be good for me.
- Right. Help you move on.
Why does everybody in this house
think l'm still in love with Spike?
No, l meant move on from
this imposed super-self-reliance.
Let somebody get close.
Oh.
- Hey, someone's here.
- Guys, guess what?
- Buffy got a date!
- No, l did.
- Fine way to steal my thunder.
- Sorry.
lt's Principal Wood,
and l think he's aligned with the First.
- Also, like, ten years older than you.
- Which is 100 years younger than your type!
Yay. Someone who doesn't remember
the lndustrial Revolution.
l think they'll end up making out.
"Oh, Principal Wood," she'll gasp,
"l love your lack of wicked energy."
Watch it, or you can talk
about your new girlfriend
who you hold hands with
under the dinner table.
ls yours evil, Xander?
Well, there's a good chance,
but l'm hoping for the best.
We're going for coffee. She has a kayak...
Dear lord, l hate that mall.
The shop assistants are rude,
and everything in the food court is sticky.
- Looks like you found her some stuff.
- Oh, hello. Yes.
That's gotta be rough.
Getting pulled out of your home,
being told you're a potential slayer
and not to bring anything.
Yes, and the language barrier is formidable.
l was concerned that
my Mandarin is a little thin.
As it turns out, she speaks Cantonese,
which is thinner.
But we muddled through and, as l suspected,
ice cream is a universal language.
What'd she say?
She's grateful to be in a land of plenty.
Let's... go and put away your new clothes.
Will, you think you can do
a computer check on Principal Wood?
Yeah, sure. Want me to check
your girl out too, Xand?
Nope. l'm goin' in blind.
l'm gonna be an optimist about this.
Why go looking for trouble?
lf it's gonna find you, it's gonna find you.
"Getting the most out of
your new microwave." Nice.
"Clock comma setting the - page 3."
You don't need a manual, it's intuitive.
There's a button marked "Clock set",
for pity's sake. What kind of a nerd are you?
- No wonder you crashed yourjet pack.
- No... Get thee behind me.
l rebuke thee.
Take that, the First!
Look, you monkey.
Ooh! Ahh! lt burns
as it ineffectually passes through me.
l'm not corporeal, remember.
Also, not a vampire, so... a cross?
What do you want from me,
Jonathan slash the First?
- l have an assignment for you.
- l follow Buffy's orders now.
l'm redeeming myself for... killing you.
l mean, for... killing Jonathan.
Really? Why? So you can earn
a spot on her little pep squad?
You think she'll ever let you in?
You're a murderer.
Confidentially, a lot of her people
are murderers - Anya and Willow and Spike.
lnteresting. And you're the only one
she makes seek redemption.
- Does that seem fair to you?
- l guess not.
You know we're headed
toward a fight, don't you?
Yeah.
What do you think the world's
gonna be like after that?
Newsflash - there's not gonna be
a slayer gang any more.
But there is going to be evil.
And as long as there is evil, l live.
And as long as l live,
you can dwell at my side.
That sounds nice.
Your assignment isn't hard. They're just girls.
- You want me to hurt the girls?
- No, not all of them.
Not Dawn, not Anya, not Willow,
and not your friend Buffy.
Just the potential slayers.
That's... horrible.
l'm gonna scream and get Buffy in here.
She can't see me. l'm gonna keep talking till
you hear what l have to say, so listen up.
The girls must die.
l could never do that.
All those girls, all that blood.
l didn't like the stabbing before.
You don't have to stab. This'll be easy.
Andrew, l want you to think.
Willow brought something to this house -
something good, something you can use.
The new microwave?
The gun.
l want you to think hard.
Where did they put the gun?
Hmm.
l don't think it's really a date.
That's what l think.
Well, it is unclear.
That's why my top says l'm comfortable in
a stodgy office or a swinging casual setting.
Or killing you, if you're a demon.
lt also says "l sometimes
get blood on my shoulder."
Or it might be pizza.
- l don't think l can fix it.
- Thanks for trying.
l wasn't talking about your date. l was
talking about this sham date of Xander's.
- l think it's part of a plan to make me jealous.
- Well, it's not working.
Are you nuts? Of course it's working.
Observe my bitter ranting.
Hear the shrill edge of hysteria in my voice.
l should really go find
something else to wear.
Fine, go. Leave me here
to stew in my impotent rage.
l'm also gonna pee,
so you should probably go.
You look nice.
Oh, thanks. Traditionally,
one wears something over this.
- Heard you got a date.
- Well, it's unclear.
l have this whole theory
about a promotion. Or he's evil.
Buffy, l'm all right.
- You don't have to...
- What? Be noble?
l'm not. Really, l'm all right.
You think l still dream of a crypt for two
with a white picket fence?
- My eyes are clear.
- Good. l'm glad.
Thank you.
Never much cared for picket fences, anyway.
Bloody dangerous.
You should try this too.
The going out thing, l mean.
There's that girl you brought
to Anya and Xander's not-a-wedding.
Yeah. There's always girls who like the look.
Bad boy - does it for some of them.
Yeah, l can see that.
l should go. l don't wanna be late.
Lissa, hi! l was afraid you weren't coming.
You said 8.30. Did you think
l was gonna stand you up?
- Well, it would be kind of karmic.
- What?
Forget it. You're gonna love the coffee.
l got a redeye.
Black coffee with a shot of espresso.
- lt's kinda rough if you're not used to it...
- lt's hot cocoa.
Well, sometimes l don't sleep too good.
- l just lost macho points, didn't l?
- Who wants macho?
l like that you like hot cocoa. Redeye, please.
Sounded good.
Yeah.
Nothing? No records or certificates?
College transcripts?
The only stuff in the system
about Principal Robin Wood is super-recent.
Like, since he moved to Sunnydale.
l've Googled till l just can't
Google no more. He's not in there.
Well, that's suspicious.
Anya, calm down. They're educational.
What's this?
Giles made them for Chao-Ahn,
and she's locked herself in the bathroom.
The other girls are starting to complain.
Those are flash cards l made
to facilitate her training.
Chao-Ahn never had a watcher.
The language problem...
You showed her these?
l wanted her to understand
the seriousness of her situation.
Holy crap!
Perhaps l'll rethink the approach.
You wanna help us get researchy?
We're trying to invade Buffy's date's privacy.
- Buffy has a date?
- (Anya) Yes. Didn't you hear?
Everybody has a date.
Buffy has a date.
Willow's been making out with this girl...
Hey!
Xander's out with some hardware-store
whore. lt's Date-Fest 2003.
Actually, Buffy's investigating
Principal Wood. lt's not a date.
Really?
Might be a date.
For God's sake! How can anyone
think about their social life?
We are about to fight the original primal evil.
These girls are in mortal danger.
Didn't you see the flash cards?
This isn't right.
lt doesn't look promising,
but this place is great.
lt's the best-kept secret in town.
lt's right down this way.
Well, it is one of the nicer dark alleys.
l promise you, it's just a little bit further.
OK.
You set me up, you son of a...
What?
l guess we should talk.
The restaurant's right there.
- And you still have to see her every day?
- Yeah, but l guess that's good.
How is that good? lt seems like
she never lets you forget what happened.
Well, it's on her mind a lot right now,
because our anniversary's coming up...
lt would have been our anniversary.
And maybe l shouldn't
be allowed to forget it. l did...
lt was a bad thing, and it hurt her real bad.
And if you'd married her, even though
you had doubts, that would've been better?
l guess not.
Sounds to me like in the long run
you're both better off.
l know it turned out good for me,
and that's what really matters, right?
l should have taken you
on a nicer date than this.
Well, l can think of something fun to do.
Thank you.
This place is nice.
How the hell did you do that?
l've had some practice.
Never took on two at once,
but l have taken out
a few vamps and some demons.
- So, you're freelance?
- Hm...
l guess that's a good way to put it.
And you know who l am?
You're the Slayer.
Right. OK.
l'm guessing that you don't work
in an office 15 feet above the Hellmouth
because you enjoy
educational administration?
Well, l actually do enjoy the work,
but yeah, you're right.
l manoeuvred myself into that school,
that office, just like l manoeuvred you there.
The Hellmouth draws the bad things in close.
Now we're headed for something really big.
l need to be here when it happens.
l wanna help.
So, you didn't hire me
for my counselling skills?
They're valuable too.
- Why didn't you tell me about you?
- l wasn't sure about things yet.
- You didn't think you could trust me?
- No, no.
l wasn't sure l was ready yet,
ready to jump into this fight.
And now you are?
Now the fight is starting, or starting to start.
l don't have time to worry any more.
l have to do something.
So, you knew who l was
before you even came here.
Yes.
How? How do you know about slayers?
Right. OK.
When l was a little boy, my mother was one.
The one, actually. The Slayer.
Your mother...
Wow, l didn't know
that any slayers had children.
l don't know of any others.
She was killed when l was four.
l still remember her, but it's a little... fuzzy.
- Something got her? A demon...?
- A vampire.
l went through this whole "avenging son"
phase in my 20s, but l never found him.
Now l just dust as many as l can find.
l figure eventually l'll get him.
That's probably why we gotjumped outside.
l'm not very popular with vampires
and l bet you aren't either.
No. Not most of 'em.
So, do you have any slayer powers?
l'm sorry...
l'm just so floored.
l have no idea what to ask.
No, l don't have powers.
No super-strength or mythic responsibilities.
l'm just a guy with a few skills, because
her watcher took me in and raised me.
So... you decided to tell me?
That's right.
ln a darkened, little,
romantic French restaurant?
Um... yeah.
l'm not really sure
how that happened, but yeah.
- Did you find the gun?
- Yes, it was in Buffy's underwear drawer.
- She has nice things.
- Show me.
l didn't take 'em, but there were
thongs and regular underpants...
- Show me the gun.
- Yeah.
Here.
Willow tried shooting Kennedy with that.
Great. There's gonna be panic
and fleeing when you start firing,
so you're gonna have to
get 'em trapped someplace.
And we're killing them because...?
Because they're the future of the slayer line.
When they're gone, the line is gone.
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
Why not have Spike do it?
He's the one with the trigger.
lt's not time for him yet.
Wait till they're training in the basement,
but don't rely on a locked door
to keep them in. You'll need more.
OK.
Say...
do you have any weaknesses l should
know about if l'm gonna work for you,
like Kryptonite or allergies?
- What are you asking?
- Oh, nothing...
Are you made out
of the evil impulses of humans,
so if everyone was unconscious
at the same time, you would fade away?
You're asking a lot of questions.
Yes, well...
l... Because...
Because l'm evil,
and l wanna do the best l can at that.
So l wanna... know stuff, like when...
When do we kill Buffy?
Are you wearing a wire?
Will, what's going on?
You think you can trick the First?
You think you could squirm free?
l hold you, Andrew. l made you do this.
Jonathan suffered.
He was your friend, and he trusted you,
and now he spends eternity in pain
because of what you did.
- No. What's happening to you?
- This is what you did to him.
Took away everything he was
and left him like this.
You started down a road with that action.
You have to keep going.
Stop looking like Jonathan. You're not him.
You're the First, and you're trying to get me
to shoot innocent girls, but l won't do it.
l'm good now.
When the fight is over,
l'm gonna pay for killing Jonathan.
You're gonna pay for more than that.
You know why?
Because the biggest, baddest
First Evil in the world's angry with you.
- (Jonathan) You think this was smart?
- l'm hearing something.
You think you can trick me?
lt's not in the headphones. lt's out here.
You only hear what l want you to hear.
You only see what l want you to see.
Agh!
So many dead girls.
There'll be so many.
l knew it.
See? l knew it.
Thanks for your help.
The rope l picked wasn't strong enough.
That would've been bad.
Listen, is this because l'm friends with Buffy?
- Who's Buffy?
- The Slayer.
- You know the Slayer?
- This can'tjust happen.
lt can'tjust keep happening
that demon women find me attractive.
There's gotta be a reason.
You just seemed like a nice guy, that's all.
l wanted to get to know you.
- And kill me?
- Sure.
Do the ropes hurt?
- Yes.
- Good.
So, we're thinking it didn't go too well.
- You should've let me do this fast.
- No, l hate that.
Ow!
You tried to record the ultimate evil?
Why? ln a complex effort
to royally piss it off?
Guess we succeeded.
God, l never should have gone in wired.
Redemption is hard.
Getting back to Spike's question,
why did you try to record it?
Ooh!
To study it. To see if we could figure
something out from what it was saying.
Because, guys, we have to face it,
we know nothing about the First.
Owee! Ow, ow!
Well, we know not to record it.
That's something.
Why did it appear to him?
lt was supposed to be pulling my strings.
lt said it wasn't time for you yet. Ow!
l'm frightened. And my chest
hurts where the tape was.
lt's OK, Andrew. You did good.
You stood up to it. That's amazing.
Thank you. You're a peach.
- What did it want you to do, anyway?
- Shoot all the girls.
- Shoot girls?
- Not you, just the potentials.
Oh, well, that's something, anyway.
Something tragic.
This proves my point. This time is crucial.
We should be circling the wagons
instead of going out on dates
when gunplay is imminent.
Willow, call Buffy. Get her back here.
We need to dispose of the gun
and figure out our next move.
- l'll go get her.
- l'll call.
- (phone rings)
- (Amanda) Bet that's her.
- Sometimes you think of calling someone...
- No, it's a text message.
- Oh, it's from Xander. lt's one of our signals.
- Signals?
Yeah, the system we set up
a while back. Like, codes.
This one's either "l just got lucky,
don't call me for a while"
or "my date's a demon
who's trying to kill me."
- You don't remember which?
- lt was a long time ago.
- lf we play the percentages...
- Something's eating Xander's head.
- Say, that's gratifying.
- Buffy will know what to do.
- l'll go get her.
- That's OK.
- We don't even know where she went.
- (phone rings)
- That's not good.
- (Spike) l'll go get Buffy.
l can probably still track her scent.
She'll be worried about the boy.
Oh, my God! Mm.
Oh, my God. That might be the best thing
l've ever had in my mouth.
lsn't it good? They soak the pears in brandy.
Here. You need a bite with the sauce.
Mm.
- What are you doing here?
- ls there a problem?
lt's Xander.
Look, l know what happens
if that seal down there gets all excited.
l don't think you understand
what you're doing.
The seal opens, and a vicious
vampire creature comes out.
Then you do understand.
But what makes you think that's a good idea?
The end is coming, the final fight.
Everyone is hearing the drumbeat.
lt's telling us to pick our partners,
align ourselves with the good or the evil.
Argh!
Couldn't have done it without you, Xander.
Thanks for the great date.
- You sure he's in the high school?
- Willow did a locator spell. Useful stuff.
l'm not surprised.
That school's at the centre of everything.
- How much longer till we get there?
- Ten minutes.
- How do you two know each other?
- He works with me.
You know, in the struggle against evil.
Mm. Cool.
Xander!
Buffy!
He's a vampire.
(Xander) Oh, God, hurry!
Hey.
l think your friend's gonna be OK.
Hey, Xand. l'm here.
So, how's your date going?
Where are they? lt's after two.
l can't believe Buffy hasn't
brought him home yet. His slut ate him up.
His slut didn't eat him up.
Besides, l thought you were all angry at him.
- My feelings are changeable, but intense.
- (Andrew) l understand your fear, Anya.
l know fear myself cos, you know,
l enraged that primal force.
- They're not back yet?
- l'm worried. l think we should go find them.
Xander could be injured
or trapped or eaten up.
lt is late. A little reconnaissance
might be helpful.
She says she can't sleep.
l made myself some warm milk.
You can have it.
She's shy.
They're back! Oh, here they come.
- ls Xander all right?
- Looks OK.
Damn him!
- What happened?
- What do you think happened?
Another demon woman was attracted to me.
l've decided l'm turning gay.
Willow, gay me up.
- Come on, let's gay.
- What?
You heard me. Just tell me what to do.
l'm mentally undressing Scott Bakula
right now. That's a start, isn't it?
Captain Archer.
Let's get this gay show
on the gay road. Help me out.
What if you just start
attracting male demons?
- Clem liked you.
- lt would serve you right.
Children, enough.
- l need some stylish new clothes.
- Oh, enough!
Have you learned nothing
from tonight's assorted chaos?
There isn't time for fun and games
and quips about orientation.
These aren't a joke.
This... happens.
Girls are gonna die. We may die.
lt's time to get serious.
Did anybody tell you about
what happened around here tonight?
Willow did.
The First is back in the mix.
lt talked to the little boy.
Said it wasn't time for me yet.
l should move out.
Leave town... before it is time for me.
No. You have to stay.
- You've got another demon-fighter now.
- That's not why l need you here.
ls that right? Why's that, then?
Cos l'm not ready for you to not be here.
And the principal?
How's he fit in?
You look good.
You're not my mother.
l give you a compliment,
and you don't say thank you?
- Did l raise you that way?
- You didn't raise me at all.
Well, l was dead.
So you're the First.
Why are you here? Why now?
Cos you've been coming up in the world.
Taking the demons out.
lt makes a mother proud.
Yeah?
Well, think how pleased she'll be
when l help take you out.
Until it's time for that,
l've got no use for you.
Would you like to know who killed me?
- l know you went looking for him.
- You don't know anything.
ls that right?
Well, check it out after l tell you.
Check the timing.
Reread what the witnesses said,
and the people...
- Who is it?
- You met him.
You know him.
You fought at his side.
Spike.
Now, what do you say?
Thank you.
Visiontext Subtitles: Claire Bates
Urgh! Argh!
ENGLlSH SDH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org