Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
Whenever a slayer turns 18.
It's a time-honoured rite of passage.
It's an archaic exercise in cruelty.
- We're finished.
- Not quite. She passed. You didn't.
I have recommended to the Council that
you be relieved of your duties as Watcher.
You're fired.
- The Council's orders are to concentrate...
- I don't think I'm taking any more orders.
Tell your Council, until the next slayer comes
along, I'm not working for them any more.
- What about the Key? They all over it?
- They're interested.
But they didn't guess about Dawn?
They don't know that it's her?
No.
Here, I'll get that. Sorry.
Mom's still not 100 per cent
and I haven't been taking up the slack.
- No, the place looks fine, Buffy.
- Yeah, it's just us.
That must have belonged to...
Aren't we supposed to have a meeting?
Yes, we're here for a reason.
I've had some rather...
Well, I've had some news.
It seems that the Council of Watchers
has found some information
that may help us out.
- About Glory?
- Presumably.
We'll find out when they arrive.
Could be very important.
Arrive? They're coming here? Now?
Why do they have to come here?
Don't they have phones? "'AIIo, Buffy!
Here's some stuff we know, pip pip."
Yeah! Phones. I'd like them on phones.
What's so bad about them?
Aren't they good guys?
I mean, watchers,
that's like other Gileses, right?
Yeah, they're scary and horrible.
They can appear a bit... well, hard-nosed.
But their agenda is the same as ours.
They want to save the world and kill demons.
Kill the current demons, right?
Current demons.
Giles, I don't want them to come here.
I don't trust them. Make them not come here.
They're already on their way. Our old friend
Quentin Travers is heading up a delegation.
Their test almost killed me.
And when I was Faith,
they almost killed me again.
I can't handle almost being killed right now.
I don't like the sound of this.
They don't sound very ex-demon-compatible.
Are you sure they're English? I thought
they were gentler than normal people.
Maybe it won't be so bad this time. I mean,
Buffy, they did think you were Faith last time.
Now they know you're you,
maybe they won't care enough to kill you.
It's notjust that.
They're gonna screw everything up.
It's a delicate time right now.
I have to take care of Dawn, and...
But that's not new.
You've always taken care of her.
Right. Right, I know that.
It's just, you know, there's Glory.
I don't need them looking over my shoulder
when I don't know what we're dealing with.
That's precisely why we need to talk to them.
Dawn, honey, what are you doing
up at this hour? Go back to bed.
- I was just getting a snack.
- Dawn, are you listening?
I can get a snack if I want to.
- She was listening.
- Does it matter?
I mean, is she really gonna
set the junior high school buzzing
with "There's a delegation a-coming"?
No, I guess not. You know, it's just...
sometimes we say stuff, and... it's all good.
Giles, you were saying something?
Just that if the Council
knows something about Glory,
her agenda or her origins,
then maybe it will help us
get a grip on what we're dealing with.
Right now I think we're a bit lost.
Mistress!
Oh, God! Please don't hurt me, I beg of you!
If you just let me go,
I swear I won't tell anyone!
- Help her!
- We're here for you, Great One.
- Drink.
- What is this?
What the hell are you things doing to me?
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Very good. Delicious.
No, I'm good. It's OK.
I know you're all always
looking at me. I can tell.
Always tell. I can see.
My hat. Where's... my hat?
Where's... my hat?
Try not cutting things
so close next time, understood?
- Yes. We live to serve.
- As always.
Cool. Take this mess out
with the rest of the trash.
And you have something to tell me?
- Indeed, Glorificus.
- And I'm waiting.
We have found that the signs of the
alignment are moving faster than expected.
Meaning?
If you are to use the Key,
you must act quickly.
Fine.
I have been cooling my heels
in this crappy little town long enough.
Sunnydale's got too many demons
and not enough retail outlets.
All you need is the Key.
Yes, and I bet Mousy the Vampire Slayer
has an idea where it is.
If I may remind Your Eminence,
you don't have much time.
Baby, if that girl's the only thing
between me and my Key,
I don't need much time.
If you're serious about this, madam,
you need to be very careful.
Measure precisely,
and please don't step ahead.
He's quite right.
Wouldn't want to do anything dangerous.
Turn the wrong person into a badger.
Quentin. I didn't realise you were here.
Evidently.
It's been a while. I see you've brought
some of our colleagues with you.
Would you care to introduce us?
First I thought we might catch up.
Well, certainly.
This is the shop, obviously. It's been a very
interesting transition into the world of retail.
It's going rather well.
I'll give you a grand tour if you like.
That's all right. I think
I can see what you've been up to.
Yes, well, I do limit my time here, obviously.
Buffy and I have been training a great deal
these days. There's a back room that we...
Yes. I thought you were keeping
that space for the really dangerous items
that should be kept out of the public's hands.
- Or maybe you don't worry about that.
- I'm very careful.
Most of this stuff couldn't harm anyone.
Incense, dime-store trinkets...
- But there are some things...
- I'm sorry, who are you?
There are some very potent elements here.
Focusing crystals, runic artefacts,
an amulet of Cauldis.
Also this statue. Its removal
from Burma is a criminal offence,
and when triggered,
it has the power to melt human eyeballs.
In that case I severely underpriced it.
Giles, sorry, but this is just
for the duration of our stay.
I think you can see why.
What? What is just for the duration?
Magic Box shoppers,
we're going to have to ask you to leave.
The store is closing early today.
Terribly sorry for the inconvenience.
Hey! Giles, what are they doing?
Customers, please bring your money back.
You knew you'd do this
before you even saw the place.
I'm sorry. It's just for the duration
of the Council's review.
Council? You're the Council?
Welcome to our store.
We're closed now. I'll be in the back.
What review? Let's just
stop and talk about this.
Miss? Excuse me, you work here?
Yes, I do.
Ever since I moved here from Indiana, where
I was raised by both a mother and a father.
Anya, just go. You don't have to talk to him.
She works for me.
Now, tell me about this review.
No one said anything to me about this.
Let's sit down and talk about it over here.
You all stand around and look sombre.
Good job.
You used to respect us, Giles.
You used to be one of us.
You used to pay me. If you recall,
firing me was not my idea.
Touché.
But you were on the inside once. You know
what sort of resources we command.
We've discovered information
about this creature, your Glory.
Some of it is clearly vital,
the rest merely extremely disturbing,
and it won't be handed over
until we're convinced that you and your
slayer are prepared for it. Thus the review.
I'm not having you put her through
another of your insane tests.
It's not a test. It's a check of her methods.
We need to know that this information is safe.
You can trust her.
Buffy's come very far recently.
She's acquired a remarkable focus.
Now, Rasputin was associated
with a certain obscure religious sect.
They held the tenet that in order
to be forgiven, one first had to sin.
Rasputin embraced this, and proceeded
to sin impressively and repeatedly.
The notion that he was in fact evil
gained strength years later,
when the conspirators who set out to kill him
found it nearly impossible to do so.
- "Nearly impossible"?
- I'm sorry, there was a question?
Miss Summers, of course.
I... about, you know, killing him...
You know, they poisoned him and they beat
him and they shot him, and he didn't die.
Until they rolled his body in a carpet
and drowned him in a canal.
But there are reported sightings of him
as late as the 1930s.
There is near consensus in the academic
community regarding Rasputin's death.
There was near consensus about Columbus,
until someone asked the Vikings
what they were up to,
and they're, like, discovering
this America-shaped continent.
I just... I'm only saying,
you know, it might be interesting
if we came at it from, you know,
a different perspective, that's all.
Well, I'm sorry if you find these facts
so boring, Miss Summers.
Maybe you'd prefer I step aside,
so that you can teach your own course.
Speculation 101 perhaps?
Intro to Flights of Fancy?
- I only meant...
- What was it you were on about last week?
Mysterious sleeping patterns
of the Prussian generals?
Now, some of us are here to learn.
Believe it or not, we're interested
in what actually happened.
It's called studying history.
You can sit down now.
Unless you have
something else to add, Professor?
"Miss Summers"!
"Some of us are here to learn, Professor"!
- "Maybe you'd like to teach your own class"!
- Who are you talking to?
Spike, why did you do that?
Not for money, if that's what you're thinking.
Your heartfelt gratitude's plenty.
- Expect I'll be getting that any moment.
- Gratitude? For getting in my way?
Getting in your way? I saved you.
I was regrouping.
You'd have been regrouped
into separate piles. You needed help.
I didn't need you. I never need you, Spike.
I get it. You just don't like
who did the rescuing, that's all.
Wishing I was your boyfriend.
Wait, he's run off.
I don't need a boyfriend,
to rescue me or for anything.
Don't need or can't keep?
You make notches in the headboard,
but eventually they get up
out of the bed and run off, don't they?
- You're disgusting.
- Rough talk.
Maybe that's your problem.
Maybe you push 'em away.
Or is it the other? Maybe you cling too much.
Or maybe your beauty's fading.
The stress of slaying ageing you prematurely.
Things not as high, not as firm.
You know what, Spike? The more I get
to know you, the more I wish I didn't.
Or maybe you just don't hold their interest.
Begging permission to speak with you, sir.
Don't touch me. You're crusty.
What do you want?
Not me. The magnificent Glory.
She wants more information on the Slayer.
She knows you know her.
The Slayer? I don't know any slayer.
Get away from me. You shouldn't be here.
I believe you do, sir.
She's short, symmetrical, hair on top?
- Buffy something.
- Buffy Summers is the Slayer?
That's the one! Very clever of you, sir.
- The Slayer. How does Glory know this?
- I do not know. I was not there.
But the beauteous Glory said for you
to tell us, please, where her dwelling is.
- Who her friends are.
- Why?
So Glory can find her, do something to her?
Why would I do that?
I don't know, sir. She just said
to tell you to do it. For her.
That was her message.
Well, I've got a message for Glory, too.
We've been developing
a sort of hybrid fighting style.
Let me outline her progress and I think you'll
see that your review isn't strictly needed.
Bad day. Bad, bad...
Miss Summers.
Good to see you again.
- Mr Travers.
- Giles is telling us of your training regimen.
Perhaps you'll favour us
with a demonstration while we're here.
- Right now?
- No need to rush you.
They're staying a little longer
than I'd anticipated.
We've already laid out our project
for Mr Giles. Nigel?
An exhaustive examination
of your procedures and abilities.
- Observe your training, talk to your friends...
- My friends?
Yes, we understand you're still
taking civilians out on your patrols.
- You've gotta be kidding me.
- Buffy, I can sense your resistance.
I don't blame you.
But your watcher hasn't reminded you lately
of the status of the players in our little game.
The Council fights evil. The Slayer
is the instrument by which we fight.
The Council remains, the slayers change.
It's been that way from the beginning.
That's a very comforting,
bloodless way of looking at it.
Giles, let me talk to Buffy,
because I think she's understanding me.
Glory is stronger than you.
She's a more powerful instrument, if you will.
We can help you.
We have information that will help.
Pass the review and we give it to you
without reservation.
Fail the review, either through incompetence,
or by resisting our recommendations...
Resisting your recommendations?
She fails if we don't do as you say! How
much under your thumb do you think we are?
- How much do you want our help?
- She's not your bloody instrument!
Giles!
I understand you think this is unfair.
There are factors which should
motivate you to go along with the review.
I don't want to do this, but obviously
we could shut this place down permanently.
You can't. You don't have that kind of power.
Of course we do, and a great deal more.
If you insist on fighting us, we'll arrange
to have Mr Giles deported within the day.
Never set foot in this country again.
Now, perhaps you're used to idle threats
and sloppy discipline, Miss Summers.
But you're dealing with grown-ups now.
Am I making myself clear?
Jinx!
Hey, what's the deal with your face?
It's a message from Ben.
He isn't going to help.
Isn't going...?
- Isn't going to help?
- No.
All he has to do is turn over that squirming
slayer girl. I have business to do with her.
If she knows where I can
start looking for my Key...
Why won't he help? He knows her.
He could go to her, he could talk to her...
He could seduce her
and bang the Key out of her!
- He is quite attractive.
- Well, of course he's attractive!
But he drives me insane.
You know what I mean?
- He drives you insane?
- Yeah!
That's it exactly!
Sweet, lumpy minion.
You're the only one that understands.
Probably cos I haven't
sucked your brain out yet.
He makes me so mad!
If I could just get my hands on him!
You know? I'll just find her myself.
It's a power play, that's what it is.
It's about who has the power.
I'm guessing they do?
Big power outage in Buffy County?
I should have set you on them,
that's what I should have done.
Giles, that Travers guy is, like, 60.
I can't hit him.
- Can I?
- I suppose not.
Well, I could. I think I will.
Can they really do what they threatened?
Kick you out of the country?
In a heartbeat.
The rough stuff, they're all right at.
They're ham-handed, but they get it done.
But this stuff, the bureaucracy, the pulling of
political strings, they're the best in the world.
They can kill you
with the stroke of a pen. Poncy sods.
Am I gonna be able
to get through this review?
Well, I suppose they'll make it
as difficult as they want to.
The physical stuff
could be a bit of a challenge.
That's not what I'm worried about.
It's the other stuff.
Examining decisions I've made. I mean, twice
I've been within slaying distance of Glory,
and twice she's kicked my ass
without even tensing a muscle.
And I haven't been able to figure out
what she is or anything about her,
except she wants the Key, which I have, and I
don't even know if it's OK to tell anyone that.
No one could have done better than you.
But no one else is gonna be asked
the questions that I can't answer.
They're gonna expect me to be
like a slayer, and know stuff,
but I'm just me and I don't know anything.
They'll go away and not tell me how to fight
Glory and I won't be able to protect Dawn!
Buffy, calm down.
The scandal here is not anything you've
done wrong. It's the way they're behaving.
Holding what they know hostage with a gun
pointed at my bleeding green card, no less.
It's humiliating.
Also smart.
They picked the perfect thing.
I can't lose you.
Thank you.
I guess I should be getting ready.
What do you think it'll be like?
How do you think they'll start?
Anya Christina Emanuella Jenkins.
20 years old. Born on the fourth of July.
And don't think there weren'tjokes about
that. "Who's our little patriot?" they'd say,
when I was younger, and therefore
smaller and shorter than I am now.
So, you spell it A-N-Y-A, then?
- Yes.
- Fine. Now we can get to the questions.
- Questions, great.
- We can answer questions.
Well, I need to know
a little bit more about the Slayer,
and about the both of you,
your relationship, whatever you can tell me.
Our relationship?
- We're friends.
- Good friends.
- Girlfriends, actually.
- Yes, we're girlfriends.
We're in love. We're lovers.
We're lesbian, gay-type lovers.
I meant your relationship with the Slayer.
Just good friends.
Best friends. Willow and me and Buffy. The
three of us were together from the beginning.
We've always gone on patrols, and done
demon research with her and everything.
Have you mastered
any fighting disciplines over the years?
No.
So, you have no special skills or powers
or knowledge that you bring to the mix.
- Neither of you.
- Just enthusiasm for killing the demons.
Go deadness for the demons.
- I don't have any powers, but I do help.
- How? Be specific.
Last year, Willow, Giles and me
combined our essence with Buffy.
Which isn't as weird as it sounds.
We merged, and I was
the heart part of a super-Buffy.
- Again, let me stress the not-as-weird thing.
- I'm told it was all very professional.
Are you saying that the Slayer
needs that level of help from you often?
- No, no, she doesn't need help.
- She'd be fine without us.
She goes off and does stuff
without even telling us.
Not that she's, like, a weird Ioner or anything.
- I'm not sure we're saying this right.
- See, here's the thing.
We can help because we do magics.
I'm working on this ball-of-sunshine thing.
- I have this theory.
- It's very cool.
And if it works, easier slaying for Buffy.
Not that it's hard for her now.
Interesting. What level are you at?
"Level"?
Magical proficiency level?
A high level.
Very high. One of those top levels.
Five!
And you're registered as practising witches
under the names as you gave them to me?
"Registered"?
- Yes! Yes, of course, we're...
- Registered.
Do either of you
know anything about the Key?
Nope. Sounds demony to me.
I don't hold with that demon nonsense.
Muffin? I cooked them myself.
So, Buffy sometimes protects you
from the dangerous elements of her work.
Yes. She's saved my life lots of times.
The vampires in this town hate her.
But we understand that you help the Slayer.
- I pitch in when she pays me.
- She pays you?
She gives you money?
Money, a nip of blood
out of some stray victim, whatever.
- Blood?
- Well, if they're gonna die anyway.
Come to think of it, that's a bit scandalous,
isn't it? I'm shocked. The girl's slipping.
- You've noticed a decline in her work?
- Yeah.
See, the poor little twig can't keep a man.
Gets her all down.
Few more disappointments, she'll be
crying on my shoulder, mark my words.
Is that what you want?
I'd think you'd want to kill her.
You've killed slayers before.
Heard of me, have you?
I wrote my thesis on you.
Well, well. Ain't that neat?
Tell me, pet, now we're such good friends,
how's the Slayer doing?
She OK? High marks in all categories?
Agility, clarity, stamina and strength.
These are the qualities that the Slayer
must possess to do herjob.
- What came after agility?
- If you want her to attack the dummy...
Phillip will attack the dummy.
The Slayer's job is to protect it.
- Do you understand?
- Protect the dummy?
As if it were precious.
Now, getting the best of Phillip
will require agility.
Listening to my instructions at the same
time, that will demonstrate clarity.
And stamina and strength
will win the long fight.
- Good luck.
- "Instructions"?
I'll be telling you what to do,
how to counter Phillip's thrusts.
We assume you're familiar with the Japanese
names for aikido and jiujitsu moves.
- Japanese?
- And... go!
Hold on a second. In America,
we usually work our way up to "go".
He wants you to bow. Take a bow.
- Punch him.
- Thanks, Giles.
Sorry.
Back kick, elbow...
Elbow... strike.
- How've you been training her?
- I trained her to win.
Know what? I'm gonna
have to do it my way, guys.
- I think she just broke my rib.
- Yes, well...
I didn't mean to. You know, I can do better.
I think I might be getting this, like, inner-ear
thing. Maybe if I got a note, I could try again?
No, that's all right. I don't think we need
to see any more physical tests for a while.
We can move on to the real review.
Look into your strategies. Plans.
Figure out what's going on in that head.
Good. Head stuff.
We start at seven tonight. Give you time to...
Well, however you prepare.
Mom?
Long day, sweetie?
So... this is where
the Slayer eats, sleeps and...
combs her hair?
So cute.
I can't even stand it.
Personally, I need more space,
but this is good for you.
It's so quaint, and...
Buffy, if I wanted to fight,
you could tell by the being dead already.
- So play nice, little girl.
- What do you want?
The Key. Why else
do you think I'd come here?
See, I think you know where it is.
- And that's a good thing.
- I'm glad you think so.
It's the only thing
keeping you alive right now.
You may be tiny queen in vampire world,
but to me, you're a bug.
You should get down
on your knees and worship me!
But no. You still think it's neat
having slayer strength. Big deal!
Stronger than humans! Who isn't?
I could crush the life from you as easy
as you'd break a nail. But I need the Key.
Kid!
- Come here a sec.
- Leave her out of this.
- Not asking twice.
- This is between you and me.
No. This is between me and my Key.
You just happen to be the thing in the way.
And you are just the darlingest thing
I ever did see in my life.
- What's your name, honey?
- Dawn.
Dawn? Did you know your sister took
my Key, Dawnie? And she won't give it back.
- I bet you know where she put it, don't you?
- She doesn't know anything.
I know some stuff.
I bet she takes your stuff all the time without
asking, doesn't she? Where's my Key, Dawn?
Go upstairs, Dawn.
You're always talking about
stuff I'm not supposed to hear.
I'm gonna figure it out, you know.
I like her. She's sassy!
And I'll kill her.
I'll kill your mom, I'll kill your friends...
and I'll make you watch when I do.
Just give me the Key. You either have it
or you know where to find it.
Obviously, this is a one-time-only deal.
Next time we meet,
something you love dies bloody.
You know you can't take me.
You know you can't stop me.
Buffy, who was that?
Pack a bag.
It's the Slayer.
For a second there I was worried.
So, what's with the family outing?
- I need your help.
- Great. I need your cash.
I'm serious.
You have to look after them.
That's a boatload of manly responsibility
to come out of nowhere. What's the matter?
- You're not feeling 100 per cent?
- No.
- They didn't put a chip in your head?
- No!
- Be funny if they did.
- Spike, I need an answer. Now.
In or out?
You're the only one
strong enough to protect them.
All right, then.
Ladies, come on in.
There's plenty of blood in the fridge.
Do you mean, like, real blood?
- What do you think?
- Mostly I think "Ew".
Keep Dawn here as long as you can.
I'll be back soon.
- I don't need to remind you...
- Yeah, yeah.
"Anything happens to 'em, I stake you good
and proper." Sing me a new one sometime.
That bit's gone stale.
I love what you've neglected
to do with the place.
Just don't break anything.
And don't make a lot of noise.
Passions is coming on.
Passions?
Do you think Timmy's really dead?
No, no, she can just sew him back together.
He's a doll, for God's sake.
What about the wedding? I mean, there's
no way they're gonna go through with that.
Look at them. Big tough
Council members picking on the books.
- Fascists.
- Why doesn't Mr Giles put them out of here?
If they deport him,
they're notjust destroying his career,
they're condemning the man to a lifetime diet
of blood sausage, bangers and mash.
Well, your slayer's 20 minutes late
and counting, Rupert.
Buffy will be here, I assure you.
Yes, but when?
Crap!
Guys? Any way we could not do this?
OK. Let's see what you are.
- Or who you are.
- One soldier in a vast army.
What army?
The Knights of Byzantium, an ancient order.
And now your enemy.
- You work for Glory?
- You think we ally ourselves with the Beast?
- You must be mad.
- You're the ones who tried killing me.
We were fools, three alone. But if it takes
a hundred men, we send a hundred men.
- If it takes a thousand, we send a thousand.
- A thousand?
So long as you protect the Key,
the brotherhood will never stop
until we destroy it and you.
You are the Slayer,
and we know what we must do.
Now, be done with it.
Kill us, and let legions follow.
Go.
- You're late.
- Yeah.
- Was there an attack?
We can begin the review at last.
We'll skip the more obvious questions.
- There isn't gonna be a review.
- Sorry?
No review. No interrogation.
No questions you know I can't answer.
No hoops, no jumps. And no interruptions.
See, I've had a lot of people
talking at me in the last few days.
Everyone just lining up
to tell me how unimportant I am.
And I finally figured out why.
Power.
I have it.
They don't.
This bothers them.
Glory came to my home today.
- Buffy, are you...?
- Just to talk.
She told me I'm a bug, I'm a flea,
she could squash me in a second.
Only she didn't.
She came into my home, and we talked.
We had what in her warped brain probably
passes for a civilised conversation. Why?
Because she needs something from me.
Because I have power over her.
You didn't come all this way to determine
whether I was good enough to be let back in.
You came to beg me to let you back in.
To give yourjobs, your lives,
some semblance of meaning.
This is beyond insolence...
I'm fairly certain I said "no interruptions".
That was excellent.
You're watchers.
Without a slayer, you're pretty much
just watching Masterpiece Theatre.
You can't stop Glory. You can't
do anything with the information you have,
except maybe publish it in the Everyone
Thinks We're Insanos Home Journal.
So here's how it's gonna work.
You're gonna tell me everything you know.
Then you're gonna go away.
You'll contact me if and when you have
any further information about Glory.
The shop will remain open. Mr Giles will stay
here as my watcher, reinstated at full salary.
Retroactive.
To be paid retroactively
from the month he was fired.
I will continue my work
with the help of my friends.
I don't want a sword
thrown at me, but civilians?
We're talking about children.
We're talking about two very powerful
witches and a thousand-year-old ex-demon.
Willow's a demon?
The boy? No power there.
"The boy" has clocked more field time than
all of you combined. He's part of the unit.
- That's Riley-speak.
- I've clocked field time.
Now...
you all may be very good at yourjobs.
The only way we're gonna find out
is if you work with me.
You can all take your time
thinking about that.
But I want an answer right now from Quentin,
cos I think he's understanding me.
Your terms are acceptable.
See? No begging.
- Rupert?
- Quentin?
When we inventoried your shop,
we found a bottle of single-malt scotch
behind the incense holders...
- It's not, you know, during working hours...
- I think I could use a glass.
- Well, I suppose we could...
- Just a minute.
Glory. I wanna know.
Well, there's a lot to go through.
Just tell me what kind of demon I'm fighting.
Well, that's the thing, you see.
Glory isn't a demon.
What is she?
She's a god.
Visiontext Subtitles: Rob Colling
ENGLISH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org