Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
l believe in you, Spike.
(Buffy) They were after Spike all along.
You know what we're up against. The First.
Now, Spike, you wanna see
what a real vampire looks like?
We won't use magic to fight this
until we know what we're doing.
- Giles.
- Buffy.
- (Buffy) They're all slayers?
- (Giles) Potentials.
Waiting for one to be called. There were
many more like them all over the world,
but now there's just a handful,
and they're all on their way to Sunnydale.
What you fought was a vampire,
but it was something more.
lt was a Turok-Han.
A ferociously powerful killing machine
as single-minded as an animal.
l think the Turok-Han
is here as an agent of the First.
They want an apocalypse? We'll give 'em one.
Cos we just became an army.
There is only one thing on this earth
more powerful than evil, and that's us.
(bus driver) Sunnydale. Watch your step.
Next stop Hillcrest.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Uh!
(Buffy) Hey!
Try picking on someone my own size.
Ow! Urgh!
Rona, right?
l just got word you were arriving.
You're her.
Her is me.
You know, l thought...
They told me l'd be safe here.
Right. Well, you are.
l mean, you will be... safer... with me around.
- This is good.
- Next time you're attacked...
Whoa, whoa. Next time?
You sayin' l'm gonna get attacked again?
Welcome to the Hellmouth.
(Kennedy) You don't have to do this.
Flooring it. ln the bag.
Cos nice big comfy bed right here.
- l mean, you oughta know. Your bed.
- Yeah.
But no. l'm OK. l just...
- l like it down here. lt's firm.
- Funny, you look a little uncomfortable.
- Or is itjust me?
- No.
l'm just, uh... uneasy cos Buffy's out.
- Right. How many girls arriving this time?
- Just one.
But since Giles has the coven searching for
other slayers-in-waiting to send 'em our way,
l bet we'll be seeing a lot more soon enough.
So you're saying l should enjoy having
this bed all to myself as long as l can?
- lt is starting to get crowded around here.
- Totally. And with this many girls,
if we don't get another bathroom in this
house soon, things are gonna get ugly.
Somebody had to share mirror time
with a bunch of siblings.
Somebody not me. l only got a half-sister
and we didn't have to share.
Her bedroom was in
a different wing of the house.
- Wing? Your house had wings?
- Yeah.
Just a couple. A few.
Our summer home in the Hamptons
didn't have any at all. Well, one, actually.
Huh.
Well, that's... that's... Huh!
But never mind my deal. What's your story,
Willow? l mean, witchcraft? Wow!
That sounds... New-Agey.
No, it's safe to say that what l practise
is definitely... Old-Agey.
- So, show me a trick.
- A trick?
Pull a rabbit out of something,
or make something float.
Uh, yeah.
Listen, Kennedy, it's almost morning
and we really need to get some sleep.
Hey, if l wanted to sleep, l'd be downstairs
catching z's with the other girls.
Annabelle was all
"Control your fear, control your fear."
Meanwhile, she's the one
that goes scamperin' off,
right into that Turok-Han vampire.
Poor Annie.
Great. So the Slayer who's supposed
to protect us let her get killed?
She didn't let her. Annabelle was foolish.
Buffy can't be faulted for arriving too late.
lt's not like she could've stopped it.
The supervampire messed her up good.
No lie. She still looked like
a big bruise when l got here,
and that was already, like, the day after.
And why isn't she back yet? Buffy?
She left to get the new girl over an hour ago.
Maybe she ran into trouble. You don't
think maybe she was too late again?
- Maybe...
- Maybe we can save maybes
for a more of a dayish part of the day, girls.
Potential slayers can function without sleep.
l'm no good without my usual 90 minutes.
l'm with him. Keep the chatter down.
Or speak up so l can hear you.
l'm bored. Episode One bored.
- You guys are all still up?
- Ah! Who needs sleep?
- Everybody, this is Rona.
- (girls) Hey.
- Hey, Rona.
Um...
Why is that guy tied to a chair?
The question you'll soon be asking is
"Why isn't he gagged?"
Molly, show our new house guest
where the kitchen is.
- l'm sure she's hungry after her travels.
- Fair enough. A bit peckish meself.
- Bit what as well?
- That's English for "hungry".
Oh.
l thought "hungry" was English for "hungry".
- Everything all right?
- She had a welcoming committee.
The First knows potential slayers
are coming here?
- l must warn the coven.
- The First will always be one step ahead.
l need to know how to stop it.
No, not stop it, hurt it.
l want to hurt it real bad.
- Tell me how.
- l, uh...
l don't know, Buffy.
l've exhausted all the sources
l have left with little result.
The watchers' records
are still really all we have to go on.
l made the rounds myself. Tried to dig up
anything useful from the demon community.
They're a community now?
What's next, a Ladies' Auxiliary?
The ones that didn't attack me didn't know
or didn't talk. We've got squat.
Squat's not gonna cut it.
What about the Turok-Han?
- (Xander) The vampire time forgot?
- (Buffy) Time may forget him, but l won't.
We know stakes don't kill it, but anything
in those ancient myths about what does?
Sunlight, fire. Germs?
Giles, with that thing guarding the entrance to
the First's crib, how will Buffy get to Spike?
l really hate to admit this,
but he's not wrong.
There's no way to help Spike
until it's out of the way.
Spike?
Sorry, l'm confused. He's that vampire
who's been killin' people, right?
- He's the one you're worried about helping?
- (Buffy) Well, we need him to...
He's the one that's been...
lt's complicated, Chloö.
l'm Chloö. She's Eve.
lt's just... Well, we've been talkin',
and... do we have some kind of plan?
You know, any kind of plan to...
keep us from dying?
We're workin' on it.
There is one avenue
that we haven't tried yet.
- Giles!
- Beljoxa's Eye.
- Exactly what part of town is that avenue in?
- l told you no.
What is Botox's eye?
Beljoxa's Eye. lt's an oracle-type creature
that exists in a dark dimension.
- lnternal vortex more like.
- Fun.
- Not really, no.
- Only demons can open the gateway to it.
Excuse me, ex-demon here.
You've still friends in the fold.
Or murderous acquaintances.
There's no reason to think Beljoxa's Eye
will have the answers we're looking for.
l'll take anything l can get.
Anya, please, we're running out of time.
Spike's running out of time.
Dreaming of me again, aren't you?
Poor Spike.
He still thinks l believe in him.
Be realistic.
l don't even believe in myself.
At least, not enough
to risk my skin to save your ass.
Not enough to face... that.
(growls)
l'm sorry, Spike.
But you need to accept this.
You know it never would've worked out.
lt's time to let go so we can both move on.
l promise, soon it'll all be...
(whispers)
(whispers) She... She...
She will come for me.
She... will come for me.
No.
l won't.
- (Anya) Why not?
- (man) You have the nerve to ask me that?
Come on, Torg, that was a lifetime ago.
Three, but who's counting?
- You broke my heart, Anyanka.
- Don't be so dramatic, Torg.
You don't even have a heart.
Six spleens, two stomachs,
half a brain maybe, but no heart.
Don't mock this.
The night we spent together
was important to me.
lt was one date. lt wasn't even a date.
We just happened to be invited to the same
massacre and you hit on me after l had a few.
l remember, you wore pink.
- Those were entrails.
- Sorry, perhaps we could skip the nostalgic...
- Sorry, no, no. Carry on.
- OK, Torg, look.
You open this tiny little gateway
to the Beljoxa's Eye for me, and l'll...
You and l can go...
(sighs)
l'll have sex with you again.
(Torg) Urgh!
Please, you're human.
The way you look now, l wouldn't
touch you for all the kittens in Korea.
You're rejecting my sexual bribery?
What am l, a leper? l can't even give it away.
- Come back when you are a leper.
- Um...
Perhaps this might change your mind.
You help us,
and the Slayer will not kill all your clientele
and burn your establishment to the ground.
(breathes heavily)
(chants spell in ancient language)
There's your stinkin' gateway, Anyanka.
Don't let it hit you on the way out.
- lt's the hair, right? Not attractive?
- Come on.
Buckle up.
- (Anya) God, l hate this place.
- Where's the Beljoxa's Eye?
(male voice) Here.
Ah! Oh.
Hi.
- (phone rings)
- Hello?
No, Giles isn't here right...
Yeah, this is Willow.
Althenea, hi! How's the coven?
Oh, l miss you guys.
Still workin' out
that Pleiadian spirit conjuring?
What?
Oh. OK, when?
Ow! Watch it. That's my joystick hand.
- l'm not gonna touch that one.
- (Buffy) OK.
Listen up, Andrew.
l don't know what to do with you.
- We don't have time to baby-sit a hostage.
- Especially one that's more than a little ripe.
So l'm here to tell you,
if you try anything, try to run...
- Did you ever see the movie Misery?
- Six times. But the book was scarier
cos instead of crushing his foot with a
sledgehammer, Kathy Bates chops it off...
- l'll be good.
- Buffy?
Word from the underground. Another
potential arrived the day before yesterday.
She's at the Sunspot Motel, near the highway.
Why are we just finding out about it now?
Bringers killed her watcher
before he could tell us.
lf it wasn't for a powerful seer in the coven,
we wouldn't even know about it now.
OK. There's still a couple
of hours of daylight left.
- You guys should be safe here. l'll get her.
- l'll go with you.
All right, retrieving a potential.
Let's do it!
Or l could just go wash up.
- Where are they going?
- Bring another newbie in from the cold.
- Another one?
- Well, the more the better, l figure.
We need all the help we can get.
- Help. Sure, that's cool, but...
- What?
l'm just not sure more scared
slayer wannabes translates as help.
- What are we all doin' here?
- lt's called training.
- Didn't your watcher teach you the word?
- l never had a watcher.
l only found out what l was - or might be -
after those crazy-ass monks came after me.
l meant why are we all botherin'?
- lt's not like we can make a difference.
- (Molly) We've gotta train.
- We gotta keep our reflexes sharp.
- (Kennedy) We have to be ready.
- lf something comes down...
- No, something's already come down.
She's right. And what are we
supposed to do about it?
l mean, l've never seen a real vampire
in my whole life, much less a slayed one.
l've seen one.
Well, my watcher once showed me
a photograph of one.
- A blurry photograph.
- That's what l'm sayin'.
Not one of us is remotely prepared
to be activated as the new Chosen One.
- l feel pretty prepared.
- Excuse the newness of me,
butjust so l understand, if a slayer dies...
Well, when the Slayer dies.
l mean, nobody lives forever, right?
- One of us...
- Gets activated. Uh-huh.
- l prefer "called".
- l heard there's more than one.
- More than one what?
- Slayer. There's another one. Somewhere.
- That doesn't make any sense.
- Like any of this does.
No matter how many there are,
one of us is gonna be the next Slayer,
with the weight of the world on her shoulders.
lt won't be me. l mean, not now.
l mean, l'm too young.
lt doesn't work that way.
ln fact, the younger the better.
l'm starting to think
it might be too late for me.
Never too late. lt could be anyone.
Especially since there are so few of us left.
They'll just run through each one of us.
One after the other.
Kinda creepy, huh?
All we do is wait around for each other to die.
- You sure this is it?
- Clerk said it's the only check-in in a week.
- Tourism must be down.
- Right in the middle of apocalypse season.
Hello.
lt's OK. We're friendly.
And we have eyes.
Buffy.
Kick the door down.
She's cold. Been dead for days.
Poor kid. Made it all the way to Sunnydale
just to get herself killed.
- lf only we...
- Eve.
Eve, who's in our house?
Just my personal opinion,
but l don't think the Slayer
can protect us from the First.
Another interesting thing:
how come the Slayer's always a girl?
- l dunno. Cos girls are cooler?
- l think a guy slayer would be badass.
Like, if there was this ninja,
a guy slayer would be like:
"You may be silent, but this'll shut you up."
- Buffy could stomp ninja ass.
- The silent warrior? Ha-ha! l think not.
She can't even slay that special vampire.
Everyone's saying.
Everyone should shut up. And stop
pretending anybody here is your friend.
And also, why's she so about saving Spike?
He's a worse killer than me by... a way lot.
Spike was being controlled by the First.
And he has a soul now.
Besides, we need his help.
What about me? Did it ever occur to anyone
that l could be a lot more useful?
- l used to be an evil genius. Hello?
- And what was your genius thing?
Well, um... raising demons mostly.
OK, so not for now,
but also there was planning.
There were, um... blueprints.
l can be in this, kickin' it righteous.
Yeah. Oh, oh, yeah.
Buffy said if you talked enough,
l'm allowed to kill you.
- Not even.
- Even.
Licence to kill, huh?
Pretty cool. You know,
Timothy Dalton never got his props
cos he came in at the end of an old regime,
but he had it going on.
He went rogue with the Broccolis.
They were just treading water, stylistically.
ls there a language that you're speaking?
l'm so alone.
Then maybe you shouldn't
have killed your only friend.
l hate that. You don't even know.
- l don't plan to.
- The Slayer's not getting it done.
l have got my ear to the ground,
and... that's the word.
Do you wanna play Kevin Bacon?
- Buffy.
- (Dawn) What is it?
- Get away from them.
- Who? Get away from who?
- What's the problem, officer?
- l said get away from them now.
- Buffy, what did Eve do?
- That's not Eve.
- Eve's dead.
- l don't understand.
Oops! One more down.
Oh, well, can't save 'em all, can ya, Buffy?
Thanks for the slumber party, girls.
lt's been real fun these past couple of nights.
- l learned a whole lot...
- Shut up and get out!
Or you'll do what? l'll be sending
a guest over to visit y'all later on tonight,
after the sun goes down, of course.
Try and make him feel welcome
before he rips y'all to pieces.
Bye.
l need to go wash up again.
lt cannot be fought, it cannot be killed.
The First Evil has been and always will be.
Since before the universe was born,
long after there is nothing else, it will go on.
l refuse to believe that.
There must be a way to destroy it.
Am l talkin' to myself here? There's no way.
OK, we tried. Let's go, Giles.
Are you saying the First will succeed
in wiping out the line of slayers?
The Eye sees not the future,
only the truth of the now and before.
Yes, we've all got that. lt's called memory.
Can you help us out with something
a little bit more demony?
lf the First has been around
for all time, then...
why hasn't it attempted
something like this before? Why now?
The opportunity
has only recently presented itself.
Opportunity?
The mystical forces surrounding the chosen
line have become irrevocably altered,
become unstable, vulnerable.
- Something the First did?
- The First did not cause the disruption,
only seized upon it to extinguish
the lives of the chosen forever.
Then what has caused the disruption?
What is responsible for letting this happen?
The Slayer.
- We should run.
- And go where, Vi?
- Annabelle ran. Look where it got her.
- Safer in than out.
How can you say that?
lt was here, Buffy, in the house.
- Livin' with us for days.
- You didn't even know it.
- None of us did.
- lt could still be here. lt could be one of us.
No, the First can only take
the form of dead people.
There'll be plenty more of those soon enough.
We're dropping like flies here.
(all talk at once)
l know you're all scared. l am too.
But Giles and Anya will be back soon.
Hopefully they will have
the information that we need.
ln the meantime, we need to stick together.
OK? We're stronger that way.
- We cannot afford to fall apart now.
- Right. Where would the Justice League be
if they hadn't put their differences aside
to stop the lmperium and his alien horde?
- Don't help me.
- (Xander) Buff, the sun goes down,
and Übervamp's on its way,
so a plan'd be good right about now.
- Will, l'm sorry to ask, but...
- l know. We need a barrier.
A major one.
Something tells me this vampire doesn't
need an invite to get into the house.
- Can you do it?
- l'll try.
- Try?
- You heard her.
Are you sure about Willow
doing the hocus-pocus?
- Last time she...
- We don't have a lot of choices.
What if it doesn't work?
What if the monster gets through?
- Then we'll deal.
- (Rona) Deal?
Fight, you mean.
How are we supposed to do that?
- And with what?
- With whatever it takes! Right?
Buffy, you fought the Turok-Han,
and it almost killed you.
- And you're the real Slayer.
- What chance do we have?
Honestly, you staked that thing,
and it didn't die.
- No, but that doesn't...
- Maybe it can't be killed.
- (Dawn) So we shouldn't try?
- (Rona) That word again.
- (Kennedy) lt's a good word.
- (Vi) Give up. Can we do that?
Surrender, l mean, so it won't kill us.
What?
l said trying is good.
- l just thought it beared repeating.
- (potential slayers all talk at once)
- We're all potential slayers.
- We need to think positive here.
- l mean, fighting is one thing...
- l don't wanna die.
(Eve) The time has come...
for all good children to say... good night.
(growling)
Take 'em all, except for her.
(growls)
Well, alone again.
l just love having you all to myself.
There's more of them now.
- And two more out back.
- Why aren't they doin' anything? Attackin'?
They don't want in.
They're here to make sure we don't get out.
Rona.
Like this'll do any good.
l mean, what's the point?
lt's this end right here. You stick that
in the bad guys. Any more questions?
- This will do me.
- Are you sure you know how to use it?
Since l was eight.
Can l have something? Come on, the
Turok-Han's coming for me too, you know.
l have a right to defend myself.
lf you say so.
Facing my fear. l'm facing my fear.
Hear that, fear? l'm facing you.
Wow!
You really can float stuff.
Just testing.
Oh, right.
Heard this voodoo once turned you
into the big scary. Big, scary Willow.
- That's something l'd almost like to see.
- No, you wouldn't.
l said "almost".
l needed to make sure.
Last time l tried using magic,
the First, it...
it turned it around on me, got inside.
l felt it surging through me
in every fibre of my being.
Pure, undiluted evil.
l could taste it.
How's evil taste?
- A little chalky.
- (Dawn) Guys?
Something's happening.
Oh, my God.
Here it comes.
(growls)
(banging on door)
Caerimonia Minerva,
saepio, saepire, saepsi.
Um... deflector shields.
Deflector shields up.
Willow...
Saepio impedimentum!
- (Chloë) lt's working.
- For the moment.
(Buffy) Will..
- lt's... it's strong.
- lt's hurting her.
- Hang on, Willow.
- l don't know.
- (Dawn) She can't hold it.
- What do we do? What do we do?
Run. Everybody run.
Aargh!
Come on!
Are you all right?
Yeah.
l just... l don't understand how Buffy's death
mucked up the whole slayer mojo.
- lt's not like she hasn't died before.
- lt's not because she died.
The Beljoxa's Eye was quite clear
about that... in its enigmatic way.
lt's because she lives. Again.
Buffy's not responsible for that.
Oh.
No.
Willow and me and Xander and Tara.
We're the ones who brought Buffy back.
We're the reason the First is here and the
reason the girls were murdered. lt's our fault.
The world would've been better off
if Buffy had just stayed dead.
No Bringers.
They'll save us for old snaggletooth.
- Where is the Turok-Han?
- Right behind us. Time to split up.
Split up? We're splitting up? ls that wise?
- Take everyone and find a safe location.
- l know a place.
- What are you gonna do?
- Try to slow the Turok down.
- Lead him away. Get him to chase me.
- You can't take that thing on yourself.
- l'll stay.
- No!
Hey, l need that.
Willow, Xander, take everyone to
a safe location. Get 'em out of here. Now!
Have to go, Dawnie.
(growls)
(roars)
- Come on, people, we gotta move.
- l'm moving. Climbing's not my thing.
- l got an inner-ear condition.
- ls falling your thing?
Cos if you don't pick up the pace,
l'm gonna come up there and drop your ass.
Way to keep up morale in a crisis.
- No wonder Buffy's the leader.
- Some leader.
- This is crazy.
- (Rona) You got that right.
- What are we doing down here?
- Quieter. Faster.
- Where are we?
- Future site of the new public library,
opening up May 2003.
lf l ever get back to work, that is.
- You call this a safe location?
- (Vi) lt's the middle of nothing.
This'll do. OK, everyone.
Spread out, take positions.
- Um, what's my position?
- And don't make a sound.
That's the plan? Spread out?
That thing is gonna kill Buffy,
then it's going to come after us.
For all we know, it's killing her right now.
Or it could just skip that part
and come straight here.
(growling)
Oh, no, no, no, no!
- (Dawn) Buffy?
- (Molly) What's she doin'?
Just watch. lt's showtime.
Looks good, doesn't it?
They're trapped in here.
Terrified. Meat for the beast,
and there's nothin' they can do but wait.
That's all they've been doing for days.
Waiting to be picked off.
Having nightmares about monsters
that can't be killed.
But l don't believe in that.
l always find a way.
l'm the thing that monsters
have nightmares about.
And right now, you and me
are gonna show 'em why.
lt's time.
- Welcome to Thunderdome.
- Two men enter. One man leaves.
This - you planned this.
Letting the barrier fail, bringing us here.
You and Buffy.
(Molly) Honestly, you staked
that thing, and it didn't die.
- No, but that doesn't...
- Maybe it can't be killed.
- (Buffy, telepathic) Willow, can you hear me?
- Yeah.
(Buffy) We're losing them.
We can't let that happen. l have an idea.
- Grab Xander.
- (Willow) Xander.
What?
(Buffy) l gotta slay the Neandervamp to get
Spike out, but l need the girls to see me do it.
(Willow) l get it, but this isn't
the best venue for a smackdown.
(Kennedy) We can whine
like little wusses, or we can fight.
(Xander) l know just the place.
- lt's killing her!
- We have to do somethin'.
Wait!
(growls)
(roars)
See? Dust.
Just like the rest of 'em.
l don't know what's coming next.
But l do know it's gonna be
just like this. Hard. Painful.
But in the end it's gonna be us.
lf we all do our parts, believe it,
we'll be the ones left standing.
Here endeth the lesson.
A knife now, is it?
What'll...
What'll that...
You can't hurt me.
You're... you're just a bloody figment, you are.
You're just...
You.
Visiontext Subtitles: Abigail Smith
Urgh! Argh!
ENGLlSH SDH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org