Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
- What kind of demon am I fighting?
- Glory isn't a demon. She's a god.
Tell me where the Key is.
We had to hide the Key. Made it human.
- Sent it to you.
- Dawn.
I know you got a lot on your mind. You
wanna let me in on any of it, let me know.
Buffy's like nobody else in the world.
But she doesn't love me.
- They want me back.
- Are you going?
- I don't know. If we can't work this out...
- This is goodbye?
Riley!
There's something
you need to know about Dawn.
Why does everybody act
all weird when I'm around?
"They had to be certain
the Slayer would protect it,
so they sent the Key to her
in the form of a sister."
- Is this blood?
- What did you do?
I'm not a key.
- I'm not real.
- You're the Key.
Go. Before she finds you. She's here!
I love you.
The only chance you had with me
was when I was unconscious.
I want you out. I want you out of this town,
I want you off this planet.
You don't come near me, my friends,
or my family again, ever. Understand?
Spike!
Spike wants me. How obscene is that?
Well, it is very strange.
I can't imagine what he's thinking.
Not that you're not attractive...
I feel gross, you know, like, dirty.
That's ridiculous. You can't be
responsible for what Spike feels.
Aren't I responsible? Something about me
had to make him feel that, right?
Something that made him say
"Woof! That's the one for me!"
- I think you should perhaps calm down.
- Me too.
Puffy Xander, I'm sorry. I guess
I got carried away. Are you OK?
I'm alive. I can tell cos of the pain.
- Do you wanna sit down?
- I'm not that bendy. I could lean.
I'll get some ice.
Here.
- Comfy?
- Yeah. This leaning, this is the stuff.
That's my secret to attracting men.
It's simple really.
Slap 'em around, torture 'em,
make their lives hell...
- Buff...
- Sure, the nice guys run away,
but every now and then you meet a real
prince of a guy like Spike who gets off on it.
Buffy. Stand me up.
The problem is not you.
Don't do this to yourself, please.
I just wanna know
that there's gonna be another good one.
One that I won't chase away.
There will be. Promise. He's out there.
He can come along any minute.
And the minute after that I can terrify him
with my strength and self-involvement.
What? I don't think you're like that.
Maybe I could change.
You know, I could work harder.
I could spend less time slaying, and laugh at
his jokes. Men like that, the joke-laughing-at.
Or maybe you can just be Buffy, he'll see
your amazing heart, and fall in love with you.
Xander, that's...
This is the day you choose to hug me?
Buffy?
You ever think you haven't found
a great relationship on the Hellmouth
because it's a Hellmouth?
Seems to me it's a pretty terrible place
to try to build anything.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Thank you for picking me up.
I'm grateful for the ride.
You sure you wanna get out here?
I mean, this place is kinda...
What are you looking for
in Sunnydale, anyway?
True love.
I might like it more than the others.
Can you spin around again?
I'm not sure. Once more.
Now could you go the other way?
You're messing with me.
- We were seeing how many times you'd do it.
- Was it five, or four and a half?
- So is anyone gonna talk about my dress?
- I like it.
You sure? I mean, it's not too mom-ish?
- That was why I liked it.
- You're both crazy.
It's not mom-ish at all. It's sexy.
It screams "Randy sex kitten.
Buy me one drink and I'II..."
Wait, that's not good either.
Oh, God. What time is it?
4.23. You have lots of time until seven.
Vast acres of time, in which you could plant
crops. Tell me about Brian and his intentions.
- Maybe he's a gigolo. Was his shirt all shiny?
- No.
He works for a publishing house.
He's a nice, normal guy, OK?
- I think I've heard of those.
- He came to the gallery, my first day back,
when I was, you know,
kinda shaky, starting over.
And he asked a question about
these antique cameos, and I was so lost,
because Carol had been doing
the ordering while I was sick.
It turned out he didn't know anything about
them either, so we had a lot to talk about.
- So what's the plan for tonight?
- Dinner and then a movie.
Or maybe it was a movie and then dinner.
Which might be better, because, you know,
then we could talk about the movie.
Or maybe a movie isn't a good idea at all,
because you can't talk during,
and then, you know, what's the point
of any of it? And about the restaurant.
Do you think it should be one with candles
and romantic music, or is that pushing it?
What do you think? Should I try to make
things romantic, or let him set the pace?
No. Love Doctor Buffy is not in.
I'm not qualified to give dating advice.
I've had exactly two boyfriends,
and they both left. Really left. "Left town" left.
Honey, you just had some bad luck.
You're going to that party.
Maybe you'll find someone there.
Or maybe Brian has a son, and Mom and I can
go on unspeakably awkward double dates.
Oh, God... Brian. What time is it now?
4.24.
- You sure the dress is OK?
- Spin again. Real fast this time.
Willow's good with computers, but me not
so much. Do you really understand all that?
At first it was confusing.
Just the idea of computers was, like,
"Whoa, I'm 1100 years old."
I had trouble adjusting
to the idea of Lutherans.
I go online sometimes, but everyone's
spelling is really bad. It's depressing.
But you have to try online trading, it's great.
The secret is avoiding the tech companies
everyone was jumping on,
and going with the smaller firms
that supply the basic components.
Anyway, I took the money from
working for Giles, and I tripled it.
Tripled? Like, first money,
then money money money?
Yes. I'm thinking about buying something
very expensive. Maybe an antelope.
Hi.
- Hi.
- Do you know where Warren is?
- And if you do, could you tell me?
- I don't think we know a Warren.
Well, all righty. No harm in asking. Thanks.
- Hi, do you know Warren? I need to find him.
- Sorry.
You can do all this stuff
with a regular computer?
I'll show you. You can also see the website
I designed for the shop. Huge photo of me.
- How ya doin'? Havin' o' the fun?
- You know, I am.
Dancing with you is better than trying
to hook up with some good-Iooking guy.
I think I liked it better when
you were kicking me in my puffy groin.
I let them do that.
Dance together. That was me.
- Very nice of you.
- A good deed.
Yes. I'm expecting a big karmic reward
any second now.
Thank you.
Buffy.
Ben. Hey. I didn't even know you were here.
And again with the nonmedical clothing.
Actually, these are orthopaedic pants.
Man, that sounded so funny in my head.
It's very, very funny.
It's funny in my head, too.
- Havin' a good time?
- Yeah, I am.
I was dancing earlier, and my friends are
here, so... But not that it's all about me.
- Are you enjoying yourself?
- I am now.
So, do you maybe wanna dance?
I'm not really good at rhythm.
Sure. I'd love to.
- Let me just dump this. I'll be right back.
- OK.
Look at these tiny grain patties.
They're woven.
That's craftsmanship.
They aren't handwoven, you know.
- Then how?
- Well, it's a machine,
and it sorta... it presses.
And there may be a mould of some sort...
Who's that?
Warren?
That girl. Tara and I met her.
She speaks with a strange evenness
and selects her words too precisely.
Well, some of us
like that kind of thing in a girl.
Warren?
- Did you get me a drink?
- Gotta go, she'll see me.
- She who? What's up, Warren?
- It doesn't matter. Come on.
- Is Warren here?
- Thought you were gettin' the crunchies.
Xander got hypnotised by the strange girl.
I am remaining calm, however.
No, I'm right with you. You don't know
what you're talking about. Here she comes.
- I heard Warren was here. Is Warren here?
- Warren who?
He's Warren. And he's looking for me.
He lost me.
- Is Warren here?
- It's that girl again.
Is she still looking for Warren?
Weird, it's been, like, all day.
There's something strange about her.
She talks funny.
Some men find that appealing.
- Have you guys seen Warren?
- Let's hope she finds him.
I don't think a girl
that looks like that'll be Ionely for long.
Definitely not.
Not me. I was just saying,
a pretty girl like that,
there's always someone lurkin' around,
lookin' for some action.
Small world.
Oh, dear. If looks could stake.
You havin' fun, pet?
Trollin' for your next ex?
I gotta say, you could do better.
- I told you, I wa...
- Thought I was gonna leave town?
It's a free country.
Free party.
If you want me to leave, you can put your
hands on my hot, tight body and make me.
Get away from me.
Was that guy botherin' you? Should I offer
to get inappropriately violent or somethin'?
- No.
- Good, cos, honestly, I don't wanna.
So, are you ready to dance?
- First...
- What's that?
Oh, yeah, my phone number.
I was gonna try to subtly work it into
the conversation, but it didn't pan out,
and I thought I should try
to give it to you before you see me dance.
You know, in case you wanna get coffee.
Thank you.
I just... I think you should know
that I kinda have this bad history
in which, you know, we go get coffee,
and it all ends with you leaving town,
and you just got here and everything...
Apparently we'd be riskin' a tragic chain
reaction, but I just really like coffee.
I think coffee might be worth it.
And I would like to get to know coffee better.
Then I'll call you.
- Have you seen Warren?
- No, sorry.
And who are you, darlin'?
I'm April.
- I'm looking for my fella.
- Maybe you just found him.
Really? Where?
That would be wrong!
You are not my boyfriend!
Bloody hell!
You threw me through a window!
- What's that about?
- You cannot say that to me.
I have a boyfriend. Warren is my boyfriend.
You know what?
My bleeding sympathies to Warren.
No one but Warren can touch me.
Excuse me. Hi.
Maybe you and I could talk, you know,
cos throwing Spike through
a window, that's really good.
- But, you know, generally speaking...
- Do you know my boyfriend?
OK, I think you need to take a second
and stop looking for your boyfriend.
I have to find him.
If I hurt you just now, I am sorry.
And I hope that your boyfriend
will take good care of you.
I dunno about you, but I've had it
with superstrong women who aren't me.
- At least she didn't do too much damage.
- Double-glazed glass ain't cheap.
And the jamb needs
to be completely repaired.
Dear God, I'm the grown-up
who sees the world through my job.
I'm like my uncle Dave, the plumber,
and I must be shunned.
- OK.
- So, what do you guys think she is?
This may sound nuts, but I kinda
got the impression she was a...
- Robot.
- Yeah, robot.
I was gonna say robot.
What do you think she wants?
- Warren, whoever that is.
- It must be the guy that built her.
It's an unusual name. There's hardly any,
except Warren Beatty and President Harding.
It's probably not either of them.
Can you track down this guy
with only a first name?
Given enough time. I can get a list of the
Sunnydale students named Warren tonight,
but then we'll have to call them
or go to their dorms,
so we probably can't start
narrowing it down till tomorrow.
She could do a lot of damage by then.
To who, Spike?
See how vigorously I don't care.
It didn't sound like she wanted to hurt
Warren. She said he's her boyfriend.
I agree. I'm not sure this is a code red.
Is there a code pink? We need more codes.
OK. We'll track down Warren tomorrow.
I'd better rescue Giles. He's been watching
Dawn while my mom's out on her date,
and I think there's only so much he can take.
Giles and Dawnie?
I bet they ended up having a blast.
Dear God, there's only so much I can take.
We'll have to change the system.
A 14-year-old's too old to be baby-sat,
and it's not fair on her.
- What'd she make you do?
- We listened to aggressively cheerful music
by people chosen for their ability to dance,
we ate cookie dough and talked about boys.
I'm sorry. I'm very, very sorry,
but if it makes you feel any better,
my "fun Buffy party night" involved watching
a robot throw Spike through a window,
so if you wanna trade... No, wait.
- I won't give that memory up for anything.
- Robot? Sounds interesting.
We're gonna work on it tomorrow.
Unless you wanna stay and...
Who wants to hear everything?
..listen to my mom talk about boys.
- Must go. See you tomorrow. Bye, Joyce.
- Bye, Rupert.
Gosh, I'd forgotten
how much fun dating can be.
I don't know. I was right here.
I didn't see Prince Charming.
I didn't even see a good-night kiss.
It looked pretty tame to me.
I suppose by your standards
it could seem pretty...
- Oh, dear.
- What?
I left my bra in his car.
- Mother!
- I'm joking.
- Good God, that's horrible. Don't do that.
- I left it in the restaurant.
No more. No more. No more!
- On the dessert cart.
- I can't hear you.
Yeah? What?
Hi. Does Warren live here?
What the hell...? What are you doin'? It's 3.30!
Yes, it is. Does Warren live here?
OK, then. Bye.
- You're certain she was a robot?
- Absolutely.
She practically had "Genuine
Moulded Plastic" stamped on her ass.
Just tryin' a little spicy talk.
She was looking for someone named Warren.
- Will checked the Sunnydale enrolment.
- And got nothin'.
I found one Warren, but he left the country
a year ago. I'm checking nearby schools.
Whoever he is, he knows his stuff.
That girl, well...
That was a nice-Iookin' girl.
It's OK for him to say that,
cos I know that he really loves me only.
- Is there something we can be doing?
- What can we do?
- Do you have any books on robots?
- Yes, dozens.
There's a lot of research
we should do... No, I'm lying.
I haven't got squat.
I just like to see Xander squirm.
Funny. Charming and funny.
I think I found him.
A Warren Meers. He went to Sunnydale High
with us for a semester,
then he went to the tech college in Dutton.
I've got a local address where his folks live.
- He's probably home for spring break.
- I'll go talk to him.
No, wait. We don't know
what you're walking into.
We have no idea what his motive is
for building this thing.
Don't you think she's just...?
Yeah, she's just sort of a...
She's a sexbot.
I mean, what guy doesn't dream about that?
Beautiful girl with
no other thought but to please you,
willing to do anything...
Too many girls. I miss Oz. He'd get it.
He wouldn't say anything, but he'd get it.
Why would anyone do that
if they could have a real person?
Maybe he couldn't - find a real person.
Come on. The guy's just a big sleaze.
Don't make excuses for him.
I'm not. I'm just saying people get Ionely,
and maybe having someone around, even
someone you made up, maybe it's easier.
But it's so weird. I mean, everyone wants
a nice, normal person to share with.
But this guy, if he couldn't find that,
I guess it's kinda sad.
- Hello?
- Hey. Ben, it's Buffy.
Is this a bad time? I know it's kinda early.
No, I just got in, is all. Night shift
at the hospital. I'm glad you called.
I found your number and figured I'd pick up
the phone a couple of times, then hang up,
and then finally call, and see if
you wanted to get that coffee, or...
Yeah. Yes. Coffee would be great.
Tomorrow night. Sure.
Bye.
Fine.
We just got here. Why didn't we just stay in
Dutton? Or we could've gone to my sister's.
I don't wanna hear about your sister's again.
Pack your stuff.
Why the rush? It's real early. Are we
even gonna say goodbye to your mom?
- You can call her.
- Is there something you're hiding from me?
Katrina, if you don't wanna pack, that's fine.
We can buy new stuff. Now let's just go.
I have to talk to you.
- Who's this?
- Is this about her?
- Yes.
- Her who? Something's going on here.
- Strange girls...
- Please, be quiet. OK? This is important.
- Wait in the kitchen.
- And I'm not important?
- Warren, just tell her to go away.
- I can't.
You're keeping secrets.
Other girls, who knows what else.
Trina, shut up.
That's it. Forget it, Warren. I'm gone.
No. Katrina!
We were at Sunnydale High together.
Do you know who I am?
Yes, I know.
April, did she hurt someone?
Not yet. Well, no one that matters.
She's looking for me. She followed me here.
- OK. Kinda figured that out.
- No, there's more.
- There's something you need to know.
- I know.
- No, wait. This is important.
- Believe me, I worked it out.
No, this is something
that you can't possibly know.
She's a robot.
A robot? Was it Ted? Cos I always said
there could've been more than one of him.
Nope, whole new robot. This one was a girl.
Buffy's trackin' down the guy that made her,
so I'll drop you off, and then...
Comin' through! Comin' through.
Fire! Fire!
Hello, all. What's goin' on, then?
Spike, you're not welcome here.
Yeah, and we're working on a way to de-invite
you from here. Even if it is a public place.
Nah, forget it. Letting him in is good,
cos then we get to toss him out.
Can we throw him out the window
like the robot did? Cos that was neat.
Robot? That's what she was?
I knew somethin' wasn't right.
Hey. Someone's glad to see me.
Aren't you, little bit?
Stay away from me.
- I think you'd better go.
- OK. Now, I was afraid of this.
Misrepresentations,
misunderstandings, slurs and allegations.
I don't know what Buffy told you,
but the thing is,
the Slayer and I worked together to get rid
of Dru, who was up to no good, and I don't...
- Spike. Listen to me.
- It's just, I'm trying to explain.
She might have said some things that
sounded like I expressed some kind of...
We are not your friends.
We are not your way to Buffy.
There is no way to Buffy.
Clear out of here.
And, Spike, this thing. Get over it.
- I don't know what you mean.
- Yes, you do.
Move the hell on.
- I'm looking for my boyfriend Warren.
- What?
He comes from here and I need him.
But it's confusing, and I've already walked
a really long way. I'm sure he's nearby.
Warren. You're lookin' for Warren?
Yes. Do you know him?
Do you know where he is?
- Man, let me think...
- Please think.
Jeez! This is too bad - you just missed him.
Yes? Where did he go?
Warren? He headed out.
That way. Hurry, you might catch him.
Thank you.
I was getting very tired. Thank you.
- Who's Warren?
- Hell if I know.
So you have girl troubles.
You're not gettin' dates.
You start thinking "This isn't fair."
I felt like I deserved to have someone.
Everyone deserves to have someone.
- So, naturally, you turned to manufacturing.
- Kinda.
- How long did it take to build your little toy?
- No, she's not a toy.
I know what you think,
but she's more than that.
I'm sure she has many
labour-saving attachments.
No, I made her to love me.
I mean, she cares about what I care about,
and she wants to be with me.
She listens to me and supports me.
I didn't make a toy. I made a girlfriend.
A girlfriend.
Are you saying...?
Are you in love with her?
I really thought I would be.
I mean, she's perfect.
I don't know, I guess it was
too easy, and predictable.
She got boring. She was exactly
what I wanted, and I didn't want her.
- I thought I was going crazy.
- Really? You?
Then something happened.
Katrina was in my engineering seminar,
and she was really funny and cool.
She was always giving me a hard time -
real unpredictable.
She builds these little model monorails
that run with magnets, and...
Anyway, I fell in love with Katrina.
Swell. Romance and magnetic trains.
But first you decided to play with April
for five minutes, and then what?
You got bored, decided to dump her,
tell her to go away?
- Kinda.
- And she got mad. She didn't go, huh?
OK. I didn't really dump her, as much as
I went out and didn't come back.
- I left her. I left her in my dorm room.
- You left her in your dorm room?
I figured I'd just get away until her batteries
gave up, which should've been days ago.
Did you even tell her? Did you even
give her a chance to fix what was wrong?
I didn't need to. Her batteries were supposed
to run down. They should be dead by now.
- So why aren't they?
- I don't know.
I mean, maybe...
she must be recharging them somehow.
Warren, this is important. Is she dangerous?
She's only programmed to be in love.
Then she's dangerous.
Do you have any idea how to find her?
She's looking for me.
My guess is she's pretty close.
Hi.
Do you know where Warren is?
I need to get to Warren.
This is getting insane.
How many of you are there?
There's only me. April.
April. Fine. Listen up, April.
Warren is my boyfriend. Mine. And you
others probably ought to figure that out.
- Let go.
- Don't go.
- You have to stay and tell the truth.
- What?
Stop!
You're lying. He cannot be your boyfriend.
Say that he's my boyfriend.
I can't breathe.
Let go!
You have to stop lying.
All right, I'll move on.
April! April, are you there?
- If she hears my voice, then she'll answer.
- She's voice-activated?
I made it so that if she heard me
and didn't answer, it causes feedback.
If you call her and she doesn't answer,
it hurts her? You're one creepy little dweeb.
April!
Warren!
- April.
- Where have you been?
I couldn't find you, and this girl kept
lying to me, and then she went to sleep.
April, what did you do?
Please don't be angry, Warren.
I'm trying very hard to make you happy.
April, I want you to put the girl down.
Warren? What should I do?
- Talk to her.
- Put her down.
This is Buffy. Give Katrina to Buffy.
Is she broken?
- She's alive.
- Thank God.
Warren, honey, what's going on?
Why did you go away? Is it a game?
- No. No, this isn't a game.
- Did I do something wrong?
I waited a long time
and you never came back. A long time.
- I made you five sweaters.
- Great. Go and get them.
- You could wait there, and...
- Warren. You have to tell her. And do it right.
What is she saying, Warren?
What do you need to tell me?
April, I made a mistake.
- You can't make mistakes.
- No, I did.
I thought that I made you everything that
I wanted, but it wasn't what I really wanted.
I'm sorry, but it's over.
But I can be whatever you want. I love you.
I'll do whatever you want. Like a neck rub?
No. No. See, I know that you love me,
but the truth is, I can't love you.
It's not your fault, but I don't love you.
I love her.
She growls? You made her so she growls?
Well...
- What's going on?
- No, no, Trina... Get away.
What is...? That's a robot.
- She wasn'tjust for sex.
- Is that your ex-girlfriend?
- No, get the hell away from me!
- No, no. Trina, no. Trina, wait...
You took my man. I'm going to kill you.
I'm going to...
I can't crush!
So tired.
Warren? Where are you?
What's happening to me?
Can you cry? Sometimes I feel better
when I cry. But there might be rust issues.
Crying is blackmail.
Good girlfriends don't cry.
I've rechecked everything. I did everything
I was supposed to do. I was a good girlfriend.
I'm sure you were.
I'm only supposed to love him.
If I can't do that, what am I for?
What do I exist for?
I don't know.
It isn't fair. He wasn't fair to you.
It's getting dark.
It's so early to be dark.
Yeah.
What if he comes back
and he can't find me in the dark?
I'm here. I'll make sure that he finds you.
Maybe this is a girlfriend test.
If I wait here patiently this time,
he'll come back.
I'm sure he will.
And he'll tell you how sorry he is.
You know, he told me
how proud he was of you and...
how impressed he was with how much you
loved him and how you tried to help him.
He didn't mean to hurt you.
He's going to take me home,
and things will be right again.
They'll be fine.
When things are sad,
you just have to be patient.
Because...
because every cloud has a silver lining.
And when life gives you lemons,
make lemonade.
Clouds and lemonade, huh?
Yes.
And...
and...
things are always darkest before....
You construct the wood jamb
and frame the glass into it,
- and that's what you set into the opening.
- Yeah?
One of the cool things about that
is the jamb can be shimmed to be square,
even if the opening isn't.
Shimmed? Is that even a real word? Do you
have any idea what you're talking about?
Yeah, I do. Scary, isn't it?
I've turned into someone
you want around after a crazed robot attack.
And if you ever start your own business,
you have your slogan right there.
And she wasn't crazed.
Yeah?
She devoted everything
to making this one person happy.
And then it was, like, with him gone, there
was just no reason for her to exist any more.
Robots are the strangest people.
No. People are the strangest people.
I mean, look at me
obsessing about being with someone.
It's like I don't need a guy right now.
I need me.
I need to get comfortable
being alone with Buffy.
Well, I'll say this,
she's a pretty cool person to be alone with.
Thank you.
Hi, it's Buffy.
I hope this is your machine.
There wasn't a message.
Anyway, about coffee.
I...
I just... I don't think this is the best time
for me to be drinking coffee.
I'm sorry.
And bye.
- What the hell?
- If I may, Your Inconceivableness.
It sounds to these humble ears like our Ben
tried to make a date with the Slayer.
A date with the Slayer?
No. No. No, no, no. He is planning something,
he's working against me.
She turned us down?
Trina? No, wait. Listen. Listen, I'm so sorry.
I guess I am s... No, no, just give me
a chance to explain. I... Yes.
No, but she... No, no, listen, I'll do anything.
No, don't hang up!
- How did you get in here?
- Your mum let me in.
- I'm placing an order.
- I'm not making any more girls.
Sure you are.
And here's your specs.
You're gonna make her real good for me.
Hey, Mom!
Still a couple of guys gettin' it right.
Hey! Flower-gettin' lady!
Want me to pick Dawn up from school?
Mom?
What are you doin'?
Mommy?
Visiontext Subtitles: Kerrie Slavin
ENGLISH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org