In every generation, there is a Chosen One.
She alone will stand against the vampires,
the demons and the forces of darkness.
She is the Slayer.
Is she dying?
I think she's singing.
To a telephone, in Hindi.
Now, that's entertainment.
Why is she singing?
She's sad because
her lover gave her 12 gold coins.
But then the wizard
cut open a bag of salt...
and now the dancing minions have
nowhere to put their big maypole...
- fish thing.
- Uh-huh.
Why is she singing?
Her lover?
I thought that was her chiropractor?
Because of that thing he did with her feet?
No, that was personal.
And we thought just because we didn't have
any money or any place to go,
this'd be a lackluster evening.
I know! We could go to the Bronze, sneak
in our own tea bags and ask for hot water.
Hop off the outlaw train, Will,
before you land us all in jail.
I, for one, am giddy and up.
There's a kind of hush all over Sunnydale.
No demons or vampires to slay.
I'm here with my friends.
So how does
the water buffalo fit in again?
Callie! Callie.
Where are you going?
The party's just gettin' started.
"Reptile Boy"
See? Dr Debbi says
when a man is speaking,
you make serious eye contact
and really, really listen.
And you laugh at everything he says.
- You dreamed about Angel again?
- Third night in a row.
What did he do in the dream?
- Stuff.
- Oh, stuff.
Was it one of those vivid dreams
where you could feel his lips
and smell his hair?
It had surround sound!
I'm just thinking about him
so much lately.
You two are so right for each other.
- Except for the, uh...
- Vampire thing.
That doesn't make him
a bad person... necessarily.
I'm brainsick.
I can't have a relationship with him!
Not during the day, but... you could
ask him for coffee some night.
It's the non-relationship drink of choice.
It's not a date.
It's a caffeinated beverage.
OK, sure, it's hot and bitter,
like a relationship that way, but...
- What's like a relationship?
- Nothing I have.
- Coffee?
- Huh?
There's really no comparison between
college men and high-school boys.
- I mean, look at that.
- So, Cor, you're datin' college guys now?
Well, not that it's any of your business,
but I happen to be dating
a Delta Zeta Kappa.
Oh, an extraterrestrial!
So that's how you get a date
after you exhausted all the human guys.
You'll go to college someday, Xander.
I just know your pizza-delivery career
will take you so many exciting places.
Oh! I told Giles I'd meet him
in the library ten minutes ago.
Aw, he won't be upset. There hasn't been
much paranormal activity lately.
Just because the paranormal is more
"normal" and less... "para" of late...
is no excuse for tardiness
or letting your guard down.
- I haven't let my guard down.
- Oh, really?
You yawned your way through
weapons training last week, you, you, you,
you skipped hand-to-hand entirely...
Are you going to be prepared if a demon
springs up behind you and does this?
Well, I'm, I'm not a demon.
Which is why you should let go now.
Thank you.
When you live on top of
a... a mystical convergence,
it's only a matter of time
before a fresh hell breaks loose.
Now is the time that
you should train more strictly.
You should...
hunt and patrol more keenly.
You should hone your skills
day and night.
And the little slice of life
that still belongs to me
from, I don't know,
7 to 7.05 in the morning,
- Can I do what I want then?
- Buffy, you think I don't know
- what it's like to be 16?
- No. I think you don't know
what it's like to be 16,
and a girl, and the Slayer.
Fair enough. No, I don't.
Or what it's like
to have to stake vampires
while you're having
fuzzy feelings towards one.
Taking on the undead doesn't
exactly do wonders for your social life.
That's exactly where
being different comes in handy.
Right. Who needs a social life
when you've got your very own Hellmouth?
Yes! You, you, you have
a duty, a, a purpose.
You have a commitment in life. Now,
how many people your age can say that?
We talkin' foreign or domestic?
How about none?
Well, here's a hard fact of life:
we all have to do things we don't like.
And you have hand-to-hand this afternoon
and patrol tonight.
So I, I suggest you come straight here
at the end of, of period six
and, and get your homework done,
and don't dawdle with your friends.
And don't think sitting there pouting
is gonna get to me, because it won't.
It's not getting to me.
Boy, what a long day.
- And you skipped three classes.
- Yeah. And, of course, they flew by.
Buffy.
Aren't you supposed to be doing
your homework in the library?
I'm dawdling... with my friends.
Works for me.
- You OK?
- Jeez.
- Cordelia.
- Hi, Richard.
Nice car.
So, uh, we're having a little get-together
tomorrow night at the house.
And... it's gonna be
a really special evening.
- Excuse me?
- Oh. I would... I'd love, love to go.
So, who's your friend?
- Her? Oh, she's not my friend.
- She's amazing.
She's more like a sister, really!
We're that close.
Why don't you introduce us?
OK.
OK, so tonight, channel 59: Indian TV.
Sex, lies, incomprehensible story lines.
I'll bring the betel nuts.
Come on. Richard and his
fraternity brother wanna meet you.
Well, I don't really wanna meet
any fraternity boys.
If there was a God,
don't you think he'd keep it that way?
Uh, I-I believe we were dawdling here!
- Hi, sweetheart. I'm Richard. And you are?
- So not interested.
- Oh! She's such a little comedienne.
- What? She likes to play hard to get?
No, Richard. I think
you're playing easy to resist.
Feel free to ignore him. I do all the time.
I'm Tom Warner. I'm a senior
at Crestwood College, and I...
And I just feel like a complete dolt
meeting you this way, so...
here I stand in all my doltishness.
Right! Like she's gonna fall for that.
- I'm... Buffy Summers.
- Oh, nice to meet you.
- Are you a senior here?
- Junior.
Oh, me too. Except that
I'm a senior and I'm in college.
So we have that in common.
And... I major in history.
Mm, history stumps me.
I have a hard enough time remembering
what happened last week.
No, nothin' happened last week -
don't worry. I was there.
She's gonna walk away.
Now.
So, uh...
My friend invited your friend
to a party we're having this weekend.
You know, actually
he's not even really my friend.
I only joined the fraternity because
my father and grandpa were in it before me.
You know. It meant a lot to them.
OK, boots, start a-walkin'.
Oh, I know, I talk too much anyway.
They're really dull parties
full of really dull people, so...
Would you like to come
and save me from a really dull fate?
Oh, I wish I could, but...
- I'm sort of involved.
- Oh, sure, of course you are.
Well, thanks for letting me ramble.
You know, people underestimate
the value of a good ramble.
Buffy!
Oh, I gotta go.
- It was nice to meet you.
- Oh. Same here.
I hate these guys. Whatever
they want just falls into their laps.
- Don't you hate these guys?
- Yeah. With their charmed lives
and their movie-star good looks
and more money than you can count...
I'm hating.
I'm going to attack you.
Word of warning for your own good:
I won't be pulling any punches.
Please don't.
Good. So, um, you're on patrol.
And, uh, I'll see you in the morning.
There's blood on it.
Hi.
It's nice to... Blood?
I can smell it.
It's pretty thin.
Probably belonged to a girl.
Probably.
I-I was... just... thinking,
wouldn't it be...
funny some time to see each other
when it wasn't a blood thing?
Not funny ha-ha.
What are you sayin',
you wanna have a date?
- No.
- You don't wanna have a date?
Who said date? I-I-I never said date.
Right. You just wanna have
coffee or something.
- Coffee?
- I knew this was gonna happen.
What? What do you think is happening?
- You're 16 years old. I'm 241.
- I've done the math.
You don't know what you're doing,
you don't know what you want...
Oh. No, I, I think I do.
I want out of this conversation.
Listen. If we date, you and I both know
one thing's gonna lead to another.
One thing already has led to another.
You think it's a little late
to be reading me a warning label?
I'm just trying to protect you.
This could get out of control.
Isn't that the way it's supposed to be?
This isn't some fairy tale.
When I kiss you,
you don't wake up from a deep sleep
- and live happily ever after.
- No.
When you kiss me, I wanna die.
Buffy! Did you lose weight?
And your hair...
All right, I respect you too much
to be dishonest.
The hair's a little...
Well, that really
isn't the point here, is it?
The Zeta Kappas have to have
a certain balance at their party.
And Richard explained it all to me,
but I was so busy "really listening"
that I didn't hear much.
Anyway, the deal is they need you to go.
And if you don't go, I can't.
And I'm talking about
Richard Anderson, OK?
as in Anderson Farms,
Anderson Aeronautics...
and Anderson Cosmetics.
Well, you see why I have to go?
Buffy, these men are rich,
and I am not being shallow.
Think of the poor people
I could help with all my money.
- I'll go.
- You'll go?
Great! I'll drive.
Oh, Buffy, it's like we're sisters!
With really different hair.
- I pledge my life and my death.
To the Delta Zeta Kappas
and to Machida whom we serve.
On my oath, before my assembled brethren.
I promise to keep our secret
from this day until my death.
In blood I was baptized,
in blood I shall reign, in his name.
and in blood I shall reign,
in his name.
You're now one of us.
- In his name!
- Brewski time!
- Party!
So, what's a girl like you
doing in a place like this?
- Please, let me go.
- Let you go?
OK, let me think. Mm, no!
God, I love high-school girls.
You're going to the fraternity party?
What made you change your mind?
- Angel.
- He's going with you?
She's got a date with Angel!
Isn't that exciting?
- I'm elated.
- I, I'm not going with Angel.
I'm going with...
- Ye gods! Cordelia.
- Cordelia?!
Did I sound a little jealous just then?
'Cause I'm not really... Cordelia?
Cordelia's much better for you than Angel.
- What happened with Angel?
- Nothing. As usual.
- A whole lot of nothing with Angel.
- Bummer.
I don't understand.
I mean, he likes you. More than likes.
- Angel barely says two words to me.
- Don't you hate that?
When he does,
he treats me like I'm a child.
That bastard!
You know, at least
Tom can carry on a conversation.
- Yeah! Tom? Who's Tom?
- The frat guy.
Oh, Buffy, I don't think so.
Frying pan, fire?
You know what I'm sayin'?
Will you be ready
if a vampire's behind you?
Didn't see you three... creeping about.
Um, how did it go last night?
I found this.
E-N-T
- I've seen something like that before.
- It's broken in two.
I don't know what the rest of the letters
might have spelled.
- And there's blood on it.
- Oh. I didn't see any.
- Angel showed up. He could smell it.
- The blood?
There's a guy you wanna party with.
- Blood.
- In Sunnydale. What a surprise.
OK, here's what we're gonna do. She should
probably make the rounds again tonight.
And we should try to figure out
who that bracelet belongs to.
Yes, good idea, yes.
She'll patrol, and, and we'll reconvene...
Uh, hello? "She" is standing right here!
- And she's not available.
- Why not?
- Buffy, this is a little more important...
- I've got a mountain of homework to do,
And, um... my mom's not really feeling well
and she could probably use my help.
And, um, to be truthful,
I'm not feeling all that well myself.
Oh, w-well, um, sorry, of course.
If-if-if you're not well.
Oh, I'll take an early pass
this evening, and, um...
one later on, but
for the bulk of the evening...
You should stay home with your mother.
- Well, say it.
- I'm not gonna say it.
- You lied to Giles.
- 'Cause she will.
Look, I wasn't lying.
I was just protecting him
from information that
he wouldn't be able to...
- digest properly.
- Like a corn dog.
Like you don't have a sick mother,
but you'd rather go to a frat party...
where there's gonna be drinking
and older guys and probably an orgy.
Whoa! Whoa, rewind. Since when
do they have orgies, and why aren't I
- on the mailing list?
- There's no orgies!
I heard a lot of wild things go on
at frat parties.
OK, you know what? Look, seven days a week
I am busy saving the world.
Once in a great while
I wanna have some fun.
And that's what I'm gonna have. Fun!
This isn't about fun. This is about duty.
Your duty to help me achieve
permanent prosperity, OK?
Dos and don'ts:
don't wear black, silk, chiffon or spandex.
These are my trademarks.
And don't do
that weird thing with your hair.
- What weird thing with my...
- Don't interrupt.
Do be interested if someone should
speak to you. It may or may not happen.
But do be polite
and laugh at the appropriate intervals.
Do lie to your mom about
where we're going.
It's a fraternity
and there will be drinking.
So, Cor, you printing up business cards
with your pager number
and hours of operation,
or just going with a halter top tonight?
Oh, are we feeling a little envious?
You could belong to a fraternity of rich
and powerful men... in the Bizarro World.
- Do you guys wanna join us?
- Nah. I gotta digest and all.
Make-up, make-up. Well...
Give it your all
and keep to the shadows.
We're gonna have a blast!
I can't believe she lied to Giles.
My world is all askew.
Buffy's lying?
Buffy's going to frat parties?
That's not askew, that's cockeyed.
Askew means cockeyed.
Oh.
Well, there's nothing we can do about it.
We'll help Giles.
- I'm goin' to the party.
- What?
I've got to keep an eye on Buffy.
Those frat guys creep me.
- You wanna protect her?
- Mm-hm.
And prove that you're just as good
as those rich, snotty guys?
- Mm-hm.
- And maybe catch an orgy?
If it's on early.
Why do they park
so darn close to you?
- Are you ready for this?
- I don't know.
- Maybe this wasn't such a good idea.
- Me, too. Let's go.
Come on!
- Beaucoup babes!
- Ooh, yeah!
You know what's so cool
about college? The diversity.
You've got all the rich people
and all of the other people.
- Richard!
- Welcome, ladies.
Thank you.
- Oh. Is there alcohol in this?
- Just a smidge.
Come on, Buffy. It's just a smidge.
- I'll just...
- I understand.
When I was your age
I wasn't into grown up things either.
Have you seen our multi-media room?
Oh, the one with the cherry walnut paneling
and the two forty-eight-inch televisions
on satellite feed?
- No. Wanna show me?
- What about...?
Oh, her? She's happiest by herself.
(#"Wolves" by Clement & Murray)
# Her name's Alexandra,
She walks into the room...
# All the guys' eyes are upon her
- Cheers.
# What a girl! I think
# she's got her hungry eyes on you
# Yeah, you
# She said she
# runs with the wolves
# She thinks she
(# "She" by Louis Says)
# Bend, and I'll break you
# Leave, and I'll take you back again
New girl!
- Easy, man.
- Dance!
# So bend and I'll break you
- Easy, man.
- Come on, sweetheart. Yeah!
- Could I have this dance?
- Come on!
# If she bends, then she breaks...
- Thanks for...
- No.
We're not all a bunch of drunken louts.
Some of us are sober louts!
I'm really glad that you decided to come.
And... you're not.
No. It's...
I shouldn't be here.
Because you're seeing someone.
No.
You're not seeing someone?
Someone's not seeing me.
So... why shouldn't you be here?
Because I have obligations.
People that...
I'm responsible for...
or to... or with...
It's complicated.
You're big on responsibility. I like that.
But there's such a thing
as being too mature.
You should relax...
and enjoy yourself once in a while.
You think I'm too mature?
I talk too much.
Have you picked up on that yet?
Anyway, the, uh, Hulk is gone, so...
you don't have to dance with me.
He might come back.
# She hates you,
but then she makes a mistake
# Confused and a lot to take...
Godzilla's attacking downtown Tokyo!
Who's this dork?
Never seen him before in my life.
We got us a crasher.
So, have either of you seen
a pair of girls here?
One's about... so high?
- Hey, guys.
- New pledge.
- New pledge!
New pledge! New pledge!
You OK?
Yeah. I was just thinking.
To my Argentinian junk bonds
that just matured into double digits.
To maturity.
What the hell. I'm tired of being mature.
- Bent.
- Sent.
Rent.
Uh, Lent. Dent.
Went. Kent.
- Kent! That's it!
- Her boyfriend's name was Kent?
No. Kent Preparatory School.
Just outside of town.
That's where I've seen these bracelets.
- What are you doing?
- Pulling up their school newsletter...
for the past few months
to see if there's anything about...
A missing girl.
Come on, dance, pretty boy! Keep it movin'.
Come on. Shake it! Don't break it!
Wrap it up and I'll take it!
OK, big fun, guys. Who's next?
You are, dollface.
Keep on dancing! All right!
Keep it up, yeah! Come on, keep it goin'!
Tom?
Ooh, sorry.
OK.
Nice bed.
Just need to stop spinning for...
Get away from her!
- I wasn't doing anything.
- I saw what you were doing.
- I was just having a little fun.
- She's not here for your fun, you pervert.
She's here for the pleasure
of the one we serve.
In his name.
And that goes for the other one, too.
Callie Megan Anderson.
Missing for over a week.
No one's seen her.
No one knows what happened to her.
This being Sunnydale and all,
I guess we can rule out something good.
- I'm calling Buffy.
- No!
- Why not?
- Because Buffy... and her mother...
Are sick. You're quite right.
There's no point in disturbing them
until we know more.
You mean like...
if there are others?
Brittany Oswald, junior at St Michael's,
disappeared a year ago.
So did Kelley Percell, sophomore at Grant.
- A year?
- Almost to the day.
An anniversary or perhaps some other event
significant to the killer.
Killer? Now there's a killer?
We don't know that there's a...
No, but this being Sunnydale and all...
Gulp.
We need to know
where Buffy found that bracelet.
We can begin our search there.
Good idea! Call Angel.
He was there when Buffy found it.
We're gonna need
all the help we can get.
- Party's over, jerkwater.
- Wait. A friend of mine was here.
You know, in that light...
with that wig on an' all...
you're still butt ugly!
Buffy, where are we?
In the basement, as far as I can tell.
What's happening?
What did they do to us?
They drugged us.
Why? What are they gonna do to us?
- I don't know.
- I wanna go home.
No one's going home.
Ever.
Look, one of them's...
different than the others.
Nicer.
Tom.
He's the one to watch out for.
- She's last.
- Last? For what?
Who's first?
Answer me!
Three stones.
Three of us.
Buffy...
Stay calm. We'll get out of this.
Why did I ever let you
talk me into coming here?!
She found the bracelet in the cemetery,
near the south wall.
South wall.
What are you doing?
Oh, sorry. The reflection thing
that you don't have.
Angel, how do you shave?
South wall,
that's near the college. And...
the fraternity house!
- A fraternity?
- Could they be taking these girls?
Let's get out there.
Buffy...
We don't know that it's concrete.
Let's not disturb her until...
...is there! With Cordelia!
They went to a party
at the Zeta Kappa House.
- She lied to me?
- Well...
- Did... she have a date?
Well, why do you think
she went to that party?!
Because you gave her the brush-off!
And you never let her do anything
except work and patrol, and...
I know she's the Chosen One,
but you're killing her with pressure.
I mean, she's 16 going on 40!
And you! I mean,
you're gonna live for ever.
You don't have time
for a cup of coffee?!
OK.
I don't feel better now,
and we've gotta help Buffy.
One day I'll have money, prestige, power.
And on that day, they'll still have more.
- Machida.
- In his name.
We who serve you...
we who receive all that you bestow...
call upon you in this holy hour.
This holy hour.
We have no wealth...
no possession, except that
what you give us.
- Except what you give us.
- We have no power...
no place in the world...
- except that what you give us.
- Except that what you give us.
What are they,
some kind of cult or something?
Yeah. Psycho-cult.
- You've gotta do something.
- It's been a year since our last offering.
A year in which our bounty overflowed.
We come before you
with fresh offerings.
Offerings? He's talking about us?
Do you see anyone else
chained up in here?
Accept our offering, dark lord,
and bless us with your power...
- Machida!
- What's down there?
- Come forth
and let your terrible countenance look upon
your servants and their humble offering.
We call you, Machida.
In his name, Machida!
There's something down there
and he's gonna throw us down there with it!
- I don't think so.
- No? Well, that's good. That's...
I don't think we go to it.
I think it comes to us.
Oh, my God!
Come on, Buffy!
Oh, come on!
For he shall rise from the depths
and we shall tremble before him.
He who is the source
of all we inherit and all we possess.
- Machida.
And if he is pleased with our offerings,
then our fortunes shall increase.
Machida, let our fortunes increase.
And on the tenth day of the tenth month,
he shall be enhungered
and we shall feed him.
Feed him?! Oh, no!
Looks like everyone's gone.
- Hey.
- Hey!
What are you guys doing here?
A bunch of girls are missing.
The Zeta Kappas may be involved. And Buffy.
Are you wearing make-up?
No. I think Buffy's still inside
somewhere with Cordelia.
Their car's still here.
- Why are you wearing that?
- I found it in their trash.
I saw them through the window.
They were wearing robes.
They went down to the basement.
I was gonna sneak in.
They may be involved
in some kind of ritual.
- With the missing girls.
- With Buffy!
OK, that is the guy you wanna party with.
- Hey, Reptile Boy!
- No woman speaks to him.
You don't want her. Look at her.
She's all skin and bones.
- Half an hour later you'll be hungry.
- I told you to shut up!
You speak again,
and I'll cut your throat.
Got locked out dumping the trash.
Let me in. I don't wanna miss the, uh...
- Come on.
- You know what. Where are they?
Something's going on upstairs. Go! Go!
Feed, dark lord.
That's for the wig! That's for the bra!
Some guy's attacking Buffy with a sword!
Also, there's a really big snake!
That's for the make-up!
And that's for the last
sixteen and a half years!
Guys! Buffy! Snake! Basement now!
You bitch!
I'll serve you to him in pieces.
Tom, you talk too much.
Help! Help!
Let her go, Wormy!
You did it.
You saved us.
I've never been so happy
to see anyone in my whole...
You guys, I just...
hate you guys.
The weirdest things
always happen when you're around.
And you!
You're goin' to jail for 15,000 years.
I told one lie. I had one drink.
Yes. And you were very nearly
devoured by a giant demon snake.
The words "let that be a lesson"
are a tad redundant at this juncture.
- I'm sorry.
- So am I.
I...
I drive you too hard
because I know what you have to face.
From now on,
no more pushing, no more prodding.
Just, um...
an inordinate amount of nudging.
Come on, come on, hurry!
There you go.
Thank you, Jonathan.
Did we forget something?
Um...
Cinnamon, chocolate, half-caf, non-fat.
Extra foam!
Young men are the only way to go.
Says here that they've all been
sentenced to consecutive life sentences.
"Investigators found the bones
of missing girls in a huge cavern
beneath the frat house.
And older bones dating back 50 years."
"A surprising number of corporations
whose chairmen and founders
are former Delta Zeta Kappas
are suffering from
falling profits, IRS raids..."
Oh, "and suicides in the boardroom."
Starve a snake, lose a fortune.
Boy, I guess the rich
really are different, huh?
Have you heard from Angel?
When he got so mad about you being
in danger, and changed into a... grrr...
it was the most amazing thing I ever saw.
- I mean, how many guys can...
- Angel, Angel, Angel.
Does every conversation we have
have to come around to that freak?
- Hey, man, how you doin'?
- Buffy.
- Angel.
- Xander.
I hear this place, uh, serves coffee.
I thought maybe you and I
should get some...
Sometime.
If you want.
Yeah.
Sometime.
I'll let you know.
# If she bends, then she breaks
# She loves you,
but then she takes it away...
Subtitles' extension and timing by: UAR
...
www.tvsubtitles.net