Previously on ''Buffy the Vampire Slayer'':
- Got a spare bed for a wanted fugitive?
- Hello, Faith.
You got a rough sitch here, trying to turn
a bunch of little girls into an army.
They're potential slayers, just like we were.
Call me Caleb.
- l heard you have something of mine.
- l do now.
No!
l work in mysterious ways.
- Argh!
- Xander!
lt's not a happy scenario,
but we're dealing with the Big Bad
that can be any dead person it wants.
- At long last.
- The Slayer.
We've spent all this time worrying
about the seal and the Hellmouth.
The bad guys always go where the power is.
They're protecting something at the vineyard.
lt's time we go in and take it away from them.
- How about... we don't?
- This is a hell of a lot to ask.
And now suddenly
you're all acting like you can't trust me?
We have to be together on this.
You can't be a part of it.
So l need you to leave.
- l swear l didn't want it to go...
- Don't.
Whether you wanted it or not,
their lives are yours.
Power to the people?
You sound like a child of the seventies.
We're saying we're in charge of ourselves.
- OK, let's try not to freak out.
- Now Buffy's not here,
we have a say in how and when
we lose our necks.
Maybe you don't have to be so blunt
about the losing of the necks bit.
Let the girl speak the truth.
We're all on death's door,
ringing the doorbell like
girl scouts trying to make quota.
Maybe everyone here shouldn't have a say.
We need a way of having
constructive dialogue without going mad.
Do you know the parliamentary procedure?
That's a convenient way of...
- l wonder if...
- We should get into smaller groups,
so it wouldn't be so chaotic.
Faith, what do you think?
When l was involved with the Model UN,
the parliamentary procedure was a lifesaver.
She's gonna be fine.
Really, it's for the best.
Yeah? Then why do l feel like this?
We had a system to allow us
to organise our conversation.
- l hear you, but...
- Shouldn't we get to business?
We're wasting time
arguing about how to argue.
- Why don't we...?
- Do not mention parliament.
- l second that.
- Everyone, listen to me. Chill.
All right? lt's been a long night,
and l don't know about you, but l'm wiped.
We should sleep and
figure it out in the morning.
- Do we have time to waste?
- l understand you guys are wicked stressed.
Frankly, our situation blows.
We've gotta stay cool.
lt's the only way to get through this.
- Can everyone handle that?
- Yeah.
We'll get some rest and then
tomorrow things won't seem so...
- What happened?
- The lights went out?
- (Amanda) l'll get some candles.
- (Kennedy) l'll check the fuse box.
Don't bother.
All the lights on the street went out.
Which means?
The people from the power company
have got the hell out of Sunnydale.
- l think l'm freaking out.
- Someone get a flashlight.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Don't move.
- Get out of my house.
- Hey.
l thought the place'd be empty.
l was looking for a place to crash.
You really should leave.
You can'tjust kick me out of my own house.
Why not? lt's what
all the cool kids are doing nowadays.
lt's not your house.
lt's not your town.
Not any more.
Got any Tab?
(deep sigh)
l spy with my little eye
something that begins with a T.
- Tapestry.
- Good one. How did you...?
Tapestry's the only thing
in the whole bloody room.
So say you, but l say look deeper.
l'll look deep into yourjugular.
- Don't spazz out.
- l'm not...
Don't say another word.
Rock, paper, scissors?
What's the matter with you?
Don't you understand what's happening?
Yeah. We're waiting till it's night so you can
ride on your motorcycle without exploding.
While we're stuck here,
the Slayer's facing hell knows what.
What's the worst thing
that could happen to her?
(growls)
All right. So, what do we know?
We know we're basically
the last humans left in Sunnydale.
And all the evil in town wants us dead.
- l don't wanna die.
- Don't worry.
lt's more likely you'll live long enough
to watch most of your friends die first.
- And then you'll die.
- We also know
Caleb told Buffy everything's going down
at the seal. We should head...
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
We know we've got a lot of enemies.
We'll start there.
- l'm sorry...
- l got this, OK?
Let's go over our rogues' gallery.
Who do we have here?
Well, there's the First, who we can't touch.
There's our friend
the Reverend l Hate Women.
- Who's untouchable.
- There's the ''roid-rage'' vamps,
who are pretty much the worst. And the...
- Bringers. They're our weakest link.
- Are you thinking of attacking the Bringers?
- Maybe, or... OK, we could kidnap one.
- And what? Hold it ransom?
l'll start ripping letters from magazines.
''Dear Mr First,
if you want your Bringer back...
we'll be surprised because
you got three million of them.''
''So please disregard this letter.''
l say we get us a Bringer and make it talk.
- Find out about the First and Caleb that way.
- How do we catch one?
l'm not sure this is such a good idea.
Why look for information
when we know about the seal?
Let's go to the high school, do some recon.
No.
Just like that?
You're not even listening.
Sweetie, you're pushing too hard.
l thought things would change,
but you keep shutting me down.
Things are different,
because now l'm your boss.
Look, you guys, l'm not Buffy.
l'm not the one who's been on your asses,
but l'm not one of you any more, either.
l'm your leader, which means
l go first, and l make the rules,
and the rest of you follow after me.
ls that clear?
So, Kennedy, back the hell off
and let me do my job, all right?
OK, let's get down to business.
l was hoping you'd bring me
some better news.
And l wish l had some.
ls this gonna do anything?
Or is all this just to make the Bringers sweat?
- Do the Bringers sweat?
- Actually, l think they pant, like dogs.
l don't know if this is gonna do any good,
but we have to try everything.
You realise what will happen
if the Slayer and her girls get it?
They won't.
That's right. They won't.
Because you're going to kill all of them
and everyone they know.
Hallelujah.
l've never been the bait before. That was...
- actually, kind of scary.
- We had your back.
You did well. Your performance
as a disgruntled minion was spot on.
l'm Method.
Let's get this back to the Captain.
Oh, hey. So?
The Bringer's dumb.
You were expecting a Rhodes scholar?
- Dumb as in mute.
- Someone ripped out its tongue.
- Gross!
- Hey...
l've been reading this old Turkish spell book.
There's an old conjuration the ancient Turks
used to communicate with the dying.
Oh, yeah. l think l've read a translation of it.
There's a translation of it?
l'm over it.
So the spell is used to communicate
with people who can't talk.
lf a person was dying,
this spell would let them say their goodbyes
or gripe about how
nobody came to visit them.
Would this help us with Mr No-Tongue?
Yeah, l think so. l just need
to get together a few ingredients.
All right, cool.
While Willow does that, the rest of us can...
(Andrew) We're back!
- (Giles) Spike.
- Hey.
Hi, everybody.
l missed you guys a lot.
Sorry it took so long
to get back from our mission,
but we had to wait out the sun.
Well, l think our mission went very well.
We rode on Spike's Hog,
which was very cool, and...
played some amusing games,
and - oh, we got some information.
You know what?
l really need to urinate.
He's a breath of fresh air, isn't he?
Thank God l don't breathe.
So, l think we got a lead.
Where's Buffy?
- Um... she's not here right now.
- When does she get back?
While you were gone,
we all got together and...
talked out some disagreements
that we were having.
And eventually, after much discussion,
Buffy decided that
it would be best for all of us if...
she took a little time off, a little breather.
Uh-huh. l see.
Been practising
that little speech long, have you?
So, Buffy took time off right in the middle
of the apocalypse, and it was her decision?
- Well, we all decided.
- Oh, yeah, you all decided.
You sad, sad, ungrateful traitors.
- Who do you think you are?
- We're her friends. We just...
That's ballsy. You're her friends,
and you betray her like this?
- You don't understand.
- You know, l think l do, Rupert.
You used to be the big man, didn't you?
The teacher, all full of wisdom.
Now she's surpassed you,
and you can't handle it.
She has saved your lives again and again.
She has died for you.
And this is how you thank...
Hey. Why don't you
take it down a notch or two?
- The time for speech-giving is over, Bad Boy.
- Oh, is that right?
- Yeah, that's right. Save your lack of breath.
- All right.
You're pretty sweet on her, aren't you?
l think it's cute.
- The way she's got you whipped.
- (Giles) Enough!
Finally got what you wanted, didn't you?
- Where is she?
- l don't know.
(Willow recites in Latin)
Speak to us.
- Maybe l should rough him up a little.
- Be quiet!
l don't know, guys.
That should have worked.
- l am a drone in the mind that is evil.
- Could you just shut up?
- l say l'm part of the great darkness.
- Somebody needs a reality check.
- Or a muzzle.
- Wait.
l'm only a fragment of the We.
We work as one to serve the First.
OK, what do you - the We - do for the First?
We work to prepare for the inevitable battle.
How? Tell me exactly
what the Bringers are doing.
- Kennedy, he can't see the knife.
- We can feel the knife.
Kennedy?
We attend to the needs of the infinite evil.
We exterminate girls
and destroy the legacy of the Slayer.
We build an arsenal beneath the dirt.
We obey the commands of our teacher Caleb.
Wait. Could we go back to the dirt thing?
We build weapons
to prepare for the coming war
at the farthest edge of town.
We are everywhere.
We are like the ocean's waves.
We watch your efforts and are not scared.
We will laugh at you as you die.
What the bananas?
You are so lucky that you did not
just magically decapitate me.
We've got enough here.
We need Faith in on this.
Gather maps. We need to find a subterranean
space large enough to house an armoury.
l feel used and violated,
and l need a lozenge.
(knocking)
There you are.
Do you realise l could just walk in here,
no invite needed?
This town really is theirs now, innit?
l heard. l was over there. That bitch.
She's all smiles and reformation
when you're on your feet,
but the moment you're down,
she's all about the kicking, isn't that right?
- Makes me want...
- lt wasn'tjust Faith.
lt was all of them.
And it's not like they were wrong.
Please leave.
No. This'll change your tune.
l came here cos l got something to tell you.
You were right. Caleb is trying
to protect something from you.
And l think you were spot on all the way.
l think it's at the vineyard.
So? You were right.
- Buffy?
- l don't feel very right.
You're not fooling me.
- What do you even mean?
- You're not a quitter.
- Watch me.
- You were their leader, and you still are.
This isn't something you gave up,
it's something they took.
And the difference is?
We can take it back.
Sewer tunnel on the north side's closest,
so guess we'll start there.
Sounds fine. What time shall l tell everyone?
How about around seven?
Seven sharp.
- So, tomorrow we fight.
- Tomorrow.
Good night, Faith.
- Faith.
- Yeah?
You're doing just fine.
l'd say better than fine.
l'd say you're doing a bang-up job.
- Get out.
- Well, well! Gosh!
l think a ''hello'' or a ''nice to see you''
might be a little more welcome.
lt's the end of humanity, Faith,
not the end of courtesy.
You're wasting your time.
l know who you are, what you are.
Nobody's explained to you
how this works, have they?
You see, l am part of the First, as you kids
call it, but l'm also me, Richard Wilkins lll,
late mayor and founder of Sunnydale.
Here. l'll prove it to you.
Ask me a question only l know the answer to.
Something like:
Where did l hide the MoonPies in my office?
Or who was my favourite character
in Little Women?
Meg.
l know, l know! Most people guess Beth,
but Meg is such a proper young lady.
Remember when Jo burned her hair?
l know what you're doing.
lt won't work.
But keep talking
cos l could listen to you yap all night.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey. Language!
You're a leader now.
Keep throwing the ''h-e-double hockey sticks''
around, the girls will pick up on it.
- Let me worry about the girls.
- Of course.
You're doing a greatjob.
Much better than Buffy.
- You were smart to kick her out.
- That's not what we...
- Buffy got 'em this far.
- Why are you protecting her?
You think she cares about you?
She nearly killed you, Faith.
lt's different now.
No matter what you do, Buffy will
always see you as a killer, not as a person.
And now you have what she so
desperately wants: the respect of these girls.
All she needs is an excuse to finish what
she started when she stuck that knife in you.
You stay on guard, Faith.
Buffy's dangerous.
lf you're not careful... she'll destroy you.
l'm just sayin'.
- (Spike) No?
- No.
- You mean ''no'' as in ''eventually''?
- You really have problems with that word.
You can get them back.
Can, maybe. Should?
l'm just so tired.
They need you.
- Well, l...
- lt's bloody chaos over there without you.
- lt is?
- Yeah! Yeah. lt's...
There's junk.
Food cartons, sleeping bags not rolled up,
everyone's very scared and... unkempt.
- Sounds dire.
- l didn't see a lot.
l came, hit Faith a bunch of times, and left.
Really? l mean, not that l'm glad, but...
You say the word
and she's a footnote in history.
l'll make it look like a painful accident.
That's my problem.
l say the word, some girl dies.
Every time.
- There's always casualties in war.
- Casualties.
ltjust sounds so... casual.
These are girls that l got killed.
l cut myself off from them. All of them.
l knew l was gonna
lose some of them and l didn't...
You know what?
l'm still making excuses.
l've always cut myself off. l've always...
Being the Slayer made me different.
But it's my fault l stayed that way.
People are always trying to connect to me,
and l just... slip away.
You should know.
l seem to recall
a certain amount of connecting.
Please! We were never close.
You just wanted me
because l was... unattainable.
- You think that's all that was?
- Let's not go over the past.
Oh, no, no. Oh, let's hold on here.
l've hummed along to your pity-ditty.
l should have the mike for a bit.
Fine. The stage is yours. Cheer me up.
- You're insufferable.
- Thank you. That really helped.
- l'm not trying to cheer you up.
- What, then?
l don't know.
l'll know when l'm done saying it.
Something pissed me off, and l just...
- Unattainable, that's it.
- Fine.
l'm attainable. l'm an attain-a-thon.
May l please just go to sleep?
You listen to me.
l've been alive a bit longer than you,
and dead a lot longer than that.
l've seen things you couldn't imagine,
and done things l prefer you didn't.
l don't exactly have a reputation
for being a thinker.
l follow my blood, which doesn't
exactly rush in the direction of my brain.
So l make a lot of mistakes,
a lot of wrong bloody calls.
100+ years... and there's
only one thing l've ever been sure of:
you.
Hey, look at me.
l'm not asking you for anything.
When l say l love you, it's not because
l want you or because l can't have you.
lt has nothing to do with me.
l love what you are,
what you do,
how you try.
l've seen your kindness and your strength.
l've seen the best and the worst of you.
And l understand with perfect clarity
exactly what you are.
You're a hell of a woman.
You're the one, Buffy.
l don't wanna be the one.
l don't wanna be this good-looking
and athletic. We all have crosses to bear.
You get some rest now.
l'll check in before first light.
You can decide how you want.
Spike?
Could you... stay here?
Sure.
That diabolical old torture device,
the comfy chair. lt'll do me fine.
No. l mean... here.
Will you just hold me?
Deep down, you always wanted
Buffy to accept you.
- To love you even. Why do you think that is?
- You a shrink now?
You keep looking for love and acceptance
from these people, these ''friends'' of yours,
but you're never gonna find it.
The truth is, nobody will ever love you.
- Not the way l love you.
- Get out.
- They'll forever see you as a killer.
- l said get out.
l'll always be with you, firecracker,
in everything you do.
(Wood) Faith?
You shouldn't sneak.
l almost took your head off!
- Sorry, l knocked.
- Who... what'd you see?
Just... You're looking spooked.
What happened?
- Are you sure you're all right?
- You wanna rap about my problems now?
Lookin' to be the guy
who puts the ''pal'' in principal?
You know what? l came up here
to talk to you about weapons.
Sorry. l don't know what l'm doing. l'm just...
Listen, l'm gonna leave you alone.
l didn't mean to intrude.
lt was the First.
You're really in the game now. The First
won't show itself unless it thinks you matter.
Lucky me. l'm a player.
Look at that. My hand's shaking.
Demons, vampires, women in prison -
none of that freaks me out.
That's exactly what the First does.
Finds your Achilles heel.
No, itjust talked to me.
What, it does a heal thing too?
lt's a phrase. Your weak spot.
Oh, school thing.
l was kinda absent that decade.
So, who was it? The First.
He was like an old boss of mine.
Just a boss,
and he's got you shaking like this?
- Wouldn't give you a raise, huh?
- Yeah, right.
lt sounds retarded,
but he was like a dad to me.
Oh.
lt was my mother when it came to me.
And l mean it was her,
right down to the perfume.
- Sorry.
- Yeah.
l'm so pissed off at myself.
l knew it was a trick.
So did l, but l still wanted
my mother to hold me like a little baby.
- ln a manly way, of course.
- Of course.
Listen, nobody wants to be alone, Faith.
We all want someone who cares,
to be touched that way.
l mean, the First deals in figments,
but that wanting is real.
Hitting things
and a whole lot of Jack D dulls it some.
Among other things.
When it came to you,
did the First tell the truth?
Yeah.
lt said to watch out for Buffy,
that she's dangerous.
- And what do you think?
- Could be.
We've given her
pretty good reason to be pissed off.
You know the messed-up thing?
The First says to worry about her,
and l just wish she was here.
l'm gonna lead these girls into serious crap,
and she's the only one...
She's not the only one.
You're a slayer too, Faith.
And l think you're a good leader.
l'm an ex-con who didn't finish high school.
Well, l'm the principal of
a school where nobody finished.
- l am completely out of my league in this.
- l hear otherwise.
So...
- Tomorrow, then?
- Forget about tomorrow.
This is tonight.
lt's been a while. Am l out of line?
Hey, you're the leader.
OK, guys. Giles said Faith wants us
to start early in the morning, so...
What happened to the girls?
Looks like there's only one girl here.
What about the other ones with their sleeping
bags and their headgear and their snoring?
- They're not here, are they?
- Nope.
- That's nice.
- Mm.
Nice...
and necessary.
Come here, you.
Foreplay was threatening
to turn into twelve-play.
Something not right?
No.
No, l just...
- l guess l'm a little scared.
- lt's probably stupid to ask why, huh?
- Death, war, apocalypse.
- Me.
l'm just scared that if we...
And then l'll...
- And then...
- And then?
lsn't that the good part?
Good. Yeah, good feeling.
- But also...
- Bad stuff, like,
unrestrained moaning
and screaming with joy?
Sort of. The unrestrained part.
But l've just... l've kind of been
in a space where l... should be restrained.
l've been controlling myself and l...
lf l lose that control,
let myself go, l could just go.
You worried
you're gonna turn into Big Bad Willow?
lt's not stupid. When we first kissed, l...
l turned into... Warren.
lt's not stupid, but it's not gonna happen.
l just want you to know
that you're safe with me.
Yeah?
You can float around and l'll tether you down.
- You'll be like... my kite string?
- Mm-hm.
You'll be a kite,
and l'll be your kite string, OK?
- OK.
Mmm... come here.
- (moaning)
- They could show a little respect, you know.
l mean, they should at least
acknowledge the fact that some people
might not wanna listen to an a cappella
concert of people, moaning and groaning.
- Disgusting is what it is.
- A little jealous, huh?
Of course. l'm a lotjealous.
l mean, if we're done having sex, then...
l think other people should just knock it off.
(# ''Only Love'' by Heather Nova)
(The First) l envy them.
lsn't that the strangest thing?
Well, it does throw me a tad.
l mean, they're just...
Why, they're barely more than animals.
Feeding off each other's flesh.
lt's nauseating.
But you?
You're everywhere.
You're in the hearts of little children.
You're in the souls of the rich.
You're the fire
that makes people kill and hate.
The fire that will cure the world of weakness.
They're just sinners.
You are sin.
- l do enjoy your sermons.
- And you're in me.
Gave me strength no man can have.
You're the only man
strong enough to be my vessel.
And l know you feel me, but...
l know why they grab at each other.
To feel.
l wanna feel.
l wanna wrap my hands around
some innocent neck and feel it crack.
Amen.
So, it turned out that all these stone tablets
basically said the same thing.
The First and Caleb are protecting something,
and we don't know exactly what it is,
but it's something powerful,
and they don't want the slayers to get it.
l'm thinking it could be a weapon,
and if we're looking for an arsenal...
You're not coming.
lf one is looking for an arsenal,
what better place to find a...
Weapon.
- OK. Got it. Good thinking, Andrew.
- lt's a pleasure, Faith. Back to you.
OK, l need you four
to suss out the situation on B.
Don't talk to her or get in her way.
Or let her know you're there.
Just do a little recon.
- Where do you want me?
- By your phone. l'll call you when l need you.
What are we looking for?
ls there a reason to spy on Buffy?
We're just making sure she's OK.
Those of you coming with me to the arsenal,
you know who you are.
Everybody ready?
Let's do this thing.
Shouldn't be long now.
Prophecies say one thing.
Brute strength says another.
- We'll get it out.
- l heard you, Caleb.
- We're almost there.
- Yes, that's true. Now rouse the Bringers.
- Get them back to work.
- (crash)
(Buffy) Hey!
Heard you got something of mine.
Well, if it ain't the prodigal Slayer?
Where's it at?
l'm gonna find it sooner or later.
No, you're not. l lay one hand on you,
and you're just a dead little girl.
Lay a hand on me... if you can.
- This is embarrassing.
- Do you have to look like that?
- Will you concentrate?
- lt's just a little confusing.
Fine. Go. Kill.
Everybody stop.
l think we just found it.
- Look at all this.
- l don't get it.
Why'd they abandon all this stuff?
Maybe cos they didn't.
Aaaargh!
You whore!
You really should watch your language.
lf someone didn't know you, they might
think you were a woman-hating jerk.
ls that it? Not that that wasn't fun, but...
(Kennedy) Yo, Faith. Check this out.
Everybody get down!
Visiontext Subtitles: Claire Bates
Urgh! Argh!
ENGLlSH SDH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org