In every generation there is a Chosen One.
She alone will stand against the vampires,
the demons and the forces of darkness.
She is the Slayer.
May I cut in?
- You all right?
- Oh, thanks to you.
You hurt your hand.
Will you still be able to...
Finish my solo and kiss you
like you've never been kissed before?
You're drooling.
Xander!
You've got a little...
Their ancestors were here
long before we were.
Their progeny will be here
long after we are gone.
The simple and ubiquitous ant.
Now, if you read the homework,
you should know the two ways
that ants communicate.
Miss Summers?
Ways that ants communicate?
With other ants?
From the homework,
ants are communicating...
Touch
and, um...
BO?
Thank God someone finally
found the courage to mention that.
That would be touch and smell,
Miss Summers?
Is there anything else Miss Rosenberg
would like to tell you?
All right. Chapters six through eight
by tomorrow, people!
Can I see you for a moment?
I gather you had a few problems
at your last school.
Well, what teenager doesn't?
Cut school, get in fights,
burn down the gymnasium.
Principal Flutie showed me
your permanent record.
Well, that fire, there was
major extenuating circumstances.
- Actually, it's kind of funny.
- I can't wait to see what you'll do here.
Destructo Girl, that's me.
- But I suspect it's gonna be great.
- You mean "great" in a bad way.
You have a first-rate mind
and can think on your feet.
Imagine what you could accomplish
if you actually did the...
The homework thing?
The homework thing.
I understand you probably have
a good excuse for not doing it.
Amazingly enough, I don't care.
I know you can excel in this class
and so I expect no less.
Is that clear?
Yeah.
- Sorry.
- Don't be sorry. Be smart.
And please don't listen to
the Principal or anyone else's
negative opinion about you.
Let's make him eat that permanent record.
What do you say?
OK.
Thanks.
Chapters six through eight.
Seven, including Cheryl.
I tell you though, her sister
was lookin' to make it eight.
Ooh! Cheryl's sister? The one in college?
Home for the holidays and looking for love.
She's not my type, though. A girl's really
gotta have something to go with me.
Something like a lobotomy?
Xander, how many times've you scored?
- Well, uh...
- It's just a question.
Are we talking today or the whole week?
Ooh! Duty calls.
Babes!
- What are you doing?
- Work with me here.
Blayne had the nerve
to question my manliness.
- I'm just gonna give him a visual.
- We'll show him!
- I don't believe it.
- I know. And after all my conquests.
- Who's that?
- That must be Angel... I think.
That weird guy that warned her
about all the vampires?
That's him, I'll bet you.
Well, he's buff. She never said
anything about him being buff.
You think he's buff?
He's a very attractive man.
How come that never came up?
- Well, look who's here.
- Hi.
I'd say it's nice to see you,
but then we'd both know that's a big fib.
I won't be long.
No, you'll just give me a cryptic warning
about some exciting new catastrophe,
and then disappear into the night. Right?
- You're cold.
- You can take it.
I mean... you look cold.
Oh, right. Give her your jacket.
It's a balmy night. No one needs
to be trading clothing out there!
It's a little big on me.
- What happened?
- I didn't pay attention.
- To somebody with a big fork?
- He's coming.
- The fork guy?
- Don't let him corner you.
Don't give him a moment's mercy.
He'll rip your throat out.
OK. I'll give you
improved marks for that one.
Ripping a throat out
is a strong visual. It's not cryptic.
I have to go.
Sweet dreams to you, too.
That's all he said? "Fork guy"?
That's all Cryptic Guy said - "fork guy".
There are too many guys in your life!
I'll see what I can find out.
God, every day here is the same.
Bright, sunny, beautiful.
How ever can we escape this torment?
- Really! Morning.
- Morning.
Guess what I just heard in the office.
No Dr Gregory today.
Ergo, those of us who blew off
our homework aren't as dumb as we look.
- What happened? Is he sick?
- They didn't say anything about sick.
Something about... missing.
- He's missing?
- Well, let me think.
The cheerleaders were modelling
their new short skirts. I kinda got...
Yeah. Yeah, they said: "missing."
- Which is bad?
- If something's wrong, yeah.
He's one of the only teachers
that doesn't think Buffy's a felon.
I'm really sorry. I'm sure he'II...
Could you help me?
Uh... yes.
I'm looking for Science 109.
Oh, it's um...
I go there every day.
Oh, God, where is it?
Hi. Blayne Mall.
I'm goin' there right now.
It's not far from the varsity field
where I took all-city.
Oh, thank you, Blayne.
It's funny how the earth never opens up
and swallows you when you want it to.
What's wrong?
If Dr Gregory dropped his glasses,
why wouldn't he pick them up?
My name is Natalie French.
I'll be substituting for Dr Gregory.
- Do you know when he's coming back?
- No, I don't, um... Buffy.
- They just tell me where they want me.
- I'll tell you where I want you.
Excuse me, Blayne?
Uh, I was just wondering if you were
gonna pick up where Dr Gregory left off.
Yes. His notes tell me
you were right in the middle of insect life.
The praying mantis is a fascinating creature,
forced to live alone.
Who can tell me why?
Buffy?
Well, the words "bug-ugly"
kind of spring to mind.
There is nothing ugly
about these unique creatures.
The reason they live alone is because they're cannibals.
Well, it's hardly their fault.
It's the way nature designed them.
Noble, solitary and prolific.
Over 1800 species worldwide.
And in nearly all of them the female is larger
and more aggressive than the male.
Nothing wrong with an aggressive female.
"The California mantis lays her eggs
and then finds a mate to fertilise them."
Once he's played his part,
she covers the eggs in a protective sac
and attaches it to a leaf or twig out of danger.
Now, if she's done her job correctly,
in a few months
she'll have several hundred offspring.
You know, we should make
some model egg sacs for the science fair.
Who would like to help me
do that after school?
Good.
Hot Dog Surprise. Be still, my heart.
Call me old-fashioned.
I want no more surprises in my hot dogs.
I wonder what she sees in me.
It's probably the quiet good looks,
coupled with a certain smoky magnetism.
Miss French.
You two are probably
a little too young to understand
what an older woman
would see in a younger man.
- Oh, I understand.
- Good.
A younger man is too dumb to wonder why an
older woman can't find someone her own age
and too deperate to care about
the surgical improvements.
- What surgical improvements?
- Well, he is young.
And so terribly innocent.
Hey, those that can, do.
Those that can't,
laugh at those who... can do.
Gotta carb up for my one-on-one
with Miss French today. When's yours?
Oh, right. Tomorrow.
You came in second. I came in first.
Guess that's
what they call natural selection.
Guess it's what they call a rehearsal.
Rehearsal.
Excuse you!
Medically prescribed lunch.
My doctor ships it daily...
I'll only be here
as long as I can hold my breath.
His head! His head!
Oh, my God! Where's his head?!
Here.
Drink this.
No, thank you.
I've never seen...
I mean... I've never seen anything like...
That was new.
Who would want to hurt Dr Gregory?
He didn't have any enemies
on the staff that I'm aware of.
He was a... civilised man.
I liked him.
So did I.
We're gonna find out who did this.
We'll find them and we'll stop them.
- Count on it.
- What do we know?
Not a lot. He was killed on campus,
I'm guessing the last day we saw him.
- How do you work that out?
- He didn't change his clothing.
This is a question that
no one particularly wants to hear.
But... Where did they put his head?
Good point. I didn't want to hear that.
Angel. He warned me
that something was coming.
Yes. Yes, he did, didn't he?
I wish I knew what he meant.
I've been trying to gather
more information about the Master, our...
local vampire king.
There was one oblique reference to
a, a, a vampire who...
displeased the Master
and cut his hand off in penance.
Cut off his hand
and replaced it with a fork?
I don't know what he replaced it with.
- So why would he come after a teacher?
- I'm not certain he did.
There was an incident two nights ago
involving a homeless person
in Weatherly Park.
He was practically shredded,
but... nothing like Dr Gregory.
- Fork Guy doesn't do heads?
- Not historically.
And Dr Gregory's blood wasn't drained.
So there's something else out there
besides Silverware Man?
Oh, this is fun. We're on Monster Island.
We're on a Hellmouth.
It's a centre of mystical convergence.
Guess it's the same thing.
Unpleasant things
do gravitate here, it's true.
But we don't know there's anything
besides this chap.
He's still our likely suspect.
Where was that guy killed?
Weatherly Park?
Buffy, I know you're upset,
but this is no time to go hunting.
Not until we know more.
Please, promise me
you won't do anything rash.
Cross my heart.
Shouldn't be out here at night,
little lady.
It's dangerous.
Hold it! Police!
- I heard it. Spread out!
- Let's go over here. This way.
- You went hunting last night?
- Yes.
When you assured me you wouldn't?
Yes, I lied. I'm a bad person.
Let's move on.
- Did you see someone with a fork?
- More like a jumbo claw.
Oh.
- At least you're not hurt.
- And I saw something else.
Something much more interesting than your
average run-of-the-mill killer vampire.
Oh?
Do you know Miss French, the teacher
that's subbing for Dr Gregory?
Yes. Yes, she's lovely.
In a common,
extremely well-proportioned way.
Well, I'm chasing Claw Guy last night and
Miss Well-Proportioned is heading home.
The Claw Guy takes one look at her
and runs screaming for cover.
- He what? Ran away?
- He was petrified.
- Of Miss French?
- Uh-huh.
So, I'm an undead monster
that can shave with my hand.
How many things am I afraid of?
Not many, and not
substitute teachers, as a rule.
So what's her deal?
I think perhaps it would be a good idea
if we kept an eye on her.
Then I'd better get to class.
You were there.
You saw Dr Gregory, didn't you?
Um... You mean yesterday,
in the cafeteria, when we found him...
Don't say "dead" or "decapitated",
or "decomposing".
I'd stay away from D-words altogether.
But you witnessed the event,
so this way, please.
- No, I'm gonna be late for biology.
- Extremely late.
You have to see a counsellor. Everyone who
saw the body must see a crisis counselor.
-  I really don't need...
- We all need help with our feelings
otherwise we bottle them up and before you
know it powerful laxatives are involved.
I really believe if we all reach out
to one another, we can beat this thing.
I'm always here if you need a hug.
But not a real hug,
because there's no touching.
This school is sensitive to wrong touching.
-  But I really, really...
- No!
You have to talk to a counsellor
and start the healing. You have to heal.
- But, Mr Flutie, I don't...
- Heal!
I don't know what to say.
It was really... I mean...
One minute you're in your normal life,
and then who's in the fridge?
It really gets to you, a thing like that.
It was...
Let's just say I haven't been able
to eat a thing since yesterday.
I think I lost like
seven and a half ounces.
Way swifter than that so-called diet
that quack put me on.
Oh, I'm not saying that we should
kill a teacher every day
just so I can lose weight.
I'm just saying
when tragedy strikes, we have to
look on the bright side. You know?
Like how even used Mercedes
still have leather seats.
Keep your eyes straight ahead
on your own test.
I think you meant "pollination"
for number 14.
I'll see you here after school.
Oh, great. A pop quiz.
No, I'm not saying she craned her neck.
We are talking full-on "Exorcist" twist.
- Ouch.
- Which reminds me...
How come Blayne, who worked with her
one-on-one yesterday, isn't here today?
Inquiring minds wanna know.
Any luck?
I've not found a creature as yet
that strikes terror in a vampire's heart.
Try looking under "Things That Can
Turn Their Heads All The Way Around".
- Nothing human can do that.
- No, nothing human.
But there are some insects that can.
Whatever she is,
I'm gonna be ready for her.
What are you going to do?
My homework.
Where are the books on bugs?
- Hi.
- Oh, hi.
I was just grabbing a snack.
Can I fix you something?
No, thanks. I never eat
when I'm making egg sacs.
- If this were real, the bugs would be...
- As big as you.
Yeah. So, where do we start?
Oh, Xander,
I've done something really stupid.
- I hope you can forgive me.
- Forgiveness is my middle name.
Actually, it's LaVelle, and I'd appreciate it
if you'd guard that secret with your life.
I have a teachers' conference
in half an hour
and... I left
the paint and paper-mâché at home.
I don't suppose you'd like to come
to my place tonight to work on it there?
Come to, uh... your place?
Seven thirty?
Here's my address.
- I'll see you tonight.
- Yeah.
Ooh, yes!
Dig this. "The praying mantis can
rotate its head 180 degrees while waiting
for its next meal to walk by." Huh!
Well, come on, guys. Hah!
Well, Miss French is sort of big for a bug.
And she is, by and large, woman-shaped.
OK. Factoid one: only the praying mantis
can rotate its head like that.
Factoid two: a pretty whacked-out vampire
is scared to death of her.
Factoid three:
her fashion sense screams predator.
- It's the shoulder pads!
- Exactly.
If you're right, then she'd have to be
a shape-shifter or a perception-distorter.
Half a mo. I had a chum at Oxford. Carlyle.
Advanced degrees
in entomology and mythology.
- Entomo... who?
- Bugs and fairy tales.
I knew that.
If I recall correctly, poor old Carlyle,
just before he went mad,
claimed there was some beast...
Buffy, 911.
Blayne's mom called the school.
He never came home last night.
The boy who
worked with Miss French yesterday?
Yeah. If Miss French is responsible for...
Xander's supposed
to be helping her right now!
He's got a crush on a giant insect!
OK, don't panic.  I'll warn him.
But I need you to hack on
to the Coroner's Office for me.
- Whoa. What are we looking for?
- Autopsy on Dr Gregory.
I've been trying to figure out
these marks that I saw on his corpse.
I'm thinking they were teeth. And...
these cuddlies should
definitely be brushing after every meal.
And you were saying something about a beast?
Oh, yeah. I just need to make
one transatlantic telephone call.
Um...This computer invasion
Willow's performing on the Coroner's Office
One assumes is entirely legal?
- Of course.
- Entirely.
Right. Wasn't here, didn't see it,
couldn't have stopped you.
Good idea.
- Hey.
So how'd it go with Miss French?
Oh, it's a bit demanding being her
absolute favourite guy in the universe,
but I'll muddle through.
- Xander, she's not what she seems.
- I know. She's so much more.
OK, um... I'm gonna have to
tell you something about her and
I'm gonna need you to really listen, OK?
OK?
I don't think she's human.
I see. So if she's not human, she's...
Technically? A big bug.
This sounds really weird.
I'm aware of that.
It doesn't sound weird at all.
I completely understand.
- I've met someone and you're jealous.
- What?
Look, there's nothing I can do about it.
There's just this certain chemical thing
between Miss French and me.
I know. I read all about it.
It's called a... um... a pheromone.
It's a chemical attractant
insects give off.
She's not an insect! She's a woman, OK?
And, hard as that may be
for you to conceive,
an actual woman finds me attractive.
I realise, it's no mystery guy
handing out leather jackets.
And while we're on the subject,
what kind of a girly name is Angel, anyway?
- What does that have to do...
- Nothing! It just kinda bugs me.
Look, I really gotta...
Hi. Come on in.
Should I change? Is this too...
No! No. It's the most beautiful chest...
dress I've ever seen.
Thank you. That's sweet.
Martini?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Would you like something else?
I just need to relax a little.
I'm kind of nervous around you.
You're probably cool as a cucumber.
I like cucumbers,
like in that Greek salad with yoghurt.
Do you like Greek food?
I'm exempting Schwarma, of course,
I mean, what's that all about?
It's a big meat hive.
Hello!
Cheers.
Can I ask you a personal question?
Have you ever been with a woman before?
You mean like in, uh... the same room?
You know what I mean.
Oh, that. Well, let me think.
Yeah, there was several.
I mean, and... uh, quite a few times.
And then there was...
Oh, she was incredibly...
- No. Uh-uh.
- I know.
- I can tell.
- You can?
Oh, I like it.
You might say I need it.
- Oh, well, needs should, you know,
- Somebody help me!
needs should definitely
be met as long as
-  it doesn't require ointments
- I'm down here!
- the next day or... Do you hear?
- No.
- It sounds like someone cry...
- I don't hear anything.
Your hands are so hot!
Oh, you hurt your hand.
Buffy.
I love Buffy.
- Wow. So that's a martini, huh?
- Mm-hm.
Do you hear?
Would you like to touch me
with those hands?
Your hands are s...
really serrated.
Oh, wow, that martini. I...
really think I have to...
Miss French?
Please, call me Natalie.
Frankly, madam, I haven't the faintest idea
what time it is, nor do I care!
Now, unlock his cell, unstrap him
and bring him to the telephone immediately!
This is a matter of life and death!
Got it. Coroner's report
complete with - yuck - colour pictures.
They are teeth marks,
which match perfectly
the one insect that nips off its prey's head.
OK, I don't like this.
That's the way they feed. Head first.
It's also the way they mate.
The female bites off the male's head
while they're...
No, no, no! See, Xander's...
I like his head.
It's where you find his eyes
and his hair and his adorable smile.
Hey, hey, take it easy, Will.
Xander is not in any immediate danger.
I saw him leave school.
He's probably safe at home right now.
- Blayne!
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
Are you all right?
You gotta get me outta here. You gotta.
She... she... she gets you and...
- What? What does she do?
- She... she...
Oh, God. Oh, no.
- Blayne, what does she do?
- She... she...
She... she takes you out of the cage,
and... she ties you up
and... and she starts movin' and throbbin'
and these eggs come shootin' out of her.
- And then... and then...
- What? Then what?
she mates with you.
- She...?
- That's not the worst part.
- That's not?
- You seen her teeth?
While she's... you know,
right in the middle of...
I saw her do it!
- I don't wanna die like that.
- Blayne. Blayne, chill.
That's good. It's gonna be OK.
We'll get out of this.
You got a plan? What is it?
- Just, uh, let me perfect it.
- Oh, God.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
I understand, Carlyle.
Yes, I'll take every precaution.
Absolutely. It sounds exactly
like the creature you described.
You were right all along, about everything.
No, you weren't right about your mother
coming back as a Pekinese, but...
Try to rest, old man. Yes. Ta-ta.
Bye now.
Dr Ferris Carlyle spent years
transcribing a lost pre-Germanic language.
What he discovered he kept to himself,
until several teenage boys were
murdered in the Cotswolds.
Then he went hunting for it.
- "It" being...?
- He calls her a She-Mantis.
This type of creature, the kleptes-virgo
or virgin-thief, appears in many cultures.
The Greek sirens,
the Celtic sea maidens who
tore the living flesh from the bones of...
Giles, while we're young.
Well, basically the She-Mantis
assumes the form of a beautiful woman...
and then lures
innocent virgins back to her nest.
Virgins?
Well, Xander's not a... a...
- I mean, he's probably...
- Gonna die.
OK, OK. So this thing is breeding
and we need to find it and snuff it.
Any tips on the snuffing part?
Carlyle recommends cleaving
all body parts with a sharp blade.
- Slice and dice.
- Whatever you do, it'd better be
sudden and swift. This beast is
extremely dangerous.
Well, your buddy, Carlyle, faced it
and he's still around.
Yes, in a straitjacket,
howling his innards out day and night.
- OK, Admiral, way to inspire the troops.
- Sorry.
Xander's not home.
He told his mom he was
going to his teacher's house
to work on a science project.
He didn't tell her where.
See if you can get her address
off the substitute rolls.
And you need to record bat sonar, and fast.
Bat sonar. Right. What?
Bats eat them. A mantis hears sonar,
its entire nervous system goes kaplooie.
- Where am I gonna find...
- In the vid library.
There're no books, but it's dark and musty.
You'll feel right at home. Go!
I guess I'll handle the armoury.
Don't do anything to make her mad.
Hey, all right! Now I can get out of my cage!
- Into yours. What'd you do that for?
- A weapon.
I think you're gonna need it.
- Getting the address.
- Great. Giles?
Recording bat sonar is something soothingly
akin to having one's teeth drilled.
Let's roll.
According to Miss French's
personnel records, she was born in 1907.
- She's, like, 90 years old.
- And extremely well-preserved.
Oh, God!
He did that. He broke the cage.
Take him, not me. Take him!
What now?
We can't just kick the door down.
Yeah, that would be wrong!
Hello, dear. I thought I heard...
Are you selling something?
Because I'd like to help you out,
but, you see, I'm on a fixed income.
- I'm looking for Miss French.
- I'm Miss French.
Natalie French,
the substitute biology teacher?
Goodness, that's me!
I taught for over 30 years.
I retired in 1972.
I can't believe this!
She used Miss French's records
to get into the school.
She could be anywhere.
No, dear. I'm right here.
What's she doing?
I think it's
eeny, meany, miney
Mo?
I'm comin'. I'm comin'.
What do we do now?
Abject prayer and supplication
would spring to mind.
I saw her walking past this park
with her grocery bags.
She lives in this neighborhood.
- I'm gonna bang on doors.
- Wait! No. We do not have time for that.
- We have to do something!
- We will.
I won't be long.
Buffy?
- Oh, yeah, here it comes.
- What's happening?
How do you like your eggs, bro,
over easy or sunny-side up?
Eggs? She's gonna lay some...
"The Californian mantis lays her eggs
and then finds a mate to fertilise them."
Come on, Buffy!
- You!
- Me.
Come on! Come on! Where is she?
Which house is it?
I know you're afraid of her. I saw you!
Come on, come on.
What? What is it?
This is her, isn't it? This is her house.
This is it! Better than radar!
Buffy!
Kiss me.
- Kiss me.
- Can I say one thing?
Help!
Uh, hey! O-over here!
Hello! In the cage!
Let him go!
- Help me!
- Get them out of here.
Help me! Help me!
Remember Dr Gregory?
You scarfed his head.
Yeah, well, he taught me:
you do your homework, you learn stuff.
Like what happens to your nervous system
when you hear this.
"Extremely important to file
not simply alphabetically..."
- Giles!
- It's the wrong side!
Bat sonar. Makes your
whole nervous system go to hell.
You can go there with it.
Well, I'd say it's deceased.
And dissected.
- You OK?
- Yeah.
Just for the record, you were right.
I'm an idiot, and God bless you.
- And thank you guys, too.
- Yeah, really.
- Pleasure.
- I'm really glad you're OK.
It's so unfair
how she only went after virgins.
What?
I mean, here you guys are,
doing the right thing,
the smart thing,
when a lot of other boys your age...
Flag down on that play, babe.
I am not...
Well, you see,
that's the She-Mantis' modus operandi.
Uh, she only preys on the pure.
Well, isn't this a perfect ending
to a wonderful day!
My dad's a lawyer.
If anybody repeats this to anybody,
they're gonna find themselves
facing a lawsuit.
Blayne, shut up!
I don't think it's bad.
I think it's really... sweet.
But it's certainly nothing
I'll ever bring up again.
(# Stoner Love by Superfine)
# It's ladies choice snowball,
the guys are in line
# he knows who he's waiting for
# and she goes and picks somebody else
# then a stranger finds him, he says,
I heard a rumour there was
one less vampire walking round,
making a nuisance of himself.
There is. I guess
I should thank you for the tip.
The pleasure's mine.
Of course, it would be easier
if I knew how to get in touch with you.
I'll be around.
Or who you were.
Well, anyway, you can
have your jacket back.
It looks better on you.
Oh, boy.
All midterm papers
will be exactly six pages long.
No more, no less.
One third of your grade
will be dependent on those papers.
No more, no less.
Subtitles by: Natasha Cohn
Corrected by: UAR
...
www.tvsubtitles.net