Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
We go live to our field reporter,
who is at the waterfront
with this breaking news
about the murder that has shocked
the Mayor and residents of Sunnydale,
Fishermen discovered the body
today, the victim of a brutal stabbing,
Everyone was shocked when the slain man
was identified as Deputy Mayor, Allan Finch,
Still reeling from the news,
Mayor Wilkins had this to say:
Mr Finch was not only
my longtime aide and associate,
he was a close personal friend,
I promise you, I will not rest until whoever
did this is found and brought to justice,
Thank you very much,
Honey, you're up. It's just terrible, isn't it?
I want you to look into this. Find out all you
can about the murder of the Deputy Mayor.
But that's... I mean, that's not really
our jurisdiction, is it?
- It's no big, B. We'll get into it if he wants.
- No. Buffy's right.
The Deputy Mayor's murder was caused by
human malice. Nothing supernatural about it.
We don't know that for certain.
I say it merits investigation.
Which I'm sure the police are doing.
In the meantime, if you ask me,
there are better uses for the slayers' time.
But I don't believe I did ask you.
Considering the success
of your previous adventure...
Don't let me interrupt.
Wait. Let me interrupt. I'm in a hurry.
- What did you need?
- Psych class. Freud and Jung. Book me?
Happily.
Check out Giles, the next generation.
What's your deal?
I...
Well...
- I'm...
- New watcher.
- Does everybody know about you?
- She's a friend.
Let's not exaggerate.
So you're the new watcher.
Wesley Wyndam-Pryce.
I like a man with two last names. I'm Cordelia.
- And you teach psychology?
- I take psychology.
- She's a student.
- Well... Yes.
In fact, I am here to watch.
Girls. Buffy and Faith, to be specific.
Well, it's about time
we got some fresh blood around here.
Well, fresh.
Yes.
- Here we go.
- Thanks.
So, welcome to Sunnydale.
My.
She's cheeky, isn't she?
First word, "jail", second word, "bait".
Well, where were we?
Done.
I mean, we were done, right?
Yep. Off to patrol. So we'll see ya.
One moment, girls.
I am your commander now and,
on the matter of this murder, I am resolved.
"Natural" or "super", I want to know.
Fine by me. Always ready
to kick a little bad guy butt.
So, you gonna rat me out? Is that it?
Faith, we have to tell. I can't pretend to
investigate this. I can't pretend I don't know.
But you can pretend Angel's dead
when you need to protect him.
I am trying to protect you.
If we don't do the right thing,
it'll make things worse for you.
Worse than jail for the rest
of my young life? No way.
- What we did was...
- Yeah. We.
You were there beside me
when this thing went down.
Anything I have to answer for, you do too.
You're a part of this, B. All the way.
- Hey.
Where's Faith? I saw her around.
Figured you two were gonna
go kill some more nasty stuff.
Not right now. I think she bailed.
- Will, I...
- Actually, I...
You go ahead.
I'm late.
I'm meeting Michael, the warlock guy.
We're still tryin' to "de-rat" Amy.
OK.
So, see ya.
See ya.
So you heard the man scream
about what time last night?
I'm not sure. Seven. Maybe eight.
Can you be more specific?
Say, between seven-thirty and eight?
- Your hand.
- It's OK.
It's not working.
It does something besides shred?
It's supposed to cheer me up! Usually,
using the shredder gives me a lift. It's fun.
- And today you're not gettin' the ya-yas.
- No.
It'll take more than this
to turn my frown upside down.
I just don't understand why Allan would
leave such a paper trail about our dealings.
Do you think he was gonna betray me?
Now that's a horrible thought.
And now he's dead,
I'll never have the chance to scold him.
Maybe this'll change your mood.
- What is it?
- A bombshell.
The Deputy Mayor had
wooden splinters in his wound.
Struck right through the heart
with a sharp, pointed object.
Word is, someone was fighting vampires
not a block away from the scene.
The smart money says
it was a slayer who did this job.
What, do you think he talked? To them?
If he did,
I'm thinkin' he said the wrong thing.
Well, this is exciting.
The Slayer up for murder one.
That's sunshine and roses to me. It really is.
I'm tellin' you, we did the world a favour.
This guy was about as interesting
as watching paint dry.
Faith...
Joking. Jeez, lighten up a little, B.
He came out of nowhere.
I know.
Whatever. I'm not lookin' to
hug and cry, learn and grow.
I'm just saying it happened quick, you know?
You know what? Let's just blow.
Who cares what this guy was about?
It's moot now, don't you think?
I don't think he was in that alley by chance.
He was looking for us.
- I'd like to know why.
- So you think there's some big conspiracy?
You were saying?
So his papers are gone.
Doesn't prove anything.
Except that somebody
didn't want us to prove anything.
- Get as many men on it as you can.
- Yeah.
We'll be wantin' to turn up the heat.
So the Mayor of Sunnydale is a black hat.
That's a shocker, huh?
- Yeah. I didn't get the bad guy vibe off him.
- When are you gonna learn, B?
It doesn't matter
what vibe you get off a person.
Nine times outta ten the face
they're showing you is not the real one.
I guess you know a lot about that.
What is that supposed to mean?
Look at you, Faith.
Less than 24 hours ago you killed a man.
And now it's all zip-a-dee-doo-dah?
That's not your real face and I know it.
I know what you're feeling.
I'm feeling it, too.
Do you? So fill me in, cos I'd like to hear this.
Dirty. Like something sick creeped inside you
and you can't get it out.
And you hope it was just some nightmare,
but it wasn't.
- And we'll have to figure out...
- Is there gonna be an intermission in this?
Just let me talk to Giles. I swear...
We're not bringing anybody else into this.
Keep your head.
This will blow over in a few days.
And if it doesn't?
If it doesn't,
a freighter leaves the docks twice a day.
- Ain't fancy, but it gets you gone.
- And that's it? You live with it?
You see the dead guy in your head
every day for the rest of your life?
Buffy, I'm not gonna see anything.
I missed the mark last night. And I'm sorry
about the guy. I really am. But it happens.
Anyways, how many people do you think
we've saved by now? Thousands?
You stopped the world ending. In my book,
that puts you and me in the plus column.
We help people.
It doesn't mean we can do what we want.
Why not? The guy I offed was no Gandhi.
I mean, he was mixed up in dirty dealings.
Maybe. But what if
he was coming to us for help?
What if he was? You're still not seeing the
big picture, B. Something made us different.
- We're warriors. We were built to kill.
- To kill demons.
It does not mean we can pass judgement,
like we're better than everybody.
We are better.
That's right. Better.
People need us to survive.
In the balance, nobody's gonna
cry over a random bystander
who got caught in the crossfire.
I am.
That's your loss.
Buffy.
Tell me again.
You got home at what time last night?
Late. A little past one, I guess.
Maybe you can explain to me
what a girl your age is doin' out all night.
Just hangin'.
Hanging? By yourself?
No. I was with my friend, Buffy.
- We were at Faith's, watching TV.
- What did you watch?
Some old movie.
Infomercial.
That's funny. Cos I've got a couple of
witnesses who put you near the alley.
Witnesses?
Somebody stabbed this guy through
the heart. Strange thing is the weapon.
It was made outta wood.
Any of this mean anything to you?
Yeah. That whoever did it
wasn't hip to the Bronze Age.
Is that it? I'm kinda beat.
Yeah. I have enough for now.
Buffy, if you know something,
if you're protecting someone,
I promise you, it'd be better for everyone
if you come clean.
You mean, am I covering for someone?
Hardly. I'm not the
"throw myself on the sword" type.
I wish I could help you.
Well, call me if you remember anything.
Hey.
I need to talk to you.
Good. Cos I've been letting things fester.
And I don't like it.
I wanna be fester-free.
Yeah. Me too.
I mean, don't get me wrong.
I completely understand why you and Faith
have been doing the bonding thing.
You guys work together.
You should get along.
- It's more complicated than that.
- But, see,
it's that exact thing that's ticking me off.
It's this whole "slayers only" attitude.
Since when wouldn't I understand?
You talk to me about everything.
It's like all of a sudden
I'm not cool enough for you
because I can't kill things
with my bare hands.
Buffy, don't cry.
I'm sorry.
I was too hard on you. Sometimes I unleash.
I don't know my own strength.
It's bad. I'm bad.
I'm a bad, bad, bad person.
Will, I'm in trouble.
And Faith acts like she doesn't even care.
The way she talks,
it's like she didn't even make a mistake.
Do you think she's, like, in shock?
I don't know. But I think that detective
knows more than he's saying.
- I think he knew that I was lying.
- You have to go to Giles, Buffy.
He'll know what to do.
Giles?
Buffy.
I don't really know how to say this,
so I'm just gonna say it.
I know I've kept things from you before, but...
But...
But I've been blowing off my classes,
you know, in the sense of not attending.
- And...
- It's OK, Buffy. I told him.
- You told him?
- I had to.
He had to know what you did.
What I did?
Giles, no. That's not what happened.
- I don't want to hear it.
- No, I...
- I want no more lies.
- You can't be serious. You're setting me up?
In my office. Faith, we'll talk in the morning.
- Giles, please, you have to...
- Now.
I'm sorry.
Giles, I didn't do this. I swear.
Look, I know that I messed up badly.
But the murder was...
Faith. I know.
She may have many talents, Buffy,
but fortunately lying is not one of them.
Oh, God.
- I thought...
- I'm sorry.
I needed her to think that I was on her side.
I don't know how far she'll take this charade.
Try far.
Like, all the way.
- You should have come to me right off.
- I know.
Well, I wanted to.
- But Faith wouldn't hear of it?
- It's not all her fault.
We both thought it was a vampire.
I only realised a second before.
Buffy, this is not the first time
something like this has happened.
It's not?
The Slayer is on the front line
of a nightly war.
It's tragic, but accidents have happened.
- What do you do?
- Well, the Council investigates.
Metes out punishment if punishment is due.
I have no plan to involve them.
I mean, it's the last thing
Faith needs at the moment.
She's unstable, Buffy.
She's utterly unable to accept responsibility.
She's freaking.
So then we just have to help her deal, right?
She's in denial. There is no help for her
until she admits what happened.
I could talk to her.
Perhaps.
Or maybe I'm too close.
- Maybe one of the guys could?
- We should meet.
It may be that they're seeing
a different side of her.
OK.
In the meantime,
no one else is to know. Understood?
Of course.
Now this is extremely delicate.
If we scare her off now,
we may lose her forever.
Yes, hello. Mr Travers, please.
Quentin Travers.
Wesley Wyndam-Pryce calling.
The codeword? Monkey.
M-O-N-K... Just put him on, will you?
This is an emergency.
Maybe we should talk to Faith together,
You mean, like that intervention thing
you guys did on me?
As I recall, Xander and I
nearly came to blows.
You nearly came to blows.
I nearly came to loss of limbs.
No, Faith is too defensive
for a confrontation like that.
She'd respond better
to a one-on-one approach.
I can be the one. On her one.
Let's rephrase. I think she might listen to me.
We kind of have a connection.
A connection? Why would you think that...
I'm saying it's worth a shot. That's all.
No, I don't see it, Xander.
I mean, of all of us, you're the one person
arguably Faith has had the least contact with.
Yeah, but we hung out a little.
- Recently. And she seemed to be responsive.
- When did you guys hang out?
She was fighting one of those
apocalypse demon things and I helped her.
- Gave her a ride home.
- And you guys talked?
Not extensively. No.
Then why would you...?
I don't need to say "Oh". I got it before.
They slept together.
Fine. Let's move on.
Look, I know that you mean well, Xander,
but I just don't see Faith opening up to you.
She doesn't take the guys that she
has a connection with very seriously.
They're kind of a big joke to her.
No offence.
Oh, no. I mean,
why would I be offended by that?
However, if you still want to be of assistance,
I need some help with research.
There's still the business of
the Mayor and Mr Trick to attend to.
Yeah. They seemed pretty cosy
the other night.
Willow, can you access the Mayor's files?
What?
Sure. I can try.
Good. Yes. Because, clearly,
we'll need to take a harder look at him.
He's obviously up to something.
What about Faith?
I don't know. We need time.
She needs help now.
I owe her that.
What?
I just came by to see how you are, actually.
Sick of people asking me that, for one thing.
Can I come in? Just to talk, I promise.
Think something could happen
if I didn't want it to?
Yeah. You got me there.
Pretty much not gonna try to take ya
under any circumstances.
See? Here. Feel that.
Probably like a wet noodle to ya, huh?
- Five minutes.
- That's all I need.
For talking.
In conversation, I'm quick as a bunny.
The clock is running.
It's just I heard about what happened
and I thought you might need a friend.
So go talk to Buffy.
She's the one who killed the guy.
Yeah. I heard that version.
Version?
Either way, it sounds like it was an accident
and that's the important part.
No. The important part is that
Buffy is the "accidental" murderer.
Faith, you may not think so,
but I sort of know you.
And I've seen you post-battle. And I know,
first hand, that you're like a wild thing.
And, half the time,
you don't know what you're doin'.
And you're living proof of that, aren't you?
See, you can try to hurt me, but right now
you need someone on your side.
What happened wasn't your fault. I'm willing
to testify to that. In court, if you need me.
You'd dig that, wouldn't you?
To get up in front of all your geek pals and
say how I made you my boy toy for a night.
- No. No, that's not it.
- I know what this is all about.
You came by here
cos you want another taste, don't you?
No.
I mean, it was nice. It was great.
It was kind of a blur.
But, OK.
Someday, sure, yay.
But not now.
Not like this.
Well, like how then? Lights on or off?
- Kinks or vanilla?
- Faith, come on.
I came here to help you.
I thought we had a connection.
You wanna feel our connection?
It's just skin.
I see. I want. I take.
I forget.
No. Wait.
- It was more than that.
- I could do anything to you now.
And you want me to.
I could make you scream.
I could make you die.
Finally decided to tie me up, huh? I always
knew you weren't really a one-slayer guy.
I'm sorry about the chains.
It's not that I don't trust you. It...
Actually, it is that I don't trust you.
That thing with Xander... I know what
it looked like, but we were just playin'.
And he forgot the safety word.
- Is that it?
- Safety words are for wusses.
I bet you're not big on trust games, Faith.
You gonna shrink me now, that it?
No. I just wanna talk to you.
That's what they all say.
And then it's "Just let me stay the night.
I won't try anything."
You wanna go the long way around?
I can do that.
I'm not gettin' any older.
- How's she doing?
- It's like talking to a wall.
- Only you get more from a wall.
- But you'll keep trying?
Sure. We're just gettin' started.
- So what do I do?
- Look, right now there's nothing you can do.
This could take a while.
So I'll go to Faith's and get some of her stuff.
- That way she'll see that we're on her side.
- That's a good idea.
- OK. I'll be back.
- Look, I...
I don't want you to get your hopes up, Buffy.
She may not want us to help her.
She does.
She just doesn't know how to say it.
She killed a man.
That changes everything for her.
Giles said, with counselling,
they might not lock her up.
That's not what I mean.
She's taken a life.
I know.
She's got a taste for it now.
Not one slayer, but two.
Right here in the building.
- There was supposed to be a guard.
- Here comes my favourite part.
Where the slayers see us
in the hall together, thick as thieves.
Wait, we are thieves. And worse.
And now they know it.
They're not gonna be much of a threat in jail.
We don't have near enough
evidence to put 'em away.
No. You're gonna have to come up
with a more efficient solution.
And, Mr Trick, you'd better think of it soon.
I know what's goin' on with you.
Join the club.
Everybody seems to have a theory.
But I know what it's like to take a life.
Feel a future, a world of possibilities,
snuffed out by your own hand.
I know the power in it. The exhilaration.
- It was like a drug for me.
- Yeah?
Sounds like you need some help.
A professional, maybe.
A professional couldn't have helped me.
It stopped when I got my soul back.
My human heart.
Goody for you.
If we're gonna party, let's get on with it.
Otherwise, let me out of these things.
Faith, you have a choice.
You've tasted something few ever do.
I mean, to kill without remorse
is to feel like a god.
Right now, all I feel
is a cramp in my wrist. Let me go.
But you're not a god.
You're not much more than a child.
Going down this path will ruin you.
You can't imagine the price for true evil.
Yeah?
I hope evil takes MasterCard.
You and me, Faith,
we're a lot alike.
Time was, I thought humans existed
just to hurt each other.
But then I came here.
And I found out that there are
other types of people.
People who genuinely wanted to do right.
And they make mistakes. They fall down.
But they keep caring. Keep trying.
If you can trust us, Faith, this can all change.
You don't have to disappear into the dark.
What?
By the order of
the Watchers' Council of Britain,
I am exercising my authority
and removing you to England,
where you will accept the judgement
of the disciplinary committee.
I'm sorry for the extreme measures.
Unfortunately, this is
a rather extreme circumstance.
Whatever.
Please believe,
nobody is rushing to judgement.
The first priority of both myself
and the Council is to help you.
Now, none of that.
Tighten her restraints.
Faith, there's no point in fighting this.
Have to disagree with you. Unlock these
or I'll pop this guy's head like a grape.
Don't even think about it.
Faith, you can't keep running.
Wrong again, Wes.
It was the new watcher.
He had a couple of guys helpin' him.
Then he figured it out?
Which means Faith will be soon on her way
to England to face the Watchers' Council.
- And then what?
- They'll lock her away for a good long while.
So we head them off at the airport
and stop them.
Can I... I'm just wondering. Why?
I'm not the most objective, I know.
I kinda have an issue with Faith
sharing my people.
But she murdered someone
and accused Buffy.
Then she hurt Xander.
I hate to say it,
but maybe she belongs behind bars.
She's out of control. But Angel was getting
somewhere with her. She was opening up.
- If we could just stop Wesley...
- That's no longer an issue.
- You let her get away?
- "Let" wouldn't be how I'd phrase it, but...
- Yes, she escaped.
- That's good work.
Terrorise her,
then put her back on the streets.
That was hardly my plan.
I was trying to save her.
- But you didn't. You probably destroyed her.
- Buffy, that's enough.
We'd better find her
before she does any more damage.
Let's split up. I'll check the docks.
She's probably there.
Giles, you go to her motel.
Xander, Willow, her haunts. And be careful.
I'll try the airport.
What can I do? I want to help.
Still got your ticket back
to the mother county?
You don't give up, do you?
Not on my friends, no.
Yeah. Because you and me
are such solid buds, right?
We could be. It's not too late.
For me to change and be more like you,
Little Miss Goody Two Shoes?
- It ain't gonna happen, B.
- Faith, nobody's asking you to be like me.
- But you can't go on like this.
- It scares you, doesn't it?
Yeah, it scares me. You're hurting people.
You're hurting yourself.
That's not it.
That's not what bothers you so much.
What bugs you is you know I'm right.
We don't need the law. We are the law.
No.
Yes. You know what I'm about.
You have it in you, too.
- No. You're sick.
- I've seen it. You've got the lust.
- I'm not just talkin' about screwin' vampires.
- Don't bring him into this.
It was good, wasn't it? The sex? The danger?
Bet a part of you even dug him
when he went psycho.
- No.
- You need me to toe the line
because you're afraid you'll go over it.
You can't handle the way I live.
It tempts you. You know it could be you.
- There's my girl.
- No. I'm not gonna do this.
Why not? It feels good. Blood rising.
I hear, once you've tasted a slayer,
you never wanna go back.
Oh, no.
No, this is no good at all.
So she saved you?
She could have left me there
to die, Giles, but she didn't.
She opted to come back to town with you.
That bodes well.
She still has a lot to face
before she can put this behind her.
I'm not gonna give up on her.
Then I think she stands a chance.
You sent your boy to kill me.
That's right. I did.
- He's dust.
- I thought he might be.
What with you standing here and all.
I guess that means you have a job opening.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org