Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
- So it's her. Under our noses all this time.
- Glorificus will find the witch.
- Witch?
- Tara.
- You're not the Key, you're nothing.
- No.
Tara.
- I'm so sorry.
- They kill mice.
- Not if I get the Key first.
- Could you do it?
Take a human life with your own hands?
I told you this wasn't over.
Such pure green energy.
The Key.
Just pack the supplies we need
and that's it - we're gone.
- Giles.
- I see them.
- Buffy.
- How is he? Will?
He's stabilised, but there's
a lot of damage. We need to get him out.
We got company.
The Key.
Once the Key is activated, the walls
separating realities will crumble.
Dimensions will bleed into each other.
I won't let anything happen to you.
- Let me out.
- Will, open a door.
No.
- Buffy.
- Dawn.
Buffy, you have to get up. Buffy, please.
Buffy.
Quickly. Already we're behind schedule.
Someone's bound for a beheading.
Let's make sure it's not me.
Why do we remain when our moment
of triumph lies so close-at-hand?
The Glorious One, having acquired much
in this world, doesn't exactly travel lightly.
Minions, I can hear you.
Godlike ears don't miss much,
you know what I'm sayin'? Come here.
- He blasphemed, Magnificence.
- Spurred by treacherous urging.
Guys. I'm not gonna kill you.
Not in the mood.
What do you think that's about?
- In mercy does your power lie?
- No, brainless.
In torture, death
and chaos does my power lie.
So tell me, why am I not popping
your head like a zit right now?
- Maybe I'm just hungry.
- Yes, we shall fetch a lovely...
No, I'm not hungry.
I'm just a little tight in this skin, is all.
I've been waiting an eternity...
well, 25 human years.
And it all comes down to tonight.
- The portal shall open...
- And the great Glorificus shall return...
..to the Hell I came from,
where I'm gonna rain down
more supersized portions of slaughter,
mayhem and bloodshed
than any of you scabs can even dream about.
So, how come I ain't happy?
Got everything I ever wanted.
Still, something's off.
I don't know. What do you think?
Better part of a century spent in delinquency
just paid off. Hot-wired Ben's auto.
- Who's for gettin' the hell out?
- All in favour. Let's do it.
- You good to go?
- Don't worry about me.
- How's Buffy?
- The same.
- Still.
- It's been almost a half an hour.
Slayer's gonna be all right, won't she?
You should try again, Will.
All right, but I'm not even sure she's,
you know, really in there.
Try.
Can you hear me? Buffy.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Buffy.
She can'tjust be braindead.
I mean, she's still Buffy,
somewhere in there, right?
Spike, we won't get
Dawn back by sittin' here.
You won't any way you slice it.
That's for Buffy to decide.
Good, panic. That oughta help.
We should move her.
Unless we shouldn't. Should we?
Couldn't that make it worse?
I think I've read that somewhere.
I am so large with not knowing.
It's impossible to know for sure.
Losing Dawn, after all
that Buffy's been through...
It's pushed her too far,
into a sort of catatonia.
You don't need a diploma
to see that. Snap her out of it.
Buffy.
- Rise and shine, love.
- Spike.
Come on, people. Girl's endowed with slayer
strength. Hardly time to get dainty. Buffy.
We tried that.
We didn't try that.
Are you insane?
This could be neurological damage.
- You wanna kill her?
- We have to do something.
I can'tjust sit watching.
You waste time with kid gloves.
I'll wager, when all's said and done,
Buffy likes it rough.
Separate.
Buffy's out. Glory has Dawn.
Some time real soon, she's gonna use Dawn
to tear down the barrier
between every dimension there is.
So, if you two wanna fight,
you do it after the world ends, OK?
All right. First we head back to Sunnydale.
Xander'll take Giles to a hospital.
Anya's looking after Tara.
And Spike, you find Glory.
Check her apartment, see if she's still there.
Try anything stupid, like payback,
and I will get very cranky.
Everyone clear?
Anya.
What will you do?
- I'll help Buffy.
- OK, then.
The world is spinning.
Straight to a new day. Big day.
Will?
Now don't turn me into a horned toad for
asking, but what if we come across Ben?
I don't think a doctor's
what Buffy needs right now.
Well, yeah, especially not one
who also happens to be Glory.
- What do you mean?
- You know. Ben is Glory.
You mean, Ben's with Glory?
- "With" in what sense?
- They're working together?
No. Ben is Glory. Glory's Ben.
They're one and the same.
- Well, when did all this happen?
- Not one hour ago.
Right here, before your very eyes.
Ben came, turned into Glory, snatched
the kid and vanished, remember?
You do remember?
Is everyone here very stoned?
Ben. Glory. He's a doctor, she's the Beast.
Two entirely separate entities
sharing one body.
It's like a bloody sitcom.
Surely you remember.
- So you're saying Ben and Glory...
- Have a connection.
Yes, obviously, but what kind?
I get it. That's very crafty.
Glory's worked the kind of mojo
where anyone who sees her little
presto-change-o instantly forgets.
And yours truly, being somewhat
other than human, stands immune.
So, Ben and Glory are the same person?
Glory can turn into Ben,
and Ben turns back into Glory.
And anyone who sees it instantly forgets.
And a kewpie doll for the lady.
Excellent.
Now. Do we suspect that there may be some
kind of connection between Ben and Glory?
The Key.
Unbelievable how annoying
the groupies can be.
They merely sense that tonight
the dimensional portal shall open...
Ushering in the long
and bloody reign of the great...
What's he doing?
I must anoint the Key.
Really, don't. Go.
- But...
- Get out.
You know, you recapture your
godhood and unleash Armageddon,
all of a sudden everybody wants
to be a part of the inner circle.
You OK?
I wanna go home.
Sweetie...
You're about to.
Not that fake suburban nightmare
the monks cooked up. Your real home.
As the Key.
You fit in a lock. Well, it's like a lock.
You want a pizza?
No.
Pillow? I don't know if
this thing gets cable. Doubtful.
Please. Stop.
- You nervous?
- Yes.
I know how you feel.
It is your last night.
As, you know, a human.
This body? It's just a rental, Dawnie.
Being human? It's like a costume
for girls like you and me.
Being something else, that's what we are.
Don't.
- What?
- Don't call me Dawnie.
Wow.
You know, that actually hurt my feelings.
- I'm sorry.
- Not the point.
I'm just thinking,
I'm trying to make you feel better,
when comforting others... not part of my life.
And I'm doing it so I can stop feeling so...
- Help me out.
- Guilty?
Guilty. That's it.
But I'm not supposed to feel guilty.
I'm not supposed to feel anything. I'm a god.
I'm above it. I'm...
You.
You did this to me, didn't you?
Some sort of spell. You've been
hanging with the Wicca, you could've...
But no. Not magic. It's something else.
Still, it is you doing this.
I'm not doing anything. I swear.
We'll see.
Anoint this thing now.
You know what they're all chanting
for out there, Dawnie? Blood.
Cos we found out your blood
is the key to the Key.
All I gotta do is bleed you dry,
the portal opens up, and I can go home.
So knock yourself out, girlfriend.
Make me feel bad as you can.
Cos tomorrow you bleed, little girl.
- You sure you know what you're doing?
- I think so.
I don't know.
It's not exactly
well-explored territory, but I gotta try.
A spell like this could be really
dangerous for Buffy. And you.
Time. Time is coming.
It's OK. I'm here.
- You'll look after her while I'm...
- Sure. What do I do?
Mostly just be here for her.
There's some pills in my knapsack. Half of
one every two hours keeps her pretty mellow.
You think you'll be gone
more than two hours?
- Wish me luck?
- OK.
Good luck.
Thanks.
OK. Be good now, sweetie.
I'll be back as soon as I can, OK?
We're good?
Good luck.
Hi, Willow.
Hello, Buffy.
What are you doing here?
Actually, I'm looking for you.
Do you like dolls?
- Buffy, what are you doing here?
- I like it here.
But you know we need you.
You have to come out.
- Why?
- To be with your friends.
It's a big day for me.
- Hello.
- Mommy, Daddy.
- You're back.
- Hello, Buffy.
How's my girl?
Are you ready to meet your new baby sister?
Come on now, Buffy.
She's nothing to be afraid of.
- Who's afraid?
- Don't you want to be the big sister?
- No. I want to be the baby.
- Buffy.
You're gonna pay more attention
to her and forget all about me.
Doesn't she look funny?
Like a wrinkly old grandpa.
Like this. OK, support the head.
There you go. We're calling her Dawn.
Dawn.
I could be the one to look after her
sometimes, if you need a helper.
Mom, can I take care of her?
Yes, Buffy, you can take care of her.
OK.
Can you...
There. How you doin'?
It only hurts while I answer
pointless questions. Where's Buffy?
Willow's on it. Or in it. She's workin' some
spell, trying to reach Buffy psychically.
She's gone into Buffy's mind?
- Pretty trippy stuff.
- It's extraordinarily advanced.
I was thinking we should check
on Glory's victims while we're here.
The mental ward? I already been.
The vegetable section's closed.
It's like they all just got up and walked away.
I checked out Glory's flat.
Looks like the great one has scampered.
Gone to perform her ritual with
Dawn and leaving us entirely clueless.
Not entirely.
I know this bloke. Well,
not so much a bloke so much as demon.
But still, bookish. All tuned in to
the nastier corners of this, our magic world.
It's a bit of a last resort really, but still,
we might persuade him
to suss out Glory's game plan.
Sound worthy?
Off we go, then. Meet back at the shop?
I found Ben's room at Glory's.
Didn't learn much.
Wait. Ben? At Glory's? You're saying
all this time he's been subletting from her?
This is gonna be worth it.
Last time. From the top.
- I'm hating this, Murk.
- This would be what exactly, Your Holiness?
Memories. I'm starting to
remember the things Ben did.
People he spoke with, stuff he wore...
Kid.
I came... He came to see you, didn't he?
- Ben?
- Yeah, Ben.
You called him to the desert
when you were hiding from me. And he came.
- And then he was me, you remember?
- Yes.
See? She's not supposed to
remember that. Nobody should.
The cloak between Ben and me is fading.
I almost helped her. He... I wanted to.
I can't do this.
- Get him out of me.
- What?
Ben. The human meat sack
who's infecting me.
Do your mojo, make an incision,
or removal, or whatever you gotta do.
Help me. I'm thinking Ben's thoughts,
and I'm feeling his feelings.
And I...
Can't kill the girl.
Damn it.
- Help me.
- This I cannot do.
You risk terrible magics
in opening the portal.
Nothing comes without a price.
This is yours.
Gods don't pay.
We do this now.
I know you. You're the first original Slayer
who tried killing us all in our dreams.
- How've you been?
- Death is your gift.
- Death is my gift?
- Wait. Death is her what?
Death is your gift.
Where are you going?
Glorificus, wait.
Kill the Key now and all will be lost.
We'll be stuck on this
mortal plane for ever.
All right, you're right. It's cool.
I'm just a little emotional right now
which, if you're into irony, funny.
Leave. We need a little girl time.
Goodbye.
How do they do it?
- Do what?
- People.
How do they function in the world
with all this bile running through them?
Every day it's "Whoo-hoo!" You have
no control. They're not even animals.
They're just meatbaggy slaves to hormones
and pheromones and their feelings.
Hate 'em. I mean, really.
Is this what the poets go on about? This?
Call me crazy, but as hard-core drugs go,
human emotion is just useless.
People are puppets. Everyone getting
jerked around by what they're feeling.
Am I wrong? Really, I wanna know.
Gonna bleed you either way.
- Depends on the person.
- So you're saying some people like this.
- Some.
- Funny.
Cos I look at this world
you're so eager to be a part of,
and all I see is six billion lunatics
looking for the fastest ride out.
Who's not crazy? Look around.
Everyone's drinking, smoking,
shooting up, shooting each other,
orjust plain screwing their brains out
cos they don't want 'em any more.
I'm crazy? Honey, I'm the original one-eyed
chicklet in the kingdom of the blind.
Cos at least I admit the world makes me nuts.
Name one person who can take it here.
That's all I'm asking. Name one.
Buffy.
I can't keep following you around
like this, Buffy. We have to go.
You have to talk to me.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
Death is my gift.
Yeah. I keep hearing that, but
I'm not exactly sure what it means.
It's really not that complicated.
Not for you, maybe.
It's what I do. I mean, come on.
You've known me for how long?
It's what I'm here for. It's all I am.
Buffy, stop. No.
God, no.
What? I keep telling you, Will.
I figured it out. Death is my gift.
Ben, this is really not a good time.
Dawn. Has Glory hurt you?
No. Not yet.
But I have to get out of here.
Ben?
Are you OK?
Where is it?
- Where's what?
- All the blood.
I can feel it, still warm and wet.
Glory. Oh, God.
She slaughtered hundreds of men.
But I can feel them breaking.
Ben, something is happening
to both you and Glory.
I'm rememberin' her, aren't I? The things
she's done. Things she's going to do.
I know. She told me.
I think, whatever the magic is that keeps
you guys apart is starting to break down.
Ben, Glory could come back any minute.
- How could she do this?
- I don't know.
- We have to get out of here and find Buffy...
- No! I mean, I have ajob. I have a life!
And Glory? She never once
thinks about me in all this.
- Help me.
- How?
Highness.
- Please.
- Is everything all right?
You're not...
I'll take you as far as I can,
ditch you before she's back.
OK, now, this is weird.
Hi, Willow. What are you doing here?
Actually, I'm looking for you. Here. Again.
- Do you like dolls?
- No.
And I think we already déjà'd this vu.
- You talk funny.
- Yes.
As you'll tell me again
when we're older and in chem class.
- Buffy, what are we doing here?
- Don't you like it here?
We don't have time.
- Mommy, Daddy.
- We're home.
- You're back.
- Hi, Buffy.
We're calling her Dawn.
I could be the one
to look after her sometimes.
It's always open.
What can I do for you boys?
Want some cocoa?
- No. We need information. We need...
- Ben's Glory.
- Who's what?
- Look at this. Special Ed remembers.
Yeah. I do. Ben's Glory and Glory's Ben.
It's like this fog's lifted.
Wonderful. But not why we're here.
Hell-god type. Name of Glory...
- AKA Ben.
- ..has gone missing.
She's brewing up some major-league bad,
and she's nicked the Slayer's kid sister.
That girl you brought here. Sweet little thing.
How'd things work out with her mom?
Changed her mind, didn't she?
Yeah. You got any idea
where Glory would take her?
Glory.
You don't mean Glorificus?
Gosh. What do you wanna
get mixed up with her for?
That's a sure way to get yourselves
killed. I hear she's awfully unpleasant.
When it comes to Hell gods, my best advice
is get out of the way, and stay there.
Love to. Can't.
Well, other than that...
I'd like to help, but I'm a small-town guy.
This Glorificus, if it is her, she's big city.
- She's got Dawn.
- Right.
Well, I may know a fella, you know,
who knows a fella in China. He might...
How the hell are we
to get to China? Teleport?
I guess. You know, if you're
in that much of a hurry. Wish you luck.
You're lying.
And what's more, I believe you're standing
right in front of the very thing we need.
Idiot.
Get him.
You think only underworld
bottom feeders worship the Beast?
Her day is coming, boys.
And when she returns,
then you're gonna see somethin'.
- What have we got?
- Something worth dying for.
Buffy, will you just stop
a second and listen to me?
- Buffy. You have to stop doing this.
- Doing what?
- Killing Dawn.
- Why?
Because this never happened.
You never killed your sister.
- Will, I did this.
- In your imagination.
None of this is real.
You're stuck in some kinda loop.
I don't know what you're
talking about. Excuse me.
Buffy, why are you doing this?
I think they see us.
Stay close to me. Don't look back.
Stay very still.
I'm sorry.
Sorry?
That actually hurt, you prepubescent puke.
OK, first thought, just totally spontaneous,
unfiltered, off the top of my head...
You hit Ben in his soft human head,
and I remember the pain.
You probably think I won't waste
any precious blood of yours till tonight.
You're right. But I know a thousand ways
to hurt you that won't spill a drop.
You know those pesky feelings
I've been having? Guilt, empathy?
I'm gonna take 'em and mash 'em
back down where they belong, OK?
Now. Let's have big-girl fun. Just you and...
Leave her alone.
I said, leave her alone.
No. Little late in the game
to grow a backbone, Benjamin.
Now be good and stay quiet.
No, you don't. Get over yourself, Ben.
This is the way things are.
I'm strong, you're weak.
This is reality. Stop trying
to infect me with your...
Do you ever stop talking?
I don't know which is worse,
waking up in a dress not knowin' where I've
been, or hearing your self-involved ranting.
- Animal.
- Wrong, Glory. I'm no animal.
This is humanity you're feeling.
Welcome to the world.
No, no, no.
- Stick around, chica.
- I won't let you hurt her, Glory.
Shut your hole,
you sanctimonious little meat worm.
I'm going home no matter what you do.
- You really think I'll just let that happen?
- Benjamin, what are you doing?
You need her blood? When I'm through
there won't be enough to fill a bottle cap.
- Then you, Hell bitch, have nowhere left...
- To go.
You can't hurt her and you know it, Ben.
I know it because
I feel what you're feeling. Scared.
It's OK. You don't wanna die.
Who would? I don't.
You can't, you're immortal.
Nobody has to die here, Ben.
Just let me bleed the girl and go home.
Everything'll work out fine.
Do you believe, with all I know,
that you can trick me?
Stop and think, baby.
We bleed the kid,
return me to my seat of power,
- I become a god again...
- And I disappear.
Unless somebody up there likes you.
Give up the girl, I could like you a lot.
- I won't make a deal with you, Glory.
- When exactly did you get stupid?
I'm offering immortality here.
I believe you. That's not the problem.
You make me immortal, then what?
I'd have to kill her. I can't live with that,
not even for a day. Forget about eternity.
Baby, baby Ben. Why do you worry so much?
When you're immortal, all this crap
you've been carryin' around inside,
the guilt, the anger, the crazy-makin' pain,
it all just melts away like ice cream.
Trust me. When all this is over
I can set you up real nice.
I'm making it easy. It's you or the girl.
I can't accept that.
Accept it. I'm a god, stupid.
I'm sorry.
Don't make this harder than it already is.
I'm sorry, I got no choice. It's you or me.
No. Buffy, leave Dawn alone. What is this?
My gift. This is what I do.
I'm not talking about this.
I'm talking about this.
Right here, it happened. I know it's
something small, but it's something.
- What?
- Don't go there, Will.
I'm not. You're the one who
keeps dragging me back here.
And you wouldn't be doing that if you
weren't trying to show me something.
Do I?
Buffy, come on. It's your brain. Just tell me.
What happened here?
This was when I quit, Will.
- You did?
- Just for a second.
I remember.
I was in the magic shop.
I put a book back for Giles.
Nothing special about it.
And then it hit me.
- What hit you?
- I can't beat Glory.
Glory's going to win.
You can't know that.
I didn'tjust know it.
I felt it. Glory will beat me.
- And in that second of knowing it, Will...
- I wanted it to happen.
- Why?
- I wanted it over.
This is... All of this...
It's too much for me.
- I just wanted it over.
- If Glory wins, then Dawn dies.
And I would grieve.
People would feel sorry for me.
But it would be over.
And I imagined what a relief it would be.
I killed Dawn.
Is that what you think?
My thinking it made it happen.
Some part of me wanted it.
And in the moment Glory took Dawn...
I know I could have done something better.
But I didn't.
I was off by some fraction of a second.
- And this is why...
- I killed my sister.
I think Spike was right back at
the gas station. Snap out of it.
- What?
All this, it has a name. It's called guilt.
It's a feeling, and it's important.
But it's not more than that, Buffy. Buffies.
You've carried the weight of the world
on your shoulders since high school.
And I know you didn't ask
for this, but you do it every day.
And so you wanted out
for one second. So what?
- I got Dawn killed.
- Hello. Your sister, not dead yet.
But she will be if you stay locked
inside here and never come back to us.
And what if I can't?
Then I guess you're right.
And you did kill your sister.
Wait.
Where are you going?
Where you're needed. Are you coming?
Buffy? She's back.
- You're OK?
- Yeah. I'm OK.
- Hear you found the ritual text.
- Something like that, yes.
- Did you know that Ben is Glory?
- So I'm told. What do we know?
Well, according to these scrolls,
it is possible for Glory to be stopped.
I'm afraid it's...
Buffy, I've read these things very carefully,
and there's not much margin for error.
- You understand what I'm saying?
- Might help if you actually said it.
Glory plans to open a dimensional
portal by way of a ritual blood-letting.
- Dawn's blood.
- Yes.
Once the blood is shed
at a certain time and place,
the fabric which separates
all realities will be ripped apart.
Dimensions will pour into one another,
with no barriers to stop them.
Reality as we know it will be destroyed and...
- chaos will reign on earth.
- So how do we stop it?
The portal will only close
once the blood is stopped.
And the only way for that to happen is...
Buffy, the only way is to kill Dawn.
Visiontext Subtitles: Yasmeen Khan
ENGLISH
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org